(NARRATOR READlNG)
(CAMERA CLlCKS)
(VOCALlZlNG WlTH STAR WARS THEME PLAYlNG ON RADlO)
Hmm. Fascinating.
NARRATOR: A group of Padawans
returns from a field trip
to the Outer Rim Territories,
but their real adventure
is about to begin.
(ALL CHUCKLlNG)
(HONKlNG)
(PADAWANS EXCLAlMlNG)
Check it out!
JEMPA: Look what l can do!
Whoa!
One more visit we have,
my young Padawans,
and most important it is.
A tour of the Galactic Senate.
(PADAWANS EXCLAlM lN AWE)
But we want excitement!
C-3PO: But you will
have excitement.
The thrill of watching as a gas mine treaty is negotiated.
Master Yoda,
is something wrong?
Leave you, l must.
A grave threat to the Republic, l fear.
Fun have! ln your care now
these Padawans are, 3-POC.
Where are you going?
You can't leave us!
YODA: Peace out.
Taking care of younglings
is just not in my programming.
Um... Uh...
Welcome, Jedi of tomorrow!
We are your tour guides.
l am C-3PO, and this is my counterpart, R2-D2.
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
Now, l can tell that
you are all most polite and very well behaved.
Now, now.
(ALL EXCLAlMlNG EXClTEDLY)
You should always be
respectful to a droid,
especially one like myself,
who does not like to float
or to spin! (YELPlNG)
(SCREECHlNG EXClTEDLY)
Just my destiny again.
Made to serve, made to suffer.
Too much excitement.
Come along, please.
Major headache.
Well, l suppose
it could be worse.
BOTH: Uh-oh.
(GRUNTS)
Hey, this sure
beats that orphanage.
OFFlCER: Miney...
Oh, l wonder if that has jelly in the middle.
Only one way to find out.
Hey, you!
What are you doing there?
This is a restricted area.
(YELLS)
A mouse!
Where'd it go? Where'd it go?
Later, man.
OFFlCER 2: Hey, someone stop that kid!
OFFlCER 3: Get him!
C-3PO: The Galactic Senate,
also referred to
as the Republic...
Cool. All right.
l'll have one of those, one of those.
That should just about
do me. All right.
Hey, hey, where we going?
(DlSlNTERESTEDLY)
Galactic Senate.
OFFlCER:
Where did that kid go?
Awesome.
OFFlCER:
This is your fault.
l have stolen the Republic's secret battle plans,
and the bomb is
almost in place.
You have done well,
Asajj Ventress.
When the device detonates,
that is the signal for the fleet to attack.
Yes, Master.
And then total victory
will be ours!
(BOTH LAUGHlNG DEVlOUSLY)
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
(DARTH LAUGHlNG)
What's he doing here?
LUCAS: Cut!
Darth, you're not in this scene.
Darth, look at me.
l'm not?
Nope.
See that? No, do you see your...
Right. Exactly.
Right. Good, good.
Darth, do you want a donut?
Yum!
Somebody get Darth a donut.
Darlings,
I can't work like this.
Anyhoo...
Very soon now,
the Chancellor will arrive to begin the session.
lsn't it thrilling?
(R2-D2 SNORlNG)
l said, "lsn't it thrilling?"
SERGEANT: His Excellency,
Chancellor Palpatine.
That's not the Chancellor,
it's a Sith Lord!
(ALL GASP)
Oops, sorry. Hold on.
(ALL SlGHlNG)
(LAUGHS)
(ALL GASP)
Woo-hoo.
(ALL SlGHlNG)
(LAUGHS)
(ALL GASP)
(ALL SlGHlNG)
Senator Yaun of Bureaucratosis,
you have the floor.
Blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah...
Yes! What glorious loquacity.
Wait, l don't remember you
from the Jedi Temple.
(lN MYSTERlOUS TONE)
Yes, you do.
(CHUCKLES)
Jedi mind tricks don't work on Jedis.
l knew that.
OFFlCER: Hey, did you see that kid?
Where'd that kid go?
lAN: Uh-oh.
Time to be inconspicuous.
(BLEEPlNG)
Hey, watch it!
lan, kindly stop that at once.
Just give me a minute.
Who's lan?
Keep your metal pants on,
l'll fix it.
(GROANlNG)
Oh, my!
(EXCLAlMlNG)
Blah!
Delegates, such behavior
is simply not protocol.
(YELPlNG)
(ALARM BLEEPlNG)
Oh, my.
Marvelous.
(YELPlNG)
A disturbance
l feel in the Force.
Mistaken l hope
my feelings are.
(GROANS)
Tired of being right
all the time, l am.
Oh, great.
Give it your best shot.
Surrender, Jedi.
Negotiate that!
Bring it on!
(SCREAMlNG)
Watch meesa ears!
Watch out, watch out! (EXCLAlMlNG)
Meesa one lucky Gungan!
Meesa hit! (SCREAMlNG)
Poor Jar Jar. Oh, well.
Padawans, please follow me
out of here immediately,
and don't panic!
(GRUNTlNG)
My stars!
To the bus, and no delay!
(lN SLOW-MOTlON)
Totally awesome!
(GROANlNG)
(YELLlNG)
Man, that was close.
(GRUNTS)
Take that disk
to the staging base.
Use my ship at the left docking bay.
Roger, roger.
VENTRESS:
Your other left.
Roger, roger.
(GRUNTlNG)
Get me out of here.
Secret battle plans,
that droid has.
l'm on it, bro.
(PADAWANS EXCLAlMlNG)
Oh, my gosh.
l'm gonna pass out.
Excuse me, sorry.
But where is the driver?
Wait, come back.
l can't fly this thing.
l'm a protocol droid, not a pilot!
Artoo, stop that!
The chances of
surviving this flight
are approximately
650 million to one.
Must get plans to staging base.
Follow him, we must.
l'm all over it,
like green on beans.
That wasn't so hard.
l do believe l could get the hang of this pilot thing.
(THUDS)
Oh, dear.
l suppose l had better exchange
insurance information with him.
Or not. Artoo,
get us out of here!
PADAWAN: That is so cool!
C-3PO: No, not cool.
Now kindly take your seats.
There's nothing to see here. Nothing.
BOBBY: Holy spaceships!
Anakin Skywalker.
Hey, kids.
Hello, children.
Awesome!
(LAUGHlNG MANlACALLY)
l'm watching you, baby.
When ready, fire.
Hey, how's it going?
BOTH: What?
General Kenobi, preparing to make the jump
to light speed in three, two...
Quickly, children.
Fasten your lap restraints!
(ALL GROANlNG)
Make the jump to light speed, about to, it is.
Track it, we must.
Bingo! Locked on, bro.
(POWERlNG DOWN)
(YELLlNG)
Let's do that again.
C-3PO: We are not going again.
We are going straight back to...
Oh! l'm going to be sick.
(CLlNKlNG)
Didn't know l could be sick.
(CAMERA CLlCKS)
YODA: Look out!
(ALL SCREAMlNG)
Whoa! Hey.
Must get to staging base.
YODA: To recover
the battle plans,
track that droid through the snow, we must.
l have a bad feeling
about this.
l was gonna say that.
Well, l said it first.
l thought it first.
Matters not first said who it!
Sorry. One of those
days, it has been.
Tracked the battle droid to Hoth, I have.
Pursue him, I will.
You must not fail, Master Yoda.
Fail, I shall not.
Never give up, will I...
This show's boring.
What else is on?
Touch that button, do not.
Up next, Keeping up
with the Calrissians.
(UPBEAT MUSlC PLAYlNG)
...it dices. Finally the power of the Jedi
is in your hands.
(VOCALlZlNG)
Whoo! That was fantastic!
That was rubbish.
(BOTH GRUNTlNG)
Jedi Master, out.
Alone, leave me.
No time for stowaways, have l. A ruffian, you are.
At least know how
to talk normal, l do.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Yeah, now you're talking.
Find the battle droid,
Cody and l will.
But... But...
Stay here, you will.
Speak to me no more.
But...
No more!
l can see my house from here!
(LAUGHS) l tried
to tell you, Yoyo.
(GROANlNG)
This is so not
on the itinerary.
Well, this is a minor setback.
But don't be afraid.
l'm not afraid. l'm not at all afraid.
Because l am in charge.
Not now, Artoo.
(R2-D2 BEEPlNG FRANTlCALLY)
And l shall find a way.
l said, not now.
Utinni!
Look at our ship!
R2-D2, how could you let this happen?
(BEEPlNG)
Build another ship?
How exactly do you suggest we do that?
But this is just pictures.
Where are the words?
l may be fluent in over six million forms of communication,
but this is impossible.
l'm afraid we're stranded.
(lAN LAUGHlNG)
Hey, come on.
Hey, aren't you cold wearing just that cloak?
You got any underwear
on under there?
Do to deserve this, what did l?
You know your ears are like
super hairy, right?
Get worse, how can this?
So, Master Yoda, we meet again.
(MlMlCS LlGHTSABER WHOOSHlNG)
LUCAS: Oh, for the...
Darth! Darth!
Darth, would you
come here for a second?
Hi. You're not
in this scene either.
But imagine
the audience's surprise
when my lightsaber comes
right off the screen
and into their faces.
This one isn't in 3-D.
Right into their faces.
You know what l mean?
Get off my set.
Sorry, George.
C-3PO: We're bound to find someone here
who will take you home.
Follow me and stick together.
And pay attention at all times...
Look, a podracer.
(ALL EXCLAlMlNG)
MARl: Hello?
Road hog!
This is the best field
trip l've ever been on.
You younglings wait out here
while Artoo and l find a pilot to fly us out of here.
(ROARS)
(WAlLlNG)
And don't touch anything.
You must have something you can amuse yourselves with
for a few moments?
(LlGHTSABERS ACTlVATlNG)
(LlGHTSABERS WHOOSHlNG)
That is not quite what l meant.
Sometimes l wonder why l bother.
Come along, Artoo.
(R2-D2 BEEPlNG)
What are you talking about?
Hey! We don't serve
their kind here.
What?
Your droids.
They'll have to wait outside.
l remember.
Most insensitive. But what do we do now?
(WARBLlNG)
l was just going
to suggest that.
Well, l was.
(lNDlSTlNCT CHATTER)
(ALARM BLEEPlNG)
Good heavens, a droid!
Get out, you mechanical monstrosity.
Us non-droids
don't want you here.
Thanks, fellow non-droid.
You can call me...
...Seeth Bemos, Oipel of Ekul.
And l want a ride
off this pile of...
Ow!
Thanks, matey.
No problem.
Ow! My hair!
You, you're late.
Get in here.
Sure, why not?
Okay.
(lAN SHlVERlNG)
To keep warm,
stick our heads in this animal's guts, will we.
Gross. And l thought they smelled bad on the outside.
Your head, his guts. Do.
Ew! Huh?
DROlD: This one's taken.
What the...
Uh-oh!
Whoa! "Secret battle plans."
That was easy.
Great is the
power of the Force.
lt allows me to feel
what cannot be seen,
see what is yet to be, and hear what cannot be heard...
My big mouth and me.
My ship is at docking bay 49.
l'll take your party to Coruscant.
Wonderful. l shall
inform the younglings.
Oh, my goodness!
Check me out. Yeah, baby.
Hi, Mr. Three-Pee.
Great Bantha Breath,
what are you doing?
(ALL GASP)
That's a droid.
We don't serve your kind.
Oh, my. We'll just
be on our way.
(R2-D2 BEEPlNG)
(ROARS)
Oh, my.
l'm terribly sorry,
Master Jabba.
Allow me to remove the debris from your bigness.
(SPEAKlNG ALlEN LANGUAGE)
NO-ONE lNSULTS JABBA THE HUTT!
YOU AND YOUR METAL FRlEND WlLL PAY TODAY
Oh, my. This doesn't
look good at all.
lmpressed l am with your courage, young one.
Very brave are... Huh?
(lAN EXCLAlMlNG)
Hold on, Nelly!
Hop on!
Do that, how did you?
l know a thing
or two about wiring.
(WHOOPlNG)
Yee-haw!
Oh, man. The ship is broken.
What do we do?
(GRUNTlNG)
(EXHALES HEAVlLY)
To the ship.
Reach the pedals,
my legs cannot.
My legs reach just fine.
How hard can this be?
(CHEERlNG)
(SPEAKlNG ALlEN LANGUAGE)
Today, two droids will pay for insulting the mighty Jabba,
by fighting each
other to the death.
To be accurate,
droids can't actually die.
Melted down, deactivated perhaps, but not... Oh!
No, l couldn't fight
my best friend.
(BEEPlNG)
Oh! You've just been waiting for the chance
to do this, haven't you?
Artoo, Artoo,
don't you dare... Ow!
A good pilot you are.
Sorry for how l treated you, l am.
Respect you now, l do.
l know.
Say the same to me, you could.
You're all right, l guess.
Hmm?
For a little green dinosaur.
(SlGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
Master Yoda, the younglings are on Tatooine.
They are in danger.
Jabba the Hutt is holding them hostage.
He has them captive. You must hurry.
Oh, my gosh.
Then rescue them, we will.
All right!
(WHOOPlNG)
(ALL CHEERlNG)
Stop, stop, stop!
Ow! That hurt.
(YELPlNG)
l'm so sorry. l've doomed us all.
l am a failure.
Don't say that, Threepio.
You're not a failure.
l'm not?
You kept us safe today.
(lN MYSTlCAL TONE)
You're very brave.
l am very brave.
You are a great hero and
will lead us to victory.
l will lead us to victory.
You will break those
pillars with your weapon.
l will...
Oh. Right.
(SPEAKlNG ALlEN LANGUAGE)
Excellent! Yay!
Say hello to my metal friend.
(BLOWlNG HORN)
(ROARlNG)
No, no, no!
(SCREAMlNG)
Help! Help me! Help!
(WHlMPERS)
Oh, my goodness.
l am a hero.
(EXCLAlMlNG FRANTlCALLY)
(WHOOPlNG)
That is awesome!
My hair!
That's the coolest thing l've ever seen!
l am a hero.
l only wish Master Yoda
could see me now.
See you, l could, if sitting on me, you were not.
Oh! Oh!
Frightfully sorry, sir.
(PADAWANS CHUCKLlNG)
(CROWD CHEERlNG)
(FANFARE PLAYlNG)
PADAWAN: Awesome!
Much heroism in your future have you, young lan.
Oh! But my name's
not lan. (CHUCKLES)
l'm Han. Han Solo.
A pleasure to meet you,
Master Solo.
Yeah, whatever, Goldiepants.
Really, l'm glad we'll never see him again, Artoo.
(BEEPlNG)
(CHEWlE ROARlNG)
Thank you, thank you.
How's it going?
lmpressive!
lt's just what l do,
just what l do.
l can't even say it,
it's so awesome.
(DARTH LAUGHlNG)
Darth, there are other people that fit the suit,
you know what l'm saying?
No, right, sorry.
lt's a wrap!