"I want to go to Mars.
"Not just to visit. I want to live there.
"Because then
I'd be living proof
"that life on
Mars was possible.
"Proof that
if we had to,
"mankind could make
a fresh start.
"We're in trouble,
and it's our fault.
"And we're running out of time
and Mother Nature doesn't negotiate.
"We can't give up. Not now.
"Mars is a planet ripe
and ready for life.
"Earth's resources
may be depleted,
"but there's one resource
we must never neglect.
"It's the most valuable
"and it's the one
without limits.
"Courage. "
I wrote those words...
I wrote those words
when I was 12 years old.
My letter to the White House.
Never did I imagine
the president
would read them aloud
to a nation
mourning the loss of yet
another crew of astronauts.
Never did I dream
that I would be proclaimed
an "Emblem of Fortitude, "
a "Young Man with
a Singular Vision. "
And the rest is, well...
It's not history.
Just the beginning.
So, here we all are.
Thanks to Genesis
Space Technologies,
in 20 hours the Magellan-61
will travel six astronauts
to Mars,
not to visit,
but to live there.
The first true
citizens of Mars!
From a childhood vision
to the greatest space endeavor
the world has ever attempted,
the settlement known
as East Texas, Mars.
Come on, say it with me.
Just add water!
Yes!
Well, whatever I am,
I cannot begin to compare
to these six heroes,
living examples of
courage without limits.
And on that note,
I would like to
hand things off
to the mission head
of this historic expedition,
Lead Astronaut Sarah Elliot.
Sorry if we only have time
for a couple of questions.
You know what it's like
the night before a trip.
Scott Hubbard,
Aerospace Times.
Miss Elliot,
how does it feel to sacrifice
the next four years of
your life to Mars?
It's not a sacrifice.
It's an opportunity.
I feel humbled,
excited, and grateful for
the chance to be a pioneer.
Miss Elliot,
aren't you scared,
given the history,
given the dangers?
Of course.
I'm scared that I might let
the mission down in some way.
I was taught that people who
took risks without fear were brave.
Well, far braver are
those that take risks
despite their fear.
Courage is fear that has said its prayers.
T minus ten.
Nine. Eight.
Seven. Six.
Five. Four.
Three. Two.
One. Zero.
Ignition.
Liftoff.
Liftoff for Magellan-61 .
Stand by for docking
to Mars transfer vehicle.
Magellan speed is good.
Watch your drift, Sarah.
Contact.
Not yet! Not yet! Not yet.
Manual capture is confirmed.
Let's go to Mars!
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Sarah, can I have a word?
What's up?
Show it to me.
We can't just turn
the mission around,
correct?
Doctor,
how's she doing, anyway?
You mean, aside
from being mortified?
She's fine.
Oh, this is a disaster.
Nathaniel, she's due
shortly after they arrive.
We need to get out
in front of this.
An astronaut
behaved irresponsibly
and NASA will make
a decision what to do
as soon as the baby's born.
Decision about what?
About when to bring them back.
Tom, there's
a bigger issue here.
Subjecting a fetus
to zero gravity during
its entire gestation. . .
It's uncharted territory.
We do not go to press.
We keep
this internal for now.
We need to gather
more information.
What are you saying?
I'm saying,
we go short-term contingency.
We have Dr. Loh deliver
the baby on Mars.
We keep this quiet.
We wait this out.
Sarah may have
behaved irresponsibly,
but she's no longer
just an astronaut
and it's not just
a Genesis decision.
She's a mother now.
It's her decision, too.
Big, deep breath. Push, push, push!
Good. All right, big, deep breath.
Here we go.
And, push, push ! Good.
Okay, good. Good job, Sarah.
Keep breathing.
You're doing great.
One final push !
Come on,
come on, big, deep breath.
Is he okay?
Well done.
He looks great.
Sarah. Sarah?
Sarah?
Her heart rate is dropping.
Hey, something's wrong !
It's postpartum preeclampsia.
Push two milligrams of lorazepam, stat.
Take it easy. Take him.
You got him? You got him?
Sarah, breathe.
She's still not responding.
Give her 20 milligrams of. . .
Hurry, she's coding.
Come on, Sarah, breathe.
How long?
30 minutes
without a heartbeat.
Stop. Stop.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
She's gone. She's gone.
She's gone.
Mr. Shepherd, are you there?
We lost her.
Okay. Here's what we know.
Two-thirds less gravity
will alter the child's
internal organs.
The heart will
simply not be conditioned
to have the strength to pump
in the Earth's gravity.
Bones will be brittle,
probably oversized.
The child would
never survive the trip
back to Earth.
Yeah, but, Nathaniel,
in the eyes of the world,
isn't this whole mission,
East Texas, an experiment?
And wouldn't we be forgiven?
Experiment?
Tom, this isn't a mouse.
This is not a monkey.
This is a human being.
And in the eyes of the world,
the lead astronaut of
the Genesis Mars Mission
not only got pregnant,
but died in childbirth,
sentencing a baby to a motherless
existence in outer space.
Imagine the bloody outcry.
East Texas runs on money,
science, good faith,
and above all, good PR.
We're not only talking
about a secret,
we're talking
about a cover-up.
It will bring
the company down.
Unless.
Unless what?
Unless we don't cover up,
we take full responsibility.
We face it head-on.
Tom,
I wanna be on
the next mission.
As a passenger?
Yes.
Nathaniel, for the love of. . .
Oh, here we go.
No, actually, he's right.
There would be
no better show of support.
Thank you, Alice. Exactly.
You can imagine
their morale right now.
They've just
lost their leader.
Nathaniel,
it is out of the question.
And you know it.
Am I missing something here?
Doctor, will you
enlighten Alice, please?
Hydrocephalus.
We found it on
Mr. Shepherd's
very first medical.
A congenital brain disorder.
It's basically benign.
Benign unless he wants
to go into outer space,
and then nobody knows. . .
And what if I'm willing
to take that risk?
Sorry. Not happening.
So the child remains on Mars?
I don't. . .
We don't have a choice.
Say we come clean
and we lose our financing.
Say we give up
everything we fought for.
Say we bring everyone home.
You heard the doctor.
The child wouldn't
even make the trip.
Keeping this a secret
saves the company,
which saves East Texas,
which saves the child.
So the child
remains classified?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Can I bring your car around,
Mr. Shepherd?
Entering stratospheric flight.
Entering exospheric flight.
Altitude limit.
- Approaching outer space.
- Yes!
Decrease velocity.
Danger. Over speed.
Danger. Danger.
All perish.
Ha! There you are.
Centaur,
can you make me a map?
And what is it you'd like
a map of, Gardner Elliot?
A pathway through
the ventilation system
from my quarters
to the storage facility
on East Texas.
And why would you
like that information?
That's none of your business.
It is my business.
I'm your best friend.
No. You're a machine
with rudimentary
artificial intelligence.
A machine which
I helped to build.
That hurts my feelings.
You don't have feelings.
I do have feelings.
I'm your best friend.
I'm your teacher.
I'm your homie.
Hug it out.
Get me a map of
the ventilation system.
Information classified.
I'm sorry.
No. I'm sorry.
Information classified.
Gardner, don't.
I'm your friend.
Gardner, stop.
Once upon a time,
deep in the 15-acre wood,
Frogsy found Owl
sitting on his doorstep.
The flood had
taken away his entire...
Centaur,
look who just bypassed
the East Texas infrastructure
firewall program.
Mission number.
We're running
out of time and...
''Mother Nature
doesn't negotiate.''
...doesn't negotiate.
Letter to the White House,
and he's 1 2 years old.
Blah, blah. . .
Sorry if we only have time...
Hey, Mom.
...for a couple of questions.
You know what it's like
the night before a trip.
To be continued.
Colony 52 Bravo,
report to
the automatic air lock.
Colony 52 Bravo, report to
You're late.
Hey, Kendra.
Hey.
What's up?
Have you seen this? I mean. . .
Just, uh, so cool. I mean. . .
Works better if you turn it on.
Right.
The irrigator on 23 is blocked.
By the way, I can't reach Centaur.
What have you done with him this time?
Are you checking up on me?
Here you go, Kendra.
Thanks, Tony.
No. I'm checking up on Centaur.
Yeah, who checks up on me.
You don't fool me, Gardner Elliot.
You never have.
Okay. Uh, 23 should be clear.
Really?
Thanks a lot.
Here.
Thanks.
Okay, get on 1 7 now.
We'll make you
indispensable yet.
What?
How can I be indispensable
if no one knows I exist?
Okay.
Open.
Play.
Virtual visit.
Hey! Come on!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Want it? Come get it,
get it! Go fetch!
You go fetch it!
Hey!
What would you do
without me?
I'm gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss you, too.
Come on.
Replay.
Memo.
Print.
Centaur, some privacy.
Again? All you ever ask for
is privacy these days.
I remember a time
when you and I...
Where's the code?
Hey, Tulsa.
Say it with me.
Why?
Because misery loves company.
Why are you miserable?
Just dealing with
the basic people of
the school.
You know, everybody's
always frontin'.
Nobody's ever real,
you know?
Tell me about it.
Anyway, the second I turn 18,
I am so outta here.
Emancipation...
"Emancipation,
mobility, music. "
Are you making
fun of me, Gardner?
No, Tulsa. I just wish
I could go with you.
You've been saying that
since last summer. And you can.
No, I can't.
Oh, right. You can't
leave your house.
It's not a house,
it's a penthouse
on Park Avenue.
I can't leave
because of my disease.
Osteogenesis Imperfecta.
Yeah.
Still don't believe you.
Wouldn’t your
foster dad be unhappy?
Yeah. No more checks
from the state.
Study lab is over. Gotta go.
See ya in
the funny papers.
What does that mean?
Hmm?
You always say that.
What does it mean?
I don't know,
I had a foster sister
in Oklahoma who used
to say it all the time.
Just a different way
of saying goodbye.
I like it.
Talk tomorrow?
I'm not going anywhere.
Where'd you get
this movie?
One of the German scientists
who was here last month
left it behind.
How do you know
what's going on?
Excuse me?
It's easy.
You see those men there?
They're angels.
They look over the people
on Earth and make sure
they're okay.
You see that angel?
Mmm-hmm.
He's gonna fall
in love with her
and fall to Earth.
You're a romantic.
Then he won't be
an angel anymore.
He'll be just like her.
Hey, Tulsa,
give us a ride, you slut!
I got a Harley
you can ride.
Tulsa! Come here!
Come back here, you slut!
Hey, boy!
What up, Chuck?
Don't get up 'cause of me.
''Hey, honey, how was your day?
Make any new friends yet?''
Oh, you bet.
Boy, am I fighting them off.
I'm the most popular girl
in my class.
Hey, did you get Thursday's check yet?
'Cause I wouldn't want you. . .
Wait a second, it's Thursday!
Hey, hey, Chuck! Chuck, wake up!
You gotta do the Sanders farm.
Hey, come on,
come on, wake up.
Listen to me.
You have one single property.
It's pretty simple, all right?
1 5 minutes, tops.
Okay, the starter.
Let's try the brakes.
It doesn't have brakes.
All right.
Now check the sprays.
Check.
Not while I'm standing
behind the plane!
Okay, we are gonna
lose another property.
You do it.
What?
You can fly this thing.
You do it.
Awesome parenting.
Seriously.
Risk my life for 1 90 bucks.
Good to know what
my life's worth to ya!
It's okay. I got ya.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're okay. I'm right here.
Are you insane?
Do you think
the exit protocol
doesn't apply to you?
You could've caused
an atmospheric breach,
not to mention, died.
Nobody rides unaccompanied,
no matter who they are!
Gardner,
what's going on here?
This isn't like you.
You wouldn't understand.
My mother's out there.
How did you get past
the electronic lock?
Okay, that magnetic implant
is there to monitor
the growth of your organs,
not serve as a passkey.
And how did you even
learn how to do that?
Raised by scientists,
in a bubble.
Open.
That plaque for
your mother,
it's just a piece of
metal in the ground, okay?
Her ashes were spread
across the Pacific Ocean.
You deserve to know that.
She's not out there,
Gardner.
She's in you.
I don't like to go to
sleep with us in a fight.
We're not in a fight.
Okay.
This is how you greet
an old friend?
If he's unannounced, yes.
It's about the boy.
Mr. Shepherd,
you have no idea
how smart he is.
He's being denied connection.
Not to do this,
at this point...
I'm sorry,
but it would be inhumane.
Miss Wyndham, I'm touched by
your concern, I really am.
But none of this matters
if he can't survive.
We've been through this.
For starters,
we would have to add carbon nanotubes
to strengthen
his bone density.
It's a very
complex procedure.
It's too risky. I'm sorry.
Tom, I can't sign on to this.
With all due respect,
Nathaniel, I'm not asking.
I'm telling.
You've been gone
for 1 6 years.
You've dropped off
the face of the Earth.
Have you run this by NASA?
NASA has always felt
conflicted over this.
They wanna do
the right thing,
which this is.
They wanna bring
the boy home.
Look, this is our chance
to turn bad PR into good PR.
Wait a minute,
this has nothing
to do with PR.
I'm talking about
a boy's life.
Hang on, hang on.
Like it or not,
I'm still the founder.
East Texas is still
my brainchild.
You know, you've got a lot
more faith in how the public
will respond than I do.
Gardner.
I have some news.
Guess what?
You're taking me
to Bora-Bora?
That was a joke.
As you were.
They may have found
a cure for my disease.
Okay, mine was closer
to the truth.
But mine is the truth.
It will involve
an operation.
And some physical therapy.
Pick it up,
pick it up, pick it up.
You got it. You got it.
Keep going. There you go.
Remember what
you're running for.
Assuming
all goes well,
I'm coming to see you.
Cool.
When is this happening?
In a few months.
There's a lot of
travel involved.
Well,
don't take forever.
Once foster care
spits me out, I'm gone.
See you in
the funny papers.
File 32,
human courtship.
Here we are.
Allow me, won't you?
Well, I guess
chivalry’s not entirely dead.
At least not in Nantucket.
Repeat.
Here we are.
Allow me, won't you?
Well, I guess
chivalry’s not entirely dead.
Chivalry's not entirely dead.
At least not in Nantucket.
Bravo. Well done.
Are you gonna visit
your ex-husband?
I hacked into
the scientist records.
Aren't you the clever
computer stalker.
Why'd you get divorced?
Well, he changed
when we found out I
couldn't have children.
Uh, did that make you sad,
that you couldn't have
children?
That's a tough one.
Meant I didn't have
to choose.
And, uh, motherhood
wasn't a dream I was
chasing at that time.
My father is somewhere
on that thing.
Earth.
We could go and find him.
We don't have
to tell him who I am.
I could just
see him, you know?
Maybe I could
ask for the time.
No one has to know.
Do you know
where he lives?
No.
His name?
Gardner, I promise,
I don't know
anything about him.
Nobody does.
How am I supposed
to act on Earth,
with the people?
Mr. Shepherd?
Your coffee.
Excuse me, sir.
Do you have
an appointment? Sir!
Tom !
Sir!
Nathaniel.
Stop!
What are you doing here?
I'm here to meet him.
Impossible.
No. No, what's impossible
is shuttling back
and forth to Mars.
What's impossible
is building
our salvation there.
But I made
those things happen.
So don't tell me
what's impossible.
Gardner?
Gardner, how are you feeling?
Water.
You okay?
It's water.
Are you thirsty?
No. No, there's. . .
Let's get this back on.
There's water everywhere.
All right.
I feel so heavy.
But light.
Is that normal?
I believe the term is "euphoria.''
Sorry about
the quarantine.
It's to protect you
from us, not us from you.
Same bubble, different planet.
Nothing's changed, has it?
Well, except that.
It's so blue.
And green.
There's so many colors.
I'm Nathaniel Shepherd.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
I just weigh so much.
I know who you are.
I want to be them.
That's funny.
Because they wanna be you.
I got so many questions
about Mars.
Not as many as
I have about Earth.
Oh, you'd be surprised.
I'll go first.
What's your favorite thing
about Earth?
Uh, rain. My turn.
What's your favorite
thing to do on Mars?
To pretend it's Earth.
My turn.
Did you see
my mother die?
No.
Yes.
Yes. I'm sorry.
What scares you?
You. You're very disarming.
Are you gonna keep
going out of turn?
Yes.
Can I stay on Earth?
I can't answer that.
Why rain?
Because it washes
everything clean.
Gardner. . .
Kendra.
Hello.
We meet in person.
Hmm.
How you feel?
Heavy.
So what's
giving me some concern
are these inconsistencies
in this last batch of tests.
What about blood?
Blood work is
virtually normal.
But if we're
going to be sure. . .
Virtually? Virtually?
Is that what we do
around here now?
Virtually?
Because I like to think
the importance of our work
subscribes more to "definitely.''
Meaning?
Meaning, troponin.
Testing for troponin
is my point.
Run the test for
troponin, please.
Troponin.
Troponin it is.
Hey.
They need to do more tests.
They already did their tests.
They said I'm fine.
I know. I know.
I'm more than fine.
Hey.
They're sending me back
to Mars, aren't they?
They didn't say that.
Well, they don't have to.
There's been a breach.
Where?
Quarantine.
Word of warning, guys.
These are the real deal.
The boots are weighted
for gravity compensation,
as if you were from Mars
returning to Earth.
It's going to feel
very different.
I don't believe this.
He's tipped the pressure!
Raised by scientists.
Lock it down.
This is not a drill.
There he is!
Where's that go?
Zone H. He's headed
to Service.
Relax. It's a dead end.
Okay.
He changed.
Okay, guys, check
the loading dock.
Thanks.
All right,
you can go.
I have to talk to you.
Gardner trusts me,
he doesn't trust you.
Kendra, give me a minute.
We need teams at
the Washington
Avenue Amtrak Station,
the airport, and cover
the bus stations, yeah?
You got it.
I'm coming with you.
Kendra, thank you,
but I am good.
State police are helping
with blockades.
They've been told
he needs a heart transplant
and a donor's suddenly
become available.
I promise I will
keep you updated.
You claim to be concerned
about Gardner's health,
but I think you care more
about keeping him secret.
You were saying?
It's one of
four ambulances.
Come on !
You found Waldo.
I'm Gardner.
This fire, it's so warm.
I like your shades.
I like yours.
You wanna trade?
Do you know
where Colorado is?
Used to.
Greyhound station's
about a three iron in
that direction.
Golf reference.
Do you play?
Used to.
What's your favorite thing
about Earth?
Dreaming. How 'bout you?
So far, uh,
meeting you.
Weird kid.
Oh, this is so cool !
Open.
Close. Open.
Open. Open, open.
Close.
What's your favorite thing
about Earth?
How do
we know for sure
he's going to see her?
Because she's
the only person
he knows on Earth.
Right. Read that to me.
Here she is. Uh. . .
She was left
at the Tulsa, Oklahoma
Child Welfare Services
when she was
four years old.
A girl named Tulsa
happened to be
abandoned in Tulsa?
It's a nickname.
Right.
She's lived in
five foster homes
over the last 1 2 years.
She know his story?
He told her
he was confined to
a Park Avenue penthouse
and had
Osteogenesis Imperfecta.
Brittle bones.
Put the address
in the Sat-Trac.
We'll land close,
but not too close.
I don't wanna spook him.
Hi.
Hi. Hello.
Get away from me.
Okay.
Gentlemen.
Tulsa? Tulsa.
It's me.
It's Gardner.
Ow! What was that for?
Why did you
ghost me like that?
Ghost?
Yeah, you completely
blew me off.
You didn't return
any of my messages.
I told you,
I was taking a trip.
For seven months?
People have phones,
you know?
You can text, email.
I couldn't contact you.
It was a very
specific type of travel.
Very specific type of travel?
Who even talks like that?
Tulsa, can you slow down,
'cause gravity is very heavy.
Oh, I'm sorry that
this is heavy for you, but
I really do not appreciate
being blown off
by the one person
who I don't. . .
Tulsa, I would
never ghost on you.
Okay,
I've actually gone through
quite a lot to get here.
The only person who what?
Who I don't hate.
You're taller than
I thought you'd be.
You're meaner than
What are you wearing?
This is so weird.
Look, I have a lab, okay?
So, I don't know.
Um. . . Can you just
stay here, all right?
Do not move, Gardner.
And those were the highlights
of the 1 9th century
Industrial Revolution.
Now, the 20th century
had some of
the greatest inventions. . .
Hello.
And you are?
Gardner.
Are you
a transfer student?
Okay.
Where are you from, Gardner?
East Texas.
I don't think
I have you on my roster.
Okay.
All right, folks.
Telephone, phonograph. . .
I told you
to wait for me.
. . .movie camera,
light bulb. . .
I've waited long enough.
. . .were all inventions
of one father.
Who is he?
Thomas Edison.
Good. Give me one fact
about Thomas Edison.
The dude was bad-ass.
Edison wasn't a bad-ass.
Excuse me?
Edison invented
direct current,
but it was Nikola Tesla
who invented
alternating current.
Edison got jealous
and claimed AC
electrocuted pets.
To prove it,
he electrocuted an elephant.
That's not bad-ass,
that's a bad person.
You see, folks?
You learn something
new every day.
Thank you, uh. . .
Excuse me.
That's our emergency
eye wash station.
Okay.
Oh, dear.
So the operation worked.
You're all better now?
Yeah. Yeah.
Tell me where
you're really from.
Mars.
You're from Mars?
Yeah.
All right, fine,
don't tell me.
Okay, look at this.
This is my mother.
She died.
I'm sorry.
What for?
It wasn't your fault.
It was mine.
I killed her.
But this is my father.
You're gonna help me find him.
I don't know
where he is, but. . .
Well, you have
your father's smile.
I found the house.
Route 1 4, latitude 40,
34 longitude.
All right.
You stay here.
Gardner!
Gardner, you need
to come with me now!
No.
We're here to help!
You're putting yourself
in great danger!
Why can't you just
leave me alone!
This is my life!
Gardner.
Gardner, please.
Come on,
just come with us. . .
I'm going to find my father.
He's all I have.
Is there
another way around?
That's not true.
You have me.
No, I don't.
Kendra, you told me yourself,
you don't want children.
Gardner,
that's not what I meant.
You know that.
You never
wanted children.
And I'm sorry you had
to raise me at all.
Hey.
Yeah?
I'll get the van.
You go.
Okay.
Go!
Duck!
Ah !
Sorry!
Okay. All right,
you're gonna need
to get in.
Hurry! Come on !
Gardner, let's go!
Go faster!
I'm trying to help him !
Just jump!
Come on.
All right, get in.
There you go!
All right,
you may wanna hop in.
Whoo-hoo!
No!
Gardner,
take a seat, please.
- Okay.
- Gardner!
There you go.
All right.
Come on !
You know how to
fly this, right?
Nope.
Wow.
Whoa!
Oh, no.
Ah. . .
The pressure!
I know, right?
No, Gardner,
the oil pressure!
All right, I got 'em.
My God,
they're landing
on a freeway.
Okay. All right, um,
it's gonna be a little tricky.
I usually have
a landing strip.
Coordinates.
I need coordinates.
Tulsa.
Tulsa, pull up! Pull up!
Ah. . .
Brake! Brake!
It doesn't
have brakes!
Whoa!
We're gonna have to jump.
Let's jump!
Oh, no.
Oh.
No.
Holy crap.
All right, we gotta go.
Come on. Come on.
No bodies.
What?
Are you sure?
Positive.
The fellas went through
the wreckage with
a fine-tooth comb.
They're alive.
Somewhere.
You had one job!
One job,
to protect Gardner!
To keep him
from making contact
with the outside world.
Preventing exactly
this kind of eventuality.
You're hanging this on me?
I admired you
more than anyone.
And you wanna know what?
We've been shouldering
East Texas for you.
For years.
What are you trying
to say, Kendra?
I'm trying to say
the whole mission
was your job,
your responsibility.
You just gave up.
And where were you?
Hey.
When's the Beemer
gonna be ready?
Later.
All right, well, can you
get the paperwork started?
Please.
Sir?
This is stealing.
Yeah, whatever.
It's wrong.
How do you suppose
we find your father?
You got the paperwork
on this BMW?
Okay.
You know, right and
wrong seem to change
when you really
need something.
Don't worry, I'll get it.
All right.
Friend of yours?
Where are we going?
Anywhere off the grid.
Disabling the phone.
Okay.
So, uh, Gardner,
when you said that
you killed your mother,
what exactly did
you mean by that?
She died giving birth to me.
That doesn't mean
that you killed her.
So, who's that guy?
He founded East Texas.
Where I'm from.
Well, I thought you said
you were from New York.
Who was the woman?
Kendra?
She's an astronaut.
Who you know from Mars?
Yeah.
You know what, get out.
Get out.
Get out!
I don't understand. . .
You know, I don't like
to be played, Gardner.
That's what it is. Mars?
Some weird disease?
People have been lying
to me my entire life,
which is whatever,
'cause people suck.
They suck. They lie.
They use you to
get what they want,
and then they just
throw you away.
And the thing is,
I didn't even like Calculus.
No, just Mr. Hall's
always drunk
and nobody can understand
what he's saying,
but he doesn't care
what we do on our computers.
Tulsa. . .
So that's what
I looked forward to.
Tulsa, I'm not. . .
To Calculus.
To talking to you.
So get out!
Tulsa, I'm not lying to you.
My mother was an astronaut.
She made a mistake.
I was born on Mars.
Just because people
lied to you before,
it doesn't mean I'm lying now.
And just because
something sounds
crazy to you,
doesn't mean it's not true.
So if you really
wanna get rid of me,
you have to get out.
Because I'm gonna
find my father.
You know, when people
talk to me that way,
they get their ass kicked.
Try it. I'm rockin'
this gravity.
Okay. Maybe you actually
believe it yourself.
What?
I'm sorry.
For what?
For people lying.
For people sucking things.
I'm sorry you're angry.
I'm not angry.
No.
Allow me, won't you?
What are you doing?
Chivalry's not dead.
At least not in Nantucket.
I'm on a road trip
with an insane person.
Whoa!
What is. . .
It's just a horse.
Come on, honey.
Let's go.
We should not
be doing this.
Well, we need a device
that's not being traced.
You wanna know where
your father is, right?
Okay.
Hey, it's unlocked.
Consider yourself lucky.
I consider myself
a criminal.
Okay.
Well,
there was a Sarah Elliot
who was an astronaut.
Yeah.
I'll give ya that.
It says
she died tragically
from pressure suit failure
shortly after arriving.
Well, I'm a secret.
Yeah. Of course you are.
And I'm an enigma.
Same person.
I know.
That's what I've been. . .
Damn it!
We lost connection.
Yup, they're
pretty cheap here.
Your best option
is disabling
all the decoys
and piggybacking off
the firehouse next door.
Right.
Oh, cool. Thanks.
Pay for my wrap
and I won't tell.
No, no, no, we don't
have money. I'm sorry.
We have money.
Great. Why don't
you say that louder?
We have money!
No, no. Sorry, sorry,
he doesn't speak sarcasm.
Here, take it.
My mother was wearing this
when she died.
It's some sort
of ring, I think.
It's like half a ring.
Part of a bigger ring?
There's words on it.
Let's see.
These words are
in Havasupai.
An Indian tribe
in Arizona.
Yup. It's signed.
Shaman Neka.
Gardner, I think this is
some kind of wedding ring.
And he married them.
That's Shaman Neka.
All right.
How far is Arizona?
Smile.
Oh, no.
Oh, not smiling.
Running. Come on.
Let's go.
Two teenagers
spotted last night.
We think
they're still in there.
Where is he?
- Sir, you gotta calm. . .
- Stop it!
What have. . .
Let her go!
- Hey!
- We got him.
Are you okay?
Nathaniel. Nathaniel.
Talk to me.
What's going on?
You're right, Kendra.
I gave up.
I withdrew.
And the greater
the pressure to reemerge,
the more I retreated.
As long as he was
just a face, on the screen,
I could almost handle it,
sentencing a boy to a life
he never asked for.
But it's like
the malignancy of any secret,
it just kept getting worse.
Every time I go
over it, what I did,
the choices I made. . .
I swear, I couldn't
have done anything else.
But that's not the point.
I dealt with the problem.
I just had no idea what
the solution would do to me.
It killed me.
And it's still killing me.
I need to make this right.
Yes.
Gardner's blood
has elevated levels
of troponin.
The news is
not good, Kendra.
Thank you.
Talk to me about troponin.
What?
Elevated troponin
and Gardner.
Oh.
His myositic pool
was depleted.
I read the chart.
It's not necessarily
a problem on its own,
but in conjunction
with elevated levels
of troponin. . .
He's suffering
from an enlarged heart.
His heart can't handle
our atmosphere.
Our gravity.
He's running out of time.
Is that a balloon?
Tulsa, there's a balloon !
Yeah.
Tulsa, there's a balloon
up there!
All right, all right.
Wow, it's huge!
Burgers and balloons.
You really gotta slow down.
That's your fifth?
These taste so good.
Hey, uh,
can you check in there,
just see
if there's any cash?
In here?
Yup.
Cowboys always
stash away a few bucks.
No, that's for your mouth.
You just gotta blow in it.
No, you gotta. . . Yeah.
There ya go.
So cool.
Nice.
There ya go.
Uh. . .
You got schmutz
on your face.
All right.
Thanks.
Yeah.
All right. Go change.
Relax, this place has
like a million stores
and a trillion dollars.
No, there are cameras. . .
All right,
all right, all right.
But, look, this is
the last of our money.
So, we'll buy the clothes,
then change.
Hey.
Break my heart
Break my hands
You can take anything
but my plans
I've got big things to do
You can laugh
Have your fun
I’ll be standing right here
when you're done
Oh, oh...
I've got big things...
Yo.
Is that your song?
Maybe.
It's beautiful.
Whatever.
What goes on in there?
I don't know.
Got us some sleeping bags.
Ready?
Yeah.
Oh, and I'm driving
this time.
In your dreams.
Excuse me, sir.
Play that again.
They're moving aimlessly.
Why New Mexico?
Both hands on the wheel.
Both eyes on the road.
Dude, do you have a problem?
'Cause you've definitely
been looking at me for
the last four hours
and it's starting
to freak me out.
You're so beautiful.
And then you blurt that out,
just like that? What?
Yeah. Why wouldn't I?
Uh. . . Because you may wanna
just play it cool, you know?
Ease yourself
into the love game.
But I do think
you're beautiful.
You're the most beautiful
girl I've ever seen.
Okay, just
slow your roll, kid.
You gotta calm down.
I don't wanna calm down.
And I don't understand
why this is making you
so upset.
Hey, first of all,
I'm not upset.
I am uncomfortable.
There's a difference.
Secondly,
people don't go around
saying what they feel
whenever they feel it.
They have guards and shields
and other metaphors.
Why?
Because we're all messed up
and scared and trying to be
something that we're not.
And if we all went
around just declaring
our innermost desires
to the exact people
we felt them for,
well, then we'd all end up
happy, or something.
Look, Gardner. . .
I'm happy that
you think I'm beautiful
and I've kind of had
an amazing time with you.
But the last thing I'm gonna
do is actually tell you that.
You just did.
You're blushing.
I'm not blushing.
Both hands on the wheel?
No.
What is happening?
This is. . .
I believe the term is "euphoria."
I got an idea.
Hail in the southern desert,
extending from Las...
Close your eyes.
How did you just
become more beautiful
in 20 seconds?
Do you wanna kiss me?
Yeah.
But I don't know how.
You will.
You don't understand.
On Mars, people,
they didn't do this.
We just had scientists
and they studied
ground samples.
Shut up, Gardner.
I thought about you
every day, up there.
I know
what's gonna happen.
What?
I'm gonna fall
in love with you
and I'll fall to Earth.
I'll be just like you.
That old line.
Okay, I'll shut up now.
No, no, no.
Hold that thought.
To myself?
All my life,
I couldn't feel anything.
I couldn't feel water.
I couldn't feel a fire.
I couldn't feel
wind on my face.
And now I can.
That's nothing compared to
what I feel with you.
I was so scared
I wouldn't know
how to be human.
You make me human, Tulsa.
Well, that's incredible.
I know, right?
It has so many legs.
Oh.
Everything's cool !
This is reservation property.
The tourist lookout
is 1 5 miles that way.
Yeah, we know. Um. . .
And we hope
we're not intruding,
but we're looking
for Shaman Neka.
Right on !
When you know, you know!
Know what?
I am not sure.
Come on !
I've married many couples.
Well, there were
no state records.
Um. . . Do you keep any?
I'd keep her.
What was her name?
Sarah Elliot.
Sarah.
So, I made this
ring 1 6 years ago.
Stop. Stop!
The other half of this ring
is with your father.
This is the check.
It doesn't say his name.
No, she paid.
That's her address.
Do you have that photo?
Do you mind if
I borrow your computer?
Not at all.
Okay, great.
Okay.
Summerland, California.
Huh.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I think this is it.
Yeah, one second,
I think that's. . .
We found it.
Well, let's go.
You look like crap.
You okay?
Yeah.
Do you know
where we're going?
Oh, yeah.
Paris, Venice,
and Cairo.
Hello. Checking in?
Hi. Uh, we just left
the keys in the ignition.
Checking in.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Well, you wanted
to see the world.
Here you have it.
It's like a big toy.
No, no, no, look.
That's Paris.
New York. Shanghai.
And look over there,
Venice.
It feels weird.
I mean,
it's not real, you know?
It's not
how I pictured it.
It's hurting my head
to see it like this.
Well, I'm sorry,
Gardner,
but the world doesn't
always give you exactly
what you want.
It gave me you.
All right, let me be
cynical for one second.
Tulsa, just because
your parents are gone,
it doesn't mean
you can't have a family.
We can be
each other's family.
'Cause this isn't. . .
This isn't real,
but we can be real.
Okay.
I think it's time to go.
Let's get you to California.
You hear what I said?
Whoa. Yeah, I did. Uh. . .
But, Gardner,
I think you're sick.
None of this was how it was
in my head.
You need to
go to the hospital.
Except you.
We need to get you
to a hospital.
Something's wrong with you.
Gardner. Gardner.
No, no! Gardner,
Gardner, Gardner!
You're okay,
you're okay.
Please help!
I wanna scan him.
Okay. Radiology, stat.
What's his name?
Gardner.
What's his last name?
I don't know.
Well, where's he from?
Uh. . .
I don't know.
What the. . .
Look at this.
I've never seen
anything like it before.
Oh, my God,
what is that?
His heart is
grossly enlarged.
I gave him
some valsartan, but. . .
It doesn't look good.
He wasn't lying.
Gardner.
Gardner, I have to go.
Social Services are coming.
But I'm gonna
go to Summerland.
I'm gonna find your father.
And I'm gonna tell him
how amazing you are.
How much you think about him
and how badly
you wanted
to go there. Okay?
I promise.
Hey. Hey.
- We need to go.
- No, no.
We need to go.
You can't. You can't.
You have to stay here.
Gardner.
Do you even know
why you're sick?
'Cause your heart's too big.
We are going to Summerland.
You can't.
They're gonna help you.
There's nothing they can do.
They can't. Don't you see?
No matter how much
I want Earth,
Earth doesn't want me.
Hold on a sec.
I'll get my bag.
Hang on, Pop.
Social Services.
Thank God.
They used a credit card
the owner left in the car.
They're headed north,
in California.
I know where they're going.
Good evening.
Gardner?
Gardner!
I'm not dead.
Scared me.
You act like you hate
the world so much, Tulsa.
Save your strength.
It's all an act.
The beautiful music you make
gives you away.
Gardner, we're here.
Hey.
Hey, we're here.
Will you help me?
Yeah, of course.
Help you what?
Just look better.
Here.
This is the best place
I've been so far.
You ready?
Yeah.
He's gonna love you.
Hello?
Hi.
Can I help you?
Now would be
a good time
to say something.
Um. . .
Where did you get this photo?
East Texas.
That's impossible.
My mother was Sarah Elliot.
She died giving birth to me.
Sarah Elliot died
from pressure suit failure.
That's not. . .
That's what
they said, but. . .
You're my father.
Is this some kind of scam?
No, he's not lying.
It's the truth, I swear.
I just wanted
to meet you.
Why are you doing this to me?
I'm not your father.
I'm calling the police.
Okay, just stay
right here.
Stop being a dick! Okay.
Look, he risked his life
to leave the one place
he's ever known, all alone,
didn't know anybody,
never set foot on this planet.
I mean, how scary is that?
What do you want from me?
I could never do that.
Look. . .
Just to meet you.
And he's dying.
I don't know who you are,
or why you're doing this.
I am not his father.
Well, then who are you,
because that is you
in the photo,
and that is this house.
Yes, this is the house.
Our parents left it to us.
Sarah Elliot was my sister.
Oh. You gotta get some help.
Please, get some help!
Gardner!
No, he's not
your father.
He's not your father.
He's your uncle.
It doesn't matter anymore.
There's no time left, Tulsa.
Okay, let's just go back.
He's gonna
call the ambulance.
You'll get better.
My mother's here.
I can feel her.
I didn't get to choose
where I was born.
But I get to choose
where I die.
Tulsa.
Yes, Gardner?
What's your favorite thing
about Earth?
You are, Gardner.
See you in the funny papers.
Gardner! Gardner!
No, no! Gardner!
No, Gardner!
No, Gardner, no!
I got him !
Kendra! Help me!
Okay.
Let's move him over.
- There we go.
- Turn him over.
Come on.
Okay, come on.
Gardner.
You can do it.
Gardner! Gardner!
Gardner, stay with me.
Don't leave us!
Come on. Come on.
What was she like?
My mother.
She was fearless.
She was kind.
And she just
seemed so invincible.
And she made me wanna
give up living when she died.
You loved her.
Yes.
You're my father.
There they are!
Hurry! There's no time!
I knew I would find you.
You're gonna be okay.
You're not alone.
Stay with me, Gardner.
Hurry!
It's taking too long.
His blood pressure's
dropping.
We have to get him
out of our gravity.
You have to take
the plane higher.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
You know I can't do that.
That's against
all regulations.
I'm taking control.
What are you doing?
I'm taking us into
the stratosphere.
Excuse me?
Yeah, don't worry.
She can handle it.
Although I warn you,
one of you may need
to take over.
One of us may need to. . .
Yeah, there's a chance
that I may die.
But you've done
this before?
Yes.
All the time.
Virtually.
Great.
Buckle in.
All right,
let's buckle you in.
Uh. . .
Yeah, just get ready.
Come on.
Grab this strap
right there.
I have the aircraft.
No, we gotta go higher.
Try and wake him up.
Gardner. Gardner,
wake up! Gardner!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Stay in. Stay in.
I've got him.
Are we on my planet?
No.
Are we on yours?
Are you ever gonna
stop slapping me?
You have to go back.
No, Tulsa, don't. . .
I hate it. I hate it.
But, Gardner, we both know
you have to go back.
I love you, Tulsa.
And I love you.
How's he doing?
Stable, for now.
It should buy us
the time we need.
And you? You okay?
Apparently.
This is good to know.
Uh-huh.
I'm gonna miss you, Gardner.
More than anything else
in the world.
Me too.
You're the best mom
I never had.
Safe travels, okay?
Oh, miss. Hold up, miss.
Hey!
Miss, you can't
go up there.
Nice ride.
Are you gonna be okay?
You're amazing.
And I had the time
of my life with you.
But the last
thing I'm gonna do is
actually tell you that.
You just did.
T-minus ten. Nine. Eight.
Seven. Six. Five.
Four. Three. Two.
One. Zero.
Ignition. Liftoff.
Same time tomorrow?
Works for me.
Tulsa.
You have a visitor.
Um. . .
Bye.
Gotta go.
Hey.
Hi.
So, as you probably know,
I've retired from NASA.
Well, not really.
I'm running
their training program now.
And it's been great.
I mean, getting re-accustomed
to living on this planet's
been a little trying.
Anyway, um,
I'm getting off track. Um. . .
Since I couldn't
spend any money on Mars,
and I was up there
for six years,
it turns out
I actually have a lot of it.
So, I bought a ranch house
in Boulder, Colorado.
Mmm.
I like to ski and
the people are really nice.
Yeah,
it's a pretty big house.
Gets lonely at times.
Would you like to
come live with me there?
Are you getting paid?
To take me?
Oh, God, no.
No.
'Cause I age out
in a month.
Who said anything
about only a month?
I wanted to go to Earth.
Not just to visit,
but to live there.
It turns out,
people from Earth
want exactly the same thing
as people from Mars.
And I should know,
because I'm pretty sure
I'm the only one.
So far.
I don't know which is better,
but here's what I do know.
It's good to be home.