Before time began, there was the Cube.
We know not where it comes from,
only that it holds the power
to create worlds and fill them with life.
That is how our race was born.
For a time, we lived in harmony,
but like all great power,
some wanted it for good, others for evil.
And so began the war,
a war that ravaged our planet
until it was consumed by death,
and the Cube was lost
to the far reaches of space.
We scattered across the galaxy,
hoping to find it and rebuild our home,
searching every star, every world.
And just when all hope seemed lost,
message of a new discovery drew us
to an unknown planet called Earth.
But we were already too late.
Oh, God, five months of this.
I can't wait to get a little taste of home.
A plate of mama's alligators étouffée.
You've been talking
about barbecued 'gators and crickets
for the last two weeks. I'm never going
to your mama's house, Fig. I promise.
But Bobby, Bobby, 'gators are known
to have the most succulent meat.
I understand.
English, please. English.
I mean, how many times have we...
We don't speak Spanish. I told you that.
Why you got to ruin it for me, man?
That's my heritage.
Go with the Spanish. Whatever.
Hey, you guys remember weekends?
Huh? The Sox at Fenway.
- Cold hotdog and a flat beer.
- Perfect day.
What about you, Captain?
You got a perfect day?
I just can't wait to hold my baby girl
for the first time.
- He's adorable.
- That's too...
Shut up!
Hey, I'm ready to do this.
Hey, any of y'all grow some balls,
come see me on the court, man.
Hey, hey!
Watch this crossover, baby.
Like Jordan in his prime,
pushing through the front line.
- Step aside, ladies.
- Oh, man. What?
- Lennox!
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Water?
- Thank you.
Are you gonna help me with the gear?
Colonel Sharp, we have an inbound
unidentified infiltrator, 10 miles out.
Unidentified aircraft, you are
in restricted US military airspace.
Squawk ident and proceed east
out of the area.
Raptors one and two, snap to heading
two-five-zero to intercept.
Bogie is in the weeds ten miles out,
not squawking.
Unidentified aircraft, we will escort you
to US SOCCENT airbase.
If you do not comply,
we will use deadly force.
Copy the bogie.
Tail 4500 X-ray.
Sir, says here 4500 X
was shot down three months ago.
- Afghanistan.
- That's got to be a mistake.
- Check again, then recheck.
- I did, sir.
A friend of mine was on that chopper.
Unidentified aircraft, we will escort you
to US SOCCENT airbase.
- Radar, where's the inbound?
- Bogie's five miles out, sir.
- My wife on?
- Yes, Captain.
- My ladies!
- Look.
Oh, my goodness. Look at her.
She's getting so big.
Look at those cheeks.
I just wanna chew on them.
Baby, we made a good-looking kid.
I know that people say that all the time,
but, wow, we made
one good-Iooking kid. Nice work.
She has your laugh.
- She laughed?
- Her first one, yeah.
You sure she didn't just fart?
No, she's a lady.
She doesn't know you yet, but she will.
4500 X. Something's not right.
Bogie's on the deck.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Radar's jammed.
It's coming from the chopper.
- Will?
- Sarah?
Hey, Sarah, if you can hear me,
I love you and I'll be home soon.
- To the right. Go to the right.
- Check fire.
MH-53 pilot, power down now.
Have your crew step out
or we will kill you.
Hold your fire! Stand by to engage!
My God.
They bombed the antenna farm!
We're under attack!
Go! Move! Move!
It's going after the files!
Cut the hard lines!
I need a key! It's locked!
Move! Move!
Here, come here! Come here!
Here, hide in here!
Oh, my God. Okay.
No!
Oh!
What the...
Epps, let's go!
Okay, Mr. Witwicky, you're up.
Sorry, I got a lot of stuff.
Watch.
Okay.
For my family...
Who did... Who did that?
People! Responsibility.
Okay.
So, for my family genealogy report,
I decided to do it
on my great-great-grandfather,
who was a famous man,
Captain Archibald Witwicky.
Very famous explorer.
In fact, he was one of the first to explore
the Arctic Circle, which is a big deal.
In 1897, he took 41 brave sailors
straight into the Arctic Shelf.
Move faster, men! Move! Chop! Heave!
The ice is freezing faster than
it's melting! Chop faster! Heave, men!
Heave! No sacrifice, no victory!
We'll get to the Arctic Circle, lads!
So that's the story, right?
And here we have some of
the basic instruments and tools
used by 19th-century seamen.
This here is the quadrant,
which you can get for 80 bucks.
It's all for sale, by the way.
Like the sextant here.
$50 for this, which is a bargain.
These are pretty cool.
These are my grandfather's glasses.
I haven't quite gotten them appraised
yet, but they've seen many cool things.
Are you going to sell me his liver?
Mr. Witwicky, this isn't show and sell.
It's the 11th grade.
I don't think your grandfather would be
particularly proud of what you're doing.
I know. I'm sorry. I just, you know,
this is all going towards my car fund.
You can tell your folks. It's on eBay.
I take PayPal.
Cold hard cash works, too.
And the compass makes a great gift
for Columbus Day.
- Sam!
- Sorry.
Unfortunately,
my great-great-grandfather,
the genius that he was, wound up
going blind and crazy in a psycho ward,
drawing these strange symbols
and babbling on about
some giant ice man
that he thought he'd discovered.
Okay. Might be a pop quiz tomorrow.
Might not.
- Sleep in fear tonight.
- Here, you want? Here, 50. 40? 30?
- Sam?
- Yeah. Sorry, sorry.
Okay. Pretty good, right?
I'd say a solid B-.
A B-?
You were hawking
your great-grandfather's crap
- in my classroom.
- No, kids enjoy...
- Look, can you do me a favor?
- What?
Can you look out the window
for a second? You see my father?
- He's the guy in the green car.
- Yeah.
Okay, I wanna tell you about a dream.
A boy's dream.
And a man's promise to that boy.
He looked at me in the eye.
He said, "Son, I'm gonna buy you a car.
"But I want you to bring me $2,000
and three As."
Okay? I got the 2,000 and I got two As.
Okay? Here's the dream. Your B-.
Dream gone. Kaput.
Sir, just ask yourself,
what would Jesus do?
Yes! Yes, yes.
So?
A-. It's an A, though.
Wait, wait, wait. I can't see. It's an A.
- So I'm good?
- You're good.
- I got a little surprise for you, son.
- What kind of...
Yeah, a little surprise.
No. No, no, no, no. Dad!
- Oh, you got to be kidding me.
- See?
Yeah. I am.
You're not getting a Porsche.
- You think that's funny?
- Yeah, I think it's funny.
- What's wrong with you?
- You think I'd really get you
a Porsche for your first car?
I don't want to talk to you
for the rest of this whole thing.
- Oh, come on. It's just a practical joke.
- It's not a funny joke.
- Manny!
- What?
Get your cousin out of
that damn clown suit.
He's having a heat stroke again.
Scaring white folks.
I'm hot! Makeup's melting.
It hurts my eyes.
Here? No, no, no, what is this?
You said... You said half a car,
not half a piece of crap, Dad.
When I was your age, I'd have been
happy with four wheels and an engine.
Okay, let me explain
something to you. Okay?
- You ever see 40-Year-Old Virgin?
- Yeah.
Okay, that's what this is.
And this is 50-year-old virgin.
- Okay.
- You want me to live that life?
- No sacrifice, no victory.
- Yeah, no victory. You know, I got it.
- The old Witwicky motto, Dad.
- Right.
Gentlemen.
Bobby Bolivia, like the country,
except without the runs.
How can I help you?
Well, my son here,
looking to buy his first car.
- You come to see me?
- I had to.
That practically makes us family.
Uncle Bobby B, baby. Uncle Bobby B.
- Sam.
- Sam, let me talk to you.
Sam, your first enchilada of freedom
awaits underneath one of those hoods.
Let me tell you something, son.
A driver don't pick the car.
The car'll pick the driver.
It's a mystical bond
between man and machine.
Son, I'm a lot of things,
but a liar's not one of them.
Especially not in front of my mammy.
That's my mammy. Hey, Mammy!
Don't be like that.
If I had a rock, I'd bust your head, bitch.
I tell you, man, she deaf, you know?
Well, over here, every piece of car
a man might want or need.
This ain't bad.
- This one's got racing stripes.
- Yeah.
It got racing...
Yeah, what's this?
What the heck is this?
I don't know nothing about this car.
- Manny!
- What?
What is this? This car! Check it out!
I don't know, boss! I've never seen it!
That's loco!
Don't go Ricky Ricardo on me, Manny!
Find out!
Feels good.
- How much?
- Well,
considering the semi-classic nature
of the vehicle,
with the slick wheels
and the custom paint job...
- Yeah, but the paint's faded.
- Yeah, but it's custom.
It's custom faded?
Well, this is your first car.
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
- Five grand.
- No, I'm not paying over four. Sorry.
Kid, come on, get out. Get out the car.
No, no, no.
You said cars pick their drivers.
Well, sometimes they pick a driver
with a cheap-ass father. Out the car.
Now, this one here
for four Gs is a beaut.
There's a Fiesta with racing stripes
over there.
No, I don't want a Fiesta
with racing stripes.
This is a classic engine right here.
I sold a car the other day...
Gee. Holy cow.
- No, no, no. No worries.
- You all right?
I'll get a sledgehammer and knock
this right out. Hey, hey, Manny!
Get your clown cousin
and get some hammers
and come bang this stuff out, baby!
... greater than man...
That one's my favorite,
drove all the way from Alabammy.
$4,000.
Steve.
Hello, Mr. Secretary.
They're so young.
They're the top
subject matter experts, sir.
NSA's recruiting right out of
high school these days.
Guys, that's the Secretary of Defense.
I am so underdressed.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Secretary of Defense.
Please be seated.
I'm John Keller.
Obviously, you're wondering
why you're here, so these are the facts.
At 1900 local time yesterday,
the SOCCENT Forward Operations
Base in Qatar was attacked.
So far as we know,
there were no survivors.
The objective of the attack
was to hack our military network.
We're not sure
exactly what they're after,
but we do know that
they were cut off during the assault,
which would lead us to assume
that they're going to try it again.
Now, no one's taken responsibility
for the attack.
And the only real lead we have so far
is this sound.
That's the signal
that hacked our network.
NSA's working at full capacity
to analyze it
and intercept further communications,
but we need your help
to find out who did this.
Now, you've all shown considerable
ability in the area of signals analysis.
We're on a hair-trigger here, people.
The President has dispatched
battle groups
to the Arabian Gulf and Yellow Sea.
This is as real as it's ever gonna get.
Now I'm gonna leave you
to your officer-in-charge.
You'll break up into teams
and you'll start your work.
Good luck to us all.
All right, Mojo. I got the car.
Now I need the girl.
I need money to take out the girl
is what I need.
Zero bids.
Great. Broke.
Come on, Mojo.
You want your pain pills?
No. Premature.
Good. What's up?
Nothing. You know, just driving my car.
Driving my car.
It's like clockwork.
All right, I know you get wasted
on these things,
but if you piss in my bed again,
you're sleeping outside. Okay?
That's it for today. No more. Crackhead.
- Ron, this one is uneven.
- Yeah. Probably.
This one is wobbly.
- Yeah. I'll take care of that real soon.
- Couldn't we have hired a professional?
- Sam...
- What?
I do not like footprints on my grass.
- What foot... There's no footprints.
- That's why I built my path.
So why don't you go from my grass
onto my path, okay?
- It's family grass, Dad.
- Well, when you own your own grass,
- you'll understand.
- This... I can't do it anymore.
- You're putting girl jewelry on a boy dog.
- What?
He's got enough self-esteem issues
as a Chihuahua, Mom.
That's his bling.
I want you home at 11:00!
- Yeah, all right.
- 11:00!
Please, for the love of God, drive safely.
Seat belt on!
Wow. You are so cheap.
Well, it's his first car.
Supposed to be like that.
At this time, we can't confirm
whether there were any survivors.
Oh, my God.
Our bases worldwide are, as of now,
at DEFCON Delta,
our highest readiness level.
We're dealing with
a very effective weapons system
that we have not come across before.
But our prayers are with the families
of the brave men and women...
Honey, Daddy's gonna be okay.
I've never seen a weapons system
like this.
The thermal shows this weird aura
around the exoskeleton
like it's cloaked
by some kind of invisible force field.
That's impossible. There's no
such thing as invisible force fields
except in, like, comic book stuff, right?
- Man, I don't know.
- What is that?
My mama, she had the gift, you know?
She saw things. I got the gene, too,
and that thing that attacked us?
I got a feeling it ain't over.
How about you use
those magic voodoo powers
and get us the hell out of here, huh?
When I took that picture,
I think it saw me.
It looked right at me.
All right, we got to get this thing
back to the Pentagon right away.
They got to know what
we're dealing with here.
My radio's fried.
- I got no communication with aerial.
- Hey, Mahfouz.
- How far do you live from here?
- Not far. Just up that mountain.
- Do they have a phone?
- Yes.
All right, let's hit it.
Dude, are you sure
we're invited to this party?
Of course, Miles.
It's a lake. Public property.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, dude, Mikaela's here.
Just don't do anything weird, all right?
- I'm good, right?
- Yeah, you're good.
Okay.
Hey, guys, check it out.
Oh, hi.
Hey, bro. That car. It's nice. Hey.
So, what are you guys doing here?
We're here to climb this tree.
I see that. It looks... It looks fun.
- Yeah.
- You know, I thought I recognized you.
You tried out for the football team
last year, right?
Let's go call your mom.
Oh, no, no, that... No.
That wasn't like a real tryout.
I was researching a book I was writing.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah? What's it about?
Sucking at sports?
No, it's about the link between
brain damage and football.
No, it's a good book.
Your friends'll love it.
You know, it's got mazes in it and,
you know, little coloring areas,
sections, pop-up pictures.
It's a lot of fun.
That's funny.
Okay, okay. You know what? Stop.
Hey, guys, I know of a party.
Let's go, let's head.
You got to get out
of the tree right now. Get...
Just get out of the tree
right now, please.
What are you doing?
Did you see that dismount?
All the chicks were watching.
You're making me look like an idiot.
We both looked like idiots just now.
- Hey, how about you let me drive?
- Oh, no. No, no, no. This is not a toy.
These 22s, I don't want you
grinding them. No.
Why doesn't my little bunny
just hop in the back seat?
God, I can't even tell you how much
I'm not your little bunny.
Okay.
You'll call me.
Who's gonna drive you home, tonight?
Hey, man, what's wrong
with your radio?
- I'm gonna drive her home tonight.
- What?
She's an evil jock concubine, man.
Let her hitchhike.
She lives 10 miles from here, okay?
It's my only chance.
You got to be understanding
here, all right?
All right. We'll put her in the back.
I'll be quiet.
- Did you say, "Put her in the back"?
- I called shotgun.
I'm not putting her in the back.
You got to get out of my car.
- That's a party foul.
- What rules?
Bros before hos.
Miles, I'm begging you to get out
of my car. Okay?
You can't do this to me.
You got to get out of my car right now.
Who's gonna come around
when you break?
Mikaela! It's Sam.
Witwicky.
I hope I didn't get you
stranded or anything.
You sure?
So, listen, I was wondering
if I could ride you home.
I mean, give you a ride home
in my car, to your house.
There you go.
So...
I can't believe that I'm here right now.
You can duck down if you want.
I mean, it won't hurt my feelings.
Oh, no, no, no.
I didn't mean here with you.
I just meant here, like, in this situation,
this same situation that I'm always in.
'Cause, I don't know, I guess I just
have a weakness for hot guys,
for tight abs and really big arms.
Big arms?
Well, there's a couple new additions
in the car.
Like, I just put in that light there.
And that disco ball. And so the light
reflects off the disco ball.
Yeah.
Are you new to school this year?
It's your first year here?
Oh, no, no.
We've been in the same school
since first grade.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Yeah, a long time.
Well, do we have any classes together?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Really? Which?
History. Language arts. Math. Science.
- Sam.
- Sam. Yeah.
- Sam Wilkicky.
- Witwicky.
God, you know what? I'm so sorry.
I just...
- No, it's cool.
- I just didn't recognize you.
Yeah, well, I mean,
that's understandable.
No, no, no. No. Come on.
Sorry, I'm just working out the kinks.
You know, it's a new car.
When I get that feeling
I want sexual healing
This radio is, like, you know...
It's an old radio, too, so...
Sexual healing
Look, this isn't something that I,
you know...
I can't get this radio to stop.
Look, I wouldn't try this on you.
'Cause this is like a romantic thing
that I'm not trying to do.
Not that you're not worthy
of trying something like this on.
- No, of course not.
- I'm a friend of yours.
I'm not a romantic friend.
Romantic friends do this.
I mean, I'm not that friend.
I mean, we... I could be.
I feel good
Just pop the hood.
Stupid. Shut up, shut up, shut up.
Whoa, nice headers.
You've got a high-rise
double-pump carburetor.
That's pretty impressive, Sam.
Double-pump?
It squirts the fuel in
so you can go faster.
I like to go faster.
And it looks like
your distributor cap's a little loose.
Yeah? How'd you know that?
My dad. He was a real grease monkey.
He taught me all about this.
I could take it all apart, clean it,
put it back together.
That's weird.
I just wouldn't peg you for mechanical.
Oh, my God.
Well, you know,
I don't really broadcast it.
Guys don't like it when you know
more about cars than they do.
Especially not Trent. He hates it.
Yeah, no, I'm cool with, you know,
females working on my engine.
I prefer it, actually.
- Okay. You want to fire it up for me?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, no problem.
- Thanks.
- You know, I was thinking.
You know, if Trent's such a jerk,
why do you hang out with him?
You know what? I'm just...
I'm gonna walk.
Good luck with your car.
All right.
Walking's healthy, right?
Oh, God, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on, please.
Please, you gotta work for me now.
Don't let her walk away. Come on,
come on, come on. Please, please.
Baby come back
any kind of fool could see
Hey!
There was something
in everything about you
Baby come back
you can blame it all on me
Hey!
Wait a second!
I was wrong
and I just can't live without you
There it is.
I had fun.
So, you know, thanks for listening.
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- You... You think I'm shallow?
I think you're... No, no, no.
I think there's a lot more
than meets the eye with you.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right, I'll see you at school.
All right.
That's stupid.
That was a stupid line.
"There's more than meets
the eye with you." Stupid.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God. I love my car.
Hey, guys, I think the other team
figured it out. Iran.
Come on, man. This is way too smart
for Iranian scientists.
- Think about it.
- What do you think, kid? Chinese?
No way. This is nothing like
what the Chinese are using.
This is Air Force One.
Level of flight, level three-three-zero.
We will hunt down this enemy.
And when we do,
we'll know just what to do with them.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Apparently, there are
very few survivors.
Yes, Mr. President?
Yeah, can you wrangle me up
some Ding Dongs, darling?
I joined the Air Force to bring the man
Ding Dongs. I'll be in storage.
Shoot.
Gross.
Do you hear that?
Are you getting this?
I think they're hacking
the network again.
Oh, my God. This is a direct match
to the signal in Qatar.
- Are you running a diagnostic?
- Should I be?
- Yes, you should.
- So I am.
Someone!
They're hacking into Air Force One!
We need a senior analyst.
- I think they're planting a virus.
- A virus?
- It's streaming right now.
- They are planting a virus
and stealing a whole lot of data
from your system at the same time.
Code Red. We have a breach.
Air Force One, someone onboard
has breached the military network.
I'm in the cargo hold. Clear. Clear.
- You got to cut the hard lines.
- What?
- Whatever they want, they are getting it.
- Sir?
Permission to take down
the Defense Network.
- Cut all server hard lines now.
Someone's tampered
with the POTUS mainframe.
What the...
Shots fired in the underdeck.
Repeat, shots fired.
Crew, prepare for emergency descent.
I want our President in that bunker.
And I don't want to discuss a damn
thing other till that becomes reality.
That's our first priority.
That's our only priority right now.
Air Force One is on the ground.
Oh, God. No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
That's my car!
No!
No, no, no, no.
Dad, call the cops!
Where you going with my car, buddy?
Where you going?
Hello? 911 emergency!
My car has been stolen!
I'm in pursuit! Right?
I need all units, the whole squadron.
Bring everyone!
No, don't ask me questions, all right?
My father's the head
of the neighborhood watch!
Oh, my God.
My name is Sam Witwicky.
Whoever finds this, my car is alive,
okay? You saw that?
Since this is my last words on Earth,
I just wanna say, Mom, Dad, I love you,
and if you find Busty Beauties
under my bed, it wasn't mine.
I'm holding it for Miles.
No, no, wait that...
Okay, that's not true. It's mine
and Uncle Charles gave it to me.
I'm sorry. Mojo, I love you.
No! No! No! No!
Oh, my God.
No, you're a good dog!
Good dog! Good dog!
Oh, my God.
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey! All right! Oh!
No! No!
Okay. Please, please don't kill me!
I'm sorry! Take the keys!
I don't want them! Car's yours!
Listen, listen, listen.
- Good, you're here.
- Let me see your hands!
- No, no, no! It's not me!
- Let me see your hands.
- The guy's inside.
- Shut up! Walk towards the car.
Put your head on the hood.
Whoever did this finally managed
to infiltrate our defense network,
which is what they tried to do in Qatar,
only this time it worked.
- What did they get?
- We still don't know.
- Talk to me about the virus.
- It's a Spider-bot virus.
We're not sure what it's going to do,
but it may cripple the system.
- Can we stop it?
- Every time we try an antivirus,
it adapts and speeds up.
It's like it's not a virus anymore.
It's become the system.
Obviously the first phase
of a major attack against the US.
The only countries
with this kind of capability
are Russia, North Korea, maybe China.
- I'm sorry, that's not correct.
- Excuse me, young lady.
I didn't see you standing there.
You would be who?
I'm just the analyst
who detected the hack.
Hold on. It was you? You did it?
- Her team.
- Sir, I was just trying to say,
they hacked your firewall in 10 seconds.
Okay. Even a supercomputer
with a brute force attack
would take 20 years to do that.
Maybe you can explain, then,
how our latest satellite imagery
shows North Korea
doubling its naval activity.
Maybe it's a precaution,
because isn't that what we're doing?
The signal pattern is learning.
It's evolving on its own.
And you need to
move past Fourier transfers
and start considering
quantum mechanics.
There is nothing on Earth that complex.
What about an organism?
A living organism?
Maybe some kind of
DNA-based computer?
- And I know that that sounds crazy...
- That's enough. That's enough.
We have six floors of analysts
working on this thing.
Now, if you can find proof to back up
your theory,
I'm gonna be happy to listen to you.
But if you don't get a filter
on that brain-mouth thing, you're gonna
be off the team. You understand?
Look, I can't be any clearer
than how crystal clear I am being.
- It just stood up.
Wow. That's really neat.
Okay, chiefie.
Time to fill her up. And no drippy-drippy.
What are you rolling?
Whippets? Goofballs?
A little wowie sauce with the boys?
- No, I'm not on any drugs.
- What's these?
Found it in your pocket. "Mojo."
Is that what the kids are doing now?
Little bit of Mojo?
- Those are my dog's pain pills.
- You know, a Chihuahua. A little...
What was that?
You eyeballing my piece, 50 Cent?
You wanna go?
Make something happen. Do it.
'Cause I promise you I will bust you up.
Are you on drugs?
Let's hope this telephone line works.
Hey, heads up!
Heads up! Hey! Heads up!
What the heck was that?
English, dude. English.
Whoa!
Watch out!
- Open fire!
- Contact! Contact!
Everybody, quiet. Settle.
Whoa, mother... What the hell is...
Get up! Get up! Come on!
Go! Move it!
Take cover!
Fig! Cover the rear!
Cover fire! Move it! Fig, cover the rear!
Epps! Cover the rear! Move it!
Come on! Give me a mag!
Where's your papa?
Papa!
Sir, we need... I need a telephone.
- Telephone, telephone, yes!
- Telephone!
Hey, I need a mag! Give me a mag!
- Cell phone!
- I don't know how to thank you.
Fire!
This is an emergency Pentagon call!
I need you to... Do you understand?
It's an emergency Pentagon...
I don't have a credit card!
Sir, the attitude is not going to speed
things up any bit at all.
I'm going to ask you to speak
into the mouthpiece very clearly.
I'm in the middle of a war!
This is frigging ridiculous!
Ammo!
I need a credit card!
- Epps! Where's your wallet?
- Pocket!
- Which pocket?
- My back pocket!
- You got 10 back pockets!
- Left cheek! Left cheek! Left cheek!
All right, keep shooting! Keep shooting!
Okay, it's Visa.
Also, sir, have you heard about
our premium plus
world-service gold package?
No, I don't want a premium package!
Epps! Pentagon!
Give me a status.
Sir, we're tracking a Special Ops team
under fire in Qatar.
They say they're survivors
of the base attack.
Survivors?
I ain't never seen this in my life!
Need gunships on station ASAP!
Predator's coming up in a minute.
We're linking the call
to the nearest AWACS.
Unknown, man. I don't...
Man, if you seen this shit...
Predator ETA two minutes.
Hey! Make way!
- What is that?
- I don't know.
We need air support
and we need it now.
Roll in strike package Bravo
on unknown target.
I authenticate Tango Whiskey
at time 0300 Zulu.
Attention, all aircraft. This will be
a danger close-fire mission.
Weapons, I just got a call
from Falcon Ops.
Who's closer to Kill Box One Alpha?
- Send the Hogs, sir.
- Okay, send the Hogs over
to Kill Box One Alpha.
It's a danger close...
Switch the Hogs to Kill Box One Alpha,
300 feet danger close.
Friendlies in the area.
Seven-man team
north of orange smoke!
Received Kill Box One Alpha.
Engage hostile.
Attack direction west!
You're clear and hot!
Strike, tell me status of Hog right now.
Hog One-One Dark Star status.
- Lennox! The heat's coming!
- Laze the target!
We got a beam-rider incoming!
Laze target!
- Ready! Heat's coming!
- What? Bring it!
Receiving radar jamming
in vicinity of target.
No frigging way
that thing's still not down.
Spooky Three Two, use 105 shells.
Bring the rain.
Be advised, ground team is requesting
105 sabot rounds.
Did we lose them?
Warthog One confirm visual
on friendlies.
Where's Fig?
- Fig? Fig?
- Oh, God!
- God damn it!
- Get a medic!
Get a medic!
- I'm sorry.
- Black Hawk...
We'll get a medic. Just hold on.
He's got a pulse.
We need a medevac. One man down.
Patient care category urgent.
Bring them home.
You get those men stateside right now.
I want them debriefed in 10 hours.
There's only one hacker in the world
who can break this code.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Wait! Stop!
I am sorry to bother you.
- Maggie?
- Listen, I need your help.
No! This is my private area,
my place of Zen and peace.
- Listen to me.
- Glen! Who is it?
Shut up, Grandma!
- What are you doing here?
- Just give me a break, will you, please?
Grandmama! Drink your prune juice!
- What level are you on, man?
- Six.
Oh, here come the matrix!
Here come the matrix!
Glen, seriously, don't you
want to see something classified?
Yeah. Get low.
- Here we go. Here we go. Double tap.
- Hey, I just paused it. I just paused it.
Hey. I need a moment.
- Please.
- Sorry.
Hey, man, save my game.
How classified?
Like "I will go to jail for the rest of
my life for showing you" classified.
Yes! One quick peek.
Special Ops got a thermal snapshot
of whatever hit the base in Qatar.
- I want to see it.
- Well, the imager was damaged, sir.
The rangers are en route
with the imager,
but we also have a security issue.
Circle logs indicate one of
the analysts made a copy
of the network intrusion signal.
The signal strength is through the roof.
Where did you say you got this?
It hacked the national military
air-guard frequency
in less than a minute.
- No way.
- Yeah.
Looks like there's a message embedded
in the signal. Let me work my magic.
"Project Iceman"?
- What's Sector Seven?
- Who is Captain Witwicky?
Are you playing
those video games again?
Cops! Cops!
FBI! Clear right!
Lock it down! Lock it down!
Cops!
Lock it down.
Wait! I'm just a cousin! I'm just a...
Get off my Grandmama's carpet!
She don't like nobody on the carpet!
Especially police!
It was an awesome spectacle here
an hour ago
when over 40 C-17 s lifted off
of this very base.
We're not told where they're going.
Morning, Mo.
The government has been very quiet
about what's going on but in our...
- Mojo. Mojo.
- They were headed directly
towards North Korea.
Stop with the barking, Mojo.
It's too early. Please?
Miles? Miles, listen to me. Listen.
- My car, it stole itself, okay?
- What are you talking about, man?
Satan's Camaro. In my yard.
It's stalking me.
Stop!
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, my God!
Sam?
Hi.
That was... That was really awesome.
- Well, it felt awesome.
- Are you okay?
I'm not okay, all right?
I'm losing my mind a little bit.
I'm getting chased by my car right now.
I got to go.
You know what?
I'm gonna catch up with you guys later.
Oh, great. Cops.
Officer!
Listen!
Oh, that hurt.
Listen to me!
Thank God you're here!
I've had the worst day ever!
I've been... I've been followed here
on my mother's bike! Right?
And my car's right there
and it's been following me here!
So get out of the car! No! Stop!
Oh, God. Okay, okay! Okay, all right!
Okay! I'm sorry! I'm...
I didn't mean to hit your car! Look!
Okay, look, look, look! Stop, stop!
Please! Okay,
what do you want from me?
Okay.
Oh, God, no! No!