- What?
- ... and the backup generator
- is just not gonna cut it.
- Do you have an arms room?
Megatron! Megatron! Megatron!
I'll bring security to the...
Get everyone to
the NBE One chamber now!
- The lights are out!
- Move it! Move it!
Let's go!
They're popping our generators!
Megatron melting!
16502. We're losing pressure.
Stand by! Set!
We're losing pressure!
The cryogenic system is failing!
We're losing NBE One!
Forty millimeter sabot rounds
on that table!
That's good. Get all the ammo you got.
Everything you can carry. Bring it.
You got to take me to my car.
You have to take me to my car.
He's gonna know what to do
with the Cube.
- Your car? It's confiscated.
- Then unconfiscate it.
We do not know what will happen
if we let it near this thing!
- You don't know.
- Maybe you know, but I don't know.
You just wanna sit here and wait
and see what happens?
I have people's lives at stake here,
young man.
Take him to his car!
Drop it.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Drop your weapon, soldier.
There's an alien war going on
and you're gonna shoot me?
You know, we didn't ask to be here.
I'm ordering you under S-Seven
executive jurisdiction.
S-Seven don't exist.
Right. And we don't take orders
from people that don't exist.
- I'm gonna count to five. Okay.
- Well, I'm gonna count to three.
- Simmons?
- Yes, sir?
I'd do what he says. Losing's really
not an option for these guys.
All right. Okay.
Hey, you want to lay the fate of the
world on the kid's Camaro? That's cool.
No, no!
Stop! You got to stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
No, no, stop, stop, stop!
Let him go! Let him go!
Are you okay?
They didn't hurt you, right?
Listen to me. The Cube is here
and the Decepticons are coming.
No, no, don't worry about them.
They're okay. Right?
They're not gonna hurt you.
Just back up a little bit.
He's friendly. He's fine.
Okay, come on. Put the guns down.
They're not gonna hurt you.
Here, come with me.
I'm gonna take you to the All Spark.
Okay, here we go. He doing something.
He doing something.
Oh, my God.
Message from Starfleet, Captain.
Let's get to it.
He's right. We stay here, we're screwed
with Megatron in the other hangar.
Mission City is 22 miles away.
We're gonna sneak that Cube
out of here
and we're gonna hide it somewhere
in the city.
Good! Right.
But we cannot make a stand
without the Air Force.
This place must have some kind
of radio link!
- Yes. Shortwave, CB.
- Right, yes.
Sir, you got to figure out some way
to get word out to them. Let's move!
In the alien archive, sir!
- The alien...
- There's an old Army radio console.
- Will it work?
- Anything's possible!
- Did you see that...
- All right, Sam, get it in the car!
Mr. Secretary! Get our birds in the air.
When we get to the city,
we're gonna find a radio,
and I'll have Epps vector them in, okay?
Affirmative!
Warning! NBE One
cryo-containment failing.
Check that backup system!
The cryo's failing! You got to bump up
the cryo! The cryo's failing!
Come on! Get out of here!
Heads up! Look out!
Set a perimeter around
the yellow vehicle!
- This way, this way, this way!
- Up there! Let's go!
I am Megatron!
- The Cube's okay?
- Yeah, it's fine.
Well, put the seat belt on.
Pour it on him!
I live to serve you, Lord Megatron.
Where is the Cube?
The humans have taken it.
You fail me yet again, Starscream.
Get them!
Come on, Mags!
Over here, sir!
Give me a minute. Give me a minute.
Come to me, Maxwell, come to me.
Plugged in there.
- We're hot! We're live!
- Where are the mikes?
Mikes?
This doesn't work without mikes,
Simmons.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Let's find them.
Kid, get in the chair!
Just get in the chair, all right?
- Okay, I'll sit. I'll sit.
- They steal everything out of this place.
How do we get the signal out?
How do we call the Air Force?
- Glen?
- Huh?
Can you hotwire this computer to
transmit a tone through the radio?
What good is that?
Morse code! You can use this
to transmit it through that!
Okay, I'll do it! Turn it around.
Okay, let's see.
Simmons, I need a screwdriver!
There's Optimus.
Almost done.
What the hell was that?
Barricade the door!
- Get something.
- Watch out!
Six, five, four, six, three.
Here! Put some rounds in!
Master search.
I got it! We're transmitting!
Send exactly what I say!
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
Burn, you little sucker! Burn!
"This is Defense Secretary Keller.
Get me NORTHCOM commander."
- Whoa!
What was that?
Authenticate emergency action.
Blackbird 1195...
Sir, I have an authenticated
air strike order from Sec Def.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- What?
It's the same cop!
Block them, block them, block them.
Oh, my God.
Cool, Mom!
This is so not good.
He's behind the pillar!
- Shoot that mother...
- Maggie, cover fire!
It's the Air Force! They're responding!
Sucker, burn!
Oh, shit!
Yes! They're sending F-22s to the city!
Raptors, let's scramble,
scramble, scramble.
Strike and Dark Star roll call.
Looking out the right side.
Push to Kill Box One Alpha...
- Come on, let's go! Mount up!
- Move out! Move out! Go! Go!
Here, I got shortwave radios.
Wait. What am I supposed to
do with these?
Well, use them! It's all we got!
This is like RadioShack dinosaur radios
or something, man.
I'm only gonna get 20 or 30 miles
out of these things.
Are there any aircraft orbiting the city?
F-22 at 12:00.
All right, I want planes for air cover
and get Black Hawks on station
to extract that Cube. You got it?
Air Force has arrived! Pop smoke!
Raptor, Raptor, do you copy?
We have you visual.
Green smoke is the mark.
Provide air cover and vector
Black Hawks for extraction.
It's Starscream!
Please tell me you copy.
Back up! Take cover! Bumblebee!
No, no, no, no, no! Move!
- Back up! Back up!
- Retreat! Fall back!
Incoming!
Anybody hurt? Everyone okay?
Clear the area!
Oh, my God.
Bumblebee? No. Your legs!
Your legs.
Here. Here, back, back, back, back!
You all right?
Please get up. Bumblebee? Get up!
Ratchet!
- What the hell was that?
- What are you talking about?
What do you mean, what am
I talking about? They shot at us!
F-22 pilots would never fly
below buildings.
That's alien. That ain't friendly!
You got to get up. You're okay.
You're okay.
Come on!
Army Black Hawk inbound
to your location. Over.
Alpha 273 degrees, 10 miles.
November Victor, 1.2 clicks north.
Move out! Let's go!
Let's go! Move!
I'm not gonna leave you.
Come on, Decepticon punk!
Oh, my God!
Concentrate your fire!
Come on. Come on.
Megatron!
It's Megatron! Retreat! Move! Fall back!
Fall back!
Get our guys out of the way!
Get out of here! Go!
Get them out of the buggy! Move out!
We need air cover down here now!
Sam, help me with this.
- That all you got, Megatron?
- Come here, little cretin.
You want a piece of me?
You want a piece?
No! I want two!
What's going on?
Sir! That tank thing's getting back up.
Oh, these things just don't die.
Oh, we're so dead.
- Wrap it around the head.
- Sam!
Where's the Cube?
- Right there.
- Okay.
And take that and wrap it around
the base and then put it
around his neck.
- Okay?
- Epps, get those Black Hawks here!
That building.
- Okay.
- What?
All right, I can't leave my guys back
there, so here, take this flare.
Okay, there's a tall, white building
with statues on top.
- Go to the roof. Set the flare.
- No.
- Signal the chopper and set the flare.
- No, no. I can't do this!
Listen to me! You're a soldier now!
All right? I need you to take this Cube.
Get it into military hands
while we hold them off,
or a lot of people are gonna die.
- You got to go. You got to go.
- No, I'm not leaving.
- You need to go. Go.
- No, I'm not leaving
till I get Bumblebee out of here, okay?
Army Black Hawk requested.
Immediate evac for civilian boy
with precious cargo.
Headed to rooftop marked by flare.
- Sam, we will protect you.
- Okay.
- Epps, where are those planes?
- Sam!
No matter what happens,
I'm really glad I got in that car with you.
Sam! Get to the building! Move!
- Decepticons, attack!
- Hit it!
- Cover fire!
- Move to cover!
Watch out!
- Girl, get that tow truck out of here!
- I'm going! I'm going!
Get out of here now!
Megatron!
Prime.
Humans don't deserve to live.
They deserve to choose for themselves.
Then you will die with them!
Join them in extinction!
Keep moving, Sam!
Don't stop!
No!
Sam, get to the building!
Give me that Cube, boy!
Did that jerk just dent my car?
You're not gonna get me.
You're not gonna get me!
I smell you, boy!
Maggot!
Oh, no!
I'll drive! You shoot!
This isn't going well!
Shoot! Shoot!
Nice shot.
- That tank is definitely dead now.
- All right, let's go! We got business!
Hey!
Hey! I'm over here!
We've got the boy.
Watch out!
Missile!
Hang on, Sam!
No! No!
Is it fear or courage
that compels you, fleshling?
Where do I go?
Give me the All Spark
and you may live to be my pet.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I'm never giving you this All Spark!
Oh, so unwise.
I got you, boy.
Hold on to the Cube!
- Oh, no. Oh, no!
- Disgusting.
Sam?
You risked your life to protect the Cube.
No sacrifice,
- no victory.
- Lf I cannot defeat Megatron,
you must push the Cube into my chest.
I will sacrifice myself to destroy it.
Get behind me.
It's you and me, Megatron.
No, it's just me, Prime.
At the end of this day,
one shall stand, one shall fall.
You still fight for the weak!
That is why you lose!
Fighter jets in 60 seconds.
We got friendlies mixed with bad guys.
Targets will be marked.
Hey.
Bring the rain. All right?
All right, let's kill these things.
- Move, move, move!
- Remember, aim low.
Armor's weak under the chest.
Target marked. Still waiting.
Time on target, 20 seconds.
F-22s, we're still waiting.
Move out!
Incoming!
Weapons armed. Status green.
Run! Move!
Second wave's on approach.
What is that? Break off!
- Copy.
- It's either a massive amount of...
Two, get a lock! Pop that guy!
Stay on him. Keep him in your sights.
Take him out!
Two's down!
I'll kill you!
Mine! All Spark!
Sam! Put the Cube in my chest! Now!
Sam!
No, Sam!
Hold up.
You left me no choice, brother.
Sam, I owe you my life.
We are in your debt.
Prime, we couldn't save him.
Jazz.
We lost a great comrade
but gained new ones.
Thank you, all of you.
You honor us with your bravery.
Permission to speak, sir?
Permission granted, old friend.
You speak now?
I wish to stay with the boy.
If that is his choice.
Yes.
Gentlemen, the President has ordered
Sector Seven be terminated
and the remains of the dead aliens
disposed of.
The Laurentian Abyss is
seven miles below sea level,
deepest place on our planet.
The massive depth and pressure there,
coupled with subfreezing temperatures,
would crush and entomb them,
leaving no evidence.
With the All Spark gone,
we cannot return life to our planet.
And fate has yielded its reward,
a new world to call home.
We live among its people now,
hiding in plain sight,
but watching over them in secret,
waiting, protecting.
I have witnessed
their capacity for courage.
And though we are worlds apart,
like us, there's more to them
than meets the eye.
I am Optimus Prime
and I send this message
to any surviving Autobots
taking refuge among the stars.
We are here.
We are waiting.
Can you shed any light on the recent,
so-called alien activity in the area?
Do you know what? I think that
if there was some sort of an alien
- infestation...
- Yeah.
They, the government,
would be the first to let you know.
The government would let us know.
- I mean, this is America.
- Yeah.
You know, that's how we know
we live in a free land,
because there's no secrets.
They'd say, "Hey! Duck and cover."
Your head is kind of a different size
than it is on television.