Oh, shit! Oh, shit, shit, shit!
Oh, God! Oh, shit!
It's a bad dream.
Are you username LadiesMan217?
I don't know what you're talking about!
Yeah.
Where is eBay item 21153?
Where are the glasses?
Get back!
Stop!
God!
What is your problem, Sam?
Okay, there's a monster right there!
It just attacked me!
Here he comes! All right, get up.
Get up and run! You have to run! Okay.
Sam, what is that thing?
- You have to get in the car. Get in.
- I don't want to.
- Get in the car. Trust me. Trust me!
- Sam.
Get in! Go, go, go, go, go.
Go, go, go, go!
Oh, God! We're gonna die!
We're gonna die!
No, we're not. No, we're not gonna die.
- Oh, my God!
- Trust me. He's a kick-ass driver!
Oh, my God! No!
We're gonna die!
Oh, my God!
We're locked in.
The car won't start.
At least we ditched the monster, right?
Okay.
Time to start.
He's got me! Oh, God!
He's going to kill me!
No. No, no, no!
Get off!
Kill it! Kill it!
Get it, get it, get it, get it!
Not so tough without a head, are you?
Here, come on.
What is it?
It's a robot.
But like a...
Like a different...
You know, like a super-advanced robot.
It's probably Japanese.
Yeah, it's definitely Japanese.
What are you doing?
I don't think it wants to hurt us.
It would have done that already.
Really? Well, do you speak robot?
Because they just had, like,
a giant droid death match.
- I think it wants something from me.
- What?
Well, 'cause the other one was
talking about my eBay page.
You are the strangest boy
I have ever met.
- Can you talk?
- XM Satellite Radio...
Digital cable brings you...
... Columbia Broadcasting System...
So you... You talk through the radio?
Thank you, you're beautiful.
You're wonderful, you're wonderful.
So, what was that last night?
What was that?
Message from Starfleet, Captain...
Throughout the inanimate vastness
of space...
Angels will rain down
like visitors from heaven! Hallelujah!
Visitors from heaven? What...
What are you,
like, an alien or something?
Any more questions you want to ask?
He wants us to get in the car.
And go where?
Fifty years from now,
when you're looking back at your life,
don't you want to be able to say
you had the guts to get in the car?
This car's a pretty good driver.
I know.
Why don't you go sit in that seat, there?
I'm not going to sit in that seat.
He's driving.
Yeah.
You're right.
- Well, maybe you should sit in my lap.
- Why?
Well, I have the only seat belt here.
You know, safety first.
- Yeah, all right.
- Right?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
There, see? That's better.
You know, that seat belt thing was
a pretty smooth move.
Thank you.
You know what I don't understand?
Why, if he's supposed to be, like,
this super-advanced robot,
does he transform back
into this piece-of-crap Camaro?
Whoa! Whoa!
Oh, see? No. Get...
No, that doesn't work. See?
Move it, you moron!
Great, now... See?
Fantastic.
Now you pissed him off.
That car is sensitive.
I mean, $4000 just drove off.
What?
This is you...
Oh, my God!
Come on, let's go.
This is the coolest thing I've ever seen!
Explosions everywhere!
This is easily a hundred times cooler
than Armageddon. I swear to God!
Fire, fire, fire, fire!
Whoa! Sweet!
Oh, dude, I hope this guy's got
asteroid insurance,
'cause he is so boned!
What is that?
There's something in the tree, dude.
No, there's something
in the thing by the tree!
Could you guys just give me
a space rock?
Excuse me, are you the tooth fairy?
Hey, sweetheart, what are you doing
out here by yourself?
Holy God! What happened to the pool?
Are you Samuel James Witwicky,
descendent of Archibald Witwicky?
They know your name.
Yeah.
My name is Optimus Prime.
We are autonomous robotic organisms
from the planet Cybertron.
- But you can call us Autobots for short.
- Autobots.
- What's cracking, little bitches?
- My first lieutenant. Designation, Jazz.
This looks like a cool place to kick it.
What is that?
How did he learn to talk like that?
We've learned Earth's languages
through the World Wide Web.
My weapons specialist, Ironhide.
- You feeling lucky, punk?
- Easy, Ironhide.
Just kidding.
I just wanted to show him my cannons.
Our medical officer, Ratchet.
The boy's pheromone level suggests
he wants to mate with the female.
You already know
your guardian, Bumblebee.
Bumblebee, right?
Check on the rep
Yep, second to none
So you're my guardian, huh?
His vocal processors were damaged
in battle. I'm still working on them.
Why are you here?
We are here looking for the All Spark.
And we must find it before Megatron.
Mega-what?
Our planet was once a powerful empire,
peaceful and just,
until we were betrayed by Megatron,
leader of the Decepticons.
All who defied them were destroyed.
Our war finally consumed the planet,
and the All Spark was lost to the stars.
Megatron followed it to Earth,
where Captain Witwicky found him.
My grandfather.
It was an accident
that intertwined our fates.
Come back!
I think the dogs have found something.
The ice is cracking!
Captain! Grab my rope, Captain!
I'm all right, lads!
Can we throw you a rope, Captain?
Megatron crash-landed
before he could retrieve the Cube.
Men! We've made a discovery!
He accidentally activated
his navigation system.
The coordinates to the Cube's location
on Earth were imprinted on his glasses.
How'd you know about his glasses?
- EBay.
If the Decepticons find the All Spark,
they will use its power to transform
Earth's machines and build a new army.
And the human race
will be extinguished.
Sam Witwicky,
you hold the key to Earth's survival.
Please tell me
that you have those glasses.
It's like
a self-regenerating molecular armor.
Look at the scorch mark
where the sabot round hit.
Melted right through.
Hey, aren't sabots hot-Ioaded for, like,
a 6,000-degree magnesium burn?
Close to it. It melts tank armor.
So this metal skin must react
to extreme heat.
- Heads up!
- Oh!
I thought you said
that thing was dead, man!
Strap it down! Strap it!
This thing is wicked.
All right, get on the horn
with Northern Command.
Tell them that our effective weapon
is high-heat sabot rounds.
Recommend we load them
on all the gunships. Go.
You want that piece?
Okay, Maggie, look. Let me break
it down to you how it's gonna happen.
They gonna come through that door
and be good cop, bad cop.
Don't fall for that, all right?
That's why I ate their food.
See, they put the plate of donuts
out here to test your guilt.
If you don't touch it, you're guilty.
I ate the whole plate.
The whole plate. Okay?
It's me and you.
They walk through that door,
you don't say nothing.
She did it! She did it!
She's the one you want! All right?
I was just sitting at home
watching cartoons,
playing video games with my cousin,
and she came in there.
- And then...
- Glen, you freak.
Hey! I am not going to jail for you
or anybody else!
I have done nothing bad my entire life!
Hey, man, I'm still a virgin.
Okay, so what?
I've downloaded a couple of
thousand songs off the Internet.
Who hasn't? Who hasn't?
- I promise!
- Glen, shut up!
No, you shut up! Don't talk to me!
Don't talk to me, criminal!
- Oh, sugar rush.
- This is... This is not his fault.
See? So can I go home now?
- Oh, okay. I won't.
- But just listen to me.
Okay, whoever hacked into your military
system downloaded a file, all right?
It was something about
someone named Witwicky
and some government group, right?
Named Sector Seven.
You have to let me talk to
Defense Secretary Keller
before you go to war
with the wrong country!
Whatever fell out of the sky
ended up right behind...
- What did he say?
- What?
- Did he hear it, too?
- Yeah, Jack heard it, too. Yeah.
- What does he think it is?
- He thinks it's a military experiment.
- What a knucklehead.
- Yeah, well, I think it's a plane.
Still no official word as to
what happened. You can see...
- Yeah!
- Call Sam.
- Yeah. Why?
- He should be home in 15 minutes.
Well, I'll call him in 15 minutes.
If you wait 15 minutes, he'll be late
and you'll have to ground him.
Well, I can't ground him
if he's not late, can I?
I need you to stay here, all right?
You got to stay here
and you're gonna watch them.
- Okay, okay.
- All of them.
- Do you hear what I'm saying?
- Yeah, okay, okay.
Five minutes, all right?
- Thanks for staying on my path.
- Oh, yeah. No, no, Dad. Hey!
The... Oh, the path. I'm sorry.
I forgot about the path.
I'm gonna sweep the whole thing
right now. How about that?
- You know, I buy half your car...
- Yeah.
...then I bail you out of jail and then
I just decided to do all your chores.
- The chores.
- Yeah. Life is great, huh?
Life... Life is fantastic, is how good it is.
It's so... Oh, the trash cans. Sorry, Dad.
I'm gonna do the trash cans now.
No, no, I don't want you
to strain yourself.
No, no, I won't strain myself, Dad.
- I'll do it.
- It would hurt my feelings if you do it.
- You sure? I don't mind, I don't...
- I promise...
No, no, no, I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna do the trash cans
and I'm gonna scrape the grill
and I'm gonna... I'm gonna sweep up
the whole house right now.
- Tonight, right now?
- Right now.
The...
I love you. God, I love you
just so much right now.
You know,
Mom wanted me to ground you.
- You're three minutes late.
- Right?
Oh, well, just another thing
you did for me, Dad,
because you're such a swell guy.
One more thing, huh?
All right, I love you!
Sleep good, handsome man!
What are you doing?
No, watch the path! Watch the path!
Watch the... Please, please, please.
No, no, wait. No, no, no! Oh, no!
- Sorry. My bad.
- Oh, I... You couldn't...
You couldn't wait for five...
You couldn't wait for five minutes?
I told you to just stay! Just stay! God!
- I told you to watch them. I told you.
- Okay, you know what?
- They seem to be in a little bit of a rush.
- Oh, this is bad. No!
Mojo, Mojo! Off the robot! God!
- Oh, wet.
- No, no, no, no, no! Easy! Easy!
Hold on! Hold! This is Mojo.
This is Mojo. He's a pet of mine.
He's a pet. Okay? That's all.
If you could just put the guns away...
- Put the... Put them away. Please.
- You have a rodent infestation.
- A what?
- Shall I terminate?
No, no, no, no.
He's not a rodent, he's a Chihuahua.
This is my... This is my Chihuahua.
We love Chihuahuas! Don't we?
He's leaked lubricants all over my foot.
- He peed on you? Bad Mojo. Bad Mojo!
- Bad Mojo!
I'm sorry.
He's got a male dominance thing.
That's all it is.
- My foot's gonna rust.
- All right.
Okay, okay.
- Shut up and go hide!
- Just hurry.
Autobots, recon.
I hope he's okay. He's in the kitchen.
Got some ice on his nose.
I had to slap him around a little bit.
You did not.
- You didn't even ground him.
- Almost, almost.
Where are they? No, no, no, no, no.
Come on, come on.
- What? What is this?
- Time is short.
- They really want those glasses.
- Come on. What are you doing?
- I'm gonna help you.
- Okay.
- Please hurry.
- Yeah, no, no. It's definitely gone.
- What do you mean?
My glasses were in the bag.
They were in the backpack
and now the backpack isn't here.
Well, they're gonna be pissed,
so what do you wanna do?
So what I think you should do is
you should...
You should check this whole...
This whole section here.
Just give it a clean sweep,
and I'll get the corner here.
Yeah, no, no, no. Not there.
That's my... That's my private...
- Sorry. That's nothing.
- You just...
- You just told me to look...
- I know,
but I didn't mean to look inside
of my treasure chest.
You should be way more specific
so I don't get in trouble in your room.
I'm already stressed out enough.
Okay. What now?
No. No, no. No, no, no.
This isn't hiding. This isn't hiding.
This is my backyard, not a truck stop.
Oh, God. Oh!
Okay, I saw it. The UFO landed
right here and now it's gone.
My moped's under there, man!
Who's gonna pay for that?
Sam? Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam.
- He's back here.
- I can't deal with this. I can't...
What? Oh, no, no, no.
- This is my mother's flower...
- Oops.
Okay, listen. You got to listen to me.
If my parents come out here
and see you, they're gonna freak out.
My mother's got a temper, okay?
We must have the glasses.
I know you need the glasses.
I've been looking everywhere.
They're not here.
They're definitely not here.
Keep searching.
I need you to be quiet for five minutes.
Ten minutes. Okay?
Please, I'm begging you. You got to...
You're making a racket.
I can't concentrate.
You want me to look and I'm hearing...
Calm down, calm down.
You got to do something here.
- Autobots, fall back.
- Thank you. Please, for five minutes.
Good? Good? Okay.
- Move!
- Get away!
What's the matter with you?
Can't you be quiet?
He wants us to be quiet.
Earthquake! Move, move, move, move,
move! Earthquake!
Judy! Judy, get under the table! Move it!
Duck and cover right now!
How did you get over there so fast?
Wow! That was tingly!
- You got to try that!
- Yeah, that looks fun.
- Sam?
- Sammy?
- What the hell is that?
- I don't know.
- Sam?
- That's weird.
- Sam!
- Ratchet, point the light.
- Come on, hurry.
- Listen, we got a major issue in here.
What's with the light?
You gotta stop the light.
What's going on? Turn it off.
You gotta tell him to shut it off.
- Shut it off.
- Sam, are you in there?
How come the door's locked?
You know the rules.
No doors locked in my house!
You know he'll start counting
- if you don't open the door!
- One more chance. Five...
Oh, dear.
- Four. It's coming off the hinges, pal.
- He's counting!
- Sam, just open the door.
- Three.
- Oh, my.
- Two.
- He's counting.
- Stand back.
- What's up? What's with the bat?
- Who were you talking to?
- I'm talking to you.
- Why are you so sweaty and filthy?
I'm a child. You know, I'm a teenager.
We heard voices and noises
and we thought maybe you were...
It doesn't matter what we thought.
What was that light?
No, what light? What?
There's no light, Dad! There's no light!
You got two lights in your hand!
That's what it is.
- Maybe it bounced...
- There was light under the door.
Look, you can't... You can't just bounce
into my room like that.
You got to knock.
You got to communicate.
- We knocked for five minutes.
- I'm a teenager.
- We knocked.
- You didn't knock.
- You were screaming at me, okay?
- No.
This is repression,
what you're doing here.
- You're ruining my youth, okay?
- Oh, for Pete's sakes!
You are so defensive!
Were you masturbating?
- Judy.
- Was I...
- No, Mom.
- Zip it, okay?
- It's okay.
- No, I don't masturbate!
That's not something for you
to bring up.
- That's a father-and-son thing, okay?
- Father-son thing.
I mean, you don't have to call it that
word if that makes you uncomfortable.
You can call it Sam's happy time or...
- Happy time?
...my special alone time...
- Stop.
- Mom.
- Judy, stop.
...with myself.
- Mom, you can't come in and...
- I'm sorry.
It's just been a weird night.
I've had a little bit to drink.
- No, no, Dad.
- Yeah, well, we saw a light.
Oh, parents.
I don't know where it was, but we saw it.
Earthquake! It's another one! Another
earthquake! Get in the doorway!
- Okay!
- Aftershock! Aftershock!
Oh, I hate these.
- Got to ride it out. Ride it out!
- Quick, hide.
- Hey, the lights are back on.
- Hide? What?
- Where?
- Come on, get out of that tub.
Can't you take safety seriously?
- Good Lord, this floor is filthy, Sam.
- Oh, oh, man! Man. Oh.
Oh, no! Look at the yard.
The yard is destroyed.
Judy? Better call the city.
We got a blown transformer!
Power pole's sparking all over
the place!
Oh, man. Yard's a waste.
Trashed. Gone.
- It's a wash. The whole yard.
- You're kidding.
The parents are very irritating.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Can I take them out?
Ironhide, you know
we don't harm humans.
What is with you?
Well, I'm just saying we could.
It's an option.
We heard you talking
to somebody, Sam.
- We wanna know who.
- Mom, I told...
Hi. I'm Mikaela.
I'm a... I'm a friend of Sam's.
Gosh, you're gorgeous.
Isn't that the prettiest girl?
- She can hear you talking, Mom.
- Thank you.
Oh, my goodness. I'm sorry you had to
hear our little family discussion about...
- Sorry that we're bugging you.
- Do you have my backpack?
- Come on, hon. Let's go.
- Oh, it's in the kitchen.
Oh, yes. Okay. Okay.
- Yeah.
- Your mom's so nice.
I want you to distract my parents
while I slip out and get these glasses
to them, okay?
- Ronald Wickity?
- It's Witwicky. Who are you?
We're the government. Sector Seven.
- Never heard of it.
- Never will.
Your son's the great-grandson
of Captain Archibald Wickity, is he not?
It's Witwicky.
May I enter the premises, sir?
Ron, there's guys all over the front yard.
What the heck is going on here?
Your son filed a stolen car report
last night.
We think it's involved in
a national security matter.
- They're ripping up my rose bushes!
- National security?
That's right. National security.
My God, Ron, they're everywhere.
There's guys in suits all around
the house! Look at this!
Could you stay off the grass?
Get me a sample
and some isotope readings.
They're pulling bushes out
of the ground!
Good Lord! They've got to get
their hands off my bush!
- Drop the bat, ma'am.
- Hey, hey, hey, that's my...
I'm carrying a loaded weapon.
But you'd better get those guys
out of my garden
or I am gonna beat the crap out of them!
Are you experiencing any flu-like
symptoms? Aching joints? Fever?
- No!
- What is this?
How you doing, son?
Is your name Sam?
- Yeah.
- Well, I need you to come with us.
Whoa, way out of line.
Sir, I am asking politely. Back off.
- You're not taking my son.
- Really?
You gonna try to get rough with us?
No, but I'm gonna call the cops
because there's something fishy
going on around here.
Yeah. There's something a little fishy
about you, your son,
your little Taco Bell dog and this
whole operation you got going on here.
- What operation?
- That is what we are gonna find out.
I think direct contact.
- Son?
- Yeah.
- Step forward, please.
- Just stand?
Fourteen rads.
Bingo! Tag them and bag them!
If you hurt my dog, I'll kick your ass!
Get me a sample on
that vegetation ASAP!
Sam! Do not say anything, Sam!
- Yeah.
- Not a word until we get a lawyer!
So,
LadiesMan217.
That is your eBay username, right?
Yeah, but, you know,
it was a typo and I ran with it.
What do you make of this?
My name is Sam Witwicky, okay?
And my...
Is that you?
Yeah, that sounds like LadiesMan.
Last night at the station, you told
the officer your car transformed.
- Enlighten me.
- Well, here's what I said, okay?
'Cause this is a total misunderstanding
that my car had been stolen...
- Really?
...from me, from my home,
but it's fine now because it's back!
It came back!
- Well, not by itself.
- Well, no.
Because cars don't do that
because that would be crazy.
That's funny. That is so funny.
So what do you kids know
about aliens, huh?
Oh, you mean, like a Martian?
Like what, E. T.? No.
- It's an urban legend.
- Yeah.
You see this?
This is an l-can-do-whatever-l-want
and-get-away-with-it badge.
- Right.
- I'm gonna lock you up forever.
Oh, God. You know what?
Don't listen to him.
He's just pissy 'cause he's got to
get back to guarding the mall.
You, in the training bra, do not test me.
Especially with your daddy's parole
coming up.
What? Parole?
- It's nothing.
- Oh, grand theft auto, that ain't nothing?
You know those cars my dad
used to teach me to fix?
Well, they... They weren't always his.
You stole cars?
Well, we couldn't always afford
a babysitter,
so sometimes he had to take me along.
She's got her own juvie record
to prove it!
She's a criminal. Criminals are hot.
That'd be a real shame if he had to rot
in jail the rest of his natural life.
It is time to talk!
Big! It's big!
Go, go, go, go!
- I can't see it! I can't see it!
- Shift your weight towards the front!
All right! All right!
You A-holes are in trouble now.
Gentlemen, I want to introduce you
to my friend, Optimus Prime.
Taking the children was a bad move.
Autobots, relieve them of their weapons.
Freeze!
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Give me those!
Whoa!
Hi, there.
You don't seem afraid.
Are you not surprised to see us?
Look, there are
S-Seven protocols, okay?
I'm not authorized
to communicate with you
except to tell you
I can't communicate with you.
- Get out of the car.
- All right.
- Me? You want me to get...
- Now!
All right, all right. Get out. Hey.
All right, I'm... I'm getting out.
I'm getting out. You see?
Very nifty how you put us down
without really killing us.
You're good with handcuffs, too,
now, huh?
How you doing?
- You weren't supposed to hear all that.
- How's it going, huh?
- Yeah.
- This is real.
Now, listen. If I choose to engage
with him, mum is the word, all right?
Sam, I have a record
because I wouldn't turn my dad in.
When have you had to sacrifice
anything in your perfect little life?
Big guys. Big guys with big guns, huh?
What is Sector Seven? Answer me.
I'm the one who asks questions
around here. Not you, young man!
- How'd you know about the aliens?
- Where did you take my parents?
- I am not at liberty to discuss it.
- No?
Hey. You touch me,
that's a federal offense.
Do-whatever-you-want
and-get-away-with-it badge, right?
Yeah. Brave now all of a sudden, with
his big alien friend standing over there.
- Where is Sector Seven?
- Wouldn't you like to know?
Hey!
Bumblebee, stop lubricating the man.
Get that thing to stop, huh?
- All right, tough guy, take it off.
- What are you talking about?
- Your clothes, all of it, off.
- For what?
For threatening my dad.
Little lady, this is the beginning
of the end of your life.
You're a criminal.
Let's face facts. It's in your gene pool.
Those are nice.
Now get behind the pole.
All right.
This is such a felony, what you're doing.
- I will hunt you down, okay?
- He'll hunt you down.
- Without any remorse!
- No remorse.
- Enjoy.
- Okay?
- We have got to alert everyone.
- They already know. Speaker.
Optimus! Incoming!
Roll out.
Okay, I'm picking up rad readings
under that bridge right down there.
Okay, I'm getting really good rad
readings. Forty-two and higher.
Up you get.
Okay, we're dropping in.
Really strong readings right down
below us. There he is.
Ship one and two, come on in.
That's it, right there.
Mark him, mark him.
Okay, there he is. 11:30. 11:30.
Right off the nose.
I got it. 12:00.
Okay, I'm tracking him. I've got him.
Got him going down the street.
Okay. Where'd he go, guys? I lost him.
Got no IR signature. Where'd he go?
Okay, I lost him. I lost him.
Okay, we're coming around.
Easy, you two.
No! No! No, Sam! Sam, don't drop me!
Sam, don't! Sam, don't! I'm slipping!
I'm slipping!
- Hold on!
- No!
Sam!
All right, we've got him pinned.
We've got him pinned in the river.
I'm in for the shot.
Stop! Stop!
Wait! No!
- Take the shot, get him.
- Take the shot.
No!
No! Stop!
Stop!
Get down on the ground! Get down!
Get down!
What? Okay.
Look, he's not fighting back!
Freeze it! Freeze it! Freeze it!
Stop hurting him!
Don't let him move!
I got him here!
No!
Happy to see me again?
Put him in a car
with his little criminal friend.
I want that thing frozen
and ready for transport!
Hang back. Let me check it out.
Optimus,
are we just gonna stand here
and do nothing?
There's no way to free Bumblebee
without harming the humans.
- But it's not right. He...
- Let them leave.
The Chinese and the Russians
are nearing our area of operations
in the western Pacific.
We feel like this could get
out of hand real fast.
But the next couple of hours
may just define his presidency.
US and Chinese task forces
approaching 100 nautical miles
of cruise missile range.
Tell the strike group commander that
he's not to engage unless fired on first.
- Yes, sir!
- Mr. Secretary?
Tom Banachek. I'm with Sector Seven,
Advanced Research Division.
Never heard of it. I'm a little busy, Tom.
I think you can see that.
- What's going on here?
- I don't know.
Sit rep! Talk to me!
- The whole room's gone down, sir.
- I can see that!
The virus was coded to shut us down.
- General?
- I'll take a seat.
What do you mean, "shut us down"?
They used our network to spread out
to the whole world.
The blackout's global.
We have no communications,
satellite and land lines are dead.
You mean to tell me that I cannot pick
up this telephone and call my family?
Mr. Secretary? I'm here under
direct order from the President.
You really need to see
what I have in the case.
You'll have to accept that
there are certain things
you won't understand right away.
Sector Seven is a special-access
division of the government
convened in secret under
President Hoover 80 years ago.
You may remember NASA JPL
lost the Beagle 2 Mars Rover.
We told them to report the mission
a complete failure. It wasn't.
Beagle 2 transmitted 13 seconds.
This was classified above top secret.
EDA ended at 170 hours, 48 minutes.
More than just a pile of Martian rocks.
This is the image from Mars.
Here's the image your
Special Ops team was able to retrieve
from the base attack.
We believe they are of
the same exoskeletal type,
and obviously not Russian
or North Korean.
Are we talking about an invasion?
We intercepted the message
from your Special Ops team.
These things can be hurt by
our weapons and now they know it.
That's why the virus shut us down,
so we can't coordinate against
their next attack,
which I would bet my ridiculous
government salary is coming soon.
Get word to our fleet commanders
over the National Guard frequency.
It's a shortwave radio channel.
It might be still working.
Tell them to turn their ships around
and come home. ASAP!
And inform all commands to prepare
for imminent attack.
Captain Lennox, we need you and
your team to come with us right now!
Let's go!
She's in here.
What's going on?
You're coming with me.
- You're going to be my advisor.
- Me, too?
Who's this?
- He's my advisor.
- He comes, too.
- So...
- What'd they get you for?
I bought a car.
Turned out to be an alien robot.
Wow.
Who knew?
Make a hole! Watch your back!
Please, let this work.
Fire it up, Optimus.
The code.
The code on these glasses indicates
the All Spark is 230 miles from here.
I sense the Decepticons
are getting ready to mobilize.
They must know it's here, as well.
What about Bumblebee?
We can't just leave him to die
and become some human experiment!
He'll die in vain
if we don't accomplish our mission.
Bumblebee is a brave soldier.
This is what he would want.
Why are we fighting to save
the humans?
They're a primitive and violent race.
Were we so different?
They're a young species.
They have much to learn.
But I've seen goodness in them.
Freedom is the right of
all sentient beings.
You all know there's only one way
to end this war.
We must destroy the Cube.
If all else fails, I will unite it
with the spark in my chest.
That's suicide.
The Cube is raw power.
It could destroy you both.
A necessary sacrifice to bring peace
to this planet.
We cannot let the humans pay
for our mistakes.
It's been an honor serving with you all.
- Autobots, roll out!
- We rolling!
Team attention! Present arms!
At ease. Captain, Sergeant.
Got your intel. Excellent work.
Thank you, sir.
What about the gunships?
They're being retrofitted
with sabot rounds now.
If they hit us again,
we'll be ready for them.
But it won't do us much good if we can't
get world communications back up.
Hey, kid.
I think we got off to a bad start, huh?
You must be hungry?
You want a latte? HoHo?
Double venti macchiato?
Where's my car?
Son, I need you to listen to me
very carefully.
People can die here.
We need to know everything you know.
We need to know it now.
Okay.
But first, I'll take my car, my parents.
Maybe you should write that down.
Oh, and her juvie record.
That's got to be gone. Like, forever.
Come with me.
We'll talk about your car.
Thank you.
The man's an extortionist.
All right, here's the situation.
You've all had direct contact
with the NBEs.
NBEs?
Non-Biological Extraterrestrials.
Try and keep up with the acronyms.
What you're about to see
is totally classified.
Dear God. What is this?
We think when he made his approach
over the north pole,
our gravitational field screwed up
his telemetry.
He crashed in the ice,
probably a few thousand years ago.
We shipped him here to this facility
in 1934.
We call him NBE One.
Well, sir, I don't mean to correct you
on everything you think you know,
but, I mean, that's Megatron.
He's the leader of the Decepticons.
He's been in cryostasis since 1935.
Your great-great-grandfather made
one of the greatest discoveries
in the history of mankind.
Fact is, you're looking at
the source of the modern age,
the microchip, lasers, spaceflight, cars,
all reverse-engineered by studying him.
NBE One. That's what we call it.
And you didn't think the United States
military might need to know
that you're keeping a hostile alien robot
frozen in the basement?
Until these events, we had no
credible threat to national security.
Well, you got one now.
- So why Earth?
- It's the All Spark.
All Spark? What is that?
Well, yeah, they came here looking
for some sort of cube-Iooking thing.
Anyway, Mr. NBE One here, AKA
Megatron, that's what they call him,
who's pretty much the harbinger
of death, wants to use the Cube
to transform human technology
to take over the universe.
That's their plan.
- And you're sure about that?
- Yeah.
You guys know where it is, don't you?
Follow me.
You're about to see our crown jewel.
Carbon dating puts the Cube here
around 10,000 BC.
The first Seven didn't find it until 1913.
They knew it was alien because of
the matching hieroglyphics on the Cube
as well as NBE One.
President Hoover had the dam built
around it.
Four football fields thick of concrete.
A perfect way to hide its energy
from being detected by anyone
or any alien species on the outside.
Wait, back up. You said
the dam hides the Cube's energy.
- What kind exactly?
- Good question.
Please step inside.
They have to lock us in.
Oh, wow.
What's that? Freddy Krueger done
been up in here or something?
Oh, no, man.
Freddy Krueger have four blades, man.
That's only three. That's Wolverine!
- Right? That's Wolverine!
- That's very funny.
Anybody have any mechanical devices?
BlackBerry? Key alarm? Cell phone?
I got a phone.
Nokias are real nasty.
You've got to respect the Japanese.
They know the way of the samurai.
Nokia's from Finland.
Yes, but he's, you know, a little strange.
He's a little strange.
We're able to take the Cube radiation
and funnel it into that box.
- Mean little sucker, huh?
- That thing is freaky!
Kind of like the itty-bitty
Energizer Bunny from hell, huh?
He's breaking the box.
Go! Go! Go!
Move!
Gentlemen, they know the Cube is here.
Banachek. What's going on?
Well, the NBE One hangar
has lost power...