[BELL RINGING]
[PEOPLE CLAMORING]
MASTER:
I warned you.
Did I not warn you what would come
of dealing with Dwarves?
Now they have done it.
They have woken the dragon!
They have brought an apocalypse
upon our heads!
BRAGA:
Come on. Quickly.
Quickly.
MASTER:
Faster now...
...I am trying to evacuate myself here.
Careful, man.
Never mind the books.
Get on! Get the rest of it.
ALFRID: But, sire, should
we not try to save the town?
MASTER:
The town is lost.
Save the gold!
BRAGA: You heard him. Get a move on.
GIRL: Da!
MAN 1: Come on.
MAN 2:
Pile them up!
[SMAUG ROARING IN DISTANCE]
We have no time.
We must leave.
BOFUR: Get him up.
FILI: Come on, brother.
- Come on. Come on. Let's go.
- I am fine. I can walk.
- Fast as you can.
- We're not leaving.
Not without our father.
If you stay here, your sisters will die.
Is that what your father would want?
[BARD GRUNTING]
BARD:
Open this door!
Do you hear me?
[PEOPLE CLAMORING IN DISTANCE]
MAN:
I can see him!
WOMAN:
Look!
[GRUNTING]
MAN:
Down here! Now!
FILI: Give me your hand.
BOFUR: Come on. We got to go.
Quickly now.
Hurry.
FILI:
Kili, come on!
MAN 1: It's around the corner!
MAN 2: Keep on going, man!
[PEOPLE CLAMORING]
MAN 3:
Dragon!
[SMAUG ROARING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[BARD GRUNTING]
Come on, come on!
Faster!
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
If only we could take...
...more of these people with us,
but they're hardly...
Worth it. I quite agree.
MAN: Help!
Help!
[ALL CLAMORING]
BOFUR:
Look out!
[WOMEN SHRIEK]
MASTER:
Move it!
Come on!
Faster!
My gold!
We're carrying too much weight.
We need to dump something.
Quite right...
...Alfrid.
[YELLS]
[GRUNTING]
Faster!
[YELLING]
[ALL CLAMORING]
[BELL RINGING]
[ROARING]
Poor souls.
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Da.
TILDA:
Da!
He hit it!
- He hit the dragon! He did!
- No.
He hit his mark!
I saw.
His arrows cannot pierce its hide.
I fear nothing will.
What are you doing?
FILI: Come back! Bain!
SIGRID: Bain!
BOFUR:
Bain!
Get back here!
FILI: Bain!
TAURIEL: Leave him.
We cannot go back.
Bain!
[GRUNTS]
Dad.
Bain! What are you doing? Why didn't
you leave, you were supposed to leave!
- I came to help you.
- No!
Nothing can stop it now.
This might.
Bain.
You go back.
You get out of here.
Now.
Dad!
No!
[YELLS AND GRUNTS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
- Stop, stop!
- Halt! Halt!
Who are you...
.....that would stand against me?
Now, that is a pity.
What will you do now...
...Bowman?
You are...
...forsaken.
No help will come.
MASTER:
Now's our chance! Go! Go!
Head for the open water!
Hmm.
Is that your child?
You cannot...
...save him from the fire.
He will...
...burn!
BARD:
Stay still, son.
Stay still.
SMAUG:
Tell me...
...wretch...
...how now shall you challenge me?
You have nothing left...
...but your...
...death!
[ROARING]
BARD:
Bain.
Look at me.
You look at me.
Little to your left.
That's it.
[ROARS]
BARD:
Bain! Hold on!
[GROANING]
What was that?
What happened?
It fell.
I saw it.
It's dead.
Smaug is dead.
GLOIN:
By my beard...
...I think he's right.
Look there!
[RAVENS CAWING]
The Ravens of Erebor
are returning to the Mountain.
BALIN:
Aye.
Word will spread.
Before long...
...every soul in Middle-earth will know...
...the dragon is dead!
[DWARVES LAUGHING]
GALADRIEL:
You are not...
...alone...
...Mithrandir.
[GALADRIEL SPEAKING IN ELVISH]
[ALL CLAMORING]
WOMAN 1:
Help me!
WOMAN 2:
Where's my baby?
MAN 1:
Please!
ALFRID:
Somebody help me!
Help!
[YELLING]
MAN 2:
Over there!
TILDA:
Da!
TILDA: Da!
Aah!
Why me?
[ALL GRUNTING]
KILI:
Tauriel.
FILI:
Kili!
Come on.
We're leaving!
They are your people.
You must go.
Come with me.
I know how I feel.
I am not afraid.
You make me feel alive.
I can't.
Tauriel.
[SPEAKS IN DWARVISH]
I don't know what that means.
I think you do.
[IN ELVISH]
BOFUR:
One more!
Keep it.
As a promise.
HILDA:
These are dry. You will need them.
WOMAN 1: Thank you.
Here.
Oi!
Give me one of them.
I will catch my death...
...in this cold.
HILDA:
Find your own!
You're not in charge now,
Alfrid Lickspittle.
That is where you are wrong.
In the absence of the Master...
...the power cedes to his deputy...
...which in this instance is my good self.
Now give me that blanket!
[GRUNTING]
Master's deputy?
Don't make me laugh.
You're a sneak-thief.
More like. I will be dead before
I answer to the likes of you.
Maybe that can be arranged.
I wouldn't go turning on your own, Alfrid.
Not now.
[GRUNTS]
- Da!
- Come here!
You're alive.
[BARD LAUGHING]
BARD:
It's all right, darling.
PERCY: It was Bard!
He killed the dragon!
I saw it with
me own eyes.
He brought the beast down!
Shot him dead...
...with a Black Arrow.
[ALL CHEERING]
MAN 1:
Thank you, Bard!
MAN 2: Good man.
WOMAN 2: Thank you!
MAN 3:
You have saved us all!
MAN 4:
Bless you.
All hail to the Dragon-Slayer!
All hail...
...King Bard!
I have said it many times.
This is a man of noble stock.
A born leader!
BARD: Do not call me that.
I am not the Master of this town.
Where is he?
Where's the Master?
HILDA: Halfway down the Anduin.
With all our coin, I don't doubt.
You would know.
You helped him empty the treasury.
No.
I tried to stop him.
MAN 5: Liar!
Cheat!
MAN 6:
You're a mongrel!
I begged.
I pleaded.
MAN 7:
Away with him!
MAN 8: Tar him!
I said, "Master...
...no!
[ALL SHOUTING]
Think of the children."
MAN 9:
Hang him!
"Will nobody think of the children?"
Ow!
MAN 10:
To the tree with him!
[ALFRID SCREAMING]
WOMAN 3: Hang him hard!
MAN 11: Take him down!
Enough!
Let him go!
[ALFRID THUDS]
Look around you!
Have you not...
...had your fill of death?
[ALFRID GRUNTS AND THUDS]
Winter is upon us.
We must look to our own.
To the sick and the helpless.
Those who can stand,
tend to the wounded.
And those who have strength
left, follow me.
We must salvage what we can.
What then?
What will we do then?
We find shelter.
BOFUR:
Hello!
Bombur?
Bifur?
Anybody?
BILBO:
Wait!
OIN: It's Bilbo!
BOFUR: He's alive!
Stop! Stop!
Stop.
You need to leave.
We all need to leave.
We only just got here.
I have tried talking to him,
but he won't listen.
- What do you mean, laddie?
- Thorin!
Thorin. Thorin.
He's been down there for days.
He doesn't sleep.
He barely eats.
He's not been himself.
Not at all.
It's this place. Ahem.
I think a sickness lies on it.
KILI:
Sickness?
What kind of sickness?
BILBO:
Fili.
Fili!
THORIN:
Gold.
Gold beyond measure.
Beyond sorrow...
...and grief.
Behold...
...the great...
...treasure hoard of Thror.
Welcome...
...my sister-sons...
...to the Kingdom...
...of Erebor.
Balin!
[ALL LAUGHING]
Kili!
BALIN:
Thank Durin, you're alive.
Bombur!
ORI:
You're alive!
THORIN: Any sign of it?
DWALIN: Nothing yet.
ORI:
Nothing here.
THORIN: Keep searching!
GLOIN: That jewel could be anywhere.
THORIN:
The Arkenstone is in these halls.
Find it!
DWALIN: You heard him.
Keep looking.
THORIN: All of you!
No one rests until it is found.
SMAUG:
I am almost tempted to let you take it.
If only to see Oakenshield......
...suffer.
Watch it...
...destroy him.
Watch it corrupt...
...his heart..
...and drive him mad.
MAN:
I have got you.
BARD:
Take only what you need.
We have a long march ahead.
[IN ENGLISH]
Where will you go?
There is only one place.
ALFRID:
The Mountain.
You are a genius, sire.
We can take refuge
inside the Mountain.
It might smell a bit of dragon,
but the women can clean that up.
It will be safe and
warm and dry...
...and full of stores...
...bedding, clothing...
...the odd bit of gold.
What gold is in that
Mountain is cursed.
We will take only
what was promised to us.
Only what we need to rebuild our lives.
Here.
Pull your weight.
News of the death of Smaug
will have spread through the lands.
Aye.
Others will now look
to the Mountain...
...for its wealth...
...for its position.
What is it you know?
Nothing for certain.
It's what I fear may come.
AZOG [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
BOLG [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
[IN ENGLISH]
You saw something out there.
The Orc I pursued out of Lake-town,
I know who he is.
Bolg, spawn of Azog the Defiler.
A Warg pack was waiting for him
on the outskirts of Esgaroth.
They fled into the North.
These Orcs were different
from the others.
They bore a mark
I have not seen for a long time.
The mark of Gundabad.
Gundabad?
An Orc stronghold...
...in the far North of
the Misty Mountains.
FEREN [IN ELVISH]:
[IN ELVISH]
[IN ENGLISH]
You may tell my father...
...if there is no place for Tauriel,
there is no place for me.
Legolas.
It is your king's command.
[IN ELVISH]
[IN ENGLISH] I ride North.
Will you come with me?
To where?
To Gundabad.
[GANDALF SPEAKING IN ELVISH]
[MUMBLING]
ORC [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
[ORC GRUNTS]
[SNARLS]
[ROARS]
[GALADRIEL GRUNTS]
SAURON [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
Nine...
...for mortal Men doomed to die.
SAURON:
I am not alone.
Are you in need of assistance, my lady?
[NAZGUL SNARLING]
You should have stayed...
...dead.
[ALL GRUNTING]
Mithrandir...
...come back.
[GASPING]
He is here.
Yes.
The darkness has returned.
RADAGAST:
Gandalf!
Climb on!
He is weak.
He cannot remain here.
It is draining his life.
Go!
Quickly!
Come with me, my lady.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Go!
[NAZGUL SCREECHING]
SAURON:
You have no...
...power here...
...servant of Morgoth.
You...
...are nameless.
Faceless.
Formless..........
Go back to the void...
...from whence you came!
[GRUNTING]
[GASPS]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[IN ELVISH]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
The spirit of Sauron endured.
And has been banished.
He will flee into the East.
ELROND [IN ENGLISH]:
Gondor...
...should be warned.
They must set a watch
on the walls of Mordor.
SARUMAN:
No.
Look after the Lady Galadriel.
She has spent
much of her power.
Her strength is failing.
Take her to Lothlórien.
My Lord Saruman.
He must be hunted down
and destroyed once and for all.
Without the Ring of Power...
...Sauron can never again
hold dominion over Middle-earth.
Go now.
Leave Sauron to me.
GANDALF: I need a horse.
RADAGAST: What?
Gandalf where are you going?
To warn Erebor.
They have no idea what is coming.
I saw them with my own eyes,
rank upon rank of Moria Orcs.
You must summon our friends,
bird and beast.
The battle for the Mountain
is about to begin.
THORIN:
It is here in these halls.
I know it.
DWALIN:
We have searched and searched.
THORIN:
Not well enough.
DWALIN: Thorin, we all would
see the stone returned.
THORIN:
And yet, it is still not found!
Do you doubt the
loyalty of anyone here?
The Arkenstone...
...is the birthright of our people.
It is The King's Jewel.
Am I not the king?
Know this:
If anyone should find it...
...and withhold it from me...
...I will be avenged.
[SIGHING]
Dragon-sickness.
I have seen it before.
That look.
The terrible need.
It is a fierce and
jealous love, Bilbo.
It sent his grandfather mad.
Balin, if Thorin...
...had the Arkenstone...
...or if, it was found...
...would it help?
That stone crowns all.
It is the summit of this great wealth...
...bestowing power...
...upon he who bears it.
Would it stay his madness?
No, laddie.
I fear it would
make him worse.
Perhaps it is best...
...it remains lost.
THORIN:
What is that?
In your hand.
It's... It's nothing.
Show me.
It...
I picked it up in Beorn's garden.
You have carried it all this way?
I am going to plant it in my garden.
In Bag End.
It's a poor prize to
take back to the Shire.
One day, it will grow.
And every time I look at it,
I will remember.
Remember everything that happened,
the good, the bad...
...and how lucky I am
that I made it home.
Thorin, I...
DWALIN:
Thorin.
Survivors from Lake-town...
...they're streaming into Dale.
There's hundreds of them.
Call everyone to the gate.
To the gate!
Now!
[CHATTERING]
BARD:
Come on.
Keep moving.
ALFRID: Sire!
Sire!
Up here!
Look, sire!
The braziers are lit.
So...
...the Company of Thorin Oakenshield
survived.
Survived?
You mean there's a bunch of Dwarves
in there with all that gold?
I shouldn't worry, Alfrid.
There's gold enough
in that Mountain for all.
Make camp here tonight!
Find what shelter you can.
Get some fires going.
PERCY: Come on, hurry along now.
BARD: Alfrid.
You will take the night watch.
BOFUR:
Up it goes!
DWALIN:
That's it.
I want this fortress
made safe by sunup.
This Mountain was hard-won.
I will not see
it taken again.
The people of Lake-town have nothing.
They came to us in need.
They have lost everything.
Do not tell me
what they have lost.
I know well enough their hardship.
Those who have lived through
dragon fire should rejoice.
They have much to be grateful for.
More stone.
Bring more stone to the gate!
DWALIN:
That's it.
[BABY CRYING]
MAN 1: These children are starving.
MAN 2: We need food.
MAN 1: We won't last three days.
PERCY: Bard...
...we don't have enough.
Do what you can, Percy.
PERCY:
It will be all right. Don't worry.
WOMAN:
We need more water.
The children, the wounded
and the women come first.
MAN 3:
Here you are.
BARD:
Good morning, Alfrid.
What news from
the night watch?
All quiet, sire.
Not much to report.
Nothing gets past me.
Except an army of Elves,
it would seem.
My Lord Thranduil, we did not look to see
you here. I heard you needed aid.
[CHATTERING]
Here you go.
MAN 1:
Pass it back.
MAN 2:
Another one.
BARD:
You have saved us.
I do not know
how to thank you.
Your gratitude is misplaced.
I did not come
on your behalf.
I came to reclaim
something of mine.
There are gems in the Mountain
that I, too, desire.
White gems of pure starlight.
The White Gems of Lasgalen.
I know an Elf Lord who will pay
a pretty price for these.
BARD:
Wait! Please wait!
You would go to war
over a handful of gems?
The heirlooms of my people
are not lightly forsaken.
We are allies in this.
My People also have a claim
upon the riches in that Mountain.
Let me speak with Thorin.
You would try to
reason with the Dwarf?
To avoid war?
Yes.
GLOIN:
Not a bad night's work.
Come on.
Hail, Thorin, son of Thrain.
We are glad to find
you alive beyond hope.
Why do you come to the gates of the
King under the Mountain armed for war?
Why does the King under the Mountain
fence himself in...
...like a robber in his hold?
THORIN: Perhaps it is because
I am expecting to be robbed.
BARD:
My lord...
...we have not come to rob you...
...but to seek fair settlement.
Will you not speak with me?
[CAWING]
I am listening.
On behalf of the
people of Lake-town...
...I ask that you
honor your pledge.
A share of the treasure so that
they might rebuild their lives.
I will not treat with any man...
...while an armed host
lies before my door.
That armed host will attack this Mountain
if we do not come to terms.
And your threats do not sway me.
What of your conscience?
Does it not tell
you our cause is just?
My people offered you help.
And in return, you brought upon them
only ruin and death.
When did the men of Lake-town come to our
aid but for the promise of rich reward?
A bargain was struck!
A bargain?
What choice did we have but to barter
our birthright for blankets...
...and food? To ransom
our future in exchange for our freedom?
You call that a fair trade?
Tell me...
...Bard the Dragon-Slayer...
...why should I honor such terms?
Because you gave us your word.
Does that mean nothing?
Be gone!
Ere our arrows fly!
[GRUNTS]
BILBO:
What are you doing?
You cannot go to war.
- This does not concern you.
- Excuse me...
...but just in case you haven't noticed,
there is an army of Elves out there.
Not to mention several hundred
angry fishermen.
We are, in fact, outnumbered.
Not for much longer.
What does that mean?
It means, Master Baggins...
...you should never
underestimate Dwarves.
We have reclaimed Erebor.
Now...
...we defend it.
He will give us nothing.
Such a pity.
Still...
...you tried.
I do not understand.
Why?
Why would he risk war?
[GRUNTING]
It is fruitless to reason with them.
They understand only one thing.
We attack at dawn.
Are you with us?
Aye.
THORIN:
Master Baggins, come here.
You're going to need this.
Put it on.
This vest is made of silver steel.
Mithril...
...it was called by my forebears.
No blade can pierce it.
I look absurd.
I am not a warrior,
I am a Hobbit.
It is a gift.
A token of our friendship.
True friends are
hard to come by.
I have been blind
but now I begin to see.
I am betrayed.
Betrayed?
The Arkenstone.
One of them has taken it.
One of them is false.
Thorin...
...the Quest is fulfilled,
you have won the Mountain.
Is that not enough?
- Betrayed by my own kin.
- Now, uh...
...you made a promise
to the people of Lake-town.
Now, is this treasure...
...truly worth more than your honor?
Our honor, Thorin. I was also there.
I gave my word.
For that, I am grateful.
It was nobly done, but the treasure in this Mountain
does not belong to the people of Lake-town.
This gold...
...is ours.
And ours alone.
By my life...
...I will not part...
...with a single coin.
Not...
...one..
...piece of it.
TAURIEL:
Gundabad.
What lies beyond?
An old enemy.
The ancient kingdom of Angmar.
This fortress was once its stronghold.
It is where they kept
their great armories.
Forged their weapons of war.
TAURIEL:
A light. I saw movement.
LEGOLAS:
We wait for the cover of night.
It is a fell place, Tauriel.
In another age,
our people waged war on those lands.
My mother died there.
My father does not speak of it.
There is no grave.
No memory.
Nothing.
Unh!
GANDALF: Let me through!
Make way!
[MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[MEN GRUNT]
ALFRID:
No, no.
No! Oi! You!
Pointy hat!
Yes.
You.
We don't want no tramps, beggars...
...nor vagabonds around here.
We got enough trouble
without the likes of you.
Off you go.
On your horse.
Who's in charge here?
Who is asking?
GANDALF: You must set aside
your petty grievances with the Dwarves.
War is coming!
The cesspits of Dol Guldur
have been emptied.
You're all in mortal danger.
What are you talking about?
I can see you know nothing of Wizards.
They are like winter thunder
on a wild wind...
...rolling in from a distance,
breaking hard in alarm.
But sometimes a storm is just a storm.
Not this time.
Armies of Orcs are on the move.
These are fighters.
They have been bred for war.
Our enemy has
summoned his full strength.
Why show his hand now?
Because we forced him.
We forced him when the Company of Thorin
Oakenshield set out to reclaim their homeland.
The Dwarves were never meant
to reach Erebor.
Azog the Defiler was sent to kill them.
His master seeks
control of the Mountain.
Not just for the treasure within but for
where it lies, its strategic position.
This is the gateway to reclaiming
the lands of Angmar in the North.
If that fell kingdom
should rise again...
...Rivendell, Lórien, the Shire
even Gondor itself, will fall.
These Orc armies you speak of,
Mithrandir...
...where are they?
RAG-ASH [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
AZOG [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
[RUMBLING]
[WERE-WORM ROARS]
TAURIEL [IN ELVISH]:
[SCREECHING]
LEGOLAS:
These bats are bred for one purpose.
[IN ENGLISH]
For what?
For war.
[SHOUTING IN BLACK SPEECH]
[HORNS BLOWING]
[IN ELVISH]
[SHOUTING IN BLACK SPEECH]
[ALL GRUNTING AND YELLING]
GANDALF: Since when has my counsel
counted for so little?
What do you think
I am trying to do?
I think you're trying to save your Dwarvish
friends, and I admire your loyalty to them.
But it does not dissuade me
from my course.
You started this, Mithrandir.
You will forgive
me if I finish it.
Are the archers in position?
FEREN: Yes, my lord.
Give the order.
If anything moves
on that Mountain...
...kill it.
The Dwarves are out of time.
You, Bowman!
Do you agree with this?
Is gold so important to you?
Would you buy it
with the blood of Dwarves?
It will not come to that.
This is a fight they cannot win.
BILBO: That won't stop them.
You think the Dwarves will surrender?
They won't.
They will fight to the death to
defend their own. Bilbo Baggins.
THRANDUIL:
If I am not mistaken...
...this is the Halfling who stole the keys to
my dungeons from under the nose of my guards.
Yes.
Sorry about that.
I came...
...to give you this.
The Heart of the Mountain.
The King's Jewel.
And worth a king's ransom.
How is this yours to give?
I took it as my 14th share
of the treasure.
BARD:
Why would you do this?
You owe us no loyalty.
I am not doing it for you.
I know that Dwarves
can be obstinate...
...and pigheaded and difficult.
They're suspicious and secretive...
...with the worst manners you can possibly
imagine, but they are also brave...
...and kind...
...and loyal to a fault.
I have grown very fond of them,
and I would save them if I can.
Now, Thorin,
values this stone above all else.
In exchange for its return, I believe
he will give you what you are owed.
There will be no need for war.
GANDALF:
Rest up tonight.
- You must leave on the morrow.
- What?
- Get as far away from here as possible.
- I am not leaving.
You picked me as the 14th man.
I am not about to leave the Company now.
There is no Company.
Not anymore.
And I don't like to think what Thorin
will do when he finds out what you have done.
I am not afraid of Thorin.
Well, you should be.
Don't underestimate the evil of gold.
Gold over which
a serpent has long brooded.
Dragon-sickness seeps into the hearts
of all who come near this Mountain.
Almost all.
Heh.
You there.
Find this Hobbit a bed...
...and fill his belly with hot food.
He's earned it.
Hey.
Keep an eye on him.
If he should try to leave, you tell me.
ALFRID:
Move it!
Stupid Hobbit.
Wakey-wakey, Hobbit.
Up you get.
I will put the next
one between your eyes.
[ALL SHOUTING]
We have come to tell you...
...payment of your debt has been offered...
...and accepted.
THORIN:
What payment?
I gave you nothing.
You have nothing.
We have this.
KILI:
They have the Arkenstone.
Thieves!
How came you by the heirloom
of our house?
That stone belongs to the king!
And the king may have it...
...with our goodwill.
But first he must
honor his word.
They are taking us for fools.
This is a ruse.
A filthy lie.
The Arkenstone is in this Mountain!
It is a trick!
BILBO: It is no trick.
The stone is real.
I gave it to them.
You?
I took it as my 14th share.
You would steal from me?
Steal from you?
No.
No, I may be a burglar,
but I like to think I am an honest one.
I am willing to let it stand
against my claim.
Against your claim?
Your claim.
You have no claim over me,
you miserable rat!
I was going to give it to you.
- Many times I wanted to, but...
- But what thief?
You are changed, Thorin.
The Dwarf I met in Bag End would
never have gone back on his word.
Would never have doubted
the loyalty of his kin!
Do not speak to me of loyalty.
Throw him from the rampart!
Did you not hear me?
I will do it myself.
Curse you!
No! Cursed be the Wizard that forced you on this
company. If you don't like my burglar, then please...
...don't damage him.
Return him to me.
You're not making a very splendid figure
as King under the Mountain, are you, Thorin...
...son of Thrain?
THORIN: Never again will I have dealings
with Wizards!
Go.
Or Shire rats!
BARD:
Are we resolved?
The return of the Arkenstone
for what was promised?
Give us your answer.
Will you have peace...
...or war?
[CAWS]
I will have war.
[RUMBLING]
Ironfoot.
[ALL SHOUTING]
[SHOUTS IN ELVISH]
Who is that?
He doesn't look very happy.
It is Dain, Lord of the Iron Hills.
Thorin's cousin.
Are they alike?
I have always found Thorin
the more reasonable of the two.
DAIN:
Good morning.
How are we all?
I have a wee proposition if you wouldn't
mind giving me a few moments of your time.
Would you consider just sodding off?
All of you!
Right now!
Stand fast.
Come now, Lord Dain.
Gandalf the Grey.
Tell this rabble to leave, or I will
water the ground with their blood!
There is no need for war
between Dwarves, Men and Elves.
A legion of Orcs march on the Mountain.
Stand your army down.
I will not stand down before any Elf.
Not least this faithless Woodland sprite.
He wishes nothing
but ill upon my people.
If he chooses
to stand between me and my kin...
...I will split his pretty head open!
See if he's still smirking then.
[ALL SHOUTING]
He's clearly mad, like his cousin.
You hear that, lads?
We're on!
Let's give these bastards
a good hammering!
[SHOUTING IN DWARVISH]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[RUMBLING]
Were-worms.
[ROARING]
Oh, come on.
[ORCS SHOUTING IN BLACK SPEECH]
[IN BLACK SPEECH]
[HORN BLOWING]
The hordes of hell are upon us!
To battle!
To battle, sons of Durin!
[ALL GRUNTING AND SNARLING]
FILI: I am going over the wall.
Who's coming with me?
OIN: Aye!
DWALIN: Yes. Come on, let's go!
THORIN: Stand down.
ORI: What?
Are we to do nothing?
I said, stand down!
The Elves.
Will they not fight?
GANDALF: Thranduil!
This is madness!
[SHOUTING IN DWARVISH]
DAIN:
Charge!
Yes!
[SPEAKING IN DWARVISH]
BILBO:
Uh, Gandalf?
Is this a good place to stand?
[IN BLACK SPEECH]
[HORN BLOWING]
[SPEAKING IN ELVISH]
[ORC SHOUTING IN BLACK SPEECH]
[ALL SHOUTING IN CADENCE]
Azog.
He's trying to cut us off.
BARD:
All of you!
Fall back to Dale!
Now!
GANDALF:
To the city!
Bilbo!
This Way!
[GRUNTING AND SNARLING]
[TROLLS ROAR]
[ROARS]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[PEOPLE CLAMORING AND SCREAMING]
Sigrid!
Tilda!
My children!
Where are my children?
I saw them!
They were down in the old market!
The market?
Where are they now?
Tilda!
Sigrid!
Bard!
Orcs are storming over the causeway!
Get the bowmen to the eastern parapet.
Hold them off as long as you can.
Archers!
This way!
The Orcs have taken Stone Street!
The market's overrun!
The rest of you...
...follow me!
[ALL SHOUTING]
ALFRID:
Charge! Onward!
To the death!
[SCREAMING]
SIGRID:
Da!
BOTH:
BAIN: Over here!
Da. We're down here!
[SNARLS]
[SCREAMING]
BARD:
Bain!
Sigrid!
Get down!
[GRUNTING]
Listen!
I need you to gather the women and children.
Take them to the Great Hall
and barricade the door.
You understand?
You must not come
out for any reason.
We want to stay with you!
Show your father some respect.
You leave it to me sire.
You heard him.
We make for the Great Hall. Alfrid!
Women and children only.
I need every man fighting.
See that you return.
I will get them to safety, sire.
Then my sword is yours to command.
Get up!
Look after them.
Shift it, granny!
Make for the Great Hall!
ALFRID:
Out of my way!
Abandon the cripples!
[ORCS GROWLING]
[IN BLACK SPEECH]
You buggers!
Where's Thorin?
We need him!
Where is he?
[IN BLACK SPEECH]
[HORN BLOWING]
Fall back!
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
DWALIN:
Since when do we forsake our own people?
Thorin...
...they are dying out there.
There are halls beneath halls
within this Mountain.
Places we can fortify...
...shore up, make safe.
Yes.
Yes...
...that is it.
We must move the gold further underground
to safety. Did you not hear me?
Dain is surrounded.
They're being slaughtered, Thorin.
Many die in war.
Life is cheap.
But a treasure such as this cannot
be counted in lives lost.
It is worth all the blood we can spend.
You sit here in these vast halls
with a crown upon your head...
...and yet you are lesser now
than you have ever been.
Do not speak to me...
...as if I were some lowly Dwarf Lord...
...as is if...
...I were still...
...Thorin...
...Oakenshield.
- I am your king!
- You were always my king.
You used to know that once.
You cannot see what you have become.
Go.
Get out.
Before I kill you.
DWALIN:
You sit here with a crown upon your head.
You are lesser now
than you have ever been.
THORIN: But a treasure such as this
cannot be counted in lives lost.
BALIN:
A sickness lies upon that treasure.
BARD: The blind ambition of a Mountain King.
THORIN: Am I not the king?
- This gold is ours.
- And ours alone.
I will not part with a single coin.
BARD: He could not see beyond his own desire!
THORIN: As if I were some lowly
Dwarf Lord, Thorin Oakenshield.
A sickness which drove your grandfather mad.
Oakenshield.
DWALIN:
This is Thorin, son of Thrain, son of Thror!
THORIN: I am not my grandfather.
I am not my grandfather.
GANDALF: You are the heir
to the Throne of Durin.
DWALIN:
They are dying out there.
GANDALF: Take back Erebor.
DWALIN: Dain is surrounded. Dying.
Is surrounded.
Dying.
GANDALF:
Take back your homeland.
BILBO:
You are changed, Thorin.
THORIN:
I am not my grandfather.
BILBO: Is this treasure truly worth more
than your honor?
THORIN:
I am not my grandfather.
[RUMBLING]
GANDALF:
This treasure will be your death!
[SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
Fall back!
Fall back...
...to the Mountain!
Fall back!
AZOG [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
[HORN BLOWING]
KILI: I will not hide behind a wall of stone
while others fight our battles for us!
It is not in my blood, Thorin.
No.
It is not.
We are sons of Durin.
And Durin's Folk...
...do not flee from a fight.
I have no right to ask
this of any of you.
But will you follow me...
...one last time?
[ORC SHOUTING IN BLACK SPEECH]
[ALL SHOUT IN BLACK SPEECH]
[IN BLACK SPEECH]
[TROLLS ROAR]
[HORN BLOWING]
Thorin.
[BELL RINGING]
[ALL SHOUTING]
DAIN:
To the king!
To the king.......
[SHOUTING IN DWARVISH]
The Dwarves.
They're rallying.
They're rallying to their king.
Any man who wants
to give their last...
...follow me!
[ALL SHOUTING]
I say we stand with our men
in life and in death.
I am with you.
HILDA: Arm yourselves.
Come with us.
WOMAN: No, no, no.
You leave an old woman be. Don't be afraid.
WOMAN [IN DEEP VOICE]: I said, get off!
Alfrid Lickspittle.
You are a coward.
"Coward"?
Not every man's brave enough
to wear a corset. You're not a man.
You're a weasel.
[CHATTERING]
Dain!
Thorin!
Hold on!
I am coming!
[YELLS]
Hey, cousin!
What took you so long?
[LAUGHING]
There's too many of
these buggers, Thorin.
I hope you have got a plan.
THORIN:
Aye.
We're going to take out their leader.
Azog?
I am going to kill that piece of filth.
Lead on!
[GROANS]
We may yet survive this.
Gandalf!
It's Thorin.
And Fili, Kili...
...and Dwalin.
He's taking his best warriors.
To do what?
To cut the head
off the snake.
[YELLS]
Die!
[IN ENGLISH]
Gandalf!
Legolas.
Legolas Greenleaf.
There is a second army. Bolg leads a force
of Gundabad Orcs. They are almost upon us.
Gundabad.
This was their plan all along.
Azog engages our forces,
then Bolg sweeps in from the North.
The North? Where is the North exactly?
Ravenhill.
Ravenhill?
Thorin is up there. And Fili and Kili.
They're all up there.
KILI:
Where is he?
It looks empty.
I think Azog has fled.
I don't think so.
Fili...
...take your brother.
Scout out the towers.
Keep low and out of sight.
If you see something report back.
Do not engage.
- Do you understand?
- We have company.
[GOBLINS GRUNTING]
Goblin mercenaries.
No more than a hundred.
We will take care of them.
Go! Go!
DWALIN:
Come on!
Recall your company.
[HORN BLOWING]
My lord, dispatch this force to Ravenhill.
The Dwarves are about to be overrun.
Thorin must be warned.
By all means, warn him.
I have spent enough Elvish blood in defense
of this accursed land. No more. Thranduil?
I will go.
Don't be ridiculous.
You will never make it.
Why not?
Because they will see you coming
and kill you.
No, they won't.
They won't see me.
It's out of the question.
I won't allow it.
I am not asking you to allow it, Gandalf.
TAURIEL [IN ELVISH]:
[IN ENGLISH]
You will not turn away.
Not this time.
Get out of my way.
The Dwarves will be slaughtered.
Yes, they will die.
Today...
...tomorrow...
...one year hence,
a hundred years from now.
What does it matter?
They are mortal.
You think your life is worth more than
theirs when there is no love in it?
There is no love in you.
What do you know of love?
Nothing.
What you feel for that Dwarf is not real.
You think it is love?
Are you ready to die for it?
LEGOLAS [IN ELVISH]:
[IN ENGLISH]
I will go with you.
[ROARS]
[SCREAMS]
Get up.
Get away from me.
I don't take orders from you.
People trusted you.
They listened to you.
The Master's mantle was there for the
taking and you threw it all away.
For what?
BARD:
Alfrid, your slip is showing.
[CREATURE ROARS]
Hey.
Stay here.
Search the lower levels.
I have got this.
Where is that Orc filth?
Thorin.
Bilbo.
You have to leave here.
Now.
Azog has another army attacking
from the North.
This watchtower will be completely surrounded.
There will be no way out. We are so close.
That Orc scum is in there.
I say we push on.
No.
That's what he wants.
He wants to draw us in.
This is a trap.
[SNIFFS]
Ah...
[CREATURE ROARS]
[RUMBLING]
Find Fili and Kili.
Call them back.
Thorin, are you sure about this?
Do it.
We will live to fight another day.
[DRUM BEATING]
[GRUNTING]
Oh...
AZOG [IN BLACK SPEECH]:
Go.
Run!
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
Kili!
DWALIN:
Thorin.
No.
[ROARING]
[YELLING AND GRUNTING]
[SCREECHING]
[SHOUTING IN BLACK SPEECH]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[IN BLACK SPEECH]
No.
[ALL SHOUTING]
TAURIEL:
Kili.
[GRUNTS]
[IN BLACK SPEECH]
Kili!
Tauriel!
Kili.
[ROARS]
[GROANS]
[CHOKING]
[TAURIEL YELLS]
[GRUNTS]
No!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[TAURIEL GASPS AND COUGHS]
[HORN BLOWING]
[RUMBLING]
Mm.
[ROARS]
Tauriel!
[SQUAWKING]
[ROARING]
[SCREAMS]
[SNARLS]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
[GROANING]
[SQUAWKING]
The Eagles are coming.
[COUGHING AND GASPING]
Bilbo. Don't move. Don't move.
Lie still.
- Oh.
- Mm. Mm.
I am glad you are here.
Shh, shh. Unh.
I wish to part from you in friendship.
No. You are not going anywhere, Thorin.
You're going to live.
I would take back my words and
my deeds at the Gate.
You did what only a
true friend would do.
Forgive me.
I was too blind to see it.
I am so sorry
that I have led you into such peril.
No, I am glad to have shared
in your perils, Thorin.
Each and every one of them.
It is far more than
any Baggins deserves.
Farewell......
...Master Burglar.
Go back to your books.
And your armchair.
Plant your trees.
Watch them grow.
[GROANS]
If more people...
...valued home...
...above gold...
...this world would be a merrier place.
[GRUNTS]
No. No, no, no. No.
Thorin. Thorin, don't you dare.
Thorin.
Thorin. Thorin, hold on.
Hold on, please.
The Eagles...
The Eagles... The Eagles are here.
Thorin?
The Ea...
[SOBBING]
[SNIFFLING]
I cannot go back.
Where will you go?
I do not know.
Go north.
Find the Dúnedain.
There's a young Ranger amongst them.
You should meet him.
His father, Arathorn, was a good man.
His son...
...might grow to be a great one.
What is his name?
He's known in the Wild as Strider.
His true name...
...you must discover for yourself.
Legolas.
Your mother loved you.
More than anyone.
More than life.
They want to bury him.
Yes.
If this is love,
I do not want it.
Take it from me.
Please.
[VOICE BREAKING]
Why does it hurt so much?
Because it was real.
[SIGHS]
[HORNS BLOWING]
BALIN: There is to be
a great feast tonight.
Songs will be sung.
Tales will be told.
And Thorin Oakenshield...
...will pass into legend.
I know that's how you must honor him.
But to me, he was never that.
He was...
To me...
...he was...
Well, I think I will slip quietly away.
Will you tell the others I said goodbye?
You can tell them yourself.
If any of you are ever
passing Bag End, uh...
...tea is at 4.
There's plenty of it.
You are welcome anytime.
Uh...
Don't bother knocking.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
[GANDALF CHUCKLES]
GANDALF: Ah, the borders of the Shire.
It is here I must leave you.
That's a shame.
I quite liked having a Wizard around.
Seems they bring good luck.
You don't really suppose, do you,
that all your adventures and escapes...
...were managed by mere luck?
Magic rings should not be used lightly,
Bilbo.
Don't take me for a fool. I know you
found one in the Goblin tunnels. No.
And I have kept my eye on you ever since.
Well, thank goodness.
Farewell, Gandalf.
Farewell.
You, uh... You needn't worry about that ring.
Fell out of my pocket during the battle.
I lost it.
You're a very fine person, Mr. Baggins.
And I am very fond of you.
But you're only quite a little fellow...
...in a wide world after all.
[HOBBITS CHATTERING]
Wait a minute,
that's my mother's glory box.
And that's my dining chair.
Ah... Put that pouf down!
What is going on?
WORRYWORT:
Hello, Mr. Bilbo.
You're not supposed to be here.
What do you mean? On account of you
being presumed dead and all.
I am not dead.
Presumed or otherwise.
WORRYWORT:
I am not sure that's permitted. Mr. Bilbo!
TOSSER: Twenty-one! Any advance on 21?
Any advance on 21?
Ha, ha! Sold to Mrs. Bolger.
Somewhere for Fatty to put his feet on.
[ALL LAUGHING] So do I have any
bids for this? This is Shire-made.
None of your Dwarvish reproductions here, honestly.
BILBO: Stop!
Stop! There's been a mistake!
LOBELIA: Who are you?
What do you mean "Who am I"?
You know perfectly well who I am
Lobelia Sackville-Baggins.
This is my home and those are my spoons.
Thank you very much.
TOSSER: This is most irregular.
Excuse me.
TOSSER: It's been more than 13 months
since the disappearance.
If you are in fact, Bilbo Baggins
and undeceased. Can you prove it?
What? Well, uh, something official with
your name on it would suffice.
- All right.
- Right.
[CROWD MURMURING]
A contract of employment as a bur...
Never mind as what.
There.
My signature.
Yes, well... Uh...
Well, it certainly seems to be in order.
Yes.
Seems there can be no doubt.
Who is this person you pledged
your service to?
Thorin Oakenshield?
He...
He was my friend.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
No, thank you!
We don't want any more visitors,
well-wishers or distant relations!
GANDALF:
And what about very old friends?
BILBO: Gandalf?
GANDALF: Bilbo Baggins.
BILBO: My dear Gandalf! Ha, ha!
GANDALF: It's good to see you.
One hundred and 11 years old.
Who would believe it?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
BILBO:
Come on, come in!
Welcome.