Finally...
the warring nations of earth had
forgotten their differences...
and banded together
to save our planet.
The United Global Space Force
was searching the galaxy...
for worlds rich with drinkable
water and breathable air.
The hypergate was our best hope
to colonize space...
our best hope for survival.
But as we prepared
to launch ourselves...
into the black of space...
terrorists, calling themselves
"The Global Sedition..."
were preparing to strike.
Grissom base, this is Cargo 7
requesting landing clearance.
Roger, transport.
This is Grissom gate control.
Please download security codes.
Downloading.
Transport, I've got two blips
inside your radar signature.
They're hiding in your shadow.
I don't see anything.
This is gate control.
Battle stations.
Two Sedition fighters
are attacking the hypergate.
Battle stations.
Gate control, this is Eagle One.
I'm locked and loaded.
Ready to fly.
Roger, Eagle One.
You're clear to launch.
Jeb, where are you, buddy?
This cold war just got hot.
They're Sedition raiders.
It's another
mutant suicide squad.
Here we go. Man-to-man.
Split them up.
Last one to kill a bad guy
buys the beer.
I'm gonna go through the gate,
get in front of him.
That's not standard procedure,
Don.
I'm gettin' some heat.
You gen-techs are ugly up close.
Target lock.
Show time.
Bogey One dispatched.
Don, he's right on my tail.
Damn! Can't shake him.
I've been hit!
Weapons are off-line.
I'm gonna jettison
the main drive core.
There you are.
Am I good or what?
Warning. Failure
in redundant drive systems.
Gate control,
this is Ranger One.
Engines will not respond.
Don, I'm falling
towards the hypergate.
Breaking thrusters won't fire!
Impact in 30 seconds.
Ranger One, this is base.
Rescue craft
have been dispatched.
Grissom, those pods will never
reach him in time.
I'm going in.
Major West, you are not
authorized to jeopardize--
Never liked that station anyway.
Warning. Proximity alert.
Hang on, Jeb. I'm coming in.
Abort. Abort!
I'll give you a little kiss.
Don't take this the wrong way.
Impact in five seconds.
Does this mean
we're going steady?
You're not getting out
of buying those beers that easy.
With intrepid pioneering spirit,
the Robinson family...
will journey to the distant
world of Alpha Prime.
What kind of future can
our children look forward to?
A future in paradise.
The Jupiter mission...
made possible by the Army and
Silicon Graphics Corporation.
S.G.I. Saving the future
for our children.
Give me a break.
Holo-call
from Houston middle school.
Hello?
Hello, Principal Cartwright.
What has he done this time?
He hacked our main power grid
to run his experiment.
The school was in chaos.
Yeah, right.
We didn't even have lights.
This is no laughing matter,
Professor Robinson.
Will is terribly gifted.
The changing shape of education.
His little time machines,
though pure fancy...
are the products
of a truly brilliant mind.
No more monkey business.
I mean it.
The boy is starved
for attention.
I know your life is anything
but normal right now...
but wasn't there some way...
his father could have
attended the science fair?
As you are aware...
Alpha Prime is the only other
habitable planet...
yet detected
by deep space recon.
My crew will sleep away
our 10-year journey there...
in suspended animation.
Once we have rendezvoused with
the research colony on Alpha...
I will supervise
construction of a hypergate.
By then,
technicians here on Earth...
will have completed
the companion hypergate...
in our planet's orbit.
Once both gates are complete...
ships will be able to pass
instantaneously between them.
Immediate colonization
of Alpha Prime will be possible.
Can't you just use
the Jupiter's hyper-engine...
to zap straight to Alpha Prime?
Hyperspace exists
beneath normal space.
If you try to enter hyperspace
without a gate...
your exit factor is random.
There's no telling
where you'd come out.
Ninety-eight percent of
the galaxy is still uncharted.
There's a lot of space
to get lost in.
How is Captain Daniels
recovering from the flu?
Will he pilot the mission?
Ladies and gentlemen.
You came to get your first look
at the Jupiter 1.
Don't you think
you've waited long enough?
Let's move into the launch dome.
One more question, Professor.
Now that the mission's
been pushed up...
how do your children feel
about leaving the earth behind?
They couldn't be more excited.
This mission sucks!
I don't wanna leave early.
I don't wanna go at all.
We will discuss this at dinner.
For the last three years, I've
missed everything training...
so I can spend the next 10 years
missing everything else.
I'm not staying home for dinner.
I'm seeing my friends.
Penny.
I'm going out to say good-bye
to my entire life.
Penny, I need you here tonight.
Wait a minute.
On this eve, before she's torn
from everything she knows--
kidnapped...
hurled into deep space
against her will--
what thoughts fill the mind
of the daring space captive?
Are there boys on Alpha Prime?
What will I wear?
What will it be like to jettison
your body into deep space?
First...
you'll try holding your breath.
But your blood's
already begun to boil.
Then your skin inflates
like a balloon.
Then...pop.
Do they have a name
for what's wrong with you?
Dad says don't bring them.
Like anything I do
matters to him.
Don't sweat it, kid.
I got apology videos
for two birthdays.
He forgot last year completely.
This mission's the only thing
he cares about anymore.
So that's a no to family dinner?
Let's see.
Do I spend my last night
on Earth...
watching Mom and Dad pretend
not to be fighting again...
or blow 10 years worth
of allowance at the mall?
You do the math.
Mom's gonna go thermal.
What's she gonna do,
ground me?
I'm nervous about jamming in
a new pilot the last second.
The Global Sedition
is getting brave.
First the hypergate,
then Daniels.
Next time, they may attack
the launch dome.
We can't afford to wait.
Will's science fair. Reminder.
Apology video for Will.
He'll understand.
Ben, listen.
My family is on this mission.
I need a pilot who's
more than just spit and polish.
I've got your man.
He just doesn't know it yet.
At ease, Major.
Why was I pulled
from active duty?
Those gen-techs
may attack again.
I need to be up there.
Do you know Professor Robinson?
By reputation. Your father's
battle strategies...
were required reading
at the academy.
What can you tell me
about the Jupiter mission?
The Jupiter
is an oversized robot.
Everything's automatic.
Any monkey in a flight suit...
can pilot that ship
out of the solar system...
and set her down on Alpha Prime.
It's a baby-sitting job, sir.
No offense.
Major, are you aware Earth's
resources are severely limited?
Every schoolchild knows...
that our recycling technologies
will cure the environment.
Sending a family
across the galaxy...
is a stunt to sell computers
to people of all ages.
Every schoolchild was lied to.
Recycling technologies
came too late.
All fossil fuels
are virtually exhausted.
The ozone layer is down to 40%%%.
In two decades, the earth will
be unable to support human life.
The new Global Sedition knows
the truth as well as we do.
They're building
their own hypergate.
They hope to colonize
Alpha Prime first.
If they're successful...
western demons like you and l,
Major West...
will be left on Earth to die.
Captain Daniels doesn't have
the flu, does he?
Captain Daniels was murdered
in his apartment last night.
The flu story is a cover.
I flew with Mike.
We should blast their bases!
A decisive strike now!
My squadron is alert status--
Your rescue stunt was foolhardy!
I had a friend in trouble.
So you endangered
a $10-billion spacecraft...
disobeyed a direct order
because of a friend?
I did...
sir.
He'll do.
Congratulations.
You're the new pilot
of the Jupiter mission.
Where's my money?
The Sedition hired me
to provide access...
to Daniels' apartment
and no more.
My work is done.
They found a replacement pilot.
Our attack
on the hypergate failed.
How tragic for you.
We require a more direct
intervention on your part.
I see.
It will cost you.
I'm afraid that my price
has just become...
astronomical.
Holograph off.
Come in.
Control hasn't received
results of the preflight exams.
The Robinsons
have checked out 100%%%.
They're fit as a fiddle
and ready to fly.
Wish them luck...
for me.
Mission protocols are simple.
Robinson is in command...
unless you encounter
a military emergency.
In that case, Major West,
you are in charge.
I'm a fighter pilot.
There must be better candidates.
Hell, even my own family
can't stand me.
Shut up.
Jeb Walker.
He's an excellent flyer.
He's perfect for this mission.
Welcome aboard, Major.
Looks like somebody sprung
for the full-extras package...
on this beauty.
If you have to be a baby-sitter,
it's not such a bad nursery.
Wouldn't you agree?
I don't get it.
I can't get the cryo-sleep
systems up over 96%%%.
Dr. Smith approved the specs.
Dr. Smith is the base physician.
I am responsible in flight.
These tubes will be perfect,
or the ship will not launch.
Is that clear?
Absolutely, Doctor.
Judy, I want to introduce you
to Major West.
He'll be taking Mike's place.
He's heavier than Mike.
We'll have to recalibrate.
I'd be happy to discuss
my dimensions, Doctor...
say, over dinner?
West.
I've read about you.
You're a war hero, aren't you?
Well, yes, actually.
Who was it who said,
"Those who can't think, fight"?
I think that it was me.
It was nice to have met you.
That's one cold fish
I'd love to thaw.
I'm not gonna make it over
for dinner tonight, Dad.
It's gonna be a long flight.
Maureen, pick up the phone,
honey.
I know you're there.
Are you still packing?
I'm just leaving.
Go to bed.
Sweetie?
He won first prize again.
Is this the new model
he's been working on?
Crazy idea he's got about a...
time machine?
Pretty sharp stuff for a midget.
Sorry about dinner.
That new pilot--
John, the family needs you here.
This whole thing
is about family.
My only condition
for accepting this mission...
was that we could bring
the children with us...
not leave them behind...
so future generations
would have a new home.
You're off saving humanity,
so what does it matter...
that Will
has to blackout his school...
to get his father's attention...
Penny's been dragged home
by security 3 nights in a row...
Judy's become a ghost,
like her father?
I have to compensate
for the new launch time.
What do you think I'm doing?
Revising life-science protocols.
I'm also dealing
with two kids...
who are leaving
an entire planet behind.
Sorry, but there's no manuals
on how to deal with this.
Maybe it doesn't do any good...
saving a world of families
if we can't save our own.
Is that it, Professor?
John.
I know, baby.
I'm scared, too.
Med supplies for the Jupiter 2?
That's what it looks like.
They're not taking any chances.
Forgive me if I forego the kiss,
my sleeping behemoth...
but the time has come to awake.
Robot is on-line.
Reviewing primary directives.
One--
preserve the Robinson family.
Two--
maintain the ship's systems.
Spare me the chatter,
my steely centurion.
Sadly, I fear I have far more
dire deeds in store for you.
Robot is on-line.
Reviewing primary directives.
Sixteen hours into mission,
destroy Robinson family.
Destroy all systems.
That's more like it.
Farewell,
my platinum-plated pal.
Give my regards to oblivion.
Apparently you have completed
your mission on schedule.
I do so admire a spot
of timely terrorism.
I thought I told you
never to call me here.
The transmission signal
will be traced.
I just wanted to express
my most sincere gratitude...
for your unflagging loyalty.
Good work, good doctor...
and good-bye.
Jupiter 1 launch
in three minutes.
Mom, just--
Shoot.
Mom, I'm fine.
That's supposed to be there.
This is almost acceptable.
-Mom, don't.
-What?
Vogue says this will be
the style in 10 years.
Can we cut back on her oxygen...
so she's not so annoying
when she wakes up?
Does he have to wake up at all?
That's it. I'm gonna turn
this spaceship around.
Satellite defense net locked
and a-ok.
-Everything's gonna be fine.
-30 seconds. Mark.
-Hey, there, buddy.
-Com-links encoded and secure.
-Good night, guys.
-Good night.
Here we go.
Artificial gravity at 100%%%.
You get a "C"
in paternal expression...
but an "A" for effort.
-I'm doing the best I can.
-Come here.
You always get an "A" in this.
Main drive systems on-line.
Sweet dreams.
See you there.
You are at "T" minus one minute
and counting, Major West.
Houston, the bird is hot.
She's all yours.
I'll try to give you
a smooth ride.
Mission control,
this is Dr. Robinson.
We are in the green.
Roger, Doctor. You are go
to initiate cryo-stasis.
One question.
Is there room
in these tubes for two?
There's barely enough
for you and your ego.
Don't sweat it, doc.
I do this all the time.
Just drive carefully.
You are at "T" minus 40 seconds
and counting.
Ready.
You are at "T" minus
30 seconds and counting.
20 seconds and counting.
Control, this is Jupiter 1.
The Robinsons are all tucked in.
We are ready to fly.
Major West, your escape vector
is clear of all traffic.
Op is go on your command.
Roger, Houston.
And the monkey flips the switch.
Jupiter 1 boosters disengaged.
This is Jupiter 2.
Diverting all spacecraft control
to the main computer.
Eight years of flight training.
Navigational holographics
on-line.
Fifty combat missions.
Course confirmed for slingshot
exit of the solar system.
So I can take the family camper
on an interstellar picnic.
Ten years is a lifetime.
Sleep well, old friend.
I never liked
these freezing tubes.
Bad dreams.
Navigational interface
confirmed.
Cryo-sleep systems are 100%%%.
Shit!
Robot is on-line.
Sixteen hours into mission,
destroy Robinson family.
Destroy all systems.
Disable program !
Sixteen hours into mission,
destroy Robinson family.
Destroy all systems.
Robot is on-line.
Destroy.
Destroy all operating systems.
Destroy Jupiter 2.
Destroy cryo-sleep systems.
Destroy.
Destroy navigational systems.
Come on!
Wake up, damn you!
I can't stop this infernal
contraption on my own.
Emergency cryo-stasis
desequencing in process.
Destroy all systems.
Destroy Robinson family.
Maureen, the children!
Destroy.
Run!
-Destroy.
-Deactivate safety.
That was a mistake.
Dad!
Mom, let's go!
-Will, stop!
-Destroy.
Destroy Jupiter 2.
Destroy Robinson family.
Look away, baby.
Robot, disable pulse blaster.
Command accepted.
Cancel attack sequence
and stand by.
If the family won't come
to the science fair...
bring the science fair
to the family.
Showoff.
Robot.
On-line. Standing by.
Return to docking bay
and power down.
Major, you all right?
Next picnic, no robots.
Where's Judy?
Stabilize the operating systems.
Fire control.
Attempting
containment protocols.
I want to go home now.
Navigation's down.
System shorts everywhere.
Damn.
Communications are out.
Link up the secondary system.
-Shunting power from reserve.
-Come on.
Try it now.
Navigational boards are lit.
Can we reroute?
I'm locked out of the helm.
Nothing in computer control.
Main com to manual.
See if she'll respond.
The main subroutine won't open.
I'm gonna try remote ops.
Smith!
Get back!
Get away from me!
What the hell
are you doing here?
Major West,
thank God it's you.
I was in here
to do some last minute checks...
and somebody hit me from behind.
That's Sedition technology.
You're the damn spy.
You did this.
What are you doing?
Throwing out the trash!
I need help!
I can't get Judy out!
She's dying!
Touch me,
and the girl dies!
I don't deal with dead men.
Kill me, kill the girl.
How much is your revenge worth?
I can save her life...
only if you give me your word
as an officer you'll spare mine.
-Help her.
-I've got helm control.
We're way off course.
We're caught in the sun's
gravitational pull.
Is that what that big ball is?
We've got four minutes before
the outer hull begins to melt.
I need you to check
on the thruster alignments.
Professor!
I'll try for the Mercury mines.
I'll need Dr. Robinson's
portable gurney.
You'll find it below.
Smith, come on!
You tried to kill my family.
We trusted you.
It's the world behind the world,
Professor Robinson.
Lie once, cheat twice,
and everything becomes clear.
Do not mistake my deception
for a character flaw.
It is a philosophical choice...
that I've found
in a study of the universe.
It is a way of life.
You're a monster.
Perhaps,
but I'm also the only one...
that can save Judy's life.
Penny, precious, I want you to
short the power on my command.
Does he have to call me
precious?
Penny, precious.
Now!
She's not breathing.
Sick bay, move!
The sun won't let us go.
Heat shield breach,
60 seconds.
I need options, Professor.
We have to divert all power
to the engines.
I'm rerouting life sciences.
Rerouting life support.
Engines at 80%%%.
There's no cardiopulmonary
or respiratory functions.
Clear.
Again. Clear.
Alert.
Medical.
Rerouting error.
Systems are crashing.
We're losing her. Do something.
Come on, child.
Put a little heart into it.
The other life I save...
will be my own.
Wake up, baby, please.
That's all the power we've got.
I'm putting the pedal
to the metal. Here goes.
She can't break free.
She doesn't have enough thrust.
There's got to be a way
to get through this.
That's it.
It's working!
What is?
If we can't go around the sun,
we go straight through it...
using your hyperdrive.
Engage the hyperdrive
without a gate?
We could be thrown
anywhere in the galaxy.
Anywhere but here.
On my mark.
Three, two, one, initiate.
Hyperdrive at 100%%%.
Major, you have the com.
Dad?
Dad!
Let's see what this baby can do.
Maureen, everyone?
-Where is Judy?
-She's OK.
She is, thanks to me.
Here I am.
Either I should cut down
on the liquids...
or I should sew in a new flap
because it was really hell...
getting out of that thing.
You're...
Vitals are normal. Pulse
and respiration seem to be.
-Are you OK?
-I'm fine, really.
Come here.
Will every little problem be an
excuse for familial sentiment?
How much, Smith?
What was the price tag
that you put on our future?
You can't do it, can you, John?
You can't kill the man
without becoming the monster.
Coward.
What's happened, John?
Where are we?
I bypassed
most of the damaged systems.
We'll have to repair the rest
manually.
You had me worried, doc.
Nice to see you thawed.
You have a puzzling definition
of a smooth ride.
Computer,
map our current position.
Searching
for recognizable constellations.
This database has star maps
of all the known galaxy.
I don't recognize
a single system.
We're lost....
aren't we?
Easy, doc. God.
Please.
The cryosuit absorbed
most of the electrical charge.
You're lucky
this wasn't your hide.
Doctor, is that concern
I detect in your voice?
Great bedside manner.
What's that?
A battle scar?
Sort of.
It was a tattoo.
An ex-girlfriend's name,
but I had it removed.
Wouldn't it be easier
to use a magic marker?
Yeah, well, that's me.
A girl in every port.
So, Major, no family?
Nothing to tie you down,
no one to miss?
I've never been
the fit-in and play-nice type.
You think that's romantic?
I don't.
But what about you, doc?
Is there some lucky little nerd
you left behind?
I spent three years working
on this mission.
We're trying to save the planet.
I haven't had time for fun.
If there's no time for fun...
then what are we saving
the planet for?
Here.
Thanks.
I hate being little.
I think it broke.
I'll try and fix it.
Why aren't you up on deck
with Mom and Dad?
Have you met our parents?
Good point.
Popcorn, orchids...
waves, Billy...
kissing.
Chocolate.
It's a list...
of everything we left behind.
Never love anything, kiddo...
'cause you just end up
losing it.
Smith could still hurt us.
Maybe I shouldn't let him live.
But...
How can we bring
civilization to the stars...
if we can't remain civilized?
Right, Professor?
Have you noticed that you
take the opposite position...
to whatever I say?
Of course I do.
We're married.
Alert.
Spatial anomaly in progress.
What the hell?
I must be dreaming.
That looks like a ship.
It appears to be some sort
of hole in space.
Where does it lead?
A reasonable question.
Major, wait.
I'll wait later.
Pull back.
Let there be light.
Proteus?
She's one of ours, all right.
All right.
I've never seen a ship
like this.
No response to hails.
Scanning all military
and civilian frequencies.
Nothing.
I'm getting
inconsistent life signs...
but they may be sensor ghosts.
Computer is still on.
I'll try the standard
docking codes.
Control codes confirmed.
Initiating docking sequence.
Weird.
What kind of ship is that?
That's not one of ours.
Boys, that's not even human.
If this is all a dream...
why can't there be more girls?
As part of her enslavement...
the brave young space captive
Penny Robinson...
is forced to utilize her
dazzling technical expertise.
Identify yourself, soldier.
West, Major,
United Global Space Force...
requesting permission
to see the prisoner.
Proceed, Major West.
Could he be cuter?
I don't think so.
Breathe, Penny.
Unlock.
These quarters are unacceptable.
We're going to check out
the probe ship.
Maybe we can figure out how they
got here and how to get home.
Have a wonderful trip.
Put this on.
You're coming with us.
Out of the question. I am
a doctor, not a space explorer.
What you are
is a murderous saboteur.
I am not leaving you here...
so you can do more harm
than you've already caused.
I absolutely refuse.
Give me an excuse to kill you.
Please?
Black was always my color.
Lock.
Activate standby.
Crush, kill, destroy.
Surprise.
Safety on.
Dad, chill.
It's OK.
I hacked into his CPU,
and then...
I bypassed
his main operating systems...
and accessed his subroutines.
He's basically just running
on remote control.
I know I haven't been around--
Professor.
We're ready to go.
We'll talk later, son.
Take care of my dad.
OK, Robot?
Vacuum check complete.
Oxygen levels are normal.
Microbe scans are negative.
Clear.
The air is stale, old.
That's the smell of ghosts.
I've got
her on-board computer up.
Not working?
She's working, all right.
Just--I don't know.
Too damn fast.
Dad, do you hear something?
Like the drip, drip of blood.
You really need to shut up.
Here.
This matter appears biological.
Nothing good will come of this.
You, of course, being the expert
on space exploration.
Let's go.
Trust me, Major.
Evil knows evil.
Motion sensors
are still working.
This way.
Rambler-crane series robots.
But like no design
I've ever seen.
Well, well.
Aren't we the poor cousin?
Down here.
It's a remote op station.
Come on, Dr. Smith.
Could this ship be a prototype?
Looks like some kind
of fire fight.
Captain's log is degraded.
Maybe I can gather
some fragments.
Sorry.
The hyperspace tracker seems
to be functioning normally...
but we cannot process
all the data.
There is no sign
of the Jupiter 2.
I have exceeded my timetable.
When did he make Major?
I want this on the record.
I am not willing to give up.
Don would come looking for me.
That's it. The rest
of the data's totally corrupted.
How could they launch
a rescue mission for us...
when we've only been lost a day?
There's no data
on the alien ship...
but they brought in something
that was attached to its hull.
Got it.
Some sort of egg sack?
Get back here!
Be happy to oblige...
although I don't think it's me
you should be worrying about...
but rather these.
I'm detecting motion.
Behind you.
After it. Move!
Bring Smith.
Don't even think about it.
Hydroponics.
Growth like this
would take decades.
Unhand me, you mechanical moron.
Don't move.
Easy.
Easy there, buddy.
No one's gonna hurt you.
Easy.
Relax.
Excellent.
Looks like you made a friend.
Still, I'd wait a few weeks...
before tattooing
her name on your arm.
Do yourself a favor.
Don't evolve.
Charming.
The Dr. Dolittle of outer space.
This could be a creature
from that alien ship.
But this guy's no pilot.
He looks like a child.
Try it now.
Strange.
The scales are giving off heat.
I've tapped into
the internal sensor array.
There's no other
animate life present.
Besides us,
this ship is totally deserted.
A ghost ship.
The flavor of the day
is banana beef.
Who thinks up
these combinations?
Good.
Major West, I highly
recommend you never breed.
That, by the way,
is my medical opinion.
Little thing was hungry.
I got their star maps on-line.
Here we go.
More systems
than I've ever seen.
Finding a route to Alpha Prime.
Downloading to Jupiter.
I don't like the sound
of that sound.
They're moving.
Get this infernal...
ape thing off me!
Come here.
John, get the hell out of there.
Mom says,
"Get the hell out of there."
Evacuate.
Now!
The controls are too slow.
Activate holographic interface.
Holographic interface, on-line.
They eat their wounded.
Seal the bulkhead.
Codes are locked.
Duck.
Closing bulkhead.
Fire sensor activated.
Emergency bulkhead closing.
Stop!
We have to get that door open.
Open, damn you!
Get out of here.
What is with me
and these damn doors?
I can't override
the fire protocol!
A million bucks
worth of weaponry...
and I'd trade it all back...
for a lousy...
can of Raid.
Stand clear.
Get moving! Go!
Come on!
Maureen...
can you get me anything?
Cycling through a vacuum check.
I'm overriding.
No way it's that easy.
Run!
Run! Get back!
Get back to the ship!
Move it!
Got it. Try it now.
Mom says, "Try it now."
Can we save it?
Can't without letting
the spiders into the ship.
Leave him behind!
That spider scratched me!
Stop laughing, you little worm.
Good-bye, Robot.
You couldn't save him, kid.
Save him? Of course.
What are you trying to do?
Hurry! Disengage!
This is a fun picnic.
First yellow aliens,
now giant spiders.
The crowd goes wild.
Recall your childhood
nightmares, Major.
Monsters are rarely
so easily dissuaded.
Why don't you talk to them,
bug to bug?
I think
they'd rather come inside.
Arming torpedoes.
Fire in the hole.
Alert. Detonation failure.
The robot must have damaged
the detonator cores.
They won't blow.
Alert.
Outer hub has been compromised.
DNA extrapolation coming up.
Silicone-based, mantium shell,
lack of respiratory system.
Means they do live
in deep space.
Tiny front brain implies
communal relationships.
Like beetles.
The biology lesson is over.
I could use some help.
They may be attracted
to heat and light.
Inner hull breach in 15 seconds.
I'm bringing the Proteus
fusion drives on-line.
It's working.
Let's turn up the heat.
What are you doing?
Never leave an enemy stronghold
intact.
Stop!
That's one of your father's
first rules of the game.
That is a direct order.
I hate spiders.
That's coming fast.
Get into the harnesses now.
Manual helm, engage.
-Children, secure?
-Secure.
I'm in.
Pull up.
Really? No kidding.
Thanks.
Coming in too hot.
I'll try and slow us down.
Hang on!
Everybody by the numbers.
Life sciences,
still breathing.
Video mechanics...
OK.
Mission medical, I'm alive.
Me, too.
Robotics, I mean.
I'm alive...
Major West's poor excuse for
piloting skills notwithstanding.
Oh, Dorothy.
Back in Kansas at last.
You violated a direct order.
About half the core
material's burned out.
We'll never generate
enough power to break orbit.
We can get off the ground...
but getting back into space
is another story.
I ordered you not to blow
that ship's reactors.
Life support is marginal.
It's gonna get cold in here
tonight.
Also, the pod and the chariot
are pretty much scrap metal.
Don't you walk away from me
when I'm talking to you.
Give it a rest, Professor.
I was technically
still in command.
I am commander of this mission.
Look, no offense...
but you're an egghead
with an honorary rank.
No one ever intended for you
to handle combat situations.
You handled it brilliantly,
sending us crashing down here.
Those aliens posed
a continuing threat.
I made a judgment call...
and, if I have to,
I'll make it again.
You of all people
should understand that.
Your father would back me up.
My father is dead...
killed in one of those combat
missions you admire so much.
My family is on this ship,
and you will follow my orders...
whether you agree with them
or not. Is that clear?
Save your speeches.
I like you, but I'm gonna
do whatever it takes...
to ensure the success
of this mission...
with or without your help.
Is that clear?
Am I interrupting something?
No, really.
I think you two
should slug it out.
Here we are,
stranded on an alien world...
and you want
to get into a pissing contest?
Please, go for it.
I'll have Judy down here
to declare you both unfit...
and I'll take over this mission.
I don't want to hear another
word from you. Is that clear?
Not...another word.
Better.
If you've finished hosing down
the decks with testosterone...
I suggest you come with me.
I may have found a way
off this planet.
Tell me about it.
Damn bug bite.
She...
She really is an interesting
specimen. Huh, doc?
She's fascinating.
The retinal aperture dilation...
seems directly linked
to the skin pigmentation.
What?
Can I keep her?
She's not just another fad
you can pick up and throw away.
Oh, please.
She's all alone here, and
I promise I'll look out for her.
I promise.
She kind of needs me.
The minute you misplace her,
you forget to feed her--
Don't smile. I mean it, Pen.
Thanks...doc.
We're both a long way from home,
aren't we, little one?
Blarp?
That's what we'll call you--
Blarp.
Nice girl.
Pretty girl.
Nice.
The atmosphere here
can sustain human life.
I've located 500 rads
of radioactive material...
five miles west.
We'll need at least that much to
get the core functioning again.
We start out at daybreak.
Be safer that way.
Those are my orders.
I agree
with your recommendation.
Dtente's a beautiful thing.
It's nice to see you found
a corner to suit your talents.
Turn down the bed
before you leave.
I gave my word I'd let you live.
I never said for how long.
Family hour is over.
We're dying here.
Robinson is out of his league.
Look into his eyes and tell me
you can't see his fear.
I fought in the millennial wars.
Survival is a soldier's game.
We both know this civilian fool
will lead us straight to hell.
Robinson needs our help,
if he wants it or not.
With minimal force,
we could take this ship...
and assure them we shall
continue at your command.
Of course.
My God...
you're right.
How could I have been so blind?
I'll just run and get you a gun
so we can hijack the ship, OK?
Sarcasm is the recourse
of the weak mind.
I'm hiding the pain.
Really.
Lock.
Your pain...
has just begun.
Starlight, star bright.
A million strange stars,
and only one wish.
I wish we were home.
Never seen a sky look so alien.
We really are lost,
aren't we?
When the first sailors
circled the globe...
saw a brand-new sky...
they thought they'd sailed
off the edge of the earth...
but they were really
just around the corner.
You're saying we should
just billow our sails...
and let the wind take us home?
Is that it?
Those sailors...
found familiar shapes...
in the stars...
to make the sky seem
more friendly...
and to help them
find their way home.
That's how the constellations
were born.
Porky, the wise and mighty pig.
The great...
big-eared bunny Bugs.
The way you got us down here,
that was pretty flying.
My quarters or yours?
Excuse me?
Don't play coy.
We're the only single people
of consenting age in the galaxy.
How much more of a setup
do you need?
So you figure, why not dispense
with the pleasantries...
and get down to business?
You have a way with words.
Do you want to show me
how you handle the helm?
Right here on this console?
Right here would be fine.
Why don't you just hang on
to your joystick?
Excellent technique, Major.
Really.
Hi.
Will was looking for you.
I sent him back to his room.
He's decided
he can rebuild the robot.
He wants to stay up all night
and show me his designs.
Funny creatures, men.
Try so hard not to be
their fathers...
end up making the same mistakes.
We can't get off this planet,
let alone get back on course.
I don't have time.
Just listen to him.
It doesn't matter what he says.
Just listen.
Sometimes--especially
in the eyes of their fathers--
Iittle boys have to come first.
As soon as
we get back up into space...
we'll spend a lot of time
together, I promise.
It's nice having your
whole family under one roof.
Even if we did have to go...
halfway across the galaxy
to manage it.
Good night, John.
Good night, Maureen.
Good night, Judy.
Good night, Will.
Good night, Penny.
You guys have got to be kidding.
Good morning, Will Robinson.
Solar panels are charged.
The radioactive material
we need for the core...
is in the center of that bubble.
I was afraid of this.
OK, everybody,
let's get settled now.
I think this "bubble"
out there...
is exactly the same thing
we passed through in space.
Both of them are opening
and closing doorways.
Doorways to where?
Doorways in...time.
You can't be serious.
Time travel is impossible.
It's not.
Just improbable.
What if we crossed
into a time...
years after Earth
sent a rescue mission?
Perhaps the professor
hit his head when we landed.
Think about it.
The way the Proteus
seemed deserted for so long.
Your friend looking so old.
So if we walk
inside that bubble...
we could be walking
further into the future.
Dad, what if the doorways
aren't natural?
This kind of phenomenon could
only be produced naturally.
That bubble's
the kind of side effect...
I predicted my time machine
would do.
What if someone built a device--
Son...
I appreciate your input...
but now is not the time
for flights of fancy.
You never listen to me.
Not ever.
This time bubble could be
causing these earthquakes.
No telling how long before
this planet breaks up entirely.
The major and I
are going to locate...
the radioactive material
for the core.
We may have very little time.
I'm leaving now.
That's a surprise.
You're the most important thing
in the world to me.
One day, I hope you'll
be able to understand that.
What if...
one time you don't come home?
Whenever your grandfather
went on a mission...
he'd leave these with me
for safekeeping.
When he came home,
I would always be there...
waiting to give them back.
I'm coming back.
I promise.
Listen...
about last night...
Go on. You can do it.
I'm sorry.
See, that wasn't so difficult.
Like pulling steel needles
through my cheeks.
Then you understand
what saying this feels like.
Try to come back in one piece.
Listen, doc, I'm...
I'm thinking this is your basic
"kiss for luck" occasion.
Wouldn't you agree?
Thinking.
It's not really
your strong suit, is it?
I've got a fix
on the radioactive material.
That was scientific.
Scared?
There's an alloy
in this crater wall...
that's disabling the com-links.
You're not going to be able
to communicate with the ship.
Come home to me, professor.
I love you, wife.
Come here, squirt.
Nice girl.
Pretty girl. Nice.
It's OK.
You're still in one piece.
Come on.
Can you hear me, Robot?
Hello?
Systems error!
Robot unable to locate
motor controls!
Unable to--
Calm down.
What is happening to me?
I didn't have enough time
to finish the download.
Warning!
Penny, give it back!
My circuits are unbalanced.
So I had to finish you off
with another personality.
I put my mind inside of yours.
That explains
this warm fuzzy feeling...
when I think about baseball.
Strike! You're out!
But this does not compute.
What?
Robot tried to destroy
the Robinson family.
Why did Will Robinson
save Robot's personality?
I guess sometimes friendship
means listening to your heart...
not your head.
Put that in your memory bank.
Don't worry.
I'm going to build you
a new body.
Mom always said I should
try to make new friends.
I need a microsealer.
I got it.
After much deliberation...
the space captive
has finally decided...
to accept her new role
as a member of the crew.
The Robinsons, after all,
can obviously use her help.
Blarp, come back here.
Theoretically,
this future would be fixed...
unchanged by what we do
or did in the past--
Professor?
Why don't you give
the old egghead a rest?
Out here we got two moons,
a crater the size of Miami...
and that would be
one great climb.
My father would have liked you.
What's that?
This metal's decades old.
What kind of a nightmare
is this?
Where the hell are we?
The question is,
when the hell are we?
I will tell you a joke.
Why did the robot
cross the road?
Because he was carbon-bonded
to the chicken.
We have a lot of work to do.
That sounds like old Morse code.
What does it say?
"Danger,
Will Robinson, danger."
William. Come in.
Unlock.
You said someone was in danger.
We all are.
You are wise to arm yourself.
This gun is set to fire
for me only...
so don't try anything funny.
Lock.
You misjudge me.
I only want to help you.
Help us?
You tried to kill us.
But now our fates
are intertwined.
If your father
and that idiot West fail...
I have no chance
of getting home.
It's in my best interests
that they succeed...
and I always follow
my best interests.
What monsters roam
these alien wilds?
They're fools!
To set off blindly
across this savage land.
Much as I hate to admit it...
it will be much harder
without them.
What are you talking about?
They'll be back.
They'll be OK.
Will they?
Someone should go after them.
Unlock.
I forbid it. You're a boy.
A clever one,
but a child nonetheless.
This planet
is likely full of predators.
Even if you found them,
what if they're hurt? Ravaged?
Dying?
What good could you do?
You can help them.
You're a doctor.
I'm a doctor.
We made it.
Mom didn't see us.
That's fantastic.
I told them we could get
into the bubble this way.
The bubble's growing!
Run, child!
Cool.
Wait!
Come on.
We can always go back.
It's just like stepping
between two rooms.
I can barely contain my glee.
Dad's signal is...
this way.
I loathe children.
Billy...kissing...
hot wings, orchids, corn.
Waves...Billy...
popcorn with...kissing...
What did you find?
Come on.
No time to dawdle.
Let's move along.
Follow your father's signal.
There's a good boy.
Come on.
All things really do come
to he who waits.
What is this place?
The shock must have
scrambled your brain.
Take a look around.
Don't you recognize this spot?
You're home.
This can't be.
What have you done to the ship?
Where is my family?
What chance do you think
your family had without you?
A few spiders survived
the destruction of the Proteus.
They reached this planet and...
I can still hear
the women scream.
Who are you?
You don't recognize me?
I'm your son Will.
Dad's signal
is just over this ridge.
Be still, my foolish heart.
Shit.
A boy of your intelligence
should never swear.
Shit.
Indeed.
Look, Father...
what my flights of fancy
have wrought.
I used your hyper engine
to build my time machine.
OK, Robot, put him down.
Affirmative.
Where are we?
I think the Jupiter 2,
but in a different future.
Father?
Once this core material...
is fully introduced
into the control console...
Core material.
If we could get that
back to our Jupiter...
I will open a doorway
stable enough...
for one person to take
one trip through time...
and space as well.
Commence proto-generation.
Cool, huh?
Today, I will change history.
I'm gonna go back to that day
you dragged us into space.
I'll stop the ship
from taking off.
I'll save the family.
Earth, October 1, 2058.
Target lock confirmed.
Excellent.
Son...
Look around.
The force of your time machine
is ripping this planet apart.
These violent distortions
in time...
are being caused
by your experiment.
What if it has the same effect
on Earth?
What if, in getting home...
you destroy Earth
in the process?
I know you mean well.
I'm going home.
I'm going to save the family.
You've got to listen to me.
I'm your father!
My father?
Let me tell you about my father.
I'll never forget
that morning 20 years ago.
What was it you said?
"l'm coming back.
I promise."
You promised...
and you never came home.
My father's not
coming to the rescue.
What do you think you're doing,
young man?
Let me tell you about life.
Around every corner,
monsters wait.
I know. I am one.
We monsters have no fear
in devouring little boys.
To survive, you must be
fully prepared to kill.
I can do it.
Can you?
Listen to me, my child...
I've crossed this world
with you...
risked my life,
but I would not throw it away.
Who knows what dangers
lie ahead?
You can't protect us.
I can.
I will.
Gimme the gun.
Enable gun for all users.
Voiceprint confirmed.
A brief lesson in survival
on this world or any other--
never trust anyone.
Especially me.
It's almost time.
I hope it works.
Never fear...
Smith is here.
Don't move,
Professor Robinson...
or this peculiar family reunion
will be tragically brief.
I'll ask you
to step away from that.
It's a time machine,
you idiot.
I had hoped to take over
the ship with this.
One of life's little ironies.
Let's try this dance again.
You are the puppet,
I am the puppeteer.
Do try to get it right
this time.
Robot, you will respond
to my voice alone.
Affirmative.
We need electric disrupters.
That's good I met you.
You did it.
Just like I imagined.
You linked
the dimensional sifter...
to the navigational array.
That's how it can be in
the same place at the same time.
But the spatial delivery system,
the targeting laser...
I never thought of those.
The future is never what
it seems like when you're 10.
Say good-bye to your past!
Your future lies with me.
I'm going home in your place.
What are you grinning at?
Look around you...
at this hostile world.
Do you think a boy
could have survived all alone?
Never fear...
Smith is here.
It's Dr. Smith.
Hello.
How nice to see me again
after all these years.
Confused?
Have I changed?
The spider's sting had some
unexpected side effects.
My unique gifts
gave me an advantage...
in this quarrelsome world.
After the women were savaged...
I became the father
Will never had.
Two decades of agony taught me
the error of my ways.
But you, your crude ambition
fills me with self-loathing.
You see,
I have looked within me...
and what I see is you!
I never liked me anyway.
Robot, kill them all.
Wait.
Dr. Smith, please.
Don't.
Very well.
Robot, take them inside
and keep them there.
If they move...
then kill them.
Proceed or be destroyed.
Nothing works.
I'll draw his fire,
you grab Will and get out.
Halt!
Stop!
Do you remember me?
Do you remember what I
taught you about friendship?
I need you to help us now,
because we're friends.
Logic error.
Friendship does not compute.
Forget logic.
Act with your heart.
Robot has no heart.
Robot is powered by
a fusion pulse generator.
Every living thing has a heart.
My programming has been modified
to remove all emotion.
Any attempts to override
command protocols...
may result in fusing
my neural net.
Please, Robot?
If you don't let us go,
we're all gonna die.
I'm asking you now,
will you help us?
Will you be my friend?
Robot attempting
to deactivate control bolt.
-Commands overridden!
-Do it!
Destroy Robinson family!
Destroy!
You did it.
Robot will save Will Robinson.
Robot will save his friend.
Where are they?
Wait here.
Without that core...
I can't promise
we'll get off this rock.
See if you can make it
back to our Jupiter.
I'll get the core material
and meet you there.
We don't have the trackers
to find our way back.
The family needs their father.
The crew needs their pilot.
I can't fly the ship
as well as you can.
You're their best chance
to survive.
Listen to me.
I know you never wanted
to take this job.
I think you're going to turn out
to be a grade-A baby-sitter.
So...
the camper's all yours now.
Take care of them.
Good luck.
-Dad!
-Professor!
Remember the space spiders
in the Proteus?
They're not going to be able
to get back.
Enable all missiles.
But the warheads don't work.
Just do it.
Look!
Damn, he's still breathing.
Fire in the hole.
So these sailors,
they drew shapes in the sky...
Look! It's a flare!
...to help them
find their way home.
Danger, Will Robinson!
Climb on! Hurry!
Field dampeners on-line.
Portal compression commenced.
Tell me again, old monster,
how did the girls die?
We've been over this before,
son.
In all the years since...
the spiders
have never resurfaced.
Why?
Let's forget the past.
Portal aperture reduction, 50%%%.
Careful, child!
The plasma around the portal...
will rip a man into pieces!
Haven't you made the doorway...
too small?
Not for me.
But then I'm not going, am l?
Spiders didn't kill the girls.
It was you.
I just never let myself see it.
You kept me alive
because you needed me.
Because I could
build this for you.
Poor boy.
Did you really think
I would let you go?
Let all that I have become
vanish?
Look at me!
I am no mere man!
I...am...a...god!
Within these egg sacs
grow the seeds...
of a master race of spiders.
We shall descend upon
helpless Earth...
an entire planet to rule!
An entire planet
on which to feed!
Time to die...son.
I'm not your son.
Good-bye.
My father once said...
Evil always finds its true form.
You should have killed me
when you had the chance.
You were right.
I couldn't kill the man...
but I can kill the monster!
Spare me
the fuming of the righteous.
I think there's time for a snack
before my trip.
The pain.
You ain't seen nothing yet.
Remember the Proteus?
These monsters
eat their wounded.
Take all the time you want
to die!
Wake up, son!
Dad?
Core material insertion
complete.
All table run--2058.
Mission control.
You could've taken the core
and left before it was too late.
I couldn't let you fall.
You're my boy.
Mom ! It's them.
Oh, Mom !
You all right?
You're not as dumb as you look.
I'm going to get your name
tattooed right here.
Greetings.
Where's John?
The bubble closed behind us.
It was his only way back.
I'm sorry.
We've already begun
the preflight countdown.
I'm going to save
as many lives as I can.
I kept hoping somehow
he'd make it back.
Let's go, Major.
Good-bye, my love.
Engaging primary thrusters now.
Look. He made it.
Go.
We're not getting any altitude.
We don't have enough power.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't save them.
So many years ago.
I can still feel it--
our sun...
our Earth.
It's all I've thought about--
going home.
A long time ago,
you told a small boy...
that one day he'd understand
how much his father loved him.
I could never see
how much you cared...
until now.
Come.
Let's go.
I kept hoping he'd make it back.
Good-bye, my love.
Look!
Don't make me wait another
lifetime to know how you feel.
Dad!
Dad, it worked!
Come with us!
I can't.
Only enough power for
one person, one trip, remember?
It's good to see you again, Mom.
It's good to see you all.
Take care of them, Will.
Don't forget me.
He sacrificed everything
for his family.
I'm glad you came back.
I just want you to know
I love you.
I love you very much.
The planet
is breaking up around us.
We're doomed!
Boy, that felt good.
Get us airborne.
I'm going to try
to reach escape velocity.
We don't have the core material.
The gravity wells
will pull us back down.
We might be able to--
We won't make it. I know.
We have to go...
down--
through the planet
as she's breaking up.
We can use
the planet's gravity...
What?
to throw us out the other side
and back into space.
That's insane.
I don't have time to argue.
That's a direct order.
Yes, sir, commander.
This should be interesting.
I see it.
Full burn.
Stop!
-Right!
-Left!
Let me drive.
All right, everybody,
hold your noses.
Rock and roll.
Amazing.
Nice work, flyboy.
I earn that kiss yet?
You earn this.
This one's on credit.
Cold fish, huh?
There you are. Come here.
Where have you been,
you little creep?
-Little creep?
-Oh, great.
Warning, Major West.
My sensors indicate
we have a problem.
The planet's gravity field
is collapsing.
We'll be sucked in.
No way to get clear in time.
The hyperdrive.
I'm accessing
the Proteus star maps.
Here we go again.
Targeting Alpha Prime...
I hope.
Initiate...now.
Cool.