I got nothing, sir.
No sign of Niobe or Ghost.
Nothing but blue pills.
Should we jack in and
try to contact them?
It wouldn't matter.
My gut says they're down.
Then we should start back.
No! If that ship can still fly,
we need it.
I was afraid you were
gonna say that.
Search every pipe, every hole,
every crack we know.
Sweep as wide as possible,
as fast as possible.
Captain, these lines are
crawling with calamari.
Then the sooner we
find them the better.
Thought you could use
something to eat.
Thank you.
Any change?
No.
- How is he?
- He's gonna be fine.
At least until he wakes up.
What do you mean?
Captain has some
questions for him.
He better have some
good answers.
You see these cuts?
I think they're self-inflicted.
- Why?
- VDTs maybe. I don't know.
But like I said,
the answer had better be good.
Roland. I'd like to run another
search through the Matrix.
- For what?
- For Neo.
How could he be in the Matrix, sir?
He's not plugged in.
Please, for me.
This is what keeps bothering me.
What?
His neural patterns don't read
like someone who's in a coma.
The strange thing is,
I see these patterns all the time.
- Where?
- On someone jacked in.
The big bubkis. Nada.
He's not in there.
- Sir, I got the projections.
- How long?
Based on the point of entry
and the past speed
it looks like the machines will be
in Zion in just under 20 hours.
Jesus H. Christ.
All right,
let's move with a purpose.
AK, get upstairs, I want
you on holographics.
Mauser, I want forward and
aft guns manned at all times.
And make sure we are running on
as few pads as possible.
Yes, sir.
Hey.
- Hey hey! We got a call.
- What?
Operator.
It's Seraph.
I bring word from The Oracle.
You must come at once.
Good morning.
Who are you?
My name is Sati.
Your name is Neo.
My papa says you're not
supposed to be here.
He says you must be lost.
Are you lost, Neo?
- Where am I?
- This is the train station.
- This isn't the Matrix?
- That's where the train goes.
That's where we're going,
but you cannot go with us.
- Why not?
- He won't let you.
- Who won't?
- The Trainman. I don't like him.
But my papa says we have to do
what the Trainman says
or else he will leave us here
forever and ever.
Morpheus, Trinity,
thank you for coming.
One thing I've learned
in all my years
is that nothing ever works out
just the way you want it to.
- Who are you?
- I'm The Oracle.
I wish there was an easier way
to get through this,
but there ain't.
I'm sorry this had to happen.
I'm sorry I couldn't be sitting
here like you remember me,
but it wasn't meant to be.
What happened?
I made a choice,
and that choice cost me
more than I wanted it to.
What choice?
To help you, to guide Neo.
Now, since the real test
for any choice is
having to make
the same choice again,
knowing full well
what it might cost,
I guess I feel pretty good
about that choice,
'cause here I am, at it again.
Do you know
what happened to Neo?
Yes.
He is trapped in a place
between this world and
the machine world.
The link is controlled by
a program called the Trainman.
He uses it to smuggle programs
in and out of the Matrix.
If he finds out where Neo is
before you get to him,
then I'm afraid our choices
are going to become difficult.
Why?
Because of who
the Trainman works for.
The Merovingian.
He has placed a bounty
on your lives.
You must be careful
at all times.
Seraph knows how to
find the Trainman.
He'll go with you.
For years he has protected me.
I hope he can do
the same for you.
Please, follow me.
Oracle...
I know, Morpheus.
I can see you're
filled with doubt,
clouded by uncertainty.
After everything
that has happened,
how can you expect me
to believe you?
I don't.
I expect just
what I've always expected:
For you to make up your
own damn mind.
Believe me or don't.
All I can do is tell you that
your friend is in trouble,
and he needs your help.
He needs all our help.
- Are you from the Matrix?
- Yes.
No.
- I mean, I was.
- Why did you leave?
- I had to.
- I had to leave my home too.
Sati! Come here, darling.
Leave the poor man in peace.
Yes, Papa.
I am sorry.
She is still very curious.
I know you.
Yes, in the restaurant
of the Frenchman.
I am Rama-Kandra.
This is my wife, Kamala.
My daughter, Sati.
We are most honoured
to meet you.
- You are programs.
- Oh, yes.
I am the power-plant
systems manager
for recycling operations.
My wife is an interactive
software programmer.
She is highly creative.
What are you doing here?
You do not belong here.
Kamala! Goodness, I apologise.
My wife can be very direct.
It's okay.
I don't have an answer.
I don't even know where "here" is.
This place is nowhere.
It is between your world
and our world.
- Who's the Trainman?
- He works for the Frenchman.
Why'd I know you were
going to say that?
The Frenchman does not forget,
and he does not forgive.
- You know him?
- I know only what I need to know.
I know that if you want to take
something from our world
into your world,
that does not belong there,
you must go to the Frenchman.
Is that what you're
doing here?
Rama, please.
I do not want to be cruel, Kamala.
He may never see another
face for the rest of his life.
I'm sorry.
You don't have to answer
that question.
No, I don't mind.
The answer is simple.
I love my daughter
very much.
I find her to be
the most beautiful thing
I have ever seen.
But where we are from,
that is not enough.
Every program that is created
must have a purpose.
If it does not,
it is deleted.
I went to the Frenchman
to save my daughter.
- You do not understand.
- I just have never...
Heard a program
speak of love.
- It is a human emotion.
- No, it is a word.
What matters is the
connection the word implies.
I see that you are in love.
Can you tell me
what you would give
to hold on to
that connection?
Anything.
Then perhaps the reason
you are here is not so different
than the reason I am here.
That's him.
- Get away! Get away from me!
- We don't want trouble.
- Get the hell away from me!
- We need your help.
I can't help you!
No one can help you!
Oh, no!
Damn it!
- When is the train due?
- It is already late.
It's not like the Trainman
to be late.
You think it has something
to do with me?
I cannot say.
Who knows such things?
Only the Oracle.
- You know the Oracle?
- Everyone knows the Oracle.
I consulted with her before
I met with the Frenchman.
She promised she
would look after Sati
after we said goodbye.
Goodbye?
- You're not staying with her?
- It is not possible.
Our arrangement
with the Frenchman
was for our daughter only.
My wife and I must return
to our world.
Why?
- That is our karma.
- You believe in karma?
Karma is a word, like love.
A way of saying:
"What I am here to do."
I do not resent my karma.
I'm grateful for it.
Grateful for
my wonderful wife,
for my beautiful daughter.
They are gifts,
and so I do what I must do to honour them.
- Papa, the train!
- Yes. Find your bag. Quickly.
Can I carry that for you?
All right.
Hurry it up, I'm late!
Who are you?
- He is a friend.
- Rama.
I know you.
- So that's what they wanted.
- I need to get back.
I'll pay you
whatever you want.
One way or another,
I'm getting on this train.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
You're gonna stay right here
until the Merovingian
says different.
If I know him,
you're gonna be here
for a long, long time.
- I don't want to hurt you.
- You don't get it.
I built this place.
Down here,
I make the rules.
I make the threats.
Down here, I'm god.
Get on the train
or you'll stay here with him.
We should return to the Oracle.
She will know what to do.
No. We know
what has to be done.
Shit.
You gotta be kidding.
Holy shit, it's wingless.
I get it.
You must be ready to die.
I need to speak with him.
The only way you're
getting through this door
is over my big, dead ass.
So be it.
There are no weapons
allowed in the club.
At the bottom of this elevator,
there is a coat-check girl,
and if we are lucky,
one man for checking weapons.
And if we're unlucky?
There will be many men.
Can I take your...?
Oh, my god.
What in the hell?
I don't believe this.
Hey! Hey!
Is the prodigal child returns?
L'ange sans ailes.
Are you here for the bounty,
Seraph?
Tell me, how many bullets
are there in those guns?
I don't know, but I don't think
you have enough.
- We only want to talk.
- Oh, yes.
I'm sure you do.
You have fought
through hell to do so.
Yes?
I'll tell you what I will do.
Put down the guns,
and I will promise you
a safe passage out of here.
- All three of us?
- Oh, yes, yes.
Of course.
Quelle bonne surprise, n'est pas?
Who could've guessed we'd all be
seeing each other so soon
after our last meeting?
The Fates are too kind, eh?
And since you, my little Judas,
have brought them here
I can only surmise
that the fortuneteller has
found herself another shell?
Disappointing,
but not unexpected.
I do hope, however,
she has the good manners
to learn her lesson,
and to remember that there is
no action without consequence.
And if you take
something from me,
you will pay the price.
You know why we are here?
Come now,
what kind of question is this?
Of course I know.
It is my business to know.
Some might think
this is a strange coincidence,
but I do not.
I am curious, though,
as to how it actually happened.
- Do you know?
- No.
No?
I did not think so.
But it is always best
to ask, huh?
We want to make a deal.
Always straight to business,
huh, Morpheus?
Okay.
I have something you want.
To make a deal,
you must have something
I want, yes?
And it so happens
there is something I want.
Something I have wanted
ever since I first came here.
It is said they
cannot be taken,
they can only be given.
What?
The eyes of The Oracle.
I have told you before,
there's no escaping
the nature of the universe.
It is that nature that has
again brought you to me.
Where some see coincidence,
I see consequence.
Where others see chance,
I see cost.
Bring me the eyes
of The Oracle,
and I will give you back
your saviour.
It seems a perfectly fair
and reasonable deal to me.
Yes? No?
I don't have time
for this shit.
You wanna make a deal?
How about this?
You give me Neo,
or we all die,
right here, right now.
Interesting deal.
You are really ready to die
for this man?
- Believe it.
- She'll do it.
If she has to,
she'll kill every one of us.
She's in love.
It is remarkable
how similar the pattern of love
is to the pattern of insanity.
Time's up.
What's it gonna be, Merv?
Okay. You got yourself in here,
you can get yourself out.
Are you ready for us?
Almost, sir.
They got some pretty ancient
hacks here, we're working on it.
- But you found Neo?
- Can't you see him?
No, sir.
We were reading something,
but I couldn't tell what it was.
I can't leave yet.
I have to see her.
Now?
It's my last chance.
That's it. That's the secret.
- You've got to use your hands.
- Why?
Cookies need love
like everything does.
Neo!
I was hoping to have these
done before you got here.
Oh, well.
Sati, honey, I think it's time
for a tasting.
Take the bowl to Seraph
and find out if they're ready.
Okay.
- I'm glad you got out.
- Me too.
So, do you recognise me?
- A part of you.
- Yeah, that's how it works.
Some bits you lose,
some bits you keep.
I don't yet recognise my face
in the mirror, but...
I still love candy.
No, thank you.
Remember what you were like
when you first walked
through my door,
jittery as a junebug?
And now, just look at you.
You sure did surprise me, Neo,
and you still do.
You gave me a few surprises too.
I hope I helped.
You helped me to get here,
but my question is, why?
Where is this going?
- Where does it end?
- I don't know.
You don't know
or you won't tell me?
I told you before,
no one can see beyond a choice
they don't understand,
and I mean no one.
What choice?
It doesn't matter.
It's my choice.
I have mine to make,
same as you have yours.
Does that include
what things to tell me
and what not to tell me?
Of course not.
Then why didn't you tell me
about the Architect?
Why didn't you tell me
about Zion,
and the Ones before me?
Why didn't you tell me
the truth?
Because it wasn't time
for you to know.
Who decided it wasn't time?
You know who.
I did.
Then I think it's time for me
to know a few more things.
So do I.
Tell me how I separated
my mind from my body
without jacking in.
Tell me how I stopped four
sentinels by thinking it.
Tell me just what the hell
is happening to me.
The power of the One
extends beyond this world.
It reaches from here
all the way back to
where it came from.
- Where?
- The Source.
That's what you felt when you
touched those sentinels.
But you weren't ready for it.
You should be dead,
but apparently you weren't
ready for that either.
The Architect told me that
if I didn't return to the Source,
Zion would be destroyed
by midnight tonight.
Please.
You and I may not be able
to see beyond our own choices,
but that man can't see
past any choice.
Why not?
He doesn't understand them.
He can't.
To him, they are variables
in an equation.
One at a time,
each variable must be solved,
then countered.
That's his purpose.
To balance the equation.
What's your purpose?
To unbalance it.
Why? What do you want?
I want the same thing
you want, Neo.
And I am willing to go
as far as you are to get it.
The end of the war.
Is it going to end?
One way or another.
Can Zion be saved?
I'm sorry, I don't have the
answer to that question, but...
If there is an answer,
there's only one place
you're going to find it.
- Where?
- You know where.
And if you can't find
the answer,
then I'm afraid there may be
no tomorrow for any of us.
What does that mean?
Everything
that has a beginning,
has an end.
I see the end coming.
I see the darkness spreading.
I see death.
And you are all
that stands in his way.
Smith.
Very soon, he is going to
have the power
to destroy this world.
But I believe
he won't stop there.
He can't.
He won't stop until
there's nothing left at all.
What is he?
He is you.
Your opposite,
your negative.
The result of the equation
trying to balance itself out.
- And if I can't stop him?
- One way or another, Neo...
this war is going to end.
Tonight,
the future of both worlds
will be in your hands
or in his.
How are you feeling?
Are you all right?
I need time.
- That figures.
- Captain Roland.
- What's up, Maggie?
- Bane is, sir. He's conscious.
Good.
Maybe he's got some answers.
I love that smell.
I sure am going to miss it.
- Oracle.
- I know.
I know.
Sati, honey.
Take a few cookies and
go with Seraph.
Can I come back?
I would like to come back.
- I would like that too.
- Then I'll see you tomorrow.
I hope so, hon, I hope so.
I'm scared, Seraph.
Come.
He's following us.
Well, well,
it's been a long time.
I remember chasing you
was like chasing a ghost.
I have beaten you before.
Yes, true,
but as you can see,
things are
a little different now.
And you must be
the last exile.
The Oracle told me
about you.
Really?
What did she say about me?
That you were a bad man.
Oh, I'm not so bad,
once you get to know me.
The great and powerful Oracle,
we meet at last.
I suppose you've been
expecting me, right?
The all-knowing Oracle
is never surprised.
How can she be?
She knows everything.
But if that's true,
then why is she here
if she knew I was coming?
Why wouldn't she leave?
Maybe you knew
I was going to do that,
maybe you didn't.
If you did, that means
you baked those cookies
and set that plate right there,
deliberately, purposefully.
Which means that
you're sitting there also
deliberately, purposefully.
What did you do with Sati?
"Cookies need love
like everything does."
You are a bastard.
You would know, Mom.
Do what you're here to do.
Yes, ma'am.
I really wish I could help,
but I just...
I don't remember any of it.
What about the cuts
on your arms?
Those cuts are
more than one day old.
Yeah, definitely.
You're right about that, sir.
They look like they might
be self-inflicted.
But why would I do
something like that to myself?
Unless, of course,
I wasn't myself.
But if I'm not me,
then who am I?
Has this man
been tested for VDTs?
Yes, sir. It was negative.
But he is showing a lot
of unusual neural activity.
Some cross-synaptic firing,
as well as signs of
recent trauma,
with fresh fibrotic scarring
throughout the cortex.
I want the truth.
I don't care what it takes.
Make him remember.
Sir, we found her.
- The "Logos"?
- Yes, sir.
'Bout time we got some
goddamn good news.
Are the thermals picking up
any signs of life?
No, sir. Nothing yet.
What about the ship?
Holographic says
the hull's still intact.
Drop her down and
keep a man in the rear turret.
Yes, sir.
Get a full diagnostic on that ship
as fast as humanly possible.
Careful, sir.
The squids are sneaky bastards.
It could be a trap.
What was that?
You can put that shit away,
boys.
All she needs is a jump.
- Niobe.
- Morpheus.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
We didn't know
what happened after...
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
I'm happy to see you too.
- Did you get Neo out?
- Yes.
- How did you know about that?
- The Oracle.
You saw her?
Just before
the sentinels found us.
What did she tell you?
The same thing
she always does.
Exactly what I needed
to hear.
In less than 12 hours,
the machines
will breach the dock walls.
Every simulation we've run,
we've seen that once the
machines are inside the city,
the odds of our survival
decrease dramatically.
Thus, our primary objective
must be to destroy
or disable the diggers
inside the dock.
If we can do that,
perhaps we can prevent them
from ever reaching the city.
If not, the only place
we'll be able to mount
an effective defence
will be at the entrance of
the temple.
It is small enough that it will
force them into a bottleneck,
allowing us to concentrate
the remainder of our defence.
We understand that you've
requested additional volunteers.
That is correct.
Precisely what size of force
are you planning to commit
to the primary dock objective?
Right now, the entire APU Corps
and half the infantry.
Half the infantry?
If it were up to me,
councillor...
I'd take every man,
woman and child,
put a gun in their hand
and march them
straight into that dock.
Perhaps it is best
that it is not up to you.
Time will tell, councillor.
Commander,
just one more question.
Has there been word
from the "Nebuchadnezzar"?
None, and at this point
there's no reason to expect
that there ever will be.
Perhaps.
But we can hope.
I'm afraid hope is
an indulgence
I don't have time for.
- Zee, what are you doing?
- Making shells.
They're evacuating our level.
We have to go.
- I'm not going with you.
- What?
They've called for volunteers
to hold the dock.
Kids, you stay here.
I know how you feel, Zee,
but you can't do this.
- I have to.
- Why?
Because I love him.
I love him the same as
he loves me.
And if I were out there
and he were here,
I know what he'd do.
But you're gonna get
yourself killed.
It's crazy, Zee.
Maybe it is.
But ask yourself,
if it were Dozer,
and you knew the only chance
you had to see him again
was to hold the dock...
what would you do?
Make shells.
What the shit is going on
over here?
An accident, sir.
I didn't see...
- I'm sorry.
- Who the hell are you?
A unit volunteer, sir.
What's a pod-born
pencil-neck like you
doing volunteering for
my Corps?
I want to do my part, sir.
We gotta hold the dock.
- How old are you, kid?
- Eighteen.
Should have said 16,
I might have believed that.
Okay, I'm 16.
Minimum age for
the Corps is eighteen.
Sixteen's too young.
The machines don't care
how old I am.
They'll kill me just the same.
Ain't that the goddamn truth.
Give me a chance, sir.
I won't let you down.
You do, and you'll find me
and the machines
have got something in common.
Okay, charge the igniter.
She lives again.
You want us
to patch an uplink
to reload the operations
software, Sparky?
Yeah, that'd be swell.
You could clean the
windshield while you're at it.
Uplinks are in place,
I'm bringing her back online.
Looking good, except, uhh...
Something's wrong
with the Matrix feed.
No, there's not.
You're looking
at what we're looking at.
-What the hell is
going on in there.
Whatever it is,
it can't be good.
The machines have taken
Junction 21.
The way I see it,
if we drop down
from broadcast here,
intersect 153,
we might surprise them.
We go first,
hammer as deep as we can,
and then blow our EMP.
Hopefully we can punch a hole
big enough for you to get through.
It ain't pretty,
but the way I see it,
it's the only way back.
No, it's not.
There's another way.
A support line.
It drops down right here,
1000 metres short of 21.
If we're lucky,
we may be able to slip down
without them ever knowing.
That's a mechanical line.
It's impossible.
- No one can pilot a mechanical.
- I can.
- Bullshit.
- I've done it.
That was a long time ago,
Niobe.
I said I can do it.
So what?
If you can, you'll be
the only one that can,
there's no way
we can follow you.
Hi.
I know time is always
against us.
I'm sorry that
I took so long.
- But I wanted to be sure.
- Sure of what?
- I know what I have to do.
- What?
There's no easy way
to say this,
so I'll just say it.
I have to take
one of the ships.
What?
To go where?
To the machine city.
I know it's difficult
to understand.
No, it's not. You're out
of your goddamn mind.
I still have to go.
You'll never make it.
In 100 years no ship has been
within 100 kilometres of it.
- You'll never make it.
- I have to try.
Is this what
The Oracle has told you?
No.
This is asinine.
If you want to kill yourself,
go do it, but do it without
wasting one of our ships.
You have to believe me.
I have to go.
Bullshit!
I am the captain of this ship.
I say where it has to go!
And believe me, this ship
will go to hell long before
I let you take it anywhere.
- He can take mine.
- You can't do that.
Don't even think of
trying to tell me
what I can or cannot do
with my ship
after that little speech.
- But for chrissake, Niobe...
- I'll pilot this ship,
he can take mine.
If we leave inside the hour,
we should reach Zion
as the machines do.
That's as good a plan as any.
It's a waste.
A goddamn waste.
Two ships, two directions.
Sounds like providence,
doesn't it, Morpheus?
You've never believed in
the One.
I still don't.
Then why are you doing this?
I believe in him.
Thank you.
- What's that for?
- To help you relax.
To make it easier for
you to remember.
What if I don't want
to remember?
Why would you want that?
What if I blew that EMP?
What if I did destroy
those ships,
and I am responsible for
the deaths of all those men?
If I did that...
it wouldn't be very safe
for me here, would it?
Of course, it might not be
very safe for you either.
I'm ready.
Trinity...
There's something I have to say.
Something you need to
understand.
I know I'm supposed to go.
But beyond that,
I don't know. I...
I know. You don't think
you're coming back.
I knew it the moment
you said you had to leave.
I could see it in your face.
Just like you knew the
moment you looked at me,
that I was coming with you.
I'm scared, Trin.
So am I.
It took me ten minutes
to buckle up one boot.
But I'll tell you something.
Six hours ago,
I told the Merovingian,
I was ready to give anything
and everything for you.
Do you know what's changed
in the last six hours?
No.
Nothing.
Get finished loading
that ammunition.
Just about, sir.
Let's move it. We are out of time.
You're not leaving them anything?
He said he didn't need it.
I ain't saying goodbye.
I'm saying good luck.
Thank you.
I can only hope you know
what you're doing.
Me too.
It was an honour, sir.
No, the honour is still mine.
We're ready, sir.
About damn time.
We're already late, captain,
so let's hit it and hit it hard.
Bye, baby.
Take good care of them.
Ready?
Engine's still firing.
Must be a fuse. I'll check it out.
I should've known
he'd send his bitch first.
Bane?
No one ever got away from me
as many times as you did.
Every single time,
I thought it was the last.
Every time,
I was sure we had you,
but somehow you'd
slip through our fingers.
I really can't express just
how aggravating that can be.
What are you talking about?
I think I might enjoy killing you
as much as killing him.
Neo, it's Bane. He's psychotic!
You're gonna pay for that.
Twenty-seven kilometres to go.
Captain, we've got an emergency
down here.
What is it, AK?
It's Maggie, sir.
She's dead, murdered.
I think it was Bane.
Goddamn it.
I knew it. I knew he was
out of his goddamn mind.
He fired that EMP.
Goddamn it, I should have
beaten it out of him.
We searched the whole ship,
captain.
He ain't here.
- I know where he is.
- The "Logos".
- We gotta go back.
- Too late.
You don't know that.
What if they need our help?
- It's too dangerous.
- Why?
Because if he's killed them
he'll control another EMP.
At this point,
they're on their own.
Just like us.
Mr. Anderson.
I see you are as predictable
in this world
as you are in the other.
- What?
- He's out of his mind.
It might appear that
way to you.
But Mr. Anderson and I know that
appearances can be deceiving.
Confused, Mr. Anderson?
It'll all become clear in a moment.
Now, thank you for
bringing me the gun.
You can set it down
right there.
Don't do it.
- Shoot. Shoot now.
- Yes, shoot.
Fry us. Burn us alive.
Do it. If you don't,
he'll kill us both.
Look at him. He knows
he should do it, but he won't.
- He can't.
- Do it.
Back away from the gun
and turn around.
Let her go.
Somehow familiar, isn't it?
We've been here before,
you and I, remember?
I do. I think of nothing else.
- Who are you?
- Still don't recognise me?
I admit, it is difficult to even think
encased in this rotting piece of meat.
The stink of it filling every breath,
a suffocating cloud you can't escape.
Disgusting.
Look at how pathetically
fragile it is.
Nothing this weak is meant
to survive.
- What do you want?
- I want what you want.
Yes. That's it, Mr. Anderson.
Look past the flesh.
Look through the soft gelatine
of these dull cow eyes
and see your enemy.
- No.
- Oh, yes, Mr. Anderson.
It can't be.
There's nowhere I can't go.
There is nowhere I won't find you.
- It's impossible.
- Not impossible.
Inevitable.
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
This is it. It's gotta be.
Oh, no.
I wish you could see yourself,
Mr. Anderson.
Blind messiah.
You're a symbol for all of
your kind, Mr. Anderson.
Helpless.
Pathetic.
Just waiting to be put out
of your misery.
I can see you.
It's not over, Mr. Anderson.
It's not over.
- Trinity!
- Neo.
Neo.
Oh, no. Your eyes.
I'll be okay.
It's all right, Trin.
But I think you're gonna
have to drive.
Seismic's projecting
22 minutes to breach.
They can't know we
don't have an EMP.
They'll have to attack in waves.
Concentrate our offence
on the diggers.
Order the APUs into position.
Yes, sir.
Come on, move.
All right!
This is it.
Now, you all know me,
so I'll just say this
as simple as I can.
If it's our time to die,
it's our time.
All I ask is, if we have to give
these bastards our lives,
we give them hell
before we do!
- You scared, Charra?
- Shit, yeah.
But I'll make you a deal.
You keep loading,
I keep shooting.
Deal.
- Holy Christ, would you look at that.
- Quiet.
- How far to the opening?
- 1.4 kilometres.
We're still generating
too hot a field.
Ghost,
kill all auxiliary systems.
Give me full manual.
Drop down four pads.
It'll bottom out.
- Easy, baby.
- Seven hundred metres.
If we can just get close enough...
Six hundred metres.
There.
Shit!
- Jig's up, here they come.
- Give me full power, full systems!
Man the gun turrets, every
goddamn one of them! Go, go!
Ghost, you're the best gunner
we have, go with them.
Morpheus, take his place!
I'm coming, baby.
Here they come.
Slow down,
this ain't the "Logos".
Hang on to your lunch,
Roland, here we go.
Holy Christ, I didn't know
this ship could do that.
Breach!
The dock is breached!
Knuckle up!
For Zion!
Shit.
Come on, let's go.
Knuckle up!
Reload!
Reload nine!
Go, go! Move, move!
Watch your left!
Don't let them through!
Zuka!
Oh, my god.
Where the hell's my infantry?
I want that goddamn
machine taken down!
Dig this!
Oh, shit!
- Bogey two at the breach point!
- Goddamn it!
Shit, she's got a fat ass.
Keep them off me!
Christ,
there's a shitstorm of them.
Captain, you see that?
They're after the radio.
Stop them!
Damn it!
Yeah.
Grab my belt.
Just give me one clean shot.
Damn it!
Charra!
- Commander Lock, I got incoming!
- We got a dock full of incoming!
Sir, yes, sir.
But this is different, sir.
What?
I think it's one of ours, sir.
That's impossible.
Holographics are trying
to confirm sir.
Contact them.
I want access codes.
We're trying, sir.
There's no response.
It's a trick. That's not
one of ours, it can't be.
That's a mechanical line.
No one can pilot mechanical.
Forward aft,
30 degrees at 80 percent.
Thirty degrees, 80.
Lower starboard 60 degrees,
- 20 percent.
- Sixty degrees.
- Shit! Come on, keep up!
- I'm trying!
Sir, holographic confirms.
It's the "Hammer", sir.
How can that be?
The ship is under attack,
sustaining heavy damage.
But at its present velocity,
it'll reach Gate 3 in 12 minutes.
Sir their EMP could take out
every sentinel out there.
It'd take out more than that.
It'll wipe out our entire
defence system.
We blow an EMP inside,
then we lose the dock.
Sir, we already lost the dock.
Open the gate.
Gate 3 is not responding!
We've taken critical
damage, sir!
We've lost control!
We can't open it!
There's the exit.
On my mark,
give me full power 90 degrees
to lower-left starboard.
Full power,
ninety degrees.
Now!
Hold on, baby.
Goddamn, woman,
you can drive.
We ain't home yet.
What about the gate?
Sentinels are inside the dock.
Are we too late?
- How many APUs are operational?
- Thirteen, sir.
Get me the one
closest to Gate 3.
Reload!
He's pissing metal.
Go!
Heads up!
They're coming around!
Behind you!
It's jammed!
Forget it, kid!
Get out of here!
Got it!
Captain Mifune.
Oh, no.
They're coming.
The "Hammer".
What?
You have to open that gate.
Cut the counterweights.
You can do it.
Hurry. There's no time.
Captain...
I didn't finish
the training program.
Neither did I.
- Lock that down!
- Kill the feeder!
We won't make it.
We gotta blow the EMP now.
Come on, someone, please.
Keep the weight forward.
Light as a feather,
as a feather.
Commander,
holographic reports
Captain Mifune's APU is
up and moving to Gate 3.
Don't over-squeeze
the trigger.
Captain Mifune's APU just
reached Gate 3.
- How much time?
- Two minutes to impact.
- Captain Mifune, do you copy?
- I think his radio is down, sir.
Mifune...
this is Lock.
I don't know if you can
hear me, but if you can...
the Hammer's two minutes away.
You've got two minutes, captain,
to get that gate open.
Link.
Get to the main deck!
Charge the EMP!
Do it, kid.
Neo. I believe.
- Yes!
- Can we make it?
We ain't come this far?
Almost home, almost home.
Burn it, Link!
- You did it.
- No.
We did it.
You're a hell of a pilot.
Some things in this
world never change.
But some things do?
Luckily...
some things do.
Link!
- Zee? Zee!
- Link!
I knew you'd come.
I knew it.
I made a promise.
You did wear it.
Are you kidding?
I'm never gonna take it off.
Three captains, one ship.
I assume the other ships
were lost
under equally pointless
circumstances.
It's good to see you too,
Jason.
The Council's waiting to hear
your explanation.
You forgive me for
not attending,
but I have to try to
salvage this debacle.
Did I miss something
Commander?
I thought we just
saved the dock.
That's the problem
with you people.
You can't think for five
minutes in front of your face.
That EMP knocked out almost
every piece of hardware
and every APU.
If I were the machines,
I'd send every sentinel
I had here right now.
Saved the dock, captain?
You just handed it to
them on a silver platter.
Come on, get it cut.
The bridge is clear.
Do you hear that?
Get that cable run!
I want the system back online!
Commander, it's the dock.
We've got incoming.
Order everyone to fall back.
Seal the shaft. Now.
Move it!
Oh, my god.
- All clear.
- Do it.
- Go! Come on! Run!
- Go!
Your move.
So you gave them your ship?
That is correct, councillor, I did.
Knowing what he planned
to do with it?
And The Oracle said
nothing of this?
She told me that Neo
would need my help,
and when the time came I would
choose to help him or not.
But what hope can
a single vessel have
against their entire
defence system?
None. It's completely impossible.
But he wouldn't listen.
He wouldn't even
take any ammunition.
He was totally out of
his goddamn mind.
No, he wasn't.
Neo is doing what he
believes he must do.
I don't know if what
he's doing is right.
I don't know...
if he'll reach the machine city.
And if he does, I don't know
what he can do to save us.
But I do know that
as long as there is
a single breath in his body,
he will not give up.
And neither can we.
Temperature's dropping.
Here we go.
We're over the fields,
aren't we?
How do you know that?
I can feel them.
Over there.
There's our path.
Can you see it?
Three lines.
Power lines.
Follow them.
What are they doing?
I don't know.
Lieutenant?
Goddamn it.
What do we do now,
Commander?
It is now a matter of time.
The machines will breach
the walls of this city.
I recommend that
the Council join
the rest of the non-military
personnel inside the Temple.
How long do we have?
Two hours. Maybe less.
My men have begun
fortifying the entrance
with enough artillery to
make our last stand.
Beyond that, there isn't
anything more I can do.
Commander, do you think
that we have any chance...
of surviving?
If I were you Councillor,
I wouldn't ask me
that question.
I would ask him.
Why?
Because he's the one
who believes in miracles.
There.
Those mountains.
That's it.
- Do you see what's out there?
- Yes.
If you tell me we'll make it,
I'll believe you.
We'll make it.
We have to.
Sentinels.
There's too many!
Gotcha!
Come on, Neo,
I need help here!
I can't beat them.
- What do we do?
- Go up, over them.
- What?
- The sky! It's the only way.
Then up we go.
Beautiful.
Pump the igniter.
The ship will start.
Again. Slowly.
Now!
Trin?
Trinity?
- I'm here.
- Where?
Here.
We made it.
You said we would.
It's unbelievable, Trin.
Light everywhere.
Like the whole thing
was built of light.
I wish you could see
what I see.
You've already
shown me so much.
What is it, Trinity?
What's wrong?
I can't go with you, Neo.
I've gone as far as I can.
What?
Oh, no.
Oh, no. No, no.
It's all right.
It's time.
I've done all that
I could do.
Now you have to do
the rest.
You have to finish it.
You have to save Zion.
I can't.
- Not without you.
- Yes, you can.
You will.
I believe it.
I always have.
Trinity.
Trinity, you can't die.
You can't.
Yes, I can.
You brought me back once.
But not this time.
Do you remember,
on that roof,
after you caught me,
the last thing I said to you?
You said, "I'm sorry".
I wish I hadn't.
That was my last thought.
I wished
I had one more chance
to say what really mattered.
To say how much
I loved you.
How grateful I was for every
moment I was with you.
But by the time I knew how to
say what I wanted to,
it was too late.
But you brought me back.
You gave me my wish.
One more chance to say
what I really wanted to say.
Kiss me.
Once more,
kiss me.
Get that ammunition
where it belongs!
You got one chance
to get this right.
Get that damn thing mounted!
- Hurry.
- Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Neo...
If you're gonna do something,
you better do it quick.
I only ask to say
what I've come to say.
After that, do what you want,
and I won't try to stop you.
Speak.
The program Smith has grown
beyond your control.
Soon he will spread
through this city
as he spread through
the Matrix.
You can not stop him.
- But I can.
- We don't need you!
We need nothing!
If that's true,
then I've made a mistake,
and you should kill me now.
What do you want?
Peace.
What are they doing?
What are you doing?
Morpheus!
And if you fail?
I won't.
Neo.
He fights for us.
Mr. Anderson, welcome back.
We missed you.
You like what I've done
with the place?
It ends tonight.
I know it does.
I've seen it.
That's why the rest of me
is just going to enjoy the show,
because we already know
that I'm the one that beats you.
Can you feel it, Mr. Anderson,
closing in on you?
Oh, I can.
I really should thank you for it.
After all, it was your life
that taught me the
purpose of all life.
The purpose of life is to end.
Why, Mr. Anderson?
Why, why, why?
Why do you do it?
Why? Why get up?
Why keep fighting?
Do you believe you're
fighting for something?
For more than your survival?
Can you tell me what it is?
Do you even know?
Is it freedom or truth?
Perhaps peace?
Could it be for love?
Illusions, Mr. Anderson.
Vagaries of perception.
Temporary constructs
of a feeble human intellect
trying desperately
to justify an existence
that is without meaning
or purpose!
And all of them as artificial
as the Matrix itself,
although only a human mind
could invent something
as insipid as love.
You must be able to see it,
Mr. Anderson.
You must know it by now.
You can't win.
It's pointless to keep fighting.
Why, Mr. Anderson, why?
Why do you persist?
Because I choose to.
This is my world!
My world!
Wait.
I've seen this.
This is it. This is the end.
Yes.
You were laying right there,
just like that.
And I, I...
I stand here, right here,
and I'm supposed to
say something.
I say:
"Everything that has
a beginning has an end, Neo."
What?
What did I just say?
No, no. This isn't right.
This can't be right.
Get away from me!
What are you afraid of?
It's a trick.
You were right, Smith.
You were always right.
It was inevitable.
Is it over?
Oh, no, no, no.
No, it's not fair.
It is done.
It doesn't make sense.
He did it.
He saved us.
It's over! He did it!
He did it!
He did it! It's over!
It's over! He did it!
He did it!
- What is it? What happened?
- Sir, he did it, sir. Neo, he did it.
- Did what?
- He ended the war.
The machines are gone.
The war is over, sir.
The war is over.
Zion! Zion!
Zion, it's over!
It's over!
The war is over!
I have imagined this moment,
for so long.
Is this real?
Neo, wherever you are,
thank you.
Good morning.
Well, now.
Ain't this a surprise.
You played a very
dangerous game.
Change always is.
Just how long do you think
this peace is going to last?
As long as it can.
What about the others?
What others?
The ones that want out.
Obviously, they will be freed.
I have your word?
What do you think I am?
Human?
Oracle!
We were afraid we
might not find you.
Everything's okay now.
Look, look.
Just look at that.
Beautiful.
Did you do that?
For Neo.
That's nice.
I know he'd love it.
Will we ever see him again?
I suspect so.
Someday.
Did you always know?
Oh, no. No, I didn't.
But I believed.
I believed.