I hate television...gives me headaches.
You know I heard there were so many magnetic waves
travelling through the air because of TV and telephones
then we're losing like 10 times as many
braincells as we're supposed to
like...all molecules in our heads are all unstable, all the
companies know about it but they're not doing anything about it
it's a big conspiracy.
You can pick something, I don't care.
Do you have any idea how many electro-rays
are travelling through our head every second?
I got a better one...have you heard about this
videotape that kills you when you watch it?
What kind of tape?
A tape...a regular tape
People run it...I don't know
You start to play it...and it's like
somebody's nightmare
then suddenly
this woman comes on
smiling at you, right?
seeing you through the screen
And as soon as it's over
your phone rings
Someone knows you've watched it.
And what they say is:
'You will die in 7 days.'
And exactly 7 days later...
Who told you that?
...somebody from Revere...
Who told you?
What's your problem?
I've watched it
It's a story, Katie!
No, me and Josh. We saw
it last weekend.
I thought you were with
your parents!
I wanted to tell you...
You were with Josh all weekend?
Some of his friends got this place
up in the mountains
They were trying to record
a football game
I guess the reception was so bad
What are you talking about...?
Listen to me!
We played the tape, the
game wasn't there.
It was...
What? What was it?
It was something else...
We thought it was some
kind of sick joke
but then the phone rang
It was a week ago
a week ago tonight.
You're just trying to scare me.
You freak!
You totally fell for it.
No.
So did you guys, you know, do anything?
Like what?
Oh my god. You totally did,
you're a whore...No.
There really is a tape...?
This is so lame.
Embry residence...?
Hello?
Hi, Mom.
Yeah, that was Becca.
My mom says Hi. She's glad that
you're here.
Ask her where she keeps her Vicodin.
Yeah, we're about to go to sleep.
Okay. Yeah, I will.
Ok, ok, yeah yeah I will!
No, I won't.
Bye Mom!
Becca, quit being a bitch! Where
is the remote?
Becca, quit!!!
Becca, can you hear me?
Don't tell me what to do!
I am being objective!
Listen Harvey, you punctilious prick!
You touch my column,
and I'm coming down there
poking your eye out with that little
red pencil you like so much!
Harvey?!
shooot!
Hey!
Hi.
Sorry I'm late.
No worries.
I want my own car.
Have you got a moment, miss Keller?
Um, sure!
Call me Rachel.
Please, sit down.
He certainly is very independent, isn't he?
Oh yeah. He sure is.
I never have to tell him to do anything.
Well, if that's a problem you'd be the first
teacher in history to say so.
Miss Keller...
Rachel.
I know that Aidan miss and just lost his cousin...Yes, and I'm
doing what I can to find him some good daycare, it's just...
No, that's not what I meant. By all means,
take your time.
I know they were very close.
Aidan and his cousin.
Yeah. They spent a few nights
a week together.
Did he talk to you about her death?
Well, like you said, he's not
the talkative type.
That doesn't mean he has
nothing to say.
He knows I'm there.
Yes, I'm sure he does.
But he may be expressing himself
in....other ways.
I'd like to show you something.
That's his cousin.
That's Katie.
Miss Keller...I'm bothered by
these drawings.
Listen...I appreciate your concern. But
my son lost his best friend 3 nights ago.
He's just trying to deal with it.
Yes, I understand, but these pictures
are Aidan's way of working it out.
of expressing himself, like you said.
He'll be okay.
You say she died 3 nights ago.
Yeah, that's right.
Aidan drew these last week.
What?
Nothing.
Should we read something?
I'm kinda tired.
Okay.
Sweet dreams.
We don't have enough time.
Honey, I know we've been
working a lot
and I'm sorry, but I promise you
I'm gonna make it up to you.
I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about time
before we die.
You have lots of time.
So you know when I'm
going to die?
No. No one does.
But I know you don't have
to worry about it.
Katie knew.
She told me.
Katie told you she was
gonna die?
She said she didn't had
enough time.
Good night, Rachel.
shooot!
Aidan?!
God damn it! Honey?!
Have you seen my black dress?
Aidan?
Have you seen my black....dress?
It's a little wrinkled.
It's fine.
Oh Ruthie.
I'm so sorry.
Are you alright, Dave?
Yeah, I'm fine.
How are you?
He sleeps all day
doesn't move
it's too much for him.
It doesn't make any sense, Rachel.
I spent 4 hours on the Internet and I
couldn't find one single case of a 16-year old
girl's heart just stopping.
I spoke to 3 different doctors
and not one of them could tell me
exactly what happened to my daughter.
She was close....with you
and Aidan
She confided in you.
Yeah, but she never said anything.
Nothing that would have explained
what happened.
You could find out.
It's what you do, isn't it?
Ask questions?
Rachel, please
I saw her face.
...I mean she was a little intense,
but she wasn't crazy.
And who put you into this straitjacket
if you just freaked out?
Something scared the shooot out of her.
Hi.
So who's in the mental hospital?
Becca. Katie's friend.
Oh, right. She was the one who was...
...there. When it happened.
So what do you think they
were doing up there?
Oh, thanks.
I remember I was that age
me and my girlfriend used to
sneak up to my room, get high
do you think maybe she was into...
...It's not about that.
It's about the tape.
Alan, don't even...
What tape?
The one that kills you when you watch it.
Oh, please
What was on the tape?
I haven't seen it, obviously.
But Katie told you she
saw this tape.
Not Katie, I heard it
from her boyf...
You heard it from who?
She was dating this guy Josh
He goes to Revere.
It was kind of a secret.
Kind of?
Where is he? Josh...is he here?
Josh is dead.
What?
What happened?
Supposedly he killed himself.
The same night that Katie died.
Aidan
What are you doing in here?
Come on.
We shouldn't be in her room.
It's not her room anymore.
NEXT DAY PREMIUM
PHOTO PROCESSING
Josh Turandot
Back Bay teen dies in
high-rise fall
10 p.m.
One car accident kills two;
cause not determined
10 p.m.
Time of death, that's all
I wanna know.
Name is Katie Embry,
pull the report and read the time.
No, that's ok, I'll hold.
Punctilious prick?
Nice literation, huh?
You're fired.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
I'm cooking too good a story.
What is it?
Yeah, I'm still here.
Ok, so what's the time of death?
10 p.m.
SHELTER MOUNTAIN INN
Hi, I'm sorry...
...Pick a card! Any card.
Go ahead!
Put it back.
Don't let me see it.
That your card?
No
Damn
I was wondering if you'd remember someone
from a week ago
Is there a problem?
It's my niece. She sort of
ran out on her parents.
No
I have some photos here.
That's her, and her friends
I think they stayed here
a night or so.
Yeah. They were in cabin 12.
They didn't pay.
They had a number of complaints.
Bout the TV mainly.
Reception is never good here.
That's why we bought tape-players
for videos
Quite a selection.
Mostly they're hand-me-downs
left by the guests.
Anyway
they didn't pay
and kids like that
sometimes don't
Miss?
You know...
...I'm kind of tired. I'm thinking I might
take a nap before I drive back.
I'll take cabin 12.
Hey!
This is your card, right?
That's it!
Seven Days
I'm going to school!
What do you think?
Pretty cool effect
What does this have to
do with the tape?
Take my picture.
Are you gonna look at
me at least?
This the same camera?
No
Scan the rest.
So? What do you think?
I thought you said this
was about a tape.
I'm thinking maybe you
shouldn't see it.
No, I should know more
about it first.
Well isn't that why I'm here?
So you can benefit
from my wisdom?
4 kids are dead, Noah.
Not from watching
a videotape.
Show it to me.
No credits
That was very student film.
Um, sure it's a lot
scarier at night
You're gonna get that?
So, you've been working a lot?
I'm not tired, Noah!
Ok
That tape didn't scare you?
No, not really. Sorry.
4 people are dead!
Like I said...
4 people who watched it
Come on, we watched it
It...takes...a week.
Right
You know I'm just gonna go downtown,
I gotta pick up some cameras from this guy
and then I gotta prep this thing,
I may not do it next weekend...
Noah
would you say that I'm gullible?
No
Easily rattled?
Definitely not
a little highly-strung maybe
you ain't much of a dresser
Who made it?
Where did it come from?
Alright
make me a copy,
I'll see what I can do.
Thanks
You sure this is a copy?
Yeah, why?
The numbers are all screwed up.
Same problem got copied, I guess.
That's impossible.
The numbers of the control track, they're
put on the tape whenever it's recorded
which means theoretically there
shouldn't be any images
Hey, Noah, can you pretend for 1 minute
that I don't read Video Geek Magazine?
Okay, when you record a tape
the makeup of the tracks is like a
signature for whatever did the recording
like a camcorder, VCR, whatever
so the control tracker tells
where it came from.
But to not have one, I mean that's
like being born without fingerprints.
Then how did this get recorded?
I don't know.
But I'm gonna find out
Alright, take a look
you should be able to see the camera
here in the reflection.
The angle is straight on,
but you don't
Mmm...what's that?
Looks like she's walking away
whoever she is
No, I mean up there at the top.
Uh, that's just the tracking,
I can fix that.
Wait! Go back.
There's something there.
Yeah, you're right.
There's more picture.
Hold on. I'm gonna stretch the
alignment
Yeah, it's working.
Ok, keep going.
Nonono, let me do it!
Come on!
What are you doing?
Let me do it! shooot!
Hey Noah! I picked up the cameras.
They're in really good shape.
Did you see the reports I did
about that Guatemala stuff?
It came out kind of...
overexposed
You're working?
This is a friend...Rachel Keller.
She writes for the P.I.
Rachel, this is Beth, my assistant.
Wanna prefer Partner in Crime?
She's a journalism student at
Kirkland actually.
Oh. I'll stay out of your way.
I'm not even here.
Rachel is researching the story, of
this video-hoaxes, sort of interesting.
You know video, why don't you come
and look at this thing with the tracking?
You know I'm late. I really should go.
Yeah, but why are you taking the...
I gotta go! It's good to meet you.
You're taking the tape?
I don't want her to see it.
Whoa! You don't want her to see, what
about me seeing it?
You had no problem showing it to me.
I did have a problem!
You're angry.
I'm not angry
Oh no? What are you then?
In a hurry.
I'm sorry, but I'm not gonna get all
worked up over some high school rumour.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking this is the part where
I say you're a flake, never finishes anything,
and you say I'm an obsessive bitch,
needs to lighten up,
then I storm out, all pissed-off, kicking
myself for ever thinking that you could just...
grow up!
So why don't we just cut to that part right
now and save ourselves a lot of grief!
Alright! Bye.
Watch out Missy! Bad luck.
We don't need that.
Becca? Becca.
You are almost there.
Do you remember anything
about that night?
That night with Katie.
Do you remember
how she died?
Becca?
She told you about a video tape,
didn't she?
She was afraid, wasn't she?
Something was happening to her.
Becca...
how did she die?
Please
I need to know.
And you will.
She'll show you.
Who? Who will show me?
Not now.
4 days
Yeah, well your home-VCR:s will give you a
tracking wind-up, but they won't let you stretch it
so no point really, unless we're
talking restoration.
Archives will come in here with these
primual-tapes sometimes,
tracks totally shot, servos can't
line them up, big box,
here's the most totally.....will read
to the very edge of your tape.
Just don't force her, or she'll
get pissy with you.
Your tracking, your monitor, your printer.
So, what are we watching?
Home-movies or something?
I really rather watch it alone.
Really
Whatever
Come on
Lighthouse
shooot!
Hello? Somebody!
Something you needed help with?
Hey, you got a...a...
Well, these seem to be the lot of it.
Thank you
Moesko Island
Anna Morgan
Oh my god
Mysterious Sickness Strikes
Morgan Ranch Horses
Investigators search for answers after
second horse drowning.
Anna Morgan
Horses Recovering After
Breeder's Suicide
Anna Morgan, 44, Award
Winning Horse Breeder
...may have jumped...
...suffered from hallucinations...
Eola County Psychiatric Hospital
What happened to you, Anna?
Take a double Lights, thanks.
$15.33
You're gonna die.
My cousin was 2 packs a day.
Used a patch. Never looked back.
Well, I'll keep that in mind.
Have a nice day.
You too
Hi
Sorry I'm late.
No, no problem
Everything ok?
Oh, yeah, he was an angel.
Right, I went in to tell him
that it was bedtime,
and he was already under the covers,
and then he read me a bedtime-story.
Um, he learned the word 'conundrum'.
Really?
Yeah, and then he drew my picture.
Well, here you go.
Thanks.
Sure.
Hey Ruthie, it's me. I'm sorry to call
so late, but I need a favour.
I have to go upstate, too.
To this story. I need you to
watch Aidan for me...
Oh, Rachel, I don't know.
How long will you be gone?
It's just for 2 days.
I promise.
It isn't the best time.
Rachel? Rachel are you there?
Hold On! Sorry.
Rachel? Is this about Katie?
Ruthie?
Aidan?
NOOO!!!
Why, baby? Why? Why?
I couldn't sleep.
Who is she, Rachel?
Leave him alone!!!
Rachel?
Noah
Listen to me, Rachel.
I need to talk to you, can I...
...I believe you.
Rachel, you there?
He watched the tape.
Who? Who watched it?
Our son
You took some picture.
I've seen you.
While I'm in the yard at school.
You were there.
You wish I was around more?
No
You wanna be around more?
Rachel and I we're...
Wrong
Mom's told me that story.
The thing is
I don't think I'll make
a good father.
Maybe it was because my own was
such a
disappointment.
And I don't want anyone
else to do it either.
Your father
It's a conundrum.
Yeah, it is.
Time to go, mister.
I'm not finished.
Noah said to make one for you.
You could almost draw a
line through her life.
A once...happy woman who spends
her time with her husband.
Riding horses, everything sheltered,
protected and comfortable.
Her face, there's...light.
There's pride.
And then one day something happens
and she takes this hard corner
and then light...goes out.
And then she ends up in
Eola County Psychiatric, all alone.
What happened to her?
I don't know yet, but I think it has
something to do with the horses.
I think we should go to
the island together.
It's Tuesday, Noah.
I only have 1 day left.
I need you to go to the hospital, and
find out as much as you can about Anna.
The images on the tape
relieves somewhere.
Katie saw them all, too.
I think
Before you die, you see the ring.
shooot
Hey, Rach!
Wait!
MOM
Richard Morgan,
ranch owner
Rider Injured
at horse show
Onlookers said Anna Morgan,...
...was holding her daughter
in her arms...
Daughter?
Hey you
It's ok
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Easy, boy
That's it
Hey, boy
I'm not gonna hurt you.
It's ok, calm down.
Somebody!
Jesus Christ
Somebody help!
Hey! My horse!
I need to see the records for
a patient named Anna Morgan.
Are you a relative?
Um, no
I'm sorry sir. We're a
mental health facility.
Our records are private.
Oh, she's been dead 24 years.
I don't think she'll mind.
I'm sorry.
It's impossible.
Look
I've seen 'em before.
I've been up there.
Nice try. The record-rooms
are downstairs, guy.
You win
Jerk-off
You in here, Anna?
Morgan Horse Farm
Hello?
Excuse me Mr. Morgan
I was wondering if you'd have
a moment to speak with me.
My name is Rachel Keller.
I'm a writer with the Seattle P.I.
You wanna know about the horses.
I didn't mean to...it's just I wasn't
able to find a number to reach you.
Every now and then a
writer comes along
heard about what happened
What's left to write about though?
I don't know.
I was hoping you had
just a few minutes
Well, work never ends
around here really,
but I guess I got a few.
So, what is it you're
writing, Miss?
Bout horses in general or
that horses go strange?
I read you had to put
so many down.
Loads put themselves down.
They drowned.
How did they get out?
Just broke through the fences,
and ran to the shore.
So they went crazy?
It will seem so, yes.
Or maybe they just sensed
things before they jumped.
So where are your horses now?
I don't breed anymore.
I guess you wouldn't.
Not after what happened.
That must have been hard.
On both of you.
You and your wife.
I'm sorry, Miss.
What's your name again?
Rachel
Well, Rachel. You wanna tell
me what's really on your mind?
Do you know what this is?
I think it's a message
from your wife.
Anna is on this tape. She's
right there, in that room.
You can see the lighthouse,
the horses
Where did you get that?
Shelter Mountain Inn
Is that the only one?
I made a copy.
I got a whole lot of work to do today.
Other acres out there.
A minute I think I'm done
with one thing,
another thing needs fixing.
You don't wanna see this tape?
You're not even curious?
Curious?
No. I don't think so.
Mr. Morgan
I can't help you.
Where is your daughter?
Maybe she could help...
I don't have a daughter.
Excuse me?
What is it with reporters?
You take one person's tragedy,
and force the world to experience it.
You spread it like sickness.
Mr. Morgan
Tell me, Miss! What is
it you think you know?
Then leave it alone.
Anna Morgan
hallucinations
'63  Conceived
'63  Miscarriage
'65  Miscarriage
'66  Conceived
'66  Miscarriage
'67  Conceived
Projected Thermography
Subject: Samara Morgan
Sessions Terminated 2/23/78 at father's
request see video record #SM 0015
Aidan?
It's your mom!
Hi Mom.
Honey.
The house you drew for me,
where did you see it?
Did you see it in your head?
Is that why you drew it?
In my head?
Aidan, why did you
draw that house?
She told me to.
Who?
Who told you to?
The little girl.
She talks to you?
No
She shows me things.
Did she show you the horses?
She doesn't like it in the barn.
The horses keep her up at night.
So she still lives there?
No
She lives in a dark place now.
You're getting a little old to
be ..... out there, Cal!
Your body has about outlived
its warranty, you know.
........
Let's see you catch one better.
Yeah
Good afternoon, I'm
Dr. Grasnik
I...think he was before me.
Darby? Darby is always here.
Aren't you, Darby?
He's my son's boy.
Come over on the ferry,
did you?
Yes. Um,
Have you lived here long?
Born and raised.
Only Doctor on the island.
Then you know the Morgans,
and their daughter?
Do you know their daughter?
What's this about?
Look, I'm sorry. I don't know how to
say this, but I'm seeing things in
my head, images, and
so is my son.
My son, that's why I'm here.
And somehow, I don't know how, but
it's because of that girl.
Haven't heard anybody say
that in a long time.
They wanted a child
more than anything.
Poor Anna
They tried hard for years. But
sometimes it's just not meant to be.
Then one winter they went away.
When they came back,
it was with Samara.
'Adopted' they said.
Never did say from where.
Said the mother had died
of complications.
But they had their baby,
they had their horses,
everything was fine.
Till Anna started
coming to see me.
Said she was suffering visions.
seeing things
horrible things
like they've been burned
inside her
And it only happened
around Samara,
that the girl put them there.
Were you Samara's doctor, too?
Was there anything
wrong with her?
You mean medically?
I mean whatever you mean.
When Darby there was born
we knew something wasn't
right with him,
but we loved him anyway.
Takes work, you know
Some people have limits.
So what happened to her?
I referred them to Eola
Psychiatric on the mainland.
I assume she's still there.
You don't know?
How can you not know?
We've been through
a lot of hard years out here.
mean winters
small hauls, no fish
And that was long
before the horses.
See, when you live on an
island, and you catch a cold,
it's everybody's cold.
No offense, ma'am, but what
the hell does that mean?
It means, ever since that
girl's been gone,
things have been better.
Man, you really going
back in time here.
Yeah, the lady at the reception
said it should still be here.
Should be?
You say you were the
patient's father, right?
Yep! Richard Morgan, that's me.
What is your secret?
Diet and exercise, man
No shooot!
It's all it takes.
You know, I'm not an idiot.
You try and walk out
of here with my file,
and I'll be your new,
like white on your eyes.
You understand?
Yeah, man...I just wanna watch it.
I'm responsible for every
file-tape in here.
I have a system.
And I don't want anyone
disarranging it.
I'd never
disarrange
Long as we understand each other.
Ok, now I'm mad!
Does it say who's the
last person watched it?
Yeah
It was you.
Come on! Come on!
Who you need to call, is not
responding, or is outside your area.
You piece of shooot.
Come on, Rachel
Hello?
Mr. Morgan?
Certificate Of Live Birth
Morgan
Samara
#SM 0015
This is SM 0015,
Samara Morgan
hour 14
good, very good
So what is it that's
keeping you awake?
You must sleep some time?
You dream about something?
Samara?
Let's talk about the pictures?
How did you make them?
Samara?
How did you make these
pictures?
I don't
make them.
I see them.
Then
they just
are.
Samara?
I need you to start telling
me the truth, okay?
Can I see my mummy?
No, Samara. Not until we understand
what's wrong with you.
I love my mummy.
Yes, you do.
But you don't want to hurt
her anymore, now do you?
You don't want to hurt anyone?
But I do. And I'm sorry.
It won't stop.
Well, that's why you're here.
So that I can help you
to make it stop.
He's going to meet me here.
Who?
Daddy
They just wanna help you.
Not daddy
Your daddy loves you.
Daddy loves the horses.
He want me to go away.
No, he doesn't.
But he doesn't know.
He doesn't know what?
Samara?
She's never gonna whisper
in the videocamera again!
What did you do to her?!
She was your daughter!
You killed Samara, didn't you?!
You killed her, and when your wife...
My wife was not
supposed to have a child!
Mr. Morgan?!
What are you doing?
Whispers. You can hear them
all the time, at night,
in your sleep,
even the damn horses
Mr. Morgan, come out of there!
Those twitches
Oh, Christ
These things she'll show you.
She's still showing them.
This will never stop.
Your coming here proves that.
Where is she?
Please
I have to stop her,
if I don't, my son will die!
Oh yes, he will.
She never sleeps.
Wait. No.
Rachel!
It's ok. It's ok.
You're ok
You ok?
Oh, Jesus
She doesn't like the barn.
The horses keep her up at night.
What?
The horses keep her awake.
Samara
He kept her here.
Her mother was going crazy.
Morgan blamed the child.
So he kept her here.
Alone
Not alone
Rachel
There's something under here.
It looks like it's etched
into the wood.
or burned
I've seen this tree before.
Yeah, it was on the tape.
No
I've been there.
Shelter Mountain
The sun came through the leaves,
lit them up like it was on fire.
right at sunset
right when I watched the tape.
That was a week ago.
Back to where we started from.
Something led us here, the
tree, the drawing, the wall
It doesn't matter,
we're too late.
You have to help him.
What are you talking about?
Aidan
It's up to you now, just use the time
you have, and figure something out.
We're gonna figure this out
together, right now!
It's too late, Noah...! Stop it, okay?
There's a reason that we're here!
What?!
I don't know, okay? There's something
in this room...I mean, it's in this phone,
in this television
Come on!
Kill us now, why don't you!?
Noah
look
Jesus
How far down you think it goes?
I can't see anything.
No, we should drop something.
You think she's down there?
Shhhhh!
RACHEL!!!
RACHEL?!
I'm here!
I'm alright!
I think
Can I gonna go find
something to get you out?!
Hurry!
Noah?
NOAH!!!
NOOO!
Isn't it beautiful here, Samara?
so peaceful
I know things will get better.
All I ever wanted was you.
She was still alive.
It's okay now.
it's ok
Rachel!!!
We got a sunset!
The sun is set, time
sunset, do you hear me?
It's time sunset!
Rachel?!
Rachel, are you there?!
I'm here.
They're gonna bury her next week.
It's over.
Are you okay?
She wanted that child more
than anything in the world.
How could she have done that?
She just wanted to be heard.
Sometimes children
yell, or cry, or draw pictures.
I'm gonna go home.
I can't imagine what it's like down
a well, all alone like that.
How long can you survive?
7 days
You could survive for 7 days.
Just call me sometime.
Unless you're in your movie.
Call me tomorrow.
and the day after that
Rachel?
What time is it?
It's either really late, or really early,
depending on how you look at it.
Don't you have to be at work?
Not today
What happened to the girl?
Samara?
Is that her name?
Mhmm.
Is she still in the dark place?
No
We set her free.
You helped her?
Yeah
Why did you do that?
What's wrong, honey?
You weren't supposed to help her.
It's okay now.
She's not gonna hurt you.
She's
Don't you understand, Rachel?
She never sleeps.
Pick up the phone, Noah.
Come on, pick up.
Come on, Noah!
Pick up the goddamn phone!
Come on!
Go to your room! Now!
What do you want?
What do you want!?
What do you want from me!?
Why not me?
What did I do they didn't?
She just wanted to be heard.
He want me to go away.
My wife was not supposed
to have a child!
All I ever wanted was you.
Don't you understand, Rachel?
But he doesn't know.
She never sleeps.
You take one person's tragedy,
and force the world to experience it.
You spread it like sickness.
You don't wanna hurt anyone?
But I do.
And I'm sorry.
It won't stop.
I made a copy.
Push it in.
Push
It's going to keep going, isn't it?
She'll never stop.
Don't worry, sweetie.
You're gonna be okay.
But what about the person
we show it to?
What happens to them?