[THUNDER CRASHING]
PILOT: Uh, good evening,
ladies and gentlemen. This is your pilot.
Uh, you'll notice the "fasten seatbelt"
sign is on.
We're passing through a bit
of turbulence here.
Unfortunately, we can't get up over it
and, uh, we can't get underneath it.
Just hang in there.
We'll get through this as soon as we can.
Excuse me, miss.
Oh!
-Yes?
-Can I have a different seat, please?
No, I'm afraid we're full tonight, sir.
You're gonna have to stay put.
Thanks, anyway.
[GROANING]
He's going to make you help him...
...because you're the last.
[BELL RINGS]
JOHN:
Listen...
...I really need to change this seat.
I'm sorry. There's nothing I can do.
I'm afraid of heights.
Don't be a pussy.
WOMAN:
Whoa!
It's not fair! I was almost out!
[SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
Shit.
[FREDDY CACKLING]
I'll get you, my pretty,
and your little soul too.
[LAUGHING]
[JOHN GRUNTS]
[JOHN GROANING]
[SHOUTING]
[GRUNTING]
God.
Whoa!
Oh, God.
One ticket...
...round trip.
Hurry up, boy.
You don't wanna miss the bus.
[LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
[BUS HORN HONKING]
[SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
Oh. No screaming
while the bus is in motion.
JOHN:
Goddamn it.
[JOHN SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
Now be a good little doggie
and go fetch.
Spencer, I wanna make sure
that you understand our situation.
In one week, you walk out of here.
And I expect to see some changes
in your behavior when you get home.
I know you're hearing me. I put you in here
because you gave me no choice.
-Next time, I'll leave you here and walk away.
-Thanks for the visit, Dad.
Nice job on my kid.
I expected to see some improvement.
He isn't a Toyota.
What a jerk.
[SIGHS]
-You okay?
-Yeah.
Dad came by to lay down
some ground rules for when I come home.
No more running away,
no more setting his cars on fire.
There are ways to get attention
besides blowing up the garage.
Yeah, he barely even blinked.
All he wants me to do now
is grow up to be him.
An exact copy.
I don't feel like playing football
and date-raping coeds.
One of these days,
you'll have to face your father.
KELLY:
Maggie.
Look what I found in Spencer's room.
MAGGIE:
A pipe bomb, huh?
Uh, that? Well, I was just showing the kids
some survival techniques.
[SIGHS]
I've been confiscating stuff like this
all week.
Where do they get it?
Put this downstairs
with the rest of the arsenal.
MAGGIE: The police were to dispose of it.
-Police are supposed to do a lot of things.
MAN:
Stop. Come back here.
TRACY: Take your hands off me!
-Tracy.
-What's the problem?
-She was beating on one of the kids.
-He was trying to hit on me.
-She doesn't like to be touched.
We have a session today, yes?
I have Doc's class.
Work around him.
I'm sorry, sir.
MAN:
You seen this junkie before?
No, he's new.
MAN: Beautiful. Another afternoon shot
doing juvie paperwork.
Screw that shit.
Let's just scoop him up
and take him to the shelter.
Let the bleeding hearts do the typing.
[TRACY GRUNTING]
That's it. Come on, Tracy.
That's it. Oh, yeah, she's bad.
The crowd loves her.
She's getting ready for the heavyweight
champion boxing match of the world.
Hey, hey, hey, look at her go.
You know, you are sexy when you sweat.
[LAUGHING]
You ain't getting none, Carlos.
You ain't getting none.
-You wouldn't hit a guy with a handicap.
-You call it a handicap?
I call it chicken, man.
Come on, let's spar.
-Come on, you yellow-bellied-- Come on.
-Forget it, Trace. I'm--
[INAUDlBLE DIALOGUE]
Don't tune out.
Why don't you talk back to her?
Like you talk back to your father?
Let me tell you something, Spence.
I stopped talking back when it became
hazardous to my health. You know?
-So are we set?
-Yeah, no problem.
I gave the driver our cash.
As long as we do it before dawn, we're free.
All right, that means we're gonna be
living large in Cali before the week is out.
You better be sure, man.
Trust me. I got all the bases covered.
I need to get out of here more than you do.
You don't know shit
about needing to get out.
Your family's a picnic, rich boy.
You think I hang around with you morons
by choice?
Your father didn't try to set you up
with his girlfriend's older sister.
Don't talk to me about fathers.
Yours come to visit too?
Yeah, every time I close my eyes.
[DOC HUMMING]
All right, that did it. Yep. Okay.
They caught one of your star pupils
beating up on one of our kids again.
-Tracy?
-You said you were making progress.
I only get 23 minutes a week
with these kids.
With that kind of attention,
we're lucky she didn't kill him.
[SCOFFS]
Ha, ha. Oh, that's a good attitude
for a therapist.
You know, Tracy's got some deep trauma
buried inside of her head.
Conventional therapy
is not going to work.
And dream therapy is, huh?
You're such a hippie.
You know, I can reach these kids
through their dreams.
Give me a chance,
I can help with your little problem.
I don't have a little problem.
I just have a little reoccurring dream
and I'm handling it fine.
And you are not being paid
to be a dream doctor.
-This is new.
-You like it?
These are ancient dream demons.
Supposedly, they roam the dreams
of the living...
...till they find the most evil,
twisted human imaginable.
Then they give him the power
to cross the line...
...and turn our nightmares into reality.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Maggie,
cops just brought in another kid.
Real mess. Hasn't slept for days,
bad case of amnesia.
They need your evaluation right away.
I meant the soda.
Sit down.
-Why do you wanna stay awake?
-Because if I fall asleep...
...I'm not waking up.
-Why do you think that?
-I don't think it.
I feel it.
If I fall asleep, there's gonna be trouble.
MAGGIE:
"Springwood."
Water tower.
JOHN [SINGING]:
Four thousand, five hundred
And sixty-seven bottles
Of beer on the wall
Four thousand, five hundred sixty-seven
Bottles of beer
lf one of those bottles
Should happen to fall
What a case of--
BOY: Hell, I'll break a bottle over your head
if you don't shut the fuck up!
Four thousand, five hundred and sixty-six
Bottles of beer on the wall
I won't tell.
MAN: Now you're it.
Remember what you have to do.
You gotta tag me.
That's a girl.
Over here. Come on.
Come to Daddy.
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
Play with me.
Tell me who I am.
I won't tell.
Free me, you idiot!
I'm your fucking memory!
[SCREAMS]
Oh, shit.
Asshole.
What were you dreaming about?
A room.
A house.
A little girl.
Something about, uh, the town
from my article.
I remember a water tower.
Um....
The article, do you remember
where you got it?
-No.
-The little girl, what did she look like?
-Brown hair with red ribbons.
-Red ribbons.
I don't like it. There's some connection
between your dreams and his dreams...
...and his dreams mean bad news.
You think I'm crazy, but I can feel it.
Why can't anybody talk about anything
but dreams around here?
-I'm sick of hearing about this bullshit.
-You don't believe that.
You think you can solve this puzzle,
it can help with yours.
I don't have a puzzle.
Yes, you do. And although you think
you know everything...
...you may not be ready to face
what this boy is gonna show you.
-I never said I wanted to go back there.
-I've dealt with amnesiacs before.
Taking you to Springwood is gonna trigger
some spark to help you remember.
I don't need a spark to help me
to remember that it was a bad place.
You want a spark, you go.
I'll stay here, sparkless but happy.
I'll be right there with you. Don't worry.
Kelly, gonna take the van
for a little while.
I told you not to let me fall asleep.
Is that too much to ask for?
-Go back.
-Oh, my God. Pull over.
John. John, wake up.
[BOTH SHOUTING]
-Shit.
-Oh, great.
Funny meeting you here.
Well, nice driving.
What the hell are you guys doing here?
Great plan, asshole.
-It almost worked.
MAGGIE: I can't believe you people.
Pulling a stunt like that.
Oh, my God.
Look, the first thing we have to do
is find a telephone.
You call Kelly and tell him where you are,
understand?
And then we have to figure out
how to get you home.
Are you listening?
Don't scream at me.
-It was your driving that almost killed us.
-Yeah.
[CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Two. Two for a dollar, right here.
Get them here. Here you go.
Two for a dollar.
All right. First I want you to find a phone,
call Kelly and tell him you're all right.
I want you to get in that van
and drive straight back to the shelter.
Think you can handle that,
or do I have to call the police?
-Get away from them.
-You go away.
-"Or do I have to call the police?"
-Go away. Go away.
-She ain't my mother.
MAN 1 : There goes the bra.
MAN 2: Who wants some peach cobbler
here? lt's not burned too bad.
You can just cut it
right in the middle there.
[MIMICKING ENGINE SOUND]
MAN 3: Step right up here. Right here.
Here's the place.
This is the place you wanna be here.
-There are no kids.
-What?
A town fair and there are no kids.
MAN 4:
Guys, look out.
MAN 5: Guys, what the heck you doing
over there?
-What's up, Spence?
-This phone's out of order.
-So is this town.
-You are not kidding.
Oh, what beautiful, adorable children.
Would you like to come and live with us?
It's been so long since
we've had children in the house.
So long.
This time, I swear it'll be different.
This time, I'll be careful and I'll hide you
better so that he'll never find you.
Lookie, I got your nose. Lookie.
Ethel.
I want my children back.
You know they bring him.
[CHURCH BELL RINGING]
Now, see what you done did?
Jesus.
-We're in Twin Peaks here.
-Definitely.
-Have we seen enough?
-Yeah.
Good.
All right. Come on, back in the van.
-You know, that's a very good idea.
MAGGIE: Now. Go!
I hope they make it.
Let's see what they can tell us
at the school.
-What?
-Somebody rang those bells.
Lucky us.
CARLOS:
Trace, there's a map back here.
Did l say I needed a map?
I can't get over the way
those people were looking at us.
Yeah, that was weird.
TRACY:
Shit.
SPENCER:
Nice going.
It takes talent to travel
in a complete circle.
And you're making me dizzy.
Jeez.
Do you have to do that?
You're such a heigh-ho, you know that?
I don't play that shit.
I need all the senses I got.
Put that fucking thing out.
It's hard enough staying awake...
-...without you lighting up every 1 0 seconds.
-This relaxes me.
I can relax you with these two fingers.
I'll just puncture your heart.
Mess up these seats.
You need to get laid.
Would you like the map now?
-No, I don't need any map.
-Okay.
No, of course not.
-Why'd you stop?
-Look.
SPENCER:
Oh, great.
Give me the map.
Not a word.
Carlos, I asked you for the map.
What is this? Hey.
Carlos. I asked you for the map.
What?
Yeah, well, the map says we're fucked.
Okay, look, you've had two chances.
Now it's my turn.
-Dickhead.
-Nice.
You will all be expected to pass
both a written and an oral examination.
Don't disturb him.
You will need to study this.
We've got to get the dates right. If they get
out of order, we get very confused.
John.
-You were here.
-What?
Welcome...
...to Freddy 1 01 .
Fourteen hundred and ninety-three
Freddy sailed across the sea
[CHUCKLES]
These dates, they're all within a 1 0-year
period. What the hell happened here?
JOHN:
Freddy happened here.
Here's a crucial point.
Anybody know what I'm getting at?
Anybody? Come on, people.
We covered this.
This is where they took away his child.
What child?
Taken away, put in the town orphanage.
Freddy had a kid.
Fourteen hundred and ninety-four
Freddy came back to look for more
-There's no way out.
-Not with you driving.
-Yeah, well, you didn't do much better.
-No, but at least I did it in half the time.
-Come on, where are you going?
-Away.
We're too fried to see straight.
Let's just find Maggie.
I'm not turning myself over
for any adult supervision.
This girl's getting some rest.
In fact, I think I see my kind
of neighborhood up ahead: empty.
You know, she's losing it.
-The sad thing is I'm starting to like her.
-That is sad.
Come on, Trace, wait up.
This is the one.
We'll have it all to ourselves.
SPENCER: Bet there's no heat.
CARLOS: No plumbing, right?
You'll survive.
Come on.
[TRACY SHOUTS]
-Where you going?
-Gonna go upstairs and find a bed.
Man, I'm tired.
I gotta find a bathroom.
Jeez, this place makes the shelter
look like The Ritz.
Ick. Yuck.
[SIGHS]
Great. Well...
[CHUCKLES]
...at least it beats the streets,
right, Carlos?
Oh, this is good.
I'm gonna get some sleep...
...and I will get us out of here
in the morning. That's right.
Jeez.
Why do you think that kid said
not to fall asleep?
Because he's a lame-o freak.
Miss Maggie's pet psycho.
Carlos! Carlos!
Carlos!
Tracy?
TRACY: Carlos!
-Tracy?
TRACY: Carlos?
TRACY: Where the hell are you?
Why aren't you listening to me, Carlos?
-Damn, the door's sticking again.
MAN 1 : No, I ain't giving you a damn bottle.
MAN 2: Is it ready?
MAN 1 : I'm gonna pour it all out.
CARLOS:
Tracy?
Tracy? Ugh!
Tracy, where are you?
WOMAN:
Behind you.
Mama?
Mama.
[GRUNTS]
Maybe you don't hear so good.
Maybe I clean out your ears for you.
No, no, Mama, please.
I've been a good boy. You don--
You don't understand.
I've been good, Mama.
Please, don't make me deaf, Mama.
Please.
-I'm sorry.
-I'm not.
[SCREAMING]
Oh, Carlos, lend me your ear.
No!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
Give me my hearing back!
Yes.
[SCREAMING]
Where is it?
[CHUCKLES]
No. No.
Shh.
[GROANS]
You wouldn't do that, would you, man?
No, no, no. Please. No, man.
[CHUCKLES]
Ah.
Ooh.
No, no, no.
No, no. No, please. No, no.
No.
[SCREECHlNG]
No. No, no, no. No.
[SCREAMING]
Nice hearing from you, Carlos. Ha, ha.
TRACY:
Carlos?
Carlos.
I can't find Carlos.
You see what's on this TV?
[SCOFFS]
I gotta take the van.
I'm gonna look for him.
[MEN GROANING ON TV]
CARLOS [ON TV]:
Give me some room.
Spence! Spencer!
Don't fall asleep, man! Get out!
Spencer, get out, man!
Carlos, man.
We were just looking for you.
CARLOS:
Spence! Spencer! Don't fall asleep, man!
Spencer, you stupid stoner!
We shouldn't even be here.
We're supposed to be finding out about you,
not some dead killer's kid.
We might be talking about
the same thing.
Look, the whole town is obsessing
on this Krueger character.
Don't you start.
But why else
would they be afraid of me?
Why else am I still alive
when everybody else is dead?
[SINGING]
Skip, skip, skip to my Lou
Skip to my Lou, my darlin'
Martha, no running.
Everyone, hold hands.
[SINGING]
Skip, skip, skip to my Lou
Oh, you've come back. How nice.
Do you remember me?
Well, of course, I do, my boy.
I remember every one of my children.
Especially you.
What a pretty little girl you were.
And I remember you and you.
-Do you remember the Krueger child?
-Ha, ha. Of course.
Who was it?
We're not permitted to disclose
a child's real identity.
Oh, Melissa. Melissa.
You must let Bobby have the ball.
-John.
GIBBONS: Come here. Come on.
That's all right. You share.
I wonder who has a little bare footie
around here. Let me see.
K. Krueger?
Could mean anything from Kevin to Kyle.
MAGGIE: All it really means
is there was a child here by that name.
JOHN:
No.
It's me. Ha, ha.
GIBBONS:
Yes. Oh, look....
I'm his kid.
That's why he's kept me alive.
He's trying to play
some sick game with me.
He is dead, all right?
He's dead and you're not his kid.
How do you know?
She remembered me.
MAGGIE: She remembered me too
and 50 other imaginary friends.
Let's get out of here.
GIBBONS: Let's draw a picture.
We haven't drawn a picture all day.
There you go. Clippety-clop, clippety-clop.
Isn't that fun?
[TIRES SQUEALING]
TRACY: Maggie.
-Tracy.
-I can't believe I found you.
-What are you still doing here?
I can't find Carlos and
Spencer's wasted at this old house and--
We gotta get to them
before Freddy does.
-No.
-Who's Freddy?
-I'll tell you on the way. Come on!
-Yeah. All right.
Goddamn it.
[TV HUMMING]
[SIGHS]
All right, once again.
This is your brain.
This is your brain on drugs.
Questions?
Yeah. What are you on?
Looks like a frying pan
and some eggs to me.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
Hey, Spence, let's trip out.
[IRON BUTTERFLY'S "IN-A-GADDA-DA-VIDA"
PLAYING ON TV]
Oh, cool.
-ln-A-Gadda-Da-Vida, honey
-Whoa!
Don't you know that l love you
ln-A-Gadda-Da-Vida, baby
Don't you know that l'll always be true
Now he's gone.
JOHN: He must've fallen asleep.
-Look here and upstairs.
-I'm gonna look downstairs.
-They're not here anymore.
Just humor me, will you, please?
And look.
Where am I?
FREDDY:
Jump, boy.
Whoa!
FREDDY:
Jump.
SPENCER:
Whoa!
-Dad?
-Be like me.
Be like me. Be like me.
Father knows best.
SPENCER:
Oh, stop.
[SPENCER GRUNTING]
I'm not like you.
I don't wanna be like you.
Be like me.
Now l'm playing with power.
[SPENCER GRUNTING]
All right.
Super Spencer. Yeah.
Hey, great graphics.
Whoa, I'm here.
Carlos?
Yeah.
I found Spencer!
Okay. Hold him down.
Oh, shit.
-Hold on. Hold on.
-Jesus Christ. Hold on.
-What's happening?
-He's stuck in a nightmare.
-It's kicking the shit out of him.
MAGGIE: Well, wake him up.
TRACY: He's too wasted.
MAGGIE: Spencer. Jesus.
It's Freddy.
MAGGIE: Get him out.
-Hold him.
I'll go into his dream, try and bring him out
before he gets killed.
TRACY: Come on. Hold him.
-That's crazy.
Well, what do you call that, rational?
Right, left. Right, left. Right, left.
-He's getting trashed.
-I have to go in.
What about Freddy?
Freddy won't hurt me. I'm family.
Okay, so how are you gonna go in?
Well...
...you're gonna have to lay me out.
-What is--?
-Come on, just fucking lay me out!
Wait a second.
Doc told me a different way.
There's no time to talk. Just do it!
Jesus Christ.
I told you I knew an easier way.
"Concentration and meditation."
That's what Doc always says.
This place is incredible.
Ha, ha. Pow! Bam!
-Splat.
Is that him?
Jump, boy.
Oh, shit. Spencer.
TRACY:
Come on, John. Let go of me. Let go.
JOHN:
Get out of here. Now, Tracy. Now.
Hey, you forgot the Power Glove.
No! Bastard!
Pow!
Boing. Boing.
Boing, boing, boing, boing!
VIDEO GAME DADS:
Be like me. Be like me. Be like me.
Spencer, do--
[SPENCER GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
What do you know?
I beat my high score.
[LAUGHING]
Oh, yeah.
Great to be back in business.
Thanks to you.
[SCREAMING]
Oh!
Daddy's waiting for you, little girl.
Shut the fuck up, man.
Tracy.
Spencer's gone. I couldn't stop it.
John's still in there.
I couldn't wake him up.
Come on, snap out of it!
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna pick him up
and we're gonna get the hell out of here.
[SCREAMS]
Phew.
[SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
Not again.
He's not gonna get me again.
Nothing is gonna make me
get off this bed.
Damn it.
I hate this house.
[SCREAMING]
[SHOUTS]
[GASPS]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
FREDDY:
Johnny.
Up here.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
I know why you let me go.
Oh, do you think I'm your daddy?
Mm-mm.
Wrong.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
Uh-oh. Oh!
But you let me live.
Only long enough for you
to bring me back my daughter.
JOHN:
Your daughter?
And now she's gonna take me
to a whole new playground.
No!
Grounded!
[SCREAMING]
John!
TRACY:
Oh, my God, Maggie. What's going on?
Come on, Maggie. Let's go.
[JOHN GROANING]
TRACY: Let's get out of here.
Let's get the hell out of here.
It's-- It's not a boy.
It's....
TRACY: Come on. We gotta get out of here.
Now. Come on.
Come on, Maggie. Let's go.
Come on, let's go now!
You forgot where you came from, kid...
...but I know where you're going. Ha, ha.
It's traveling time.
[SHOUTING]
TRACY:
Maggie.
What's wro--?
Maggie, get in the van. Come on.
Come on, get in the van!
We gotta get the hell out of here!
Oh, God.
TRACY:
Let's go.
[TIRES SQUEALING]
Whatever happened, it wasn't your fault.
MAN 1 : I wasn't even there, man.
MAN 2: It's gonna happen again.
MAGGIE: Carlos, Tracy, and Spencer
stowed away in the back of the shelter van.
They were trying to escape.
Can you believe it?
So I took them to the phone.
They were supposed to call you.
John Doe and I
were gonna check out the school.
But Tracy got separated.
-And then they ran away.
-What the hell are you talking about?
I'm talking about Carlos and Spencer
and the John Doe.
Kelly, they just disappeared.
You've been handling too many cases,
Maggie. Those kids were never here.
I would remember any new arrival.
Kelly, I'm talking about 48 hours ago.
I brought you a John Doe.
You don't remember? You're the one
who's handling too many cases.
Get some rest, Maggie.
And then, um...
...we got back
and no one remembers John or Carlos.
It's like they never existed.
I've been hearing strange shit.
Like some of the kids
are dreaming about Carlos.
And they don't even remember him.
I remember him.
Why?
Because I can control my dreams.
I'm not fooled by this thing you saw.
-Freddy.
DOC: Whatever he is...
...he's fucking with the line
between dreams and reality.
He didn't just kill Carlos and the others.
He erased them.
[SOBBING]
JOHN: It's not a boy. It's not a boy.
It's not a boy.
Mother!
Mother.
[GRUNTING]
[LAUGHING]
Shit.
-You're getting ready to kill somebody.
-Defend myself.
It's your mind he'll go for.
Your fear.
Oh, I knew it, I knew it, I knew it.
Maggie? What are you doing?
Who are they?
-Let me have that.
-I have to know.
I don't know. I don't know who they were.
They wouldn't tell me.
They have rules about no contact.
Oh, there's been contact.
[YOUNG MAGGIE GIGGLING]
FREDDY:
You're it. You're it.
Come to Daddy.
[LORETTA SCREAMING]
I won't tell.
Oh, God.
Fred, please.
l won't tell.
We need to talk, Loretta.
Go inside, honey.
LORETTA:
Oh, I won't tell.
-I told you never to go near my things.
-Oh, l didn't mean to, Fred, I--
Right? Isn't that right?
Right.
Stop.
Katherine.
You were such a little artist.
No, it can't be.
I know who I am.
You're my blood.
Only you could have brought me out,
in your mind.
But you can't be my father.
They took you away from me,
but I made them pay.
I took all their children away from them.
And now...
...that's over.
Come on.
The shelter.
Time to start all over again.
But this isn't Springwood.
[CHUCKLES]
Every town has an Elm Street.
[LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
Tracy.
[GASPS]
MAN:
ls it ready?
Tracy, girl.
Daddy's home.
Daddy, you're dead.
MAN:
I'm home, darling.
Come say hello.
I don't want to, Daddy.
Come on. Give Daddy some honey.
No one has to know.
You're not my daddy.
You're not my daddy!
MAN:
Come on, Tracy.
Here!
Do you love me now?!
Do you love me now?! Come on!
[SHOUTS]
He's dead.
My daddy's dead.
He's dea--
[GROANS]
No honey for Daddy?
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
What's with kids today, huh?
No respect.
You can't scare me anymore.
Oh, you better speak up.
Oh, must be my deaf ear.
[LAUGHING]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Kung fu this, bitch.
This is my dream and I do what I want.
It might be your dream, but it's my rules.
[SCREAMING]
Doc. I need to talk to Doc.
-Okay.
-Come on!
Tracy?
TRACY: Doc. Doc, is that you?
-Yeah, Tracy, where are you?
TRACY: I'm over here in one of the lockers.
You gotta get me out.
-Where the hell are you?
TRACY: Right here.
[AS TRACY]
You taught her a lot.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
But there's so much more to learn.
How about this, Doc?
[LAUGHING]
[GRUNTING]
Sticks and stones may break my bones...
...but nothing will ever kill me.
Well, let's see now.
First they tried burning me. Ha, Ha.
Then they tried burying me.
[LAUGHING]
But this, this is my favorite.
They even tried holy water.
[LAUGHING]
But I just keep on ticking.
Because they promised me that.
-They?
-The dream people.
The ones that gave me this job.
In dreams...
...I am forever.
Too bad you're not.
[WATCH ALARM BEEPING]
[MACHINE BUZZING]
Doc.
Thank God.
I think l've got a way to get him.
TRACY:
So, what's the plan, Doc?
-Thanks.
DOC: You can't get him in a dream.
But if this can come out,
he can come out.
And if he can come out, he can bleed.
-And die.
DOC: Right.
How will you know when I got him?
I'm gonna find you with this
and then I'm bringing you out.
Now, you've got to be holding him
to carry him out.
I know.
Now, he's gonna try and trick you
like he tricked Tracy.
And he's gonna try to use your eyes
to fool you. You'll use these.
-Get the hell out of here.
-You wanna live?
These mean nothing here.
But in the dream,
they can be anything you want.
He got inside of your head,
you get inside of his.
That's my job, isn't it?
Be careful. He's good at finding out
what hurts the most.
DOC: Exactly.
-That's why you gotta take me with you.
I can't.
It's gotta be me and him.
All right, Doc.
Put me in.
Strap her in.
Okay.
Take a deep breath.
-Okay.
-Good.
Ten...
...nine...
...eight...
...seven, six...
...five, four...
...three, two...
...one.
MAGGIE:
And get inside his brain.
[SHOUTING]
[SHOUTING AND LAUGHING]
I'm in his memories.
[CHANTING] Son of a hundred maniacs
Son of a hundred maniacs
Oh, yeah. Ha, ha.
MAN:
Freddy.
You ready for it, boy?
You've been a waste
since the day I took you in.
Now it's time to take your medicine.
[LAUGHING]
Thank you, sir.
May I have another?
[LAUGHING]
You wanna know the secret of pain?
If you just stop feeling it,
you could start using it.
CROWD:
Child murderer! Beast!
Kill him!
Freddy.
We know what you want.
FREDDY: I want it all!
-Of course you do.
-Then open up.
-And you shall be forever.
[FREDDY SCREAMS]
[LORETTA SHOUTING]
[FREDDY GRUNTING]
Mommy.
[CRYING]
Don't worry, baby.
Mommy just had to take her medicine
for snooping in Daddy's special work.
But you won't tell, will you?
I won't tell.
But you did tell, didn't you? Ha, ha.
And now it's time to take your medicine.
[LAUGHING]
You killed my mother!
She's got him.
Let's get her out of there.
[SCREAMING]
I've got you.
I had him.
Where the hell is he?
-Maybe the trip killed him.
-No.
Because I'm still seeing things
the way I did in my dream.
It's not over. Let's go.
DOC: Cops were supposed
to pick this stuff up.
Be glad they didn't. We're gonna have
to hit him with everything we've got.
Whoa!
Check out this knife.
-Hey, put that away.
MAGGIE: That's too small.
Guess so.
DOC:
You sure that's big enough?
-Still believe he's gonna show up, huh?
-Yep.
Come on, Tracy. Over here.
I can feel it.
-You're real here.
FREDDY: It wasn't my fault.
It wasn't.
You saw what they did to me
when I was a kid.
You saw.
I loved you...
...and your mother.
I tried so hard to be good.
I know, Daddy.
But when they took you from me,
it wasn't right.
Oh, I knew you'd believe me.
Come to Daddy.
[SCREAMS]
Maggie.
Over here.
I'm okay.
Maggie, watch out.
-Where's the key?
-I don't know.
The lock's jammed.
I didn't need a glove
to kill your bitch of a mother...
...and I don't need one now.
[GASPING]
Come on. Let go.
Come on, let go.
-No! No!
-No! Get down.
I'll show you how.
Like you showed my mother and Carlos?
And Spencer?
-Give Daddy the glove back, princess.
-Never.
Give it to me.
Give it to me. Give me that glove.
Give me the glove.
In your dreams.
[BOTH SHOUTING AND GRUNTING]
Oh, Daddy.
I remember when we used to hold hands
together when I was a kid.
-I didn't like it then either.
-Aah!
I forgot how much it hurts to be human.
[MAGGIE GROANING
AND FREDDY LAUGHlNG]
Maggie.
[SHOUTING]
What--?
Come on.
Oh, you--
[FREDDY SCREAMING]
Go ahead.
Put it on.
It's in your blood.
That's it, put it on.
Feels good, doesn't it?
Yeah. Come on.
Let your daddy show you how to use it.
[SCREAMING]
Maggie! Maggie!
Happy Father's Day.
TRACY:
Come on, Doc.
Come on. Yeah.
Come on, let's hurry.
Let's get out of here. Come on.
[GASPS]
Kids.
[SCREAMING]
-You all right?
-Yeah, I'm okay.
[CHUCKLES]
Freddy's dead.
[INAUDlBLE DIALOGUE]