- (BELL RINGING)
- (LAUGHING)
(COUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
(CHATTERING)
- Oh, really? Okay, okay.
- Yeah, why not?
Hey, isn't that Mia?
I'm so sorry.
I must have slipped.
- GIRL: Did you have a nice swim there?
- (LAUGHING)
- Don't touch me.
- (GIRL LAUGHING)
GIRL: Oh, my God!
CATHERINE:
It was an accident, I swear.
(GIGGLING)
Dude, your sister is so lame.
- She's not my sister.
- Come on. Let's go.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, my God!
CATHERINE: Such a loser!
Why is she all wet? I swear!
I'm sorry about that.
- We're going to see you tomorrow, right?
- Yeah. Tomorrow.
Okay. Bye.
It's going to be amazing!
I promise!
- Amazing!
- Bring your bikini!
Do you want to tell me
what happened?
You should just drive.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
- Hey, Mrs. Riley.
- Hey!
Whoa, did you go
for a swim in your clothes?
Shut up, Ben!
- Hey, Mimi!
- Don't call me that!
Why are you all wet?
- Why is she all wet?
- I have to talk to her, babe.
What happened?
Hey! What happened?
Somebody pushed her
in the pool at school.
No big deal.
It's not my fault
that nobody likes her.
You know,
that's a real nasty thing to say.
Sorry.
Sasha!
Look, I know it's tough moving here,
but you two got to look
out for each other, okay?
Okay.
Thanks.
You guys about done?
Yeah, you are all loaded up, boss.
- All right. Thanks, Ben.
- Yeah.
- See you tomorrow?
- See you tomorrow, Carl. Get some rest.
- Yeah. I will do.
- All right, thanks.
(KNOCKING)
Hey. Mind if I come in?
(SIGHS) What's going on?
I hate it here.
Mia, you're so much stronger
than you think you are.
And if your mom were here,
she'd be really proud of you.
Well, she's not here, is she?
Well, I'm proud
to call you my daughter.
Look, I know you and Sasha have
a hard time sometimes, but we're family.
She's not my sister.
- Mmm.
- Mmm. It's very good.
It's great.
(SIGHS)
Hey, I almost forgot to show you guys
what I found this morning.
Look at this.
Hmm.
- That's a shark tooth.
- Yeah.
- MIA: Is it a great white?
- GRANT: I think so.
Where did you find it?
We uncovered a passageway
that leads to a new part of the city.
Nice.
- But how did the shark get in there?
- I don't know.
Maybe he swam in from the sea
chasing a seal,
Got lost in the tunnels
hundreds of years ago.
That's so cool!
You can keep it.
That kind of brings me around
to something else.
Girls, I know I said I was going
to hang with you this weekend,
but opening this new passageway,
it means that there's
this team of archaeologists.
- They're gonna fly in next week.
- It's fine, Dad.
So I got to finish mapping the caves,
laying the lights,
You don't have to explain.
But your father planned something
very special for the two of you.
What?
Well, the shark tooth is a clue.
(CHUCKLES)
Girls, come on. Here, show them.
There you go.
"A glass-bottomed boat ride
to see great white
sharks in their natural habitat"?
Sounds fun to me.
No. This is for tourists.
Well, we're kind of tourists.
Girls, it's going to be awesome.
They take you out
to where the great whites feed.
You get to watch them through this
viewing gallery in the bottom of the ship.
- It's awesome.
- No. I have plans for tomorrow.
Well, you'll just have to rearrange
your plans.
And besides, I think this is
a wonderful way for the two of you
- to spend quality time together.
- GRANT: Yeah.
(SCOFFS)
JENNIFER: Where are you going?
To let Alexa and Nicole know
that I can't hang out tomorrow.
- Is that okay?
- Watch your tone.
Well, I am sorry about tomorrow,
but the sharks
are going to be really cool.
And maybe next week
you and I can go scuba diving.
Remember how much
you used to like diving with me?
Yeah, I was, like, ten years old, Dad.
Ten years old. The youngest person
I'd ever seen scuba dive.
- Come on. Are you kidding me?
- JENNIFER: And the cutest.
GRANT: Yeah, you were like
a little sea monkey.
(JENNIFER LAUGHS)
ANNOUNCER: All right, guys,
who's ready to see some sharks today?
- (BEN LAUGHS)
- (CROWD NOISE)
I'll pick you up
on the way home. Okay?
GRANT: Bye.
GRANT: Hey, Mimi.
Don't get eaten by a shark.
- Stop it!
- Yeah, Mimi, don't get eaten by a shark!
- (BEN LAUGHS)
- Whoo-hoo!
Hey, if you start to drown,
we'll come and save you.
- I'll save you!
- (LAUGHING)
- Whoo-hoo!
(GASPS)
Look!
CATHERINE: I can't believe she's here.
Oh, my gosh!
- (CAR SCREECHES)
- (CAR HORN HONKS)
(HORN HONKS)
- What the hell are you guys doing here?
- Come on. We had plans.
I told you, I can't.
Dude, I am going
to take you to a place
that no tourists would ever
find in a million years.
Chance of a lifetime.
Or would you rather stay
on this stupid boat instead?
Yeah.
ALEXA: I mean stay.
Stay if you want to.
Hey, maybe you can become
friends with Catherine.
- (IGIGGLES)
- ALEXA: Talk about how beautiful she is.
- She is beautiful though.
- Dude, shut up!
It's up to you.
- Come on!
- One second.
(TONGUE CLICKS)
You really want to spend all day
on a boat with those girls?
- Come on.
- CATHERINE: She's so scared.
(SIGHS)
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
Don't let those girls get to you.
Catherine.
- (GASPS)
- SASHA: Come on.
(LAUGHING)
Goodbye, Catherine.
Let's go. Come on.
(CHEENNG)
(HOLLERING)
(GIGGLING)
(CHATTERING)
(LAUGHING)
(IUNGLE SOUNDS)
Okay, watch your step.
Whoo!
ALEXA: Guys, come on!
We're almost there.
- SASHA: You keep saying that.
- ALEXA: This time I mean it.
(ALEXA SIGHS)
- (GASPS)
- (CHUCKLES)
Oh, my God!
(NICOLE CHUCKLES) Whoo.
NICOLE: Whoa!
SASHA: I mean, how did you
even find out about this place?
ALEXA: Uh, Ben took me here.
SASHA: Ben?
Like my stepdad's assistant Ben?
Oh, she... Stop with that.
Oh, my God!
(GIGGLING)
Okay, so how do we get down there?
Uh, so, there's a path
that'll take us around and down.
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
Or you could go that way.
What are you waiting for?
It's amazing!
SASHA: I don't know, I...
Whoo!
We should take the path.
That was amazing!
Screw the path.
- Whoo!
(LAUGHING)
Whoo!
ALL: Whoo!
That's so cool.
NICOLE: Look at all this stuff.
Whoa.
SASHA: That's a lot of scuba gear.
This is all the equipment that
your stepdad and Ben have been storing
for the archaeologist team
that's coming next week.
Is this the entrance to the City?
Guys, if my Dad finds us,
he's going to kill us.
Chill. I talked to Ben.
Your dad is on the other side
mapping out the new tunnel they found.
They will never know we were here.
Doesn't look like much of a city to me.
It's Mayan.
It was built underground
out of their burial sites,
to hide from the Conquistadors
when they invaded.
Rising sea levels
put most of it underwater.
Thank you, Professor.
Did Ben ever take you
diving into the city?
Yeah, once.
MIA: What's it like?
It's pretty insane down there.
I mean, we only went as far
as the first cave.
It was built as an entrance to...
- Is it Xibalba?
- Xibalba. Yeah.
- Place of fear.
- Yeah.
- Like I was saying, the Mayan underworld.
- Mm-hmm.
Burial caves.
Yeah, it's pretty scary,
but it's really cool.
They have all these old statues
and altars and stuff.
So what are we waiting for?
Come on. Just the first cave.
- But my dad...
- Ls miles away!
- Yeah, they have a different way in.
- Here, look.
Everything we need.
I mean, there's no fins, 80...
Come on! It's the first cave.
We're not swimming the whole city.
Guys, cave diving is dangerous.
- (MOCKINGLY) "Cave diving is dangerous!"
- No. Mia is right, Nicole.
I don't really know about this.
Look, we've come all this way and
we don't even see the temple? Really?
- It's unlike anything you ever seen.
- Yeah.
We should just go in, go once
around the first cave, and then out.
NICOLE: Yeah. Come on.
When was the last time
you went diving?
Years ago.
- I used to go all the time with Dad...
- Perfect.
But I've never been in caves before.
It's like riding a bike, right? I mean...
- Ah, come on, Mia!
- Mia!
Yeah, she's going to do it!
Okay, yeah, let's go. Let's do it!
- Let's go, Mia! Yes!
- Come on! We're doing it, let's go!
Hey, it's going to be fun, okay?
Just remember, keep your movements
nice and small.
Last thing you want to do
is kick up silt down there.
You won't be able to
see your own hands.
Okay. You guys ready?
I'm going to lead.
Keep behind me at all times.
One circuit around the first cave
and back.
Yes, teacher.
Nicole, I'm serious.
Either you do as I say, or...
Yeah, I hear you.
We don't do it at all.
(NICOLE SHRIEKS AND LAUGHS)
NICOLE: Let's go, ladies.
Get a move on.
- Everyone okay? Sasha, are you good?
- Yeah.
- Mia?
- Yeah, I'm good.
Everybody check your air gauges.
You should all have a full tank.
MIA: Mine's on 100%.
SASHA: Me too.
Come on, I'm getting old already!
Okay. Turn your lights on.
Follow me. The entrance
is just at the bottom of the steps.
Let's go.
ALEXA: You guys are going to freak out.
It's insane down there.
Come on!
SASHA: Oh, my God.
Are you sure about this?
ALEXA: Yeah, trust me.
NICOLE: Oh, my God!
This is so crazy!
MIA: I can't believe we're doing this.
Look at that.
ALEXA: Run out of air in a cave,
and your last chance is
sucking the air from those.
Seriously?
ALEXA: For sure.
You want to try it?
The corridor gets narrow up here,
so single file.
Just through here.
ALEXA: You all okay?
- NICOLE: Yup.
- SASHA: Yeah.
MIA: Yeah, I'm good.
NICOLE: Sasha, you could barely
get your ass through there.
(SASHA LAUGHS)
Shut up, Nicole.
At least I have an ass.
- AIEXA: All okay? Mia?
- MIA: Yeah.
- AIEXA: Sasha?
- SASHA: Mm-hmm.
- AIEXA: Nicole?
- NICOIE: Yes, teacher!
You guys ready for this?
(GENERATOR WHIRRING)
- (GASPS)
- NICOLE: Holy...
SASHA: Crap!
- MIA: That's so cool!
- (SASHA LAUGHS)
ALEXA: I told you guys.
Xibalba.
This place is insane, right?
Hey. Nicole! No!
- Keep behind me and keep together.
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
One lap around the altar,
and then we head back, right?
SASHA: Right.
Let's go.
Oh! (NICOLE GIGGLES)
Oh, my God!
MIA: They made human sacrifices here.
Creepy.
NICOLE: Guys, did you see that?
I think I saw something move.
ALEXA: There's nothing down here, Nicole.
- NICOIE: There was something there.
- ALEXA: Oh, come on, Nicole.
- (SASHA LAUGHS)
- Maybe it was a mermaid.
NICOLE: Shut up, Sasha. I'm serious.
ALEXA: Come on, Nicole.
Stop messing around.
MIA: Maybe it was my dad.
ALEXA: Your dad's
on the other side of the city.
ALEXA: There's nothing there.
Nicole's just being an idiot.
NICOLE: I heard that, Alexa.
Come on, let's just go back.
We said we would come in
and then head straight back out, right?
ALEXA: Nicole!
Nicole?
SASHA: Nicole, stop being an idiot.
(SIGHS)
NICOLE: Come, look, look!
NICOLE: Look!
ALEXA: Oh, my God!
NICOLE: Where are its eyes?
MIA: It doesn't have any.
MIA: It's a Mexican tetra...
A blind cave fish.
ALEXA: Wait, I heard about these.
No light down here,
so they don't need color or eyes.
They evolved without.
SASHA: How does it know
where it's going?
MIA: Heightened senses.
I didn't know they got this big.
It's probably never known a human.
It's hiding from us.
Well, who says it's us it's hiding from?
- Stop!
- (LAUGHING)
NICOLE: Here, fishy fishy!
- ALEXA: No, Nicole. I wouldn't.
- Nice to meet...
- (SCREECHING)
- ALEXA: No!
- (NICOIE SCREAMS)
- No, stop it from falling!
No!
(MUFFLED SCREAMS)
MIA: Guys? Guys?
(DISTORTED RADIO VOICE)
MIA: I can't hear you!
(ALEXA'S VOICE DISTORTED)
Nobody move! Nobody move!
MIA: Sasha, where are you?
(ALEXA'S VOICE DISTORTED)
MIA: Guys?
I can't see you guys!
Where are you?
(MIA BREATHING FRANTICALLY)
(DISTORTED VOICE)
MIA: Sasha, I-l can't hear you!
Guys, where are you?
MIA: Sasha!
MIA: I can't see anyone.
(ALEXA'S VOICE DISTORTED)
(MIA CRYING) Sasha!
(MIA BREATHING FRANTICALLY)
Sasha!
Alexa, I can't see!
(ALEXA'S VOICE DISTORTED) Mia!
BEN: Mia!
What are you doing here?
Oh, my God! I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- MIA: We were at the lake and...
- BEN: Whoa, whoa. Calm down.
- MIA: It was really stupid.
- All right? It's okay.
Let me guess. Alexa persuaded you
to come down here, huh?
And then we knocked over a stone column,
and I got totally lost in the silt.
You didn't think to come
down here with a guideline?
ALEXA: Mia! Mia!
Thank God!
BEN: Oh, man, I should've known.
So you thought you'd try
a little bit of cave diving, huh?
I'm so sorry.
Honestly, we were supposed to just
go in and then straight back out again.
BEN: That's the last time
I'm showing you any of my secret spots.
I take it Sasha and Nicole
are close by?
- AIEXA: They're waiting by the exit.
- BEN: Yeah? What a surprise.
BEN: Let's just get you guys the hell
out of here before your dad finds out.
MIA: You're not going to tell him,
are you?
BEN: Are you kidding me?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(BEN SCREAMING)
MIA: Alexa, where are the others?
Where are they?
Sasha? Nicole? Sasha?
(SASHA'S OVER RADIO)
Mia! Where are you?
NICOLE: Sasha, look!
Look, they're here! They're here!
- MIA: Guys, there's a shark.
- SASHA: Mia, what is it?
MIA: There's a shark. I'm serious.
- MIA: It killed Ben.
- SASHA: What?
ALEXA: We have to go.
We have to go now.
NICOLE: You're really
freaking me out right now.
Guys, if this is some kind ofjoke,
it's not funny.
- MIA: Sasha, behind you!
- SASHA: Yeah, right.
(SASHA SCREAMS)
Shark!
(SCREAMING)
SASHA: Swim! Swim! Come on!
SASHA: Guys, come on, move! Move!
The tunnel is starting to collapse.
We need to hurry.
SASHA: It's gonna collapse! No! No!
SASHA: Alexa!
SASHA: What do I do, Alexa?
What do I do?
Push! Help me push! Come on!
Push.
Help me move these rocks.
(NICOLE BREATHING FRANTICALLY)
- ALEXA: Push!
- NICOLE: We're trapped!
ALEXA: There has to be a way out.
ALEXA: Come on.
You guys, it's pointless.
It's pointless. Alexa! Alexa!
(SOBS)
SASHA: Alexa! Look at me.
You said Ben and my dad
went through a different entrance.
Sasha, this place is a maze.
I would never be able to find him.
(SOBS)
MIA: Guys! Guys, there's a line.
Ben. Ben, he had the guideline with him.
It leads back
to where they were working.
NICOLE: What about the shark?
MIA: It looked blind.
Like the tetra fish.
MIA: It must have evolved down here.
When my dad opened up the new cave,
it must have let him through.
SASHA: Mia, was that a great white?
Yeah, I think so.
Everybody check your air.
SASHA: I have about 40% left.
What about you guys?
MIA: I have 40.
NICOLE: Thirty-eight.
ALEXA: Thirty-five.
Okay, we don't have much
of a choice, as far as I can see.
Everyone needs to stay close, okay?
ALEXA: But what about the shark?
MIA: We can do this, Alexa.
It's going to be okay.
SASHA: Okay, come on. Let's go.
(BREATHING SOUNDS)
(SASHA WHISPERING)
The guideline. I can see it.
SASHA: Stay close. If we follow the line,
it will take us to Grant.
ALEXA: Yeah. Come on,
let's go. Let's go.
(BREATHING SOUNDS)
MIA: The line leads down here.
(MIA GRUNTS)
SASHA: This way.
- SASHA: Are you okay, Mia?
- MIA: Yeah.
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING SOUNDS)
NICOLE: Oh, my God!
What is this place?
MIA: Catacombs.
This city was built
out of their burial chambers.
SASHA: The line's caught on something.
ALEXA: Come on. Sasha,
we need to move.
SASHA: Guys.
ALEXA: No.
What are we going to do?
SASHA: We need to keep going.
We're going to die down here.
SASHA:  No.
Grant has to be close.
SASHA: We can't give up.
(ALEXA CRYING)
(BREATHING SOUNDS)
LEXA: No. No, it's a dead end.
We have to go back.
SASHA: There's no other way.
Where are we going to go back to?
ALEXA: We're going to run out of air.
We're going to drown.
- We're going to drown!
- Wait! Wait!
- (MOTOR SOUND)
- (CLANKING)
MIA: Where are they?
Sasha, where's Dad?
He must be close. Grant!
- MIA: Dad!
- SASHA: Grant!
- MIA: Dad! Where are you, Dad?
- MIA: Dad!
- NICOLE: Grant, can you hear us?
ALEXA: There's another way through.
(ALEXA SCREAMS)
(MIA WHIMPERS)
(CRYING)
(ALEXA WHIMPERING)
(WHIMPERING)
(HIGH-PITCHED ALARM RINGING)
Turn it off now! Oh, God!
(SCREAMS)
NICOLE: This way.
NICOLE: Keep going.
Go! Go inside now!
NICOLE: Come on!
NICOLE: Come on, get in! Go!
(NICOLE SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
NICOLE: This way!
Come on!
- (AIEXA SCREAMS)
- NICOLE: This way! Let's go!
NICOLE: Hurry! Come on!
ALEXA: Did the shark follow us?
MIA: I-l think we're safe here.
It's too narrow
for the shark to follow.
- MIA: Are you okay?
- ALEXA: I'm fine.
(COUGHING)
Guys, the air, it tastes bad.
It's an air pocket.
It's been here a while.
We can't breathe it for long.
So what do we do?
SASHA: I can't see any way out of here.
SASHA: How much air do you have left?
MIA: I've got 22%.
- SASHA: I'm on 20.
- ALEXA: Nineteen.
NICOLE: Twenty-one.
- (MUFFLED MUSIC)
- NICOLE: Do you hear that?
- Shh. Listen. Listen.
- (DISTANT MUSIC BEATS)
I think it's music.
- That's impossible.
- Yeah.
It's coming from over here.
MIA: It has to be my dad.
SASHA: It's a dead end.
ALL: Mia!
(MUFFLED MUSIC PLAYING)
Mia! Mia, are you okay?
- There's a gap.
- Okay?
- MIA: Yeah. I can get through.
- Okay.
I'll let you know
when I'm on the other side.
No. We should stay together.
There's no point
in all of us using our air.
- Are you sure you can do this?
- Yeah.
- SASHA: Please be careful.
- Okay.
- Okay, we're going to be right here.
- Yeah. Okay.
(MUSIC PLAYING LOUDLY)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
MIA: Dad!
(GRUNTING)
(HUMMING)
(CLANKING)
CARL: I was mid jam right now.
Grant?
Ben?
(METAL CLINKING IN THE DISTANCE)
(TORCH THUDDING ON TABLE)
CARL: Come on, guys.
Seriously, stop messing around.
COMPUTER VOICE: Track error.
Please reset.
Track error. Please reset.
Track error.
(CLINKING)
(THE CARPENTERS
"WE'VE ONLY JUST BEGUN")
(CLINKING)
CARL: What?
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (SCREAMING)
- (ALARM CHIMING)
MIA: What is that?
(ALEXA OVER RADIO)
It's an emergency alarm
designed to help
locate a diver in a cave.
MIA: Dad!
(CARL SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
MIA: I'm through.
(SASHA OVER RADIO)
Can you see anything?
MIA: Dad?
MIA: I-l can't see anything,
but I can hear the alarm.
MIA: Carl? (PANTING)
MIA: Dad!
(ALARM GETTING LOUDER)
I see it! I see the alarm!
- (AIARM SOUND STOPS)
- (MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
MIA: Dad?
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Dad!
(SCREAMING)
MIA: Guys!
(BREATHING FRANTICALLY)
MIA: Guys, I can't... I can't hear you!
Dad!
Dad! Help!
NICOLE: Why isn't she back yet?
SASHA: Mia! Mia!
SASHA: Mia!
SASHA: She's not responding.
We have to go help her.
ALEXA: What if the shark got her?
MIA: Guys! Guys, I'm lost!
I can't hear you!
Can you hear me?
(SASHA'S DISTORTED VOICE OVER RADIO)
MIA: Guys, I can't hear you!
- (SASHA'S DISTORTED VOICE ON RADIO)
- (PANTING FRANTICALLY)
Can you hear me?
(SCREAMING)
What are you doing here?
We just wanted to see the main entrance,
but then the tunnel collapsed.
Ben and Carl are both dead.
GRANT: Where's Sasha?
We found a small air pocket.
She's back there with Alexa and Nicole,
but I can't hear them any more.
It's because these columns
are breaking up the radio signal.
GRANT: You're low on air.
GRANT: We're gonna
guide them through. Follow me.
MIA: Okay.
(SASHA'S DISTORTED VOICE OVER RADIO)
- SASHA: Mia! Mia, behind you!
- (BANGING ROCKS)
- SASHA: Over here! Over here!
- (MIA SHRIEKS)
(BANGING ROCKS)
(SASHA SHRIEKS)
- AIEXA: Hey! Over here!
- (BANGING ROCKS)
Over here! Over here!
(WHIMPERING)
- (BANGING ROCKS)
- NICOLE: Over here! Over here!
(SCREAMS)
Swim!
(GASPING)
GRANT: This way!
(FRANTIC BREATHING)
(SCREAMING)
NICOLE: Swim! Come on!
(GASPING)
Dad!
SASHA: Oh, Mia!
SASHA: You guys!
NICOLE: I love you guys!
- AIEXA: We made it!
- NICOLE: You saved us, Mia!
ALEXA: I thought
we were going to die down there.
Okay, girls, this is an ascender.
You got to get yourself
into this harness.
Get your foot in this loop.
And this,
you got to work up and down.
Pump down, push up.
- AIEXA: Yeah.
- Okay?
- GRANT: We're gonna get out of here soon.
- ALEXA: Okay.
- GRANT: You ready?
- ALEXA: Yeah.
- GRANT: Okay. Push.
- (ALEXA GRUNTS)
GRANT: Yeah!
You got to use all your strength.
- ALEXA: Okay.
- GRANT: Push and pull.
GRANT: That's it, yeah!
- Ow!
- ALEXA: I'm a natural.
- NICOIE: All right, go back. Come on.
- Okay.
GRANT: One more time.
Hard as you can.
- GRANT: Yeah.
- ALEXA: Okay. (GIGGLES)
ALEXA: Okay.
GRANT: Yeah!
Keep going.
MIA: Guys! Guys, there's a shark!
(SCREAMING)
NICOLE: Get me out of here!
ALEXA: Nicole,
I can't pull us both up.
- AIEXA: Get off, Nicole!
- NICOLE: I got to get out of here!
- (NICOLE AND ALEXA SCREAM)
- It's not going to hold both of you.
- NICOLE: Let me go!
- Alexa!
Nicole, you got to get down!
Oh, my God, there's two sharks!
- No!
- (SCREAMING)
- Alexa!
NICOLE: I got to get out of here!
I'm sorry!
- GRANT: Stop!
- ALEXA: Please, let me go!
Oh, my God!
(SCREAMING)
GRANT: Unhook yourself
from that harness right now!
GRANT: Unhook yourself!
(SCREAMING)
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- (SHOUTING)
- GRANT: Girls!
- SASHA: Mia, quick!
Help! Someone help!
- Nobody can hear you, Alexa.
- Someone will hear us.
They'll hear this.
- Help! Someone help!
- (EMERGENCY ALARM SOUNDING)
- AIEXA: Help! Please!
- SASHA: Alexa, no one can hear you.
- SASHA: Turn it off!
- GRANT: Girls. Girls.
- SASHA: Shut it off!
- ALEXA: Don't!
GRANT: Girls!
Girls! Look!
(PANFING)
They're gone.
Where did they go?
They're scared of it.
The sharks, they've evolved blind,
and they have
a heightened sense of hearing.
GRANT: It must be the frequency.
Maybe we can use the alarm
to scare them away.
Someone's going to come looking for us
when we don't come back tonight, right?
The only people that know
where we are, are right here.
I just found the entrance to this cave.
I'm the only one who knows where it is.
And there's no way we can get
back up without the ascender.
What are we going to do?
We got to go back down.
There's no other way now.
- W hat?
- What?
Listen, this cave goes out to the sea.
If we follow it,
we'll come out in the ocean.
There'll be strong currents there
that are going to try and suck us down.
- So we're going to have to keep together.
- No. We're going to die down there.
If we stay here, we'll die.
We're going to watch
each other's backs.
And we can survive this.
Okay? Girls, I believe in you.
(GRANT SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
MIA: Dad!
Dad! Dad!
- No!
- Mia, get back! Mia, get back!
- Sound the alarm!
- (EMERGENCY ALARM RINGING)
Are they gone?
Are they gone? Can you see it?
I don't see it. I don't see it.
What are we going to do?
We have to do what he said.
- No!
- Yes, we have to go back down.
I can't. I can't do this.
I can't. I can't.
Mia, we have to go.
We have to do what he said.
- I can't.
- We have to go back down.
He wouldn't want you
to give up now, okay?
Do we even have enough air?
We have no choice.
What if we're wrong?
What if the alarm has nothing to do
with why the sharks are gone?
We got to try.
You ready?
(ALARM SOUNDING REPEATEDLY)
- (AIARM SOUNDING REPEATEDLY)
- (GASPING BREATHS)
(ALARM CONTINUES)
(SCREAMING)
SASHA: I can't see them.
Where did they go?
- MIA: Wait. Current!
- (LOUD RUSH OF WATER)
- (SCREAMING)
- (SOUND OF RUSHING WATER)
(ALEXA SCREAMING)
MIA: Sasha! Give me your hand!
(SASHA SCREAMS)
SASHA: Come on! No!
SASHA: Help me!
No! No!
MIA: Give me your hand!
Come on, I got you.
Help!
MIA: Come on, I got you.
Come on.
(LOW AIR ALARM SOUNDS)
(SCREAMING) I can't hold on!
The current is too strong!
MIA: Come on! Hold on!
Give me your hand!
- AIEXA: I can't hold on!
- SASHA: Mia, help! I'm falling!
Mia, I'm slipping!
MIA: Hold on,
Sasha, come on.
No! No!
Sasha!
No! No! Mia!
(SASHA SCREAMING)
Sasha!
(SASHA SCREAMING, SOBBING)
No! Sasha!
Mia! Mia, she's dead.
There's nothing you can do.
No, you don't know that.
Mia, look at me.
MIA: I'm going.
We have to keep going,
or we are going to die down here.
Do you understand me?
No!
(SOBBING)
Look. Over there.
That's the way out.
The current is going to drag us down.
We'll be okay if we stick to the side.
It's our only chance. Okay?
Okay? I won't leave you.
Grab my hand.
Let's go.
(GRUNTING)
(MIA GASPING)
(MIA GROANS)
- AIEXA: You okay?
- (MIA SHRIEKS)
(MIA GASPING)
ALEXA: Keep moving.
ALEXA: We're almost there.
ALEXA: Mia! Give me your hand!
- MIA: Alexa!
- ALEXA: Give me your hand!
MIA: I'm coming.
I'm coming.
ALEXA: Grab my hand!
Grab my hand!
(MIA GRUNTING)
ALEXA:  I got you! I got you!
- AIEXA: Are you okay?
- MIA: Yeah.
(ALEXA GRUNTING)
LEXA: Mia, this has to be the way out.
We're almost there.
ALEXA: The exit can't be far.
(ALEXA SCREAMING)
- MIA: Oh, my God!
- (SCREAMING)
(MIA SCREAMING)
(ALEXA SCREAMING)
(SASHA GASPS)
MIA: Oh, my God, you're alive!
You're alive!
SASHA: We're trapped, Mia!
Mia, we're going to die.
There's no way out.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
MIA: Don't be.
No, no! It's my fault.
If it wasn't for me, you wouldn't be here.
Stop it!
You stop it, okay?
We can't give up now.
We can share air.
I have a little more than you.
Five percent.
We're not going to die down here.
- MIA: Look!
- SASHA: Where are you going? Mia?
(MIA GRUNTING)
MIA: Sasha, come here.
Look.
Maybe there's a way through.
SASHA: The current is too strong.
It'll drag us down.
MIA: We have to try.
(MIA AND SASHA GRUNTING)
(MIA GASPING)
It's a dead end.
MIA: No, it can't be.
MIA: There! Come on!
MIA: I think I can see
the sunlight.
SASHA: It's too narrow
to climb through.
MIA: There must be another way.
(SCREAMING)
It's circling.
Oh, my God! Mia!
- Mia! I'm stuck!
- (AIR TANK SCRAPES ROCKS)
(SASHA PANTING)
Mia! It's coming!
(SHRIEKS)
(SCREAMING) No!
SASHA: I'm stuck!
I'm stuck!
SASHA: Keep going. We can do it.
We can make it.
Just keep going.
We're almost there.
Come on, Mia!
Come on, Mia! Keep going!
Come on, Mia.
I see light.
(GRUNTING)
SASHA: Come on.
We're so close.
SASHA: Mia, I'm stuck.
(GRUNTS) I'm stuck.
SASHA: We're so close.
- (ALARM RINGING)
- SASHA: I have to take my pack off.
SASHA: Come on.
(ALARM CONTINUES)
MIA: Hold your breath.
Help!
Help! Help!
(GASPING)
Oh, my God!
Mia! Mia!
We made it!
We did it!
Oh, my God!
(GASPING)
There has to be a way up.
Maybe, maybe we could climb it.
Mia! Mia!
Mia, look!
- MIA: Oh, my God! Help! Help!
- SASHA: Help! Over here!
- Help! Help!
- Help! Help! Help!
- Help!
- Over here!
Mia, we have to swim.
We have to swim.
We can do it.
MIA: Help! Help!
SASHA: Come on.
MIA: Over here!
Help!
Wait.
(DOOR OPENING)
(MUSIC PLAYING IN EARPHONES)
Oh, my God, it's chum! No!
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Whoa! Come over here.
Move!
CATHERINE: Oh, my God!
Are y'all seeing this?
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(SASHA STRUGGLING)
(SASHA SCREAMS)
MAN: Stay back!
Stay back!
Sasha!
Get out of my way!
Move!
(GASPING)
- (CROWD SHOUTING)
- (PANTING)
Come on! Come on!
MAN: Give me your hand!
(SCREAMING)
- MAN: Watch out!
- (SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED CHATTERING)
- (MIA SIGHS)
- (SASHA GASPS)
You're okay?
Look at me.
Breathe. Breathe.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, you're okay.