I LOVE YOU
4th OF JULY CROAKER FESTIVAL
Let's welcome back our six finalists to the stage.
They're pretty as can be,aren't they?
You worked hard. Your parents worked hard. We're proud of you.
She was born for this.
- Her breasts are so... ample.
- She does exercises to pump 'em up.
Guys, I'm on sexist overload as it is. Kill the commentary.
"In the spirit of Mother Teresa,what will be your contribution -
- to your community and the world at large?"
At summer's end, I plan to become a serious actress in New York City.
By entertaining the world through art, I shall serve my country.
Did you feed her this shit?
Work it. Babe!
They're eating it up.
And this year's Croaker Queen is:
Miss Helen Shivers.
That's my girl!
That's my girlfriend!
- How's my hair?
- Hurricane-proof.
It's all about hair. Don't forget it when you become a big lawyer.
Professional women think it's all about brains, and ignore the "do".
The "do" is vital. Got it.
- Are you riding with me?
- No. Tell Mom I'll be home late.
- Is Miss Croaker gonna get sautéed?
- A twit with a wit.
- Julie. A shooter on the house.
- I can't get past the slime.
How about I take you out before you leave town?
I don't think so. Max.
We've been friends since forever.
You can't leave without a farewell.
A toast... to us.
To our last summer of immature.
Adolescent decadence.
- Somebody's buzzed.
- Chum bait. Take a hike.
- Easy, easy!
- Barry, they're just friends.
Come on. This is tired.
- I'm just taking care of your girl.
- Thanks, buddy. Let's blow.
Let's beam down to Dawson's Beach.
A little joyride.
Bye.
They're making out when they hear over the radio -
- that a killer with a hook for a hand escaped from the insane asylum.
- You're telling it wrong.
- Shut up. The girl gets all scared.
She wants to go home.
The boy gets pissed and peels out.
No, the boy goes for help and the girl stays in the car.
- She hears a scratching sound...
- It's not a scratch, it's a drip.
No, the guy's been hung from a tree.
His feet are scratching the roof.
No, he's been decapitated,
and the blood's dripping on the car.
No, he wasn't decapitated,
he was gutted with a hook.
- That's the way I heard it.
- You're all wrong.
They get to the girl's house and
find a bloody hook in the car door.
That's the original story.
That's the way it really happened.
None of it really happened.
It's a bullshit story.
- No. It's not. It's true.
- I don't think so, Ray.
It's a fictional story to warn girls
of the dangers of premarital sex.
You know how terrified I am of
your I.Q., but it's an urban legend.
And they all originate from
some sort of real-life incident.
By that time I'll be finishing my
two-year deal on "Guiding Light", -
- coinciding with your first year
as quarterback for the Steelers.
Then we can elope to Europe
or the Caymans, -
- where I'll let you impregnate me
with the first of three children. -
- before you head off to rehab.
Then we can live happily...
blah. Blah. Blah.
Ray? Where did you go?
I'm gonna hook you!
- Do you really believe that crap?
- It's true.
The hook is really a phallic symbol.
Ultimately castrated.
I'm gonna miss you.
You can always ditch Boston
and come to New York with me.
We can't all sit in coffee-houses
and ramble on our laptops.
- Nobody gets me the way you do.
- I understand your pain.
I hate this.
You're gonna fall for a head-shaven,
body-piercing philosophy student.
- That sounds attractive.
- I'll never see you again.
High-school relationships are more
successful than any other kind.
Cite your source.
Are you sure?
- Give me the keys.
- Nobody drives my car but me.
I know, baby, but the Croaker Queen
has to get home now.
- Hey, you two.
- Give me my fucking keys.
Come ride in the back with me.
I'll let you do things to me.
- Nobody drives my car but me.
- Get in the car.
You can't drive for shit.
Can you say "alcoholic"?
What the hell is this crap?
What's wrong with you?
Watch out!
- What was that?
- Is everybody okay?
- I think it was an animal.
- You're bleeding.
- It's not mine.
- It must have been a dog.
Jesus Christ, my fucking car!
- Can't you see where you're going?
- It came out of nowhere.
- A dog couldn't have done that.
- A deer could.
- My dad's gonna freak on my ass.
- It was an accident.
- If it was a deer. Where is it?
- Maybe it ran off.
- I hope we didn't kill it.
- Oh, my God...
- No way.
- I thought...
- I didn't see it.
- There's no way.
This isn't happening.
Check that side.
I couldn't see it.
I swear!
- Is he dead?
- Check his pulse. You rammed him!
I think he's dead.
- Who is he?
- His face is all messed up.
- What was he doing out here?
What's your hurry?
- The guy's dead.
- You're not a doctor.
Use your brain, Julie.
If we call the police, we're fucked.
- It was an accident.
- Let's think about this.
Think about what? He crossed
the road in the middle of the night.
- You weren't drinking or speeding.
- They won't believe I was driving.
- It's my car. They'll nail my ass.
- That's not true.
I'm drunk as shit. I'm fucked!
We'll call the police
and tell the truth.
It's manslaughter.
- We're gonna fry no matter what.
- Then we leave now.
Are you crazy?
- The grille's busted and bloody.
- We can clean it up.
- We're going to the police!
- We don't have time for your shit!
Let's try to stay calm.
If there's some of the car on him.
You're looking at a hit-and-run!
- Then we dump the body.
- You've lost it.
- Let's pretend we were never here.
- We'll dump him in the water.
When they find him,
the evidence will be washed away.
If they found him at all.
Maybe the undertow could carry him
out to sea.
I won't be any part of it.
I'm scared. Julie.
I'm not like the rest of you.
I don't have the family or money
to get me out of this. Please.
This is your future, Julie. Think
about college. Your scholarship.
The guy's already dead. If we go
to the police, we're dead too.
- What do we do?
- Help me.
They're slowing down.
- Who is it?
- It's Max.
Get rid of him.
- Have you got car trouble?
- Actually...
Barry had too much to drink. We
don't want upchuck in the new car.
- It doesn't look so new anymore.
- Yeah. Don't drink and drive.
Daddy's gonna be mad.
- What can i do for you, Max?
- Wipe that grin off your face.
Ok, Max, will do.
Have a good night.
- You got that rich boy act down.
- We'll be seeing you.
Take care. Julie.
Even if his body washes ashore, -
- he'll be eaten by crabs
and small fish.
Maybe we'll get lucky with a shark.
Take him to the side.
Put him down.
- Let's do it.
- Wait.
- Should we found out who he is?
- Why?
- Just to know.
- I don't want to know.
Let's just pretend he's an escaped
lunatic with a hook. Ray, help me.
- I don't think I can.
- Barry, it's not too late.
- You, just shut up!
- Christ. I'll do it.
Get him off me!
My crown!
He's got my crown!
Over there!
- Let's get out of here.
- We're going home now.
Never, under any circumstances,
speak about this again.
It's now merely
a future therapy bill. Agreed?
- I'll never mention it again.
- We'll make a pact.
We take this to our grave.
Julie?
- Don't nod! You fucking say it!
- Yeah, ok.
- "We take this to our grave. "
- Let her go.
- You fucking say it!
- We take this to the grave.
It will be okay.
ONE YEAR LATER.
It's time to go.
Move your tired, ugly ass.
We're late.
I changed my mind.
Get your white-as-death corpse
in the car.
Come on!
You're going home for the summer
to get a tan on your pale tail.
Let's go.
Remember, sun and fun.
Julie? Welcome home, dear.
I missed you.
How's the snapper?
I really wanted monkfish,
but it's been a bad season.
- Are you on drugs?
- What?
I just wanted an honest reaction.
No, mom. No drugs.
Then, what is wrong?
You look like death.
I've had a rough year.
CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT
You got some mail.
Your report card came last week.
I know it looks bad.
But the summer session went well.
- It's also your last chance.
- It's not that serious.
What happened to my daughter?
You went away
and you don't call or visit.
Your father must be turning over
in his grave.
I KNOW WHAT YOU DID LAST SUMMER!
Who sent this? There's no postmark or return address.
- why? what does it say?
- Nothing.
Guys, easy ...
It's called glass. It breaks.
Good morning.
Well, look what the cat drug in.
Elsa. Hi. I need to talk to Helen.
Can you give me her New York number?
- Her New York number?
- Yeah, I need to talk to her.
Helen doesn't have a New York
number. Try Women's Fragrances.
Frightening, isn't it?
Julie.
- When did you get home?
- Yesterday.
- It's good to see you.
- What happened in New York?
I went for a while.
It didn't really work out.
Somebody sent this to me.
- Somebody knows.
- How?
- I don't know.
- We were so careful.
What if someody else
was there that night?
- Who? It's been a year.
- I don't know.
Has Barry seen this?
- Do you ever see Barry at school?
- It's a big campus. He is back?
- I saw his car at the gym.
- Did you guys break up?
What are you two doing here?
Hi, Barry.
"I know what you did last summer. "
What  a crock of shit.
- We need help.
- I'll say, you two look like shit.
You're a prick.
- We can't just ignore it.
- How do you know it's related?
- You did a lot last summer.
- Only one murder comes to mind.
You shut the hell up!
- We didn't murder anyone.
- He was still alive.
He was in the middle of the road.
- His name was David Egan.
- Who?
David Egan. He was found three weeks after we ...
His body was caught in a shrimp net.
It was in the paper.
I think the police called it an accidental drowning.
But he died because of us,
That's certain.
What about Ray? Have you shown
the letter to him? What does he say?
We broke up last summer. Last
I heard, he was working up north.
Let's suppose someone was there.
Why send a letter one year later?
It's probably some crack
fucking around.
Max.
- Max, you think?
- Who else? He was there.
You two wait here.
I know what I'm doing.
Go figure. I was wondering
what happened to that Barry Cox.
Hei, Max. Can we talk a second,
in private?
This isn't private enough for you?
What?
We got your letter.
- Don't fuck with me. You saw us.
- What the fuck are you on?
I'll say this once. I'll kill you.
I have no problem with that.
- Get off of me!
- Understand?
Motherfucker.
Don't you test me.
I'll call the cops on your ass.
- Did he admit to the letter?
- He wont't bother you anymore.
I scared the shit out of him.
Well, it'll be damned.
So Ray's a fisherman.
Yeah, almost a year now.
I work on that one over there.
That's nice.
Have a nice life, guys.
I'm out of here.
Have you got a minute?
I've got to get back to work.
Call me, we can get together.
We need to talk.
- And you think Max sent it?
- Barry does.
He's probably just screwing around.
He doesn't have much else to do.
- So... how's school?
- So, you're a fisherman.
Prophecy fulfilled.
I've become my father.
- I didn't think you knew your dad.
- All I know is he worked the boats.
I know you hold me responsible
for what happened last summer.
No, I'm responsible for
my own actions. I don't blame you.
But I don't want to know you either.
Hello?
I KNOW
My fucking jacket!
Hank, is anybody else there?
Just you and me.
You fucker!
Max, you're fucking dead.
Help me!
Help me! Somebody!
What do you want?
I'm sorry.
I swear. We didn't mean it.
One moment please, Officer.
- Julie ...
- What happened?
No. For the fortieth time.
I didn't see his face.
Somebody tried to kill you.
We have to go to the police.
If he wanted me dead. He could
have done it. He's fucking with us.
- Who is?
- Some guy in a slicker.
That narrows it down.
This being a fishing village.
Since you bringing it up ...
You have a slicker.
- You're not gonna throw this on me.
- This isn't getting us anywhere.
Maybe we should come clean.
No. We made a pact,
and we're gonna keep it.
That's insane. Look at us.
The secret's killing us.
We're not going to the police.
We can put an end to it, and
salvage a small fraction of a life.
It was murder. Julie.
Your words. Remember? Murder.
- We find this guy and fix him up.
- Like last night?
He's right. This guy won't go to the
police. We'll find him, talk to him.
How do we find him?
It has to be a friend or family
member of... What was his name?
- David Egan.
- Right. David Egan.
It could still be Max.
- Then find him. Prove Barry wrong.
- I just want for you and me ...
Listen to me. Get something.
There is no "you and me".
I can access the local library
and pull up all we need to know.
Egan ... David.
- All these articles are about him?
- Yeah. Or at least mention him.
Wait. July 5th, two years ago.
What's this?
"Susie Willis drowned, trapped in
a car near Dawson's Beach. "
- "The driver, Egan, was unharmed. "
- I remember that wreck.
Susie was enganged to David.
Her name was tattooed on his arm.
I saw it.
"Survived by his mother, Claire, and sister, Melissa, of Maribel County. "
They live in the sticks.
What do you think?
What have we got to lose?
Turn right...
Back there.
Do we just say, "We killed your son
and we were nearby, so... "
We play it by ear.
Angela Lansbury always had a plan.
What if they recognize us??
They could shoot us.
They could've done that already.
Jodie Foster tried this.
A serial killer opened the door.
Well, it was a good try.
Adding "breaking and entering"
to our crime?
Can I help you?
Hi. Our car stalled down the road.
Can we use your phone?
- The phone's over there
- Thanks.
Jodie.
Will you call Triple-A?
You got it ... AngeIa.
My name is Missy Egan.
Are you girls from Maribel?
- No, Southport.
- I went to Southport High.
- You looked familiar. What year?
- Class of '88.
Your name, "Egan", sounds familiar.
Did you have a brother?
I did, but he was younger than me.
David.
- What class was he?
- '92. But he died last July.
- I'm so sorry.
- Thanks.
D0 you live alone?
Yeah, I do.
My daddy died a long time ago
and my mother's in a home.
She didn't take too well
to what happened to David.
Things haven't been the same
since he died.
They're on their way.
I could make you guys a cup of tea
while you are waiting.
- Thanks.
- That's nice of you.
I think I remember David David.
He had a friend, what was his name?
Didn't he hang out with this guy...?
What was his name?
I didn't know too many
of David's friend.
There was one guy ...
He stopped by not too long after
David's death, to pay his respects.
He was a really nice guy.
He was cute and smart and...
We were sweet on each other for
a minute or so. But it didn't work.
He never said it. But I think
it hurt him to be around me.
- Where is this old friend now?
- Oh, I don't know.
- Do you remember his name?
- Billy.
- Did he have a last name?
- Blue. Billy Blue.
- We should wait back at the car.
- Don't be ridiculous. Stay.
- I don't want to miss Triple-A.
- We appreciate the phone.
Any time. I don't get
too many knocks on my door nowadays.
- Are you okay?
- I wigged out. I'm sorry.
Being in his house
and seeing his sister...
- God, do you see what we've done?
- It was an accident.
We killed a man. Then ruined
the lives of everyone he knew.
We're not that powerful.
You're giving us too much credit.
- You forgot your cigarettes.
- Thank you.
- I see you got the car started.
- Yeah, it started right up.
Funny how that happens.
- So what now?
- Now we try and find Billy Blue.
Maybe he wanted to die.
- What?
- David Egan.
His girlfriend died on the same
road, July 4th, one year earlier.
Maybe he was sitting in the road,
waiting for us to hit him.
Yeah, if that will help you
sleep at night.
What happened between us?
We used to be best friends.
We used to be a lot of things.
I miss you.
Hei, dad.
Is the washed-up has-been
having a moment?
What do you want?
We're doing inventory tomorrow.
I need you there by 10.
I can't. I'm in the parade tomorrow.
Dad put me in charge of the store,
and I want you there by 10.
The outgoing queen
has to ride in the parade.
It's tradition.
There's nothing I can do about it.
You and your hair ...
It's so pathetic.
- You can leave now.
- So very pathetic.
SOON
What?
Oh, my God...
Max...
- Are you sure he was dead?
- I saw him... with these crabs.
You do it.
He was there. And he was
wearing your jacket, Barry.
- Did the crabs carry him away?
- I believe you, Julie.
- He took the body.
- Why would he do that?
Why did he try to run you over,
and make coleslaw on Helen's head?
- Let's go back to the house.
- Where's your jacket, Barry?
Don't you see? He's got us.
We can't go to the police now.
He's watching us and waiting.
What are you waiting for?
What are you doing here?
- I've been looking for you guys.
- You're gonna die.
- Stop it.
- I didn't do anything.
- You're fucking lying!
- Leave him alone. Get a grip.
- Wake up, Julie. He's behind this.
- He's after me. Too.
I got a letter.
A letter? I got run over,
Helen gets her hair chopped off, -
- Julie gets a body in a trunk, and
you get a letter. That's balanced.
- You killed Max and took my jacket.
- Max is dead?
You always wanted to be our friend,
but were too jealous to handle it.
Fuck you.
We have to stick together.
Help each other.
So if it's not fisherboy here,
Who is it?
- We think his name is Billy Blue.
- How do you know that?
- David had a friend by that name.
- He's probably a school friend.
According to his sister,
that would make him class of '92.
Elsa was class of '92. Maybe
there's something in her yearbook.
It's hard to believe that's the guy.
His face isn't splattered
on the road.
- Maybe Blue's not his real name.
- He could have lied to Missy.
- If we bring the book to Missy...
- She could point him out.
I'm not going anywhere.
High school mugshots...
- I'll go. You've got that parade.
- Forget it.
- You have to, in case he shows up.
- I don't want him to!
This could be our chance.
We could catch him.
I'll go to Missy's. Barry, you go
with Helen. If he shows up ...
I'll pound his ass.
- You sound like vigilantes.
- It's July 4th, Ray.
Whatever he has planned is gonna
happen today, unless we stop him.
Don't you see? It's that moment
where we have to make a decision.
- Let's make the right one.
- I'll do what's smart, not right.
Then let's go.
Leave town. Dissappear.
I have disappeared.
Now I want my life back.
We have to face this.
What's it gonna be, Ray?
Barry.
Over there!
Where the hell is he?
Missy?
Please.
Missy ...
Do you remember me
from the other day? The car trouble?
What are you doing here?
Please, we need to talk.
I need to find
your brother's friend. Billy Blue.
- Can you look through the yearbook?
- What's this all about?
It has to do with your brother
and last July 4th.
- What about it?
- What happened wasn't an accident.
- I know.
- You know what?
He killed himself.
He went up there to die
where Susie died.
The whole town blamed him
for her death.
- So he blamed himself.
- How do you know it was suicide?
He left a note.
I hid it from the insurance company.
They don't pay if it's suicide.
That don't much matter anymore,
because the money's been spent.
I WILL NEVER FORGET
LAST SUMMER
This isn't a suicide note.
It's a death threat.
- What are you talking about?
- Your brother didn't kill himself.
I saw him. I was there. And
whoever sent this was there too.
- Where did you see him?
- We hit him. It was an accident.
- My brother drowned.
- "Susie" was tattooed on his arm.
He doesn't have a tattoo.
You didn't see anything. Get out!
Get out of my house.
Oh, my God...
It wasn't your brother.
- I'll be up in the balcony.
- He had a big, huge hook.
Everything's going to be all right.
I won't let anything happen to you.
Nicely done, ladies.
Now, let's meet last year's winner:
Miss Helen Shivers.
As we continue our pageant, we move into the talent competition.
Oh. Jesus.
Barry!
Somebody help him!
Excuse me.
- What's the problem?
- He's gonna kill him!
- Up in the balcony..
- Everybody stay calm.
Get off of me!
Stay behind me.
Nobody's up here. This is not
my idea of a funny joke.
The fisherman was here.
He killed Barry.
There's nobody up here.
Let's go back downstairs.
Watch your step.
Ladies and gentlemen, false alarm.
We'll resume in a few minutes.
I'm gonna take you home.
Your parents are worried about you.
You have to believe me.
Let me take you home.
Excuse me.
We'll be needing this.
Come on.
So then he killed him
with a fish-hook.
Did he use the same hook
to cut your hair off?
No. He used a scissors. Asshole.
I know I sound delusional.
But it's true.
I heard the version with a mental
patient with a hook for a hand.
We'll have to take the valley.
Look.
You little shit-stick reject...
There's been a murder. And
you'll fry in hell if you ignore it.
I'll contact Barry's parents,
and we'll put out a search for him.
He was probably
just playing a prank on you.
Oh, Jesus. I'm just gonna see
if this fella needs help.
It's him...
What's the trouble?
That's him! Behind you!
Behind you!
"Susie Willis killed.
Trapped in a car."
"Survived by her father Benjamin,
a local fisherman."
Elsa ...
Elsa!
Open the door!
Elsa, open the door!
Jesus Christ, hurry!
What are you doing? Elsa!
Open the door!
I'm coming.
- The Broad Street entrance is open.
- I'm being attacked.
You're what?
Lock the other door.
I'll call the police. Do what I say!
Elsa ...
Elsa?
Elsa, where are you?
Ray.
Ray!
- What are you doing here?
- It wasn't David Egan we killed.
It was Susie's father. Ben Willis.
- But they found David's body.
- I think Willis killed David.
- Then we killed Willis?
- But what if he didn't die?
This is crazy.
Come aboard.
- We have to find Helen and Barry.
- We will.
You...
It's you.
Billy Blue.
You went to Missy's.
- You're the friend. The fisherman.
- I can explain. Julie, wait!
- Wait.
- Stop it!
- Please, help me.
- Easy, child.
I need to call the police.
On the boat! Hurry!
Are you in some kind of trouble?
Yes. I'm in a lot of trouble.
That's a shame.
Being it's the 4th of July and all.
Kids like you should be out
having fun. Drinking, partying, -
- running people over, getting away
with murder, things like that.
You ...
- Ben Willis.
- Good. You did your homework, too.
Welcome aboard, Ray.
Open the door, Julie.
You've got no place to hide.
Come on, Julie.
- Happy 4th of July, Julie.
- Please, it was accident.
When you leave a man for dead,
make sure he's really dead.
We never killed anyone.
This whole year was for...
The guilt was killing me.
I had to know who he was.
That's why I went to see Missy.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you,
but i wanted you back.
I couldn't lose you again.
I love you, Julie.
No one gets me the way you do.
I understand your pain.
Do you have any idea
why this man would want you dead?
None.
Here it comes.
Well, don't worry.
The body will turn up.
They usually do.
ONE YEAR LATER.
I made the dean's list.
Thank you very much.
I miss you too, but I'll see you in
a couple of weeks. I love New York.
Of course I love you more.
You know that.
But I've got to take a shower.
- Julie, you got some mail.
- Thanks Deb.
A towel.
Don't start with me
You can ravage me in 2 weeks.
I love you too. Bye.
POOL PARTY THIS SATURDAY AT NOON
I STILL KNOW