Dr. cruler:
Intruder alert!
Attention all hydra
defense units!
Proceed to the
South platform.
Lethal force
is authorized.
I repeat.
Lethal force is authorized.
(Grunts)
(Laser firing)
Red skull:
Captain America.
Super soldier.
(Grunts)
One of the greatest leaders,
combatants and tacticians
who ever lived.
The only thing I hate
more than hydra soldiers
are hydra robots.
(Groans)
(Grunts)
He was once a normal man.
Did we get him?
Where is he?
(Groans)
Fire!
A weakling,
who took the experimental
super soldier serum.
That man
became unstoppable.
Coupled with his
unbreakable shield.
(All groan)
Trained in dozens
of fighting styles.
He is the pinnacle
of human potential.
One of the toughest
warriors of the modern age.
An allied hero
in world war ii,
he'd battled the forces
of hydra with some success,
until he fought
his superior.
With the fate of the globe
hanging in the balance,
their battle ended
in a draw.
Captain America: Hey!
(Grunts)
When their plane
went down in the ice,
they were frozen.
Revived only recently.
Well?
His skills
are extraordinary.
Difficult to copy,
but not impossible.
So says the taskmaster.
Don't worry,
red skull.
My photographic
reflexes can mimic
anyone, even him.
Mimicking him and
defeating him
are two very different things.
I believe a test
is in order.
(Weapons firing)
That was a test?
Well done, taskmaster.
But captain America
is more than skill.
It is his focus, will,
and mind that make
him who he is.
Sounds like somebody's
got a little man-crush
there, red...
(Chocking)
The captain and I are
two sides of the same coin.
Do not underestimate him,
or me.
You've seen my skill.
You know what I can do.
Emulating captain America
isn't enough
for my final goal.
I need the
super soldier himself.
Taskmaster:
Leave it to me.
Red skull:
That's not all.
Another avenger
possesses something
I require.
Iron man.
Stark?
Tony stark?
What do you want
with that rich fame ball?
I don't want the man.
I want his weapons.
I've been preparing
for iron man as well.
I know all
his weaknesses.
I am not convinced
you can take on
two avengers alone.
So I've prepared
reinforcements.
All: (Chanting)
Hail hydra!
Hail the red skull!
Soon you will see
what sets me apart
from captain America,
when I rule this world!
Iron man:
You sure about this, cap?
I mean, I've got
the world's most
highly advanced
repulsor-powered armor
and you've got...
No offense, a glorified
trash can lid.
Look, I don't wanna
hurt you.
Did you say trash can lid?
(Grunts)
Ah!
Wait a second,
I didn't say go!
In combat, you can't
always be the one
who says go!
That's your problem,
stark, you never strategize.
You just wing it.
(Firing)
It's called thinking
on your feet.
Or in my case,
boot jets.
I adapt to the
unexpected by being
unpredictable.
You, on the other hand,
are super predictable.
You used that same move
on the wrecking crew
last week.
(Grunts)
Whoa!
Ouch!
Worked both times,
didn't it?
Yeah, but do you
got anything new?
(Laser firing)
I'm pretty sure you
haven't seen this one.
Pretty sure I have.
(Grunts)
Well, then stop it!
Okay, you got me.
But if I had really
cut loose, you'd be
toast by now.
Well, then don't
hold back.
Your suit's a great weapon,
stark, but trust me,
it can be a crutch.
A crutch? This time,
I won't hold back.
And to make it
interesting, how about
a little bet?
When I win, you have
to wear my armor
for a month.
And don't worry,
I got one in your colors.
Well, I don't need
a stuffy sardine can,
but okay.
However, when I win,
you go to boot camp
training with me.
And I hope you like
push-ups, Tony.
I see a lot of 'em
in your future.
I usually hire someone
to do push-ups for me, but
you know what, you're on!
All right, Jarvis.
Let's turn old red, white
and blue
into plain old black and blue.
Jarvis:  If you say so.
Captain America:
You wanna say go
this time, stark?
Iron man: Very funny.
On your mark,
get-set-go!
(Laser firing)
(Grunts)
Nice one. Block this!
You're making it easy!
(Shield clanks)
So are you!
Oh, really?
Give up?
Jarvis:  Captain America
has damaged several
quantum dot nanocircuits.
Power is down by 15%.
No sweat.
Watch this.
(Shield clanking)
See? This is what
I'm talking about.
All armor,
no skill.
Don't need your skill
when my weapons
can do this!
(Explosion)
Captain America:
You need to use your
most important weapon,
your brain, more often.
Hey bucko, you're
talking to the guy
who can divide quintic
polynomials in his head
while trimming his nose hairs!
(Grunts)
Ah!
So keep your left up
and guard those
pretty nose hairs.
You've made your point.
So, now I'm gonna
make mine and win this!
(Grunts)
(Clanks)
Captain America: Fine.
We'll call it a draw.
Iron man: For now.
Just another little
tweak and...
Jarvis:  Repulsors are
at 100%, sir.
How's the repair going
on your fancy suit?
It's just
minor adjustments.
I'm ready any time!
My armor can go all day.
The best shouldn't have to.
That was the
whole point, huh?
You didn't want to spar.
You wanted to train me.
You're my friend, Tony.
And I want
to keep you alive.
Having repulsor-powered
armor is one thing.
Being an undisciplined
wild man in battle will
get you killed.
Believe me,
I've seen it before.
I get it.
And thanks, Steve.
But my ability to fly
by the seat of my
pants is who I am.
There'd be no iron man
without it.
(Explosion)
Whoa! What?
Jarvis:  Sir.
(Alarm ringing)
We're under attack!
Jarvis, a little help here?
Jarvis:  Intruders, sir.
They have infiltrated
our defense grid.
Who are they?
Jarvis system
shutting down.
(Explosion)
Huh?
Captain America:
What are they after?
They're headed
for my weapons vault!
Let's move!
Right behind, ya!
Iron man: Try to keep up.
How'd you get
ahead of me?
Quiet.
Hydra trooper:
Prep these weapons
for transport immediately!
Hydra.
Okay, here's what
we'll do. Wait!
Hey!
Do you have any idea
how much I hate it when
people touch my stuff?
(Weapons firing)
Blast him!
The nerve of these guys!
(All groan)
How's that for an entrance?
(Weapons firing)
I had an idea.
We could have
taken them all out
in 10 seconds flat!
Did you not see them
ransacking my toy chest?
(Captain America grunts)
Behind you!
Got it!
These guys are
no problem, cap!
Captain America:
Unless they get
a hold of a giant gun!
Die, heroes!
Iron man:
I'll handle it.
Eventually.
(Weapons firing)
(All groan)
(Grunts)
Hurry, Dr. cruler.
Haste makes waste.
I'm hacking as fast
as I can, Dr. fump.
Almost. Got it.
There!
We've breached
the magnetic seal,
we're in.
Help me with
the transport case!
Oh, no.
Not in there!
Cap!
Thanks.
They're in the vault.
We gotta stop 'em!
(Weapons firing)
Dr. fump: There it is.
The stark repulsor Cannon.
Powered by
its very own arc reactor.
Still a prototype,
but incredibly valuable.
(Beeping)
Report.
What is your status?
We've got
the repulsor Cannon.
Where are you, sir?
You were supposed
to be helping against
iron man and captain America.
Give me that!
Our hydra troopers
are facing two avengers!
We need your help!
I gave you the tools
to aid in your escape.
Now, return to base!
I don't think I like him.
(Both grunt)
Wait. Was this part
of the plan?
(Both scream)
(Chuckles)
Those hydra fools
don't even realize
they're simply a diversion
for a bigger prize.
(Grunts)
(Weapons firing)
So how about
that bet?
By my count I took down
one more than you did.
(Clanks)
And by my count
we're even.
And we've got a lot
of cleaning up to do.
Iron man: We'll get 'em
to the brig after we've
accounted for all my weapons,
including the ones
in the vault.
Oh, no.
No!
I should've known.
What is it?
The stark repulsor Cannon,
my latest invention,
it's gone!
That Cannon is
just as powerful as
my hand-repulsors.
Which means?
Hydra's in possession of
one of my deadliest weapons.
I'm going after it.
Let's not be hasty, Tony.
We need a plan.
Iron man:
I don't have time
for a plan!
And I don't have
flying boots to
chase after you with.
Uh...
Wake up.
I want answers.
Where are you taking
that repulsor Cannon?
Where?
Forget it, hero.
I'll never talk.
Hail hydra.
Hail the red...
(Screaming)
(All screaming)
What?
What's going on?
Where am I?
Who am I?
Oh, good grief.
What is this place?
I'm freaking out, man!
Iron man, come in.
Iron man!
Let's get out of here.
Com's jammed. Great.
Let's hope there's
a way off this tub.
I don't think stark
will mind if I borrow one
of his expensive jets.
That one doesn't
belong to stark.
You've got some
of hawkeye's skill,
but you're not him.
Hawkeye doesn't miss.
If I wanted to hit you,
I would have.
I've studied all of
the avengers' skills.
Especially yours, captain.
Taskmaster.
I've read your file.
I know all about
your talents.
Let's see you
imitate this!
Okay, you're a little
better than I expected.
(Both grunting)
Give it up, captain.
I possess the techniques
of the greatest
fighters in the world.
(Groans)
Like iron fist!
My improv catch you
off guard, taskmaster?
Oh, great.
Now I sound like stark!
Hold still, avenger!
(Grunts)
So predictable.
Oh, yeah?
(Grunts)
Okay, nice.
Kenpo, tae Kwon do
and jujitsu.
My turn!
How'd you like my judo?
I don't!
It's him!
It's iron man!
Do something!
Ugh.
Take the controls!
Eat this!
Iron man: Now this is
the part where I escort
you to the ground.
(Weapon firing)
You hydra goon!
That's my weapon!
And I'm coming
to take it back!
Note to self.
Next time I create
a weapon that can
penetrate my force field,
upgrade my force field!
Ah! Even through
my armor, this hurts.
(Grunts)
Hydra has big
plans for you, hero,
but to me, you're just
a paycheck.
Well, it's not gonna
be easy money.
(Groans)
Taskmaster: Not bad.
Wait a sec,
the weight's off!
What did you...
(Screaming)
I'm faster than
you think, captain.
Not only do I know
your fighting style,
I know exactly when
you're going
to throw your shield.
And that you
always catch it.
Iron man: Come on.
Don't poop out on me now.
Whoa!
(Iron man groans)
(Clanking)
At least today
can't get any worse.
Iron man:
Cap, you there?
Hydra got away with...
Cap?
He's offline.
Jarvis, are you
back on or what?
Jarvis:
Back online, sir!
Get me a trace
on cap, asap.
Jarvis:  No GPS location, sir.
All of captain Roger's
com devices are offline,
and his bio-signs
are not present
on the ship.
Iron man:
Well, then where is he?
You check the hangar?
None of your aircraft
are missing.
So if cap didn't leave,
that means he was taken.
The question is, where?
Easy, troops.
Don't want to harm
our prize.
He's worth a lot to me.
Take him to the
neurotransducer room
for processing.
Keep a guard on
him at all times.
Both: Yes, sir!
Make that five guards.
Oh, today is turning out
to be an excellent day indeed.
Now for my own prize.
Iron man's stealth suit.
Ah!
I've studied all of
hydra's manuals on
the iron man armor.
With this suit and my skills,
I won't have to work for jerks
like the skull anymore.
Yeah, once I get rid
of old red and crusty,
I'll take over hydra
and rule this weak world.
(Screaming)
Booby trapped.
I should've known.
Ah.
(Alarm sounding)
Automated voice:
Perimeter breach,
incoming vessel.
Ah, speak of the devil.
Taskmaster.
Where is he?
Taskmaster:
That's right, red skull.
I did what you've
dreamed of all of these years.
I give you
captain America.
(Groans)
Red skull:
Impressive, taskmaster.
You've executed
your mission
and brought me
all I need to create
a new army.
(Panting)
New army?
What, you two skull heads
can't take over
the world alone?
Our soldiers will be superior
to any this world has known.
And you are vital
to their creation.
I've finally synthesized
and even improved
upon the super soldier
serum that created you.
Your blood is the last
ingredient I needed.
I could've got his blood.
Plenty of it.
Bringing him
here was a mistake.
You just got lucky,
taskmaster.
Luck had nothing
to do with it.
My mimicry power
is unmatched.
True.
That is why
we have utilized
your unique ability in the
functioning of our new device.
What?
You made a machine
that can copy people's
skills like I do?
Red skull:
The neurotransducer
will replicate
not only
the captain's skills,
but his tactics
and combat strategies,
and then be programed
into my new army.
(Grunts)
Save your strength.
(Clanks)
The restraints
are solid adamantium.
Even the hulk
could not break them.
I'd take that bet any day.
Captain, in the name
of hydra,
I thank you for
your contribution.
(Screaming)
(Thunder rumbling)
Iron man:
Gotta be here somewhere.
Come on, come on.
Where's that
security footage?
Yes!
Taskmaster?
What was that
creep doing here?
Jarvis:
Damage report, sir.
Minimal damage to the hull,
loss of power 22%.
Inventory report.
The prototype
repulsor Cannon
is missing, and...
Oh, dear.
Oh, dear, what?
Your iron man mark vi
stealth armor seems
to be missing as well.
Seems to be?
What else can go wrong?
I'll try to find
something, sir.
I'm not in the mood, Jarvis.
My apologies, sir.
Hmm.
Cap sure went
down easy.
Let's take
a closer look.
You've gotta
be kidding me.
He was faking it
the whole time?
Of all the
reckless plans!
Perhaps captain Rogers
has adopted your quote,
"fly by the seat
of your pants," methods, sir?
Well, cap obviously
is giving me the heads-up
to come after him,
and that's what
I'm gonna do.
The captain's homing
beacon was destroyed.
How will you find him?
Actually I was gonna
ask for your help
on that one, Jarvis.
Did taskmaster leave
anything behind?
Scanning now, sir.
I've located something.
This a small amount
of mud left in the hangar
that is not from you
or captain Rogers.
Run a full spectrum analysis.
Test complete.
The composition is made up
of minerals and rare Clay
found in the baltic highlands.
Well, that narrows
it down a little.
Cross-reference
with S.H.I.E.L.D.'s list
of taskmaster's
suspected hideouts.
Right away, sir.
(Scanning)
I have one suspected location.
An abandoned military bunker
in Southern Estonia.
That's it.
Hold the fort, Jarvis.
Very good, sir.
(Groaning)
Impressive.
A lesser man would
have been obliterated.
(Beeping)
Great leader, we did it!
We have successfully
recorded captain America's
fighting skills.
They are incredibly
clean and organized.
This man is truly
a remarkable specimen.
The captain's skills
are ready for your use.
Excellent.
Your service will
be greatly rewarded.
You could've just paid
to copy my skills.
I'm a better fighter
than that patriot any day.
Doubtful.
You are a mercenary,
sorely lacking what
captain America possesses.
Courage, resolve and
dedication to an ideal.
Qualities perfect
for my new army.
So what happens
to him now?
Now I employ the second
function of this device.
Not only can it
copy brainwaves,
it can write them,
like data onto a hard drive.
(Machine sounding)
Initiating hydra
indoctrination sequence.
Your world is about
to change, soldier.
Soon you will know
nothing but absolute
obedience to hydra.
And you will answer
only to me!
I wish you had lips, skully,
so you could kiss my
star-spangled...
(Screaming)
No!
No! No!
Hydra troopers:
Hail hydra!
Hail the red skull!
(Chanting continues)
(Red skull laughing)
(Groans)
(Straining)
Get out of my head!
(Groaning)
Resistance is useless.
Great leader, your volunteers
have been prepared
for the serum.
And here I wanted to watch
captain America's will
bend like a weed
beneath my boot.
No matter.
Taskmaster, stay here
and make sure the captain's
conversion is complete.
Do not turn your
back on him for a second.
Whatever you wish.
And his shield.
(Grunts)
Very well, great leader.
I would curb that sharp tongue
of yours, taskmaster.
Lest it cuts your throat.
Hmm.
(Captain America groans)
Jarvis:  Atmospheric
re-entry complete.
I recommend
initiating deceleration.
Sir? You can slow down
any time.
Shouldn't have flown off
without cap.
Captain Rogers clearly
allowed himself
to be captured.
He was reckless.
That's not how
cap does things.
He got himself
in trouble. I know it.
Sir, we are approaching
the target coordinates
at an unsafe speed.
Knock, knock.
Automated voice:
Intruder alert!
Hello, I'm looking
for a friend of mine.
Tall, broad-shouldered,
dressed like a flag.
(Weapons firing)
Destroy him!
You know, you try
and be a nice guy...
(All groan)
I'll tell you what,
you fellas take your
10-minute coffee break.
I'll go find
my friend.
I don't get taskmaster.
I mean, he's an accomplished
bad guy, he could build
a lair anywhere.
Why some dingy
cold war bunker?
Jarvis:
Location is everything.
I scan life forms
five meters ahead.
Iron man:
I don't think that's cap.
Ready?
Ready.
Open fire!
(Weapons firing)
Well, you gotta admire
their persistence.
Activate the
sonic disruptors.
Jarvis:
Charging now, sir.
(All groan)
Sheesh, can we just get
to the boss fight already?
Figures cap'd end up
in the gym.
I don't think I wanna work out
on this thing though.
We gotta find him, Jarvis.
Iron man:
Cap! You in here?
Nice pool.
Or should I say hot tub.
Jarvis:  This is an extremely
concentrated form
of hydrochloric acid.
Lethal.
I wasn't planning
on taking a dip.
Captain America: Stark!
Huh?
Whoa, hey cap!
Same team here!
Death to all who
oppose hydra!
Oh, great.
Aw, no, cap.
What've they done
to you?
They showed me the truth.
The strength that will be
our new world order!
Whoa!
Jarvis:  Biometric scans
indicate the captain's
brain waves
have been radically altered
to those of a completely
different person.
Different person? Who?
Greetings, stark.
Oh, him.
Terrific.
Allow me introduce you
to my latest agent.
Sure, he's wearing less
festive colors, but I think
we've met.
No.
This captain America
shares my vision
of the future!
Yeah, speaking of vision,
this is strictly pay per view,
so get lost!
(Grunts)
For hydra!
For the red skull!
Cap, I thought we decided
you were gonna be like me.
This ain't me.
Everything always has
to be about you, stark.
You're selfish and conceited.
Okay. That's it!
I don't know what
the skull did to you, buddy,
but you gotta
snap out of it!
(Chuckles)
Ah!
Now stop shooting!
Don't make me hurt you.
(Weapon firing)
Don't make me laugh.
Okay.
This is your last chance!
I warned you!
Now it gets real!
(Grunts)
Wait. What is that?
Ah!
Laugh that off, stark.
Jarvis:  Sir, the armor's
been compromised.
We've lost power
to the thrusters.
Really, Jarvis?
I hadn't noticed.
Remind me to remove
stating the obvious
from your programing.
Now how do we get
this stupid thing off?
Ah!
Can't reach it...
Automated voice:
Stark armor
security codes, accessed.
Bingo.
Now you will learn
why hydra shall
reign supreme!
Gotcha!
Ah!
(Groans)
Nice one, stark,
but you're too late.
How's he doing, Jarvis?
Jarvis:
His brainwaves
are normalizing.
My scans indicate
captain Rogers is stuck
in a rem-like dream state.
Time to wake up, buddy.
(Groans)
Sorry about that, cap.
You okay?
Uh...
I just had the worst
nightmare a soldier
could have.
Where am I?
Well, you're back
where you belong.
Hydra hijacked
your brain.
Hydra?
You really had me
worried there.
Here, lemme give
ya a hand.
(Grunts)
Ah!
Automated voice:
Stark encryption decoded.
Verify.
Verification complete.
I have you now, iron man.
I thought I fixed you!
(Grunts)
You did. Don't you know
a spontaneous plan
when you see one?
I guess this means
I have to lose?
Just make it look good.
You are no match
for hydra, fool!
Says you, traitor!
Ah!
Jarvis:
Sir, system reboot
has begun!
Great news.
(Screams) Oh, it hurts!
Skull's programing
must be strong for you
to finish your own friend.
By the red skull's command,
take me to our great leader.
Yeah, well, he's not
gonna be the boss forever.
What do you think about
the skull bowing down to us?
Old red and gruesome
would keep you a slave,
I'll make you a partner.
Join me and we'll
turn hydra into a twin-headed
dragon and rule it all!
To a new hydra?
To a new hydra!
So when do we
take out the skull?
We leave
for Antarctica soon.
Antarctica, eh?
That's all I needed to hear.
(Grunts)
Ha!
Hmph, so you broke
skull's programing.
He brainwashed
the wrong guy.
You're the one
who wants to be him.
Red skull is nothing to me.
Let's see him do this!
You gonna hold
your breath forever?
I didn't want to interrupt
your terrific acting.
How about you make it easy
on yourself and give up?
I've studied you both!
I know how you fight!
Yeah, but I'm guessing
you don't know how
we fight together.
You know,
I don't think he does.
This is gonna be fun.
(Grunts)
Really?
You let yourself get
captured and turned
into a psycho?
It seemed like
a good idea at the time.
Isn't that what you
always say?
Oh, I get it. You used
my spontaneous style...
(Groans)
...to sneak in and get
brainwashed so you
could find out
where the red skull is.
Stay!
So, I win the bet!
No, it was all part of
"the plan," so I won the bet.
Let's just say we're even.
By the way,
what's hydra up to?
You don't wanna know.
You sure we shouldn't bring
him along, just in case?
He's too dangerous.
We'll have S.H.I.E.L.D.
come and get him.
Just in case.
Don't go anywhere
now, copycat.
Iron man:
So, you're not gonna change?
This outfit tricked
taskmaster, it might work
on the skull, too.
Stop stealing
my crazy idea schtick!
Jarvis:
Sir, I've got something.
The missing mark vi's beacon
is nearby but weak,
as if it were shielded.
What are you doing?
Scanning for the suit of armor
that taskmaster stole from me.
Wow, he really played you.
Were you planning
on telling me?
What?
I mean, I meant
to let him steal it.
Yeah, so we could
trace him.
Right.
All right, fine! Let's just
go bust some skulls.
(Clanking)
Automated voice:
Iron man armor
access granted.
Hmm.
I think a name change
is in order.
I kinda like
the iron master.
(Chuckles) Catchy.
So, not a word
about my flying?
Your flying is the least
of my worries.
Oh, what?
You don't like my plan?
It's just a little too "me".
Come on,
it's well thought out.
And it's the last thing
red skull would expect.
I figured the wild man
in you would love it.
This is the quietest
you've ever been.
What're you up
to back there?
I'm not saying,
just in case skull still has
some control over your brain.
You really think
I'd turn on you?
Probably not,
but I like surprises,
so I'm working on
a back-up plan just in case
yours doesn't work.
Wow, strategy
from iron man?
What I can say,
you're rubbing off on me.
Maybe I'll earn
a merit badge.
Got an incoming transmission,
better get outta sight.
Right.
Automated voice:
Approaching vessel,
identify.
This is taskmaster's ship,
vessel 6769.
Captain hydra
requesting permission to land.
6769, maintain your course.
Red skull:  Captain,
what have you to say?
Hail hydra!
Ah. Good.
Where is the taskmaster?
He tried to convince me
to betray you, sir.
He failed.
His turning
on me was inevitable,
but I did not
expect it so soon.
I took the liberty
of destroying the traitor.
You'll make
a worthy replacement.
Perhaps even my
second in command.
Iron man: Nice.
Hydra has a great
benefit package, man.
Medical, dental,
free mind control.
And you're already
wearing one of their
snazzy matching outfits.
Hey, how about
you work on that
backup plan?
Hydra tech: (Over pa)
Hydra troopers,
mobilize to 031.
All flight crews report
to mission briefing.
(Loud whirring)
I don't like this.
They're prepping for
a large scale attack.
Well, then it's
a good thing we showed
up for the party.
I can pretend to be a bad guy.
What are you gonna do?
I've got something
up my sleeve.
I pretty much invented
stealth tech so...
That's surprising,
considering how much
you like to be seen.
Captain America
cracking jokes.
I like it! Now you just have
to work on being funny.
Sir. We're to
escort you to
the great leader.
Carry on.
Hey, we've
got an intruder!
Actually, you've got two.
(Grunting)
(Chuckling) I knew
you couldn't stay
out of sight long.
No, no, it's just you
being a hydra goon
is creeping me out.
Yeah, I'm gonna need
a long shower when we're
done with this mission.
Of course, there's a giant
hydra rocket down here.
Why can't these guys
just rob jewelry stores?
That doesn't
look any better.
What is it anyway?
Captain America:
It's red skull's new army,
compliments of my blood.
(Loud whirring)
(Grunting)
(Loud shriek)
'Cause the world needs more
captain America mutations,
freaks and weirdos?
Seriously, hydra.
Iron man: Did you notice
how I didn't just run
out there this time?
Captain America:
Yes, and I was
surprised.
Iron man: You were supposed
to say, "impressed".
So, what are they
doing down here?
I don't know,
but that
looks familiar.
Isn't that
one of yours?
Iron man: They're
mass producing my
repulsor Cannon!
I'm gonna sue 'em.
Right after I beat 'em
into next Sunday.
That's not the only
thing they've ripped off.
(Loud thud)
(Hissing)
Iron man: Is that
a copy of your shield?
It's huge.
All right, so what's
our big strategy?
We destroy everything.
Now you're talking.
(Grunts)
(Grunting)
This design is ingenious.
These weapons will make
hydra unstoppable.
You know, the wattage
settings on these arc
capacitors are all wrong.
(Gasps)
Sound the alarm! (Grunts)
No, don't.
(Alarm buzzing)
Argh!
Stark! What the heck
are you doing?
What? I'm blowing stuff up!
(Grunts)
Sorry, slowpoke.
(Grunting)
(Loud explosion)
Come on, guys. You're
making this too easy!
(Beeping)
Know what happens
when you pirate my tech?
This.
(Loud explosions)
(Indistinct shouting)
You know, I'm kind
of liking this whole
strategy thing.
Time for phase two.
Let's take a peek
at what's behind that.
Incoming!
(Grunting)
(Weapons firing)
I'm disappointed your
programing failed, captain.
You made an excellent
hydra agent.
Sorry, there's
no future in it.
(Groaning)
Iron man: Or in you, skull.
(Sighs)
You will beg me
to spare you,
when I control
the world.
Taskmaster:
Is that so, red skull?
Well, look who put some
iron in their diet.
Got to admit, the new
paint job is cool.
Excellent, taskmaster.
Now that you've
acquired stark's
ultimate weapon,
you will put
it to my use.
I'm done taking
orders from you, skull.
The iron master is
taking control of hydra!
Fool, you work for me!
I love it when the
bad guys bicker.
Captain America:
Makes our job easier.
Consider this
a hostile takeover.
What? (Straining)
Can't be. Ugh...
I'm unable
attack you. Why?
Because you are
my slave.
Now bow!
(Groaning)
You thought taking
iron man's stealth armor
was your idea?
No.
I programed
you to steal it.
The memory
was erased,
but you also spent time
in my neurotransducer
and were conditioned
to think as I do.
Your recent ambition
to take over hydra?
It came from me!
You are no more
than a hired gun
and you will obey
my every command.
(Groans)
Hey, skull, you're kind
of a control freak,
you know that?
For your
first directive,
destroy iron man
and captain America!
(Grunting)
No more
playing army, skull.
You have yet
to see my army.
Or should I say
"our" army?
(Loud footsteps approaching)
So, do we do this
your way or my way?
Not sure it's
gonna matter.
Crush them!
Only chance is
to keep moving!
Clear a path,
I'll cover you!
(Loud explosion)
Oh!
(Groaning)
Come on.
I'm okay.
Let's run for it!
What are you gawking
at, idiots? Finish them!
(Loud explosion)
How many of these
things are there?
Got to get past 'em.
Come on!
Let's see you block this.
(Growling)
Oh, no.
This way!
You know, I really could
use some boot jets.
(Panting)
Bad enough these
things are strong!
But they
can fight, too!
Worse than that,
they fight smart.
(Grunting)
(Gasps)
You don't recognize
their style?
Besides being armed
with your Cannon,
my ubermen have
been enhanced with
my super soldier serum
and programed
with the captain's
superior combat skills.
All of his years of training
are going to pay off
for hydra!
Come on, Tony,
I think it's
time to go.
Whoa!
Huh?
Okay. My turn, cap.
I'll clear us a path
out of here!
(Loud explosion)
(Grunts)
(Grunting)
(Groaning)
In a way, it will be
captain America's army
that will sweep
across the globe,
led by my
unquestioningly loyal
field commander,
the iron master!
How are you
coming with that plan?
Plan? Oh, it's
incoming now.
And it's more
like a bomb.
Bomb?
(Low rumbling)
(All gasps)
(Screaming)
A gamma bomb.
Somebody call
for back-up?
Late for the
party, big guy.
No, you're
just in time.
Hulk. Smash.
(Roaring)
(Weapons firing)
(Growling)
Captain America:
Got to admit, nice plan.
I hadn't counted
on the monster.
Delay them as
long as you can.
I will initiate
the final phase.
By your command.
I'm going after red skull.
I got a score
to settle, too!
What am I supposed to do?
You're doing it!
Hoping you'd say that!
Now where's...
Found him!
(Glass cracking)
(Hulk roaring)
First you rip off
cap, now me?
There's not an original
bone in your body.
There's no such thing as
an original idea, stark.
Iron man: So let's go
with the classics.
Jarvis! Initiate
the remote!
Shut down his armor!
Jarvis:  Taskmaster has
installed a hydra encryption
device to prevent such action.
It will take
minutes to override.
(Loud buzzing)
We don't have minutes.
Computer:
Rocket fueling is complete.
Initiate the
launch sequence.
Pre-launch protocol
has begun.
(Rapid beeping)
Captain America:
Hydra cap reporting for duty.
You can't win, skull!
Oh, I've learned how
to beat you, captain.
Don't play
by the rules.
And yet you keep losing!
Red skull: Not this time!
And through my
defeats, I've learned
something else from you,
always have
a final plan.
The rocket is filled
with the super soldier serum
I used on my troops,
complete with
your blood sample.
Millions will soon
be transformed
into ultra-powered
soldiers under my control.
The planet will
be reshaped
into the image of hydra.
(Grunting)
Get off of me!
Give me that!
(Snarling)
How do you like it?
(Groaning)
Okay! I'm offended.
You wanna fight?
I'm right here.
Come out, taskmaster.
Show me
what you got.
Taskmaster: Over here.
(Loud explosion)
(Iron man grunts)
I know all
your tricks, stark.
You're looking at
the new iron man!
Jarvis, get me
into that suit!
Jarvis:  Your decryption
hacks are working,
but very slowly, sir.
Keep trying.
In the meantime,
maybe I can hack taskmaster!
(Energy pulsating)
(Groaning)
That...
That won't stop me!
Wasn't meant to.
I freed you from
the skull's programing.
You don't have to
serve him anymore.
Really?
Appreciate it, stark!
Hey, you owe me!
I'll show you
what I owe you!
Jarvis! It's now or never!
Jarvis:  Sir, I was able
to access and deactivate
his armor's energy shields.
That's all I need!
Charge up the hull.
Let's give him a shock!
(Screaming)
I can't move!
What have you done?
Ha! Taught you a lesson.
Your fist is no
match for my brain.
(Groans)
So much for
the iron copycat.
Jarvis, pinpoint
cap for me.
Hydra is making hulk mad!
Hydra won't like hulk mad!
Hulk smash!
Why, you...
Come here, ugly!
(Roaring)
(Beeping)
Your plan
ends now, skull.
Does it, captain?
I have decided
it is better you are
not with hydra, captain.
Your compassion
is a weakness.
Tell it to my shield!
Ha! The great
captain America
has missed.
It was bound
to happen.
Without your
precious shield,
you're finished.
I guess you're right.
Computer:
Launch sequence
will commence in...
30, 29, 28,
27, 26, 25...
Red skull:
You've lost your mind!
My rocket will spread
hydra's destiny all over
your beloved homeland.
Captain America: If your
rocket makes it that far.
Computer:
14, 13, 12...
Guess I didn't
miss after all.
Once in a while, you
got to do what you said,
"not play by the rules."
Computer:
Five, four, three, two...
One, ignition.
(Loud explosion)
Captain!
Captain America:
Stark! Where are you?
We have to get
out of here, now!
Stark, do you read? Over!
Hulk? This is cap.
Can you hear me?
(Grunting)
Stark! Where are you?
Hello!
Ah, you're
early this time.
All according
to my plan.
After you.
Hulk, get out, now!
Working on it.
Hulk tired
of hydra.
Hulk smash!
Oh, come on!
(Beeping)
Iron man: That was
closer than usual.
I hope hulk made
it out of there.
See if you
can reach him.
Big green,
do you copy?
Jarvis:  Hulk's com
is unresponsive, sir.
Also, the arc reactor
suffered critical
damage in the escape
and will be
shutting down now.
Are you kidding me?
Uh, stark?
What's happening?
Iron man: Experiencing some
technical difficulties.
So, this isn't
part of the ride?
Apparently, it is today.
You gonna do
something about this?
Jarvis! Reroute power
from the emergency reserve.
Jarvis:  As I informed
you earlier, sir,
the reserve was
damaged in your battle
with captain America.
Iron man:
Don't tell me that!
Options! I need options!
Dreadfully sorry, sir,
there are none.
Captain America:
So are you fixing this?
Iron man: As luck would
have it, not this time!
Stark!
This is gonna hurt!
Yeah, well, you're
the one who's always
supposed to be prepared!
Pull a parachute
out of your
shield or something!
Stark!
(Hulk shouting)
Oh, so that's
what that feels like.
Yeah.
That's two
you owe me.
(Loud explosion)
Iron man: So much for
hydra's big scheme.
See? Not all plans
work out, cap.
Mine did.
(Sighs)
(Red skull grunting)
Perimeter secure, sir.
You failed, skull.
Your need to control
captain America doomed us.
It was your treachery
that doomed us.
And for that you
will be eliminated.
Oh!
Oh, stark, you're
a piece of work.
(Grunts)
Huh?
S.H.I.E.L.D. agent:
Attention, hydra!
This is S.H.I.E.L.D.
Drop your weapons,
or you will be fired upon!
(Taskmaster laughing)
Come on out, cap.
For better or worse.
I do like the colors.
And the boot jets,
of course.
Both: Ready? Avengers attack!
(Screaming)
I'm going in.
Roger that, cap.
I'm on your wing.
Whoa...
Iron man: I'll get him.
(Grunts)
Wow. You both missed me.
I don't see how.
You're so big,
green and ugly.
Hulk: Wow! You really
can't hit me.
Come on, stark.
Iron patriot, incoming.
Now you're
getting it, cap.
That tickles. Stop it.
Yeah, you two are lame.
What's this
about, anyway?
I bet cap if he
fought more like me,
spontaneous
and unpredictable,
he'd do better.
And I bet Tony if he was
little more tactical and
strategic in mind like me,
he'd do better.
Oh, no.
Cap, those are
heat seekers!
And they've locked onto me.
Captain America:
Sorry, Tony. I was just
winging it, like you do.
Iron man:
Don't worry, I got this.
Just need some
room to maneuver.
Captain America:
You're running out of
room to maneuver.
Then it's time for
some strategy.
Hmm...
Captain America:
They're closing in!
I see!
Captain America:
There's one on your six!
Got it!
Captain America:
Only one left, I'll get it!
Iron man: Wait, no!
(Grunts)
(Both screaming)
(Hulk laughing)
(Both groaning)
So, you both lost?
We both won!
You're both good
at what you do.
Why don't you just
stick to that?
You know, he's right.
You're pretty good at
all that plotty planny stuff.
And you're fairly decent
at shooting from the hip.
We never talked
about what I'm good at.
Smashing.
Now, let's go eat.
I could go for some
raw menu macrobiotic
organic tofu.
I have no idea
what you just said.
I'm a meat
and potatoes
kind of guy.
Hulk saved you
and hulk wants pie.
Yeah, okay.
I could go for pie.
Pie it is.