Well, it was a funny thing.
I think I gave myself a dare.
It was the height of the Cold War.
The readers, the young readers,
if there was one thing they hated,
it was war, it was the military.
Or as Eisenhower called it,
"the military-industrial complex."
So I got a hero who represented
that to the hundredth degree.
He was a weapons manufacturer,
he was providing weapons for the Army,
he was rich, he was an industrialist.
But, he was a good-looking guy
and he was courageous.
He went over to Vietnam by himself
to test out one of the weapons
and then something happened
and that's how he became Iron Man,
but I thought it would be fun to take
the kind of character
that nobody would like,
none of our readers would like,
and shove him down their throat
and make them like him.
And because of the fact
that Tony Stark was such a great guy...
See, I kind of had
Howard Hughes in mind
when I was thinking of Tony.
Without being crazy,
he was Howard Hughes.
And he became very popular.
I'll tell you a funny thing about Tony,
who, as you know, had a...
His heart had been injured
and he was always afraid
that any moment he could keel over.
I loved the concept of a guy
in the armoured suit
and with all the things he could do.
And I loved the idea we came up with,
that Iron Man was really
somebody who was
Tony Stark's bodyguard.
'Cause he had to justify,
"What's this guy doing
always hanging around?"
And I thought that was kind of clever.
So there was Tony Stark,
there was Iron Man occasionally,
and, "Oh, he's Tony's bodyguard.
That's okay."
I love the name Pepper Potts
and Happy Hogan.
There's this rich man,
he has this beautiful assistant
or secretary and she's in love with him.
Now, if I were really an original writer,
I would have had her hate him.
But, what the heck.
Of all the comic books
we published at Marvel,
we got more fan mail for Iron Man
from women, from females,
than any other title.
For some reason,
females really loved Iron Man
and I figured out it was because,
first of all he was handsome,
secondly, he was rich,
and thirdly, I think a girl
would want to mother him
and say, "That's all right. You'll be okay.
Don't worry about your heart.
"I'll look after you.
"And hey, if you die,
I inherit all your money."
No, I only added that. I didn't mean that.
But I think there was
something about Tony
that aroused the maternal instinct
in women or something.
But, whatever the reason,
and I never got over that,
we got more fan mail
for Iron Man from girls.
We didn't get much fan mail from girls,
but whenever we did, it was usually...
The letter was usually
addressed to Iron Man.
The beauty part for me
about Iron Man has always been,
here you have this character,
who on the outside is invulnerable,
I mean, just can't be touched,
but inside is a wounded figure.
Stan made it very much
an in-your-face wound,
you know, his heart was broken,
you know, literally broken.
But there's a metaphor going on there
and that's, I think, what made
that character interesting.
It was very easy for me
to deal with the armour,
'cause I didn't have to draw it.
I felt sorry for the artist,
I'd make up anything.
"Add this to the armour,
do that to the armour, do that..."
Then I'd go do something else
and the poor guy had to work on it.
And I was never satisfied
with Iron Man's armour.
If you look through all the issues
of Iron Man, you will see...
I must have had his armour changed
a thousand times.
I loved Iron Man. it wasn't
too much to ask of me, drawing him,
because there was hardly a face there.
There's just... Not even a nose,
just a slight hint of a nose
and a mouth and eyes.
We never even saw
the pupils of the eyes.
And I loved it
because it was a challenge
to get to show emotion on his face
'cause he's wearing a metal helmet.
The suit is all metal,
so I would bend the...
The rules a little bit
by showing, if he was
smiling at something,
just to tweak the mouth up,
just enough to convey the message
to the readers that he's smiling.
Or anger, and then I would
do this, you know,
and then you would see
these lines in here.
And that would tell them
that he was angry.
The first cover was in pencil
about the size of a comic book cover.
And it sold right away.
And so I figured,
since it's the first cover,
and was so popular.
They even made up prints of it,
the company.
I decided to recreate it myself.
And so I did.
And that's how that came into being.
That's of course much bigger
than the cover and more interesting.
In the sense that it's big, it's in colour,
and that's how I did it.
I just copied everything
that I had in front of me,
all the detail, all the little back figures
and the lettering,
I did the best I could with it.
And it turned out good.
Well, it's dynamic.
Really dynamic and it moves.
That figure moves and he takes up
a good deal of the cover.
And of course, the lettering is big,
it's like a burst.
He's coming out of a...
Out of an explosion of some sort,
and these little figures
are just trimmings
that you can hardly see
unless you get up close.
It was a joy doing because it was
a smooth thing to do.
As a kid, I really liked that character,
precisely because I could imagine
myself in that suit.
It was fun.
When I came onto the Iron Man book,
it had been kind of...
I wouldn't say floundering,
but it had sort of lost its way
for a few years, up to that point.
It had been a kind of a step-child
for the Marvel Universe.
But it always still maintained
a certain cachet.
It was also very heavily
influenced by pop culture.
And, you know,
there was a lot of characters
going around saying they were "heavy."
"That's heavy, man. Heavy.
Can you dig it?"
These days it would be, "Whassup?"
You know...
Here's a guy
who's basically a warmonger.
A merchant of death.
Now, when the character was created,
that was not inherently a bad thing,
you know, we're talking about
in the early '60s,
before Vietnam became a disaster,
the idea of, you know,
an arms merchant
was not, by itself, a bad thing.
But, as time goes on and the war
begins to become, you know, an issue,
and something that we
as writers cannot ignore,
here you have this character
who represents the worst aspects of,
you know,
the military-industrial complex.
Now, what are you gonna do with that?
You know, you can do...
You can take it in
many different directions,
but one direction
that you might wanna take it,
if you're trying to make a hero,
is to give him an inner conflict
over the fact that he has this
place in the world.
Well, there are only a handful
of villains that stand out,
you know, in the Iron Man's
rogue gallery.
- Crimson Dynamo.
- Crimson Dynamo
and the Mandarin,
you know, being, like, the main two.
And both of them, sort of iconic
Cold War figures,
you know, the Red Star,
I think was another one.
Black Widow, you know, was
I think introduced in “on Man.
So there was this kind of Cold War
demonology going on, you know,
all the foreigners were bad
and all the Americans were good.
Well, of all of them I think
that Mandarin, you know,
spoke to me the most, because
he was sort of like the anti-Stark.
Tony is... As the richest person
in the Marvel Universe,
you can almost imagine him
sort of like the linchpin,
you know, that draws everybody
else together. It was his mansion
where the Avengers did the...
Started the Avengers.
I mean, he's the guy
who started the Avengers, in effect,
by providing them a place to stay,
you know, "Here you are."
The Avengers,
very early on, or reasonably early on,
particularly when it came to
Cap and Thor,
these guys learned who was
behind the masks or helmets
and that kind of gave Tony
a circle of peers.
A circle of people that he could
relate to on his own level.
Not necessarily
intellectually or scientifically.
S.H.I.E.L.D.,
I always felt that S.H.I.E.L.D.
was a Tony Stark creation
in some sense.
That he's the guy who put it together,
you know, or made it possible.
He certainly must have
designed the Helicarrier,
and probably sold it to them, you know?
I mean, Stark Industries was the
primary supplier of weapon technology
to the American government,
you know, for many years.
Tony's involvement in S.H.l.E.L.D.
goes right back to the beginning.
You read the very first Nick Fury story,
Nick Fury: Agent of S.H.l.E.L.D. story,
and Tony's there.
Tony's already part of S.H.l.E.L.D.,
he's designed all of their tech and stuff
and all their advanced weapons,
and all through the really early
issues of S.H.l.E.L.D.,
he kept coming back into the strip,
just as Tony Stark, inventor.
Every once in a while they'd drop
maybe a little allusion to Iron Man,
but if you weren't reading Iron Man
he was just a guy
in Nick Fury: Agent of S.H.l.E.L.D.
George Tuska is one of
the unsung heroes.
Because his work was cartoony,
in a sense,
at a time when realistic art
was in demand in comics,
people didn't take his work as seriously
as they probably ought to.
He could break a story down
as well as any of the best
comic book storytellers.
And he also drew a very dynamic
Iron Man, you know.
There was a weight and a solidity to his
version of Iron Man that I really liked.
It was the first monthly title
that I ever did
and that happened in, I think '77.
I think somebody just
up and left the company.
I was nervous and it was because
my father was working up at the office
and it was a monthly title,
and I hadn't considered
ever doing Iron Man
when I was up as a young artist.
Thought about Spider-Man
and that type of character, Daredevil.
Never thought about doing Iron Man
and it was a different type
of a character to me,
because I always had
that problem with the logistics,
the armour,
"Oh, my God. It's flexible armour."
I had this close-minded...
"That's impossible. There's gotta be
hinges somewhere, joints."
It didn't make sense. And I...
You know, you suspend belief
for the character,
and then I began to really enjoy it.
And then it blossomed into
more than what it was
because it became
a melodrama as well as a great visual.
And then, of course, he had his
personal problems, the demons,
and it became more than the simplistic
armour to save the heart
type of character.
Okay. This is the very first
complete comic I ever did
and I've been told,
over the last 30 years,
that it is the number one book
to line birdcages with.
Because of this great spot right here,
right below the little perch, right there.
Getting the first one done was probably
as good a feeling as I ever had
in anything, because you...
It's like climbing your first mountain.
You know, hitting your first home run.
I was very young,
just right out of high school, basically.
Probably the youngest guy
in the history of Marvel at the time.
I mean, there have been younger guys
since then. I think I was 19.
So getting your foot in the door
as a young guy was almost impossible.
I mean, Barry Smith had to like,
break down a ton of barriers.
He's Barry freaking Smith, you know,
one of the greatest artists in the history
of comics, in my opinion,
but even for him it wasn't easy,
and that's where I met David Michelinie.
Dave was always open immediately
for me to be involved
in helping create the stories.
He appreciated what I had to offer,
even though I was just the lowly inker,
and I started talking to him
about Iron Man, you know, which was...
From the time I was a kid,
this was the character
that I wanted to do.
I have always been a science buff.
So with Iron Man,
it was kind of that way.
I always said that, "if you can
believe the suit works,
"everything else will work."
All you gotta do is make
the suit look believable.
Make it look like it functions.
And that was really my idea going in,
was make the suit look functional.
Looking at Iron Man and saying,
"Okay, parts of him are organic,
parts of him are not."
So I just started inking him that way.
In terms of approaching Iron Man,
it was always just
making it believable to me.
I mean, people talk about
that whole Doctor Doom story,
the first Camelot thing.
I had always argued that Doctor Doom
should have been the Iron Man villain.
Not the Fantastic...
I know he belongs to the Fantastic Four,
but if there ever was a character
who was the antithesis of Tony Stark,
it was Doctor Doom.
They were the same guy
on two sides of the coin.
I mean, both monarchs,
both highly, highly educated,
you know, both very sophisticated guys.
Never were there two characters
meant to fight each other
in the history of comic books than
Doctor Doom and Iron Man, you know?
And the fact that they maintained
a mutual respect for each other,
even though they hated
what the other person stood for.
What makes Tony Stark different than
everyone else in the Marvel Universe?
And it's the world that he lives in,
that he operates in.
The corporate structure,
the world of high finance,
the world of industrial exploration.
I mean, the fact that he was a scientist
who made money off what he did.
And that's really all we tried
to do with that
was we put characters around Tony.
Each one of them served a purpose,
served a different side of Tony.
We'll drop in Jim Rhodes, he's the pilot.
And then we'll start
delving into his back story
and he was the guy
that Tony met when he was,
you know, in Southeast Asia
having just become Iron Man
who helped him get back to the States.
You know, Rhodey was that confidant,
the guy that he could trust with his life.
You know, the guy that had his back
all the time, you know,
and Beth was obviously the person
who took care of him emotionally.
Here's Tony Stark's day.
He comes in, Mrs Arbogast
hands him a piece of paper,
he signs it, a factory
goes up in New Jersey.
She comes in, hands him
a piece of paper, he signs it,
a satellite gets built.
Another piece of paper, signs it,
they close a factory in Guatemala.
You know, 10,000 people out of jobs.
He designs something,
he goes to his drawing board,
designs something,
it's sent down to the technical crew,
whatever, to the technicians,
they build it,
they do all that kind of stuff,
sales and manufacturing go to it,
he never sees the damn thing
until it's in orbit.
Who could really live that way?
It's a different set of problems,
a different track, a different...
Things like that.
That was one of the things
that I thought about with Iron Man.
This is the only character
I think you could really do that with,
where you'd start thinking about
alterations in the design
to fit specific needs and tasks.
I believe the stealth armour was the
first, but, you know, we had...
Dave and I had already discussed
several different options,
the space armour
and the undersea armour
and so forth and so on.
I'm gonna quote Dave Michelinie here,
that it was never our intention
to do anything relevant.
We were paid to, basically, do
the next episode of Iron Man.
Just that particular issue,
alcoholism was the bad guy.
Instead of Doctor Doom or
somebody like that, it was the bottle.
That was our villain of the month.
And that's really the way we treated it.
We built everything up to that,
but the point of it is, it was never...
We never attempted to be relevant.
It just... In the corporate world,
what gets to guys?
What causes the downfall?
Usually, it's greed, or
it's sex and drugs. Right?
Well, we couldn't do the sex part.
Right?
Alcohol wasn't talked
about all that much,
really, to be honest with you,
especially with kids,
you know, in that particular era.
But, you know, we treated it
as we intended to, as the bad guy.
When we set out doing
that Extremis story
we weren't even certain that it would
be a permanent thing
because on one level, it seems like
it flies in the face of the concept.
I have certainly heard from
some real hard-core Iron Man fans
of days gone by that,
no, this isn't Iron Man,
because Iron Man's whole point is
he's got a suit of armour,
he shouldn't have powers
built into himself.
But I think, you know,
two things that had gone forward is,
one, Warren Ellis is
a fantastically talented writer,
and two, Warren is Tony Stark.
Warren is so far ahead of the curve
in terms of reading up on the science,
he's so fascinated by the technology
and the way it's gonna change a society
and the way it's gonna impact
on us individually, that he just...
He just got down to the core of it.
Tony Stark as sort of...
I think the term that Warren was sort of
tossing around at the time was,
he's sort of like
the test pilot of the future.
He's there, he's the first guy there,
and he's gonna go out
and investigate all the possibilities
and see what all this stuff does
and how it affects him
and how it could affect the world
and thus in doing so, sort of,
beta-tested for everybody else.
Beyond that, it was beautifully,
digitally painted or painted by Adi,
so it had a really sophisticated,
sleek, modern look.
It was pretty successful
and it got people interested again
and the characters
started to pop a little bit
and then consequently
we went on and did Civil War
and did all the stuff
that came after that and right now...
You know, the movie notwithstanding,
Iron Man is really
poised in a position within the Marvel
line and within the Marvel Universe,
where he's like the most important
character there is.
He's the hub around
which everything circles,
and it all kind of stems,
stepping-stone wise,
from the work that Warren and Adi did.
So what happened was Joe Quesada,
the editor-in-chief of Marvel Comics,
got talking to me in email
one evening about Iron Man,
which was a character they were
putting new creative teams on
once every year or two
and it was never quite working for Joe.
This is a character who is
a test pilot for the future,
as his own redemption,
which is really the thrust behind
the Extremis graphic novel.
And Joe responded to that take
and said, "Well, off you go, then."
He was an arms dealer.
There's no two ways around it.
While that is what built his fortune,
therefore allowing him
to be a technologist,
he wasn't actually being that
at the genesis of the character.
He was just a man who made bombs.
And he's running away from that.
The only way he can look himself
in the mirror,
as far as I'm concerned,
is to be Iron Man,
is to be that figure of futurism.
After I agreed to take a shot
at Iron Man for Joe
and develop a new take,
the next thing was finding the artist.
And Joe, being Joe, already had
an artist in mind, it was Adi Granov.
A comics artist has a lot of
very strange jobs.
They're certainly the director,
to a large extent.
Cinematography is something
that's often shared
between the writer and the artist.
I created a character
called John Pillinger
who is a television journalist,
very much based on John Pilger
because in all those years
of publication,
from what I could find,
Tony Stark had very rarely been
brought up to account by the real world.
So I wanted someone there to lay it out,
both for him and the audience.
"You're an arms dealer,
that doesn't mean
"you just made a couple of bombs."
John Pillinger is there
to remind him
that somewhere in the world right now,
someone is dying because of
something he's made, and he...
They're never gonna
let him run away from it.
I really wanted to try
and ground the character.
It's less a superhero graphic novel
than it is a science fiction novel,
and that, to me, required Tony Stark
to be a real person.
He shouldn't be someone
who can just put on a costume
and fly above his concerns,
or the concerns of the world.
He's a man who
made a moral compromise in his youth.
It was simply easier and faster
to build a fortune by selling arms
than it was to do it
pretty much any other way.
When I wrote Extremis,
I moved the timeline on.
And I have Stark being
struck by shrapnel,
not in Vietnam but in a desert location
that could very well be Afghanistan.
In Iron Man: Extremis,
Tony Stark is probably not yet 30,
and he's a man passionately interested
in bringing on the future,
but he doesn't really know
what that is yet.
He's very scattered in the book.
He's working on 12 things at once,
hoping that one of them will be
the golden key
to unlocking a future
that he can live with.
That's why there are so many of us
interested in futurism.
We don't know
which path is gonna break.
We don't know which one
is going to turn out to be
the way through the woods.
The character Sal in the book
was a mentor to Tony and Maya.
The thing about Sal in the book
that makes him stand apart
from both Tony and Maya
is that he doesn't have the passion.
I think he never really had the passion,
I think that's what he admired most
in Tony and Maya.
It wasn't a huge wrench for him to just
say, "The hell with it!" to everyone.
He didn't have the passion
and need for redemption that Tony has.
I think the germ of the Extremis process
that I created for the graphic novel
was reading somewhere
a long time ago
that the human brain retains a template
of what the body should look like,
and it refers to that
when repairing wounds.
And it simply struck me that
if that could be hacked,
then you could make the body do
all kinds of interesting things.
To, some years later, a suit that he
could fold up and carry in a briefcase.
To, as you see at the start of
the graphic novel,
something that has to be
shipped in a crate,
or hangs on chains in his garage.
Very much going back to
the tank model,
which made little sense
in terms of the standard process
of technological development,
which is to make things smaller
and more effective at the same time.
So, attacking it from that aspect,
and constantly keeping the title
of the thing in mind,
it seemed to me to only make sense,
if he was wearing the Iron Man suit,
if you like, at all times,
that he became an iron man.
That a large amount of the suit itself
was stored inside his body,
using what you presume is some kind of
nanotechnological process.
So it actually fulfils physical functions
as well as laying their own potential
inside his body.
So, yeah, the Iron Man suit
is mostly contained inside his bones.
With Extremis it was my job
to reboot the character,
to reinvent the character
and present new situations
and conflicts for him,
Which I think the book did.
I think probably the favourite part
in Extremis for me
is in the second issue, when
Mallen walks into the FBI building
and I think that's where I really
hit my stride as a storyteller.
I think that's when I started feeling
comfortable with
just telling or choreographing scenes
and I think the action in it
came out quite good.
The way I approached the design
of the suit, in Extremis particularly, is
I kind of tried to add realism to my art,
so it looks like
something could actually,
you know, with suspension of disbelief,
actually function.
Before our book, the suit was actually
always in a briefcase.
But then we thought,
when we did Extremis,
how can you fit this giant suit
into a briefcase?
It just makes no sense.
So it was outside of a briefcase,
it was actually in a giant crate
that would be shipped
wherever he needed it,
but then when he actually
injects himself,
then he uses this new suit
which is much smaller.
Then I started thinking
about memory metals,
so it can be folded.
This is the kind of stuff
that I really think about.
So, memory metals
so you could fold the suit
and fit it in a suitcase
and then because he had
some kind of power, magnetic powers,
he could actually manoeuvre the suit
around him to actually fit onto him.
Well, basically, first time
Warren Ellis and I met, it was...
I think I was working on whichever issue
came before that,
I think it was issue number three.
And I was telling him how much I like
the original grey Iron Man armour,
'cause it's just a clunky tank
type of a thing,
and a few weeks later I get the script
and he's written that scene into it
because, and this is what he said,
that he wrote it because
I liked that suit so much.
I am an illustrator before anything else,
and I try to come up with
striking images, at least in my opinion,
and I try to compose images
that will tell a story in a certain way.
And when it comes to doing
sequential art, to comic book pages,
I try to serve the story
before creating beautiful images.
But I try to create beautiful images
at the same time, if that makes sense.
Iron Man in Civil War,
and ultimately Civil War is a story about
Captain America and Iron Man,
and to a lesser degree
about Spider-Man
as sort of the third, lower point
on that triangle,
and it was that from the very beginning
as the story started to crystallise
and the basic themes
of freedom versus security
kind of played themselves out.
Those two characters, because they're
so central to the mythos of Marvel
and they're both so central
to the Avengers
and the superhuman community.
This is a character who'll do
whatever needs to be done
and take the weight on himself,
that seemed to be a pretty interesting
place to put him in, in Civil War,
and to some degree a surprising place,
because again, the knee-jerk is
Cap'll be the guy that toes the line
and Iron Man will not.
As the story played out
and as we figured it out,
we got to the end where ultimately
it's gotta be the pro-registration side
that comes out on top.
And somewhere along the line there,
one of us had the notion of,
"Okay, where's that gonna leave us?"
"Let's put Tony
in charge of S.H.l.E.L.D."
That puts him
in another interesting place.
It's like running a company,
but completely different,
because it's
a worldwide peacekeeping force,
it's more military-oriented,
but a lot of the same skills
that he brings to running a company
on an economic level
can be played out
against this larger-scale thing.
Tony became more and more
the centre point, even beyond Cw“ War,
all the stuff we were doing after that,
because he was the guy in charge,
he was the man with the plan
or the guy with the vision,
and the guy that across the course
of doing these things,
putting these plans into place
and running into conﬂict with guys
that were his friends,
did things that he knew were tough.
Tony Stark is
a very difficult character to write,
because he's a lot smarter than any
writer who's ever going to tackle him.
None of us can claim to know
how to create anything technical,
you know, we're totally faking it.
He's also
a much more sophisticated character.
His lifestyle, his background.
I don't know any comic book writers
that are trust-fund babies,
that really know that side of society.
I mean, it's all gotta
come out of our heads.
He's a tough character to write
in that sense.
But it's also a lot of fun.
The Inevitable came out of the relaunch
that Warren Ellis and Adi Granov did,
which was a great relaunch, but they
weren't using any of his villains,
they weren't using
any of his rogues gallery,
and Iron Man has
a great rogues gallery.
And those villains specifically,
if I could've jammed more villains
into that story, I would have,
but three seemed to be the limit.
But I loved those characters.
Iron Man has a very specific
kind of rogues gallery.
They're also technologically based.
Whether it's the Living Laser, from...
Or the Ghost, with his stealth suit,
or Spymaster, who's sort of
the industrial espionage side
of an Iron Man story
that's also very interesting to me.
So I wanted to bring back those
characters for a modern audience.
The way I tell these stories, whenever
I'm doing a, sort of, historical tale,
is, I always, in my mind,
set them in the present.
Write them as though
they're happening right now.
There's a rule of thumb
with comic books.
It doesn't matter when it came out,
whenever you're reading it,
it's happening right now.
That's why comics are written
in the present tense.
Narrative captions are written
in the present tense,
because when you're reading a comic,
the idea is it's happening right now.
So my feeling was
the Mandarin is
Iron Man's quintessential enemy.
His opposite number.
Magic versus mechanical.
Technology versus mysticism.
It's a great opposite number pairing.
But their first encounters
didn't have a lot of mythic power.
They were one in a series of stories
that were being told at the time.
I don't think anyone knew that
the Mandarin would grow into
Iron Man's quintessential foe.
Eric Canete, I've known him for years,
we worked together in comics
a couple of times
when he was first breaking in,
and always loved his work,
but it was so technically precise
and it was kind of
a Jeff Darrow thing going on.
I just thought, "Man, you know,
this guy is made to draw Iron Man."
What I didn't expect,
what he did inject with the work,
is this life, this movement,
that comes from his years in animation.
At the moment, Dan and Charlie Knauf
are writing Iron Man.
Dan was the creator of Carnivale,
the television series,
and does a lot of writing there,
and Charlie is his son,
a young and up-and-coming
screenwriter and comic book writer.
They sort of picked up the baton
from where Warren had left it
and have carried it forward, doing all of
the Civil War connectivity stuff and all
of the Iron Man: Director of S.H.l.E.L.D.
arc, and all of this sort of thing.
The Knaufs really brought in
a very real-world espionage
kind of flavour to Iron Man,
which I think was really fantastic,
and a real-world sort of tech...
You can definitely feel the weight of
the world on Tony Stark
and on the Marvel Universe
within their stories,
so they've just done a great job of it.
They really are writing it
like a TV show.
When I was doing Carnivale, I turned on
some of my staff to graphic novels.
I said, "I want you to read these
"to sort of get a sense of
the type of storytelling."
And after Carnivale ran its course,
we got a call from...
Actually it was a friend of mine
who said,
"Hey, I was talking to a guy,
he's at Marvel,
"they really want you
to do a comic book."
And I talked to them and they said,
"Yeah, you know,
we'd love for you to do it."
it was funny because he...
They offer him this thing
and he calls me up, and I know this
because he calls me up on April 1st,
and, you know, I've been reading
comic books since I was a kid.
And he calls me up on April 1st,
he goes, "Hey, Charlie,
"are you interested in doing
a comic book with me for Marvel?"
And I go, you know,
"Shut the F up, man! This is a joke.
"Why are you
messing with me like this?"
He goes, "No, no..." I know,
this would be typical him, right?
And he goes, "No, no, I am serious,"
and, you know, after I
changed my pants, I called him back
and we sat down and we discussed,
and what was the criteria you said?
"No... I wanna do a character..."
No, no, no, they said, "Do you want
to do one of our characters?"
And I said, "Well, you know,
I'd really like to do
"one of your characters that's not...
That's underperforming.
"I'd really like you to find me a character
that's underperforming,
"and I'd like one that's
a little bit morally ambivalent."
And... "Well, how about...
Which one would you..."
I said, "Well,
my first choice would be Iron Man."
I thought, "Well,
they won't give me Iron Man."
Then they called back, said,
"Yeah, we'd love you to do Iron Man."
And I said, "Well, okay,
if I'm gonna do it,
"I have to do it with my son,
"because I'm so out of touch
with superhero books
"and he knows the idiom inside out."
And I also knew that I had my plate full
with television and film projects.
I knew Charlie was talented.
It was a little bit of a leap,
it was a little scary.
I knew I had the craft to help him
with his scene work
and I knew he knew the ins and outs
and what you can and can't do
with a comic book.
- So he does all the first drafts.
- Yeah.
So he carries the... You know,
he does the heavy lifting,
which is looking at a blank page
and then...
- We break story together.
- Yeah.
We'll break story,
then he'll do the first draft,
then I'll sit down
and we'll sit at the typewriter
and work together.
And when I'm making changes,
he's learning bits and pieces of craft
that I more or less
had to learn by myself.
It was sort of nerve-wracking,
because l thought
"What if he has no talent?"
- Yeah.
- What if he can't do it?
And then how do I deal with that?
And I certainly didn't want to be
sitting there and carrying him.
Now, I had the advantage of having
worked with my father at one time,
in a very different business,
but I understood
the psychological aspects of it.
So I'd tread that minefield before,
so I knew...
I know where there's warning signs.
But, no, he was able to
pick it up right away.
You can't teach talent.
That's the only thing you can't teach.
When we came in,
we just wanted to write a kick-ass book.
We wanted to write a book that works.
But I think when we came in with...
It would be the height of hubris.
I mean, look, Warren Ellis is a master.
I'm not gonna follow Warren Ellis in...
I mean, it's like everything he gave us
in Extremis was a gift.
Execute Program, you could see
the curve as we were moving through it.
Like, the earlier issues, when we got
to the later issues, we were going...
You know?
They said, "Just finish your story,
"you're going to be well into Civil War
by the time you finish."
So we kept track of
what was going on with Civil War,
and we really saw Tony
as being Lincolnesque.
We were... When we looked at
registration as an issue, if it was real,
absolutely!
And really, again, I think the idea is
that we saw him as
almost Abraham Lincoln.
That he's behind a cause
that's costing lives, that's unpopular,
that's costing friendships,
but he sticks to his guns.
From what I understand
from talking to artists,
it's difficult to have expressions
with a lot of these superheroes,
especially with iron Man,
he's got this big iron mask on.
Yeah, we always go,
"Go in close to the eye slit."
Yeah, what we really like
about both Patrick and Rob
is that their expressions are so good.
Granted, with Iron Man
we have to get in close,
like he said, get in
close to the iron slit.
Rob had this great scene
in one of our issues
where Maria looks up and she says,
"What's your E.T.A.?"
And he goes, "Right freaking now!"
and flies over Maria,
and he's got this great shot
of her looking up,
and her eyes are,
"What the hell's going on?"
I think that's really important.
What I like about Iron Man and
Tony Stark, what really works for me...
Actually, when I'm drawing Iron Man,
I enjoy drawing the Tony Stark scenes
more than I do the Iron Man ones.
So many of Marvel's characters are
irradiated and become a monster,
or bit by a spider or cosmic rays,
and Iron Man was...
I don't know if you can say you identify
with a guy who's a handsome billionaire
who gets all the ladies,
but he was still a real guy
and he's a self-made superhero.
He's a superhero 'cause he wants to be,
because he...
He's the engineer as a superhero.
He's superhero by design.
That's unique. I love that.
The double-edged sword
of drawing Iron Man was
on the one hand you had these
supporting characters and Tony Stark
who were very emotive and going
through extreme emotional strain,
and on the other hand you had to draw
a guy with a face plate,
whose emotions were hidden
beneath the armour.
I mean, I enjoy
the emotional aspects of it.
With Maya and Sal,
I thought the Knaufs did a wonderful job
with those characters.
Some of my favourite scenes were
what was going on with them.
And I don't know if Daniel
was ever aware of this,
but from some pictures online
I saw of him
I started to base my drawings of Sal
off of how he actually looked.
I mean, I actually think maybe Daniel
might be even more extreme-looking.
I think the picture I saw, he had a beret
and some braids in his beard,
but definitely there was
a Bohemian approach to Sal
that I picked up on
from just what I knew about Dan.
When you're doing
something like Iron Man's armour,
and you have to draw sideways, front,
back, forward,
in comics you draw
every conceivable angle.
Not having that full field of information
by accident will bring about
a style of your own.
Fortunately there are enough people
out there still
that just love the beauty
of a line approach, you know,
as opposed to photorealism.
Colour-wise, I was really looking
for more of a pastel look
so that the openness and
the simple lines would come out more.
When I was first offered
the assignment,
I was actually out on vacation
with my family
and my editor called on her cell phone
and said,
"How would you like to do Iron Man?"
And right away I want to scream,
"Are you kidding? Yeah, of course."
And she told me that
the Knaufs would be writing it
and that they had done
Carnivale for HBO,
and it just got better and better
as far as I was concerned.
To me great comics
start with great stories.
And these guys, I knew,
were going to write great stories.
When I think about the project,
I remember there was an awful lot
of research about actual places.
If they say "London," they don't just say
"London," it's Piccadilly Circle, it's...
There's a library, a specific library
I had to draw a research scene in.
There are a lot of places like that,
where they used exact locations.
So, are you ready to go?
This is my daughter, Genevieve,
and she wanted to get on this DVD, too,
so she did a drawing of Iron Man.
As you can see,
the Kuberts and the Romitas
have something to look out for, here.
I think it's pretty impressive, myself.
- What do you think?
- I think it's good, too.
Great.
- So, Genevieve, how old are you?
- I'm eight.
And how long did it take you to do this?
You spent a couple of hours on it
last night.
Yeah, a couple of hours, pretty much.
She came in, said,
"I wanna draw something."
I said, "Well, why don't you draw
one of the characters Daddy draws?"
- Then I said, "Yes."
- Yeah, so...
- Do you like Iron Man?
- Yeah, he's cool.
I've just written a serial
called Ultimate Human.
And this is a whole other
kettle of worms entirely,
because it's what they call
the Ultimate version of Tony Stark,
and the idea was that
the Ultimate books
would represent all these old characters
as if they were new once again,
to introduce an entirely new generation
to the properties,
one of whom, of course,
is Tony Stark, Iron Man.
Ultimate Human presents what I refer to
as "Ultimate Iron Man"
and "Ultimate Hulk."
These two characters have been
re-envisioned for this new line of books,
so I found myself
writing Tony Stark again.
The Tony Stark of
the Marvel Ultimate line
is a cheerful drunk
who has a brain tumour
the size of a golf ball, oddly enough,
smells of chemotherapy drugs,
needs a team of at least eight people
to load him into his Iron Man suit.
It's a very different take
on the character.
It wasn't mine, 'cause that Iron Man was
developed by a writer called Mark Millar.
Ultimate Human, as I say, presents
these two characters together.
In that universe, their Bruce Banner,
their Hulk,
is someone who became the Hulk after
taking a flawed chemical process
that would make him superhuman,
whereas their Tony Stark
is a full-bore futurist.
This is a man who plans
10 years into the future,
and the Iron Man suit is very much
part of a grander game,
a broader plan than anyone
really knows the extent of.
So they both...
They both come from the intent
of developing superhuman abilities,
and they've both in their own ways
gone horribly wrong.
What is it about Iron Man? He's a
character that can be reinterpreted
for each new generation
in a way that
more iconic characters can't.
I think what makes Tony Stark
so interesting to me
is that I happen to really love
conflicted characters,
I love characters that have,
sort of, a dark edge to them,
that they sort of walk that line,
that if they go a little bit to the left
they may be in the dark, or in the light,
and that really appeals to me.
And the fact that he's just so smart
and so Machiavellian,
not unlike myself, actually.
That really attracts me to the character,
he's not just a cookie-cutter
superhero or hero.
He's a guy with a bit of a past
and a bit of an edge to him.
Iron Man is a very conscious superhero.
His creation was very conscious.
He had to do it, you know?
And it's a conscious choice
to continue to be Iron Man.
I mean, I'm talking about
just the original premise
of he has the heart problem,
he needs to wear the chest plate.
He could've come back
from that captivity
and simply worn the chest piece,
gone on as Tony Stark,
and just gone on with his life.
But he made a conscious choice
to keep going as Iron Man.
He saw some kind of
greater good in continuing on with that.
It wasn't about the armour,
it was about the guy inside.
And that was always
what the stories were about,
the guy inside.