It's been a while since I was
up here in front of you
maybe i'll stick to the cards
There's been speculation that I was involved in the
events that occurred on the freeway and the rooftop.
I'm sorry, Mr. Stark, but do you
honestly expect us to believe that
that was bodyguard in a suit
that conveniently appeared, despite the fact
that you historically despise bodyguards?
Yes.
And this mysterious bodyguard was...
somehow equipped with...
an undisclosed Stark high-tech
powered battle suit?
I know that it's confusing.
It is one thing
to question the official story
and another thing entirely to make wild
accusations or insinuate that I'm a superhero.
I mean, let's face it I'm not,
the heroic type.
I've a laundry list of character defects,
all the mistakes that I've made...
largely public.
The truth is...
I am Iron Man.
Ivan...
Ivan?
That should be you.
Do not listen to these morons.
I'm sorry.
I can only offer you
my knowledge.
Iron Man stabilizes East-West relations
7-0 at 30 knots.
Holding steady at 15000 feet.
You are clear for exfiltration
over the drop zone.
Six months later
It's good to be back!
You missed me.
- Blow something up!
- Blow something up?
I already did that.
I'm not saying that the
world is enjoying...
its longest period of
uninterrupted peace in years...
because of me.
I'm not saying...
that from the ashes of captivity...
never has a greater Phoenix metaphor
been personified in human history.
I'm not saying...
that Uncle Sam can kick back
on a lawn chair,...
sipping on iced tea,...
because I haven't come across anyone
who's man enough...
to go toe to toe with me
on my best day!
- I love you Tony!
- Please. It's not about me.
It's not about you.
It's not even about us.
It's about legacy.
It's about what we choose to leave behind
for future generations.
And that's why for the next year...
and for the first time since 1974,...
the best and brightest men and women
of nations and corporations
the world over...
will pool their resources
share their collective vision,
to leave behind
a brighter future.
It's not about us!
Therefore, what I am saying,
if I'm saying anything,
is welcome back to the Stark Expo!
Now, making a special guest appearance
from the great beyond,
to tell you what it's all about,
please welcome my father, Howard.
Everything is achievable
through technology.
Better living.
Robust health.
And for the first time in human history,
the possibility of world peace.
So from all of us here at Stark Industries,
I would like to personally introduce you to
The city of the future.
Technology holds infinite possibilities
for mankind.
Blood toxicity 19%
soon, technology will affect
the way you live your life every day.
No more tedious work,
leaving more time,
leisure activities
and enjoying sweet life.
The Stark Expo.
Welcome.
We are coming to you live from the kick-off
of the Stark Expo
where Tony Stark
has just walked onstage.
Don't worry if you can't
make it down here now,
because this expo goes on all year long.
And I'm gonna be here checking out
all the attractions
and the pavillions and the inventions
from all around the world.
It's a zoo out there, watch out alright.
Open up. Let's go.
Nice to see you, alright.
Thank you.
I remember you.
- Call me.
- Hey, come on...
Hi there, dear friend.
It'll be a pleasure.
- See ya buddy.
- This is Larry.
The oracle of goracle.
What a pleasure, nice to see you.
Call me.
- Larry King.
- Larry!
Yes, my people, my people.
- Did it go pretty mellow?
- It wasn't so bad.
- No, it's perfect.
Look what we got here,
the new model.
- Hey, does she come with the car?
- I certainly hope so.
Hi. And you are?
- Marshall. - Irish. I like it.
- Pleased to meet you Tony
I'm on the wheel, you mind?
- Where you from?
- Bedford.
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for you.
Yeah? You found me.
- What are you up to later?
- Serving subpoenas.
Yikes.
- He doesn't like to be handed things.
- Yeah I have a peeve.
You are hereby ordered to appear before
the Senate Armed Services Committee
tomorrow morning at 9 am.
- Can I see a badge?
- You wanna see the badge? - He likes the badge.
- You still like it?
- Yup.
- How far are we from D.C.?
- D.C.?
250 miles.
Mr. Stark, can we pick up now
where we left off?
Mr. Stark?
- Please.
- Yes, dear?
- Can I have your attention?
- Absolutely.
Do you or do you not possess
a specialized weapon?
- I do not.
- You do not?
- I do not, well it depends how you define
the word weapon. - The Iron Man weapon.
My device does not fit
that description.
- Well, how would you describe your..?
- I would describe it by defining it as what it is, sir.
- As?
- It's a high-tech prosthesis.
That is, that's actually the most
apt description I could make of it.
- It's a weapon Mr Stark I hate to inform you it's a weapon.
- Please, if your priority was actually the well-being...
My priority is to get the Iron Man weapon turned
over to the people of the United States of America.
Well, you can forget it.
I am Iron Man.
The suit and I are one.
To turn over the Iron Man suit would be
to turn over myself, which is tantamount to
indentured servitude or prostitution
depending on what state you're in.
- I can't have it.
- Look, I am no expert.
In prostitution? Of course not,
you're a senator, come on!
I'm not an expert in weapons.
But we have somebody here who is an expert on weapons.
I would now like to call Justin Hammer
Our current primary weapons contractor.
Let the record reflect that I observe
Mr. Hammer entering the chamber
and I am wondering...
if and when any
actual expert will also be in attendance.
Absolutely. I am no expert.
I defer to you, Anthony.
You're the wonder boy.
Senator, if I may...
I may well not be an expert,
but you know who was the expert?
Your dad!
Howard Stark.
Really a father to us all.
And to the millitary-industrial age.
Let's just be clear, he was no flower child.
He was a lion.
We all know why we are here:
In the last six months,
Anthony Stark has created
a sword with untold possibilities.
And yet I insists it's a shield.
He asks us to trust him
as we cower behind it.
I wish I were comforted, Anthony.
I really do.
I'd like to leave my door unlocked
when I leave the house,
but this ain't Canada.
You know we live in a world
of grave threats,
threats that Mr. Stark
will not always be able to foresee.
Thank you. God bless
Iron Man, God bless America.
Well said, Mr. Hammer.
The committee would now like to invite
Lieut. Col. James Rhodes to the chamber.
Rhodey?
Hey, buddy. Didn't expect
to see you here.
Look, it's me. I'm here. Deal with it.
Let's move on.
- I just...
- Drop it. - Alright, I'll drop it.
I have before me a complete report on
the Iron Man weapon
compiled by Colonel Rhodes.
And Colonel, for the record,
can you please read page 57, paragraph 4?
You're requesting that I read specific
selections from my report, senator?
Yes, sir.
My understanding that I was going to be testifying
in a much more comprehensive and detailed manner.
I understand, a lot of
things have changed today.
You do understand that reading a single paragraph out
of context does not reflect the summary of my finding?
Just read it, Colonel. I do. Thank you.
Very well.
As he does not operate within any
definable branch of government,
The Iron Man presents a potential threat
to the security of both the nation
and to her interests.
I did, however, go on to summarize that the
benefits of Iron Man far outweigh the liabilities
and that it would be in our interest
to fold Mr Stark into the existing
chain of command.
I'm not a joiner but I'll consider
Secretary of Defense, if you ask nice.
We can amend the hours a little bit.
I'd like to go on and show, if I may, the
imagery that's connected to your report.
I believe it is somewhat premature to reveal
these images to the general public at this time.
With all due respect, Colonel, I understand.
And if you could just narrate those for us,
we'd be very grateful.
Show the images.
Intelligence suggests that the
devices seen in these photos
are in fact attempts at
making manned copies
of Mr. Stark's suit.
This has been corroborated by our allies
and local intelligence on the ground
indicating that these suits are
quite possibly at this moment operational.
Hold on a second buddy, let me see.
There's something here.
Oh, boy I'm good.
Now can I get more screens.
I need them.
Time for a little transparency.
- Let's see what's really going on.
- What is he doing?
If you'll direct your
attention to said screens,
I believe that's North Korea.
Can you turn that off? Take it off.
Iran.
No grave, immediate threat here.
Is that Justin Hammer?
How did Hammer get in here?
Justin, you're on TV, focus up.
Wow. Yeah, I'd say most
countries, 5-10 years away.
- Hammer Industries 20.
- I'd like to point out that that test pilot survived.
I think we got the point that he's making.
I don't think there's any reason...
The point is you're welcome, I guess.
- For what?
- Because, I'm your nuclear deterrent.
It's working. We're safe.
America is secure.
You want my property?
You can't have it!
But did I you a big favor.
I've successfully privatized world peace.
What more do you want?
For now!
I'm tired of all of these ass clowns!
flap you Mr Stark.
flap you buddy.
- We're adjourned, we're adjourned for today.
- Okay
You've been a delight.
My bond is with the people.
And I will serve this great nation
at the pleasure of myself.
One thing I've proven
is that you can count on me...
to pleasure myself.
- Wake up, daddy's home.
- Welcome home, sir.
Congratulations on the opening ceremonies.
They were such a success.
As was your Senate hearing.
And may I say how refreshing it is to finally
see you in a video with your clothing on, sir?
You!
I swear to god I'll dismantle you, I'll switch
your motherboard and turn you into wine rack.
How many ounces a day of this gargle
am I supposed to drink?
We are up to 80 ounces a day
to counteract the symptoms, sir.
Check palladium levels.
Blood toxicity: 24%
It appears that the continued use of the Iron
Man suit is accelerating your condition.
Another core has been depleted.
God, they're running out quick.
I have run simulations
on every known element
and none can serve as a viable
replacement for the palladium core.
You are running out of both time
and options.
Unfortunately, the device that's keeping
you alive, is also killing you.
Ms. Potts is approaching.
I recommended that you inform her of...
Mute.
Is this a joke?
What are you thinking?
- What?
- What are you thinking?
Hey, I'm thinking I'm busy
and you're angry about something.
Do you have the sniffles? I don't wanna get sick.
Keep your distance
Did you just donate our entire
modern art collection to the...
- Boy Scouts of America?
- Yes it is a...
worthwhile organization.
I didn't physically check the crates,
but basically yes.
And it's not our collection,
it's my collection. No offense.
No, you know what I think I'm actually
entitled to say Our collection,
considering the time that I've put in
over 10 years curating that.
It's a tax write-off, I needed that.
You know, there's only about 8,011 things
that I really need to talk to you about.
Dummy, hey stop now the bridgeport's
already machining that part.
The expo is a gigantic waste of time.
- I need you to wear a surgical mask until you're
feeling better is that okay? - That's rude.
There's nothing more important
to me than the Expo.
It's my primary point of concern.
I don't know why you...
The Expo is your ego gone crazy.
Wow, look at that.
That's modern art.
That's going up.
- You've got to be kidding me.
- I'm gonna put this up right now.
Stark is in complete disarray.
Do you understand that?
No, our stocks have never been higher...
- Yes from a managerial standpoint.
- Well if it's messy, then let's double back. Let's move on to another subject.
Oh, no no no, you are not taking down the
Barnett Newman and hanging that up!
I'm not taking it down, I'm just replacing
it with this, let's see where I can get...
Ok fine. My point is
We have already awarded contracts
to the windfarm people,
Don't say windfarm, I'm
already feeling gassy.
And to the Plastic Plantation Tree,
which was your idea by the way.
- Those people are on payroll, and you won't make a decision.
- Everything was my idea,
I don't care about the
liberal agenda anymore.
It's boring, boring!
I'm giving you a boring order,
you do it.
I do what?
Excellent idea, I just figured this out.
You run the company.
- Yeah, i'm trying to run the company.
- Pepper, I need you to run the company.
- Well stop trying to do it and do it.
- You will not give me the information that I need
- I need you to do it.
- I am trying to do it but...
You're not listening to me.
I'm trying to make you CEO.
Why won't you let me?
Have you been drinking?
Uh, chlorophyl.
I hereby irrevocably appoint you
Chairman and CEO
of Stark Industries effective immediately.
Yeah, done deal.
Actually, I've given this
a fair amount of thought.
Believe it or not. Been doing a bit of
a headhunting so to speak...
trying to figure out who
a worthy successor would be.
And then I realized...
it's you.
It's always been you.
I thought there'd be a legal issue,
but actually
I'm capable of appointing my successor,
my successor being you.
Congratulations!
Take it, just take it.
- I don't know what to think.
- Don't think, drink.
Notary is here! Can you please come
sign the transfer paperworks?
I'm on Happy's count!
- Sorry.
- What the hell was that?
It's called mixed martial arts.
It's been around for three weeks.
It's called dirty boxing.
There's nothing new about it.
I promise you this is the only time
I will ask you to sign over your company.
I need you to initial each box.
Lesson one:
Never take your eye off...
That's it I'm done.
- What's your name, lady?
- Rushman, Natalie Rushman.
Front and center, come in to the church.
- No, you're seriously not gonna...
- If it pleases the Court, which it does.
- No problem.
- I'm sorry. He's very eccentric.
What?
- Can you give her a lesson?
- No problem.
What?
Who is she?
She is from legal and she is potentially
a very expensive sexual harassment lawsuit
- if you keep ogling her like that.
- I need an assistant boxer. I need an assistant.
Yes, and I have three excellent potential
candidates that are lined up and ready to beat you.
- I don't have time to meet. I need someone
now I feel like it's her. - No it's not.
- You ever boxed before?
- I have, yes.
Like Tae Bo, booty boot camp, crunch,
something like that?
- How do we spell your name Natalie?
- R-U-S-H-M-A-N.
- What are you gonna google her now?
- I thought I was ogling her.
- Oh wow. Very, very impressive individual...
- You're so predictable, you know that?
She's fluent in French,
Italian, Russian, Latin...
Who speaks Latin?
No one speaks Latin. It's a dead language.
You can read Latin or you can write,
but you can't speak Latin so...
- Did you model in Tokyo?
Cause she modelled in Tokyo. - No.
I need her, she's got
everything that I need.
Rule number one: Never take your eye off
your opponent.
Oh my God!
- Happy!
- That's what I'm talking about.
- I slipped.
- You did?
Looks like a TKO to me.
- Just, um, I need your impression.
- You have quite reserved, I don't know...
- I meant your fingerprints.
- Right.
- So, how're we doing?
- Great. Just half done,... hey.
You're the boss.
Will that be all, Mr. Stark?
- No.
- Yes.
That will be all, Ms. Rushman.
Thank you very much.
- I want one.
- No.
Welcome to the Historic Grand Prix
of Monaco.
This year's race will be exciting...
It's Europe, whatever happens the next
twenty minutes just go with it.
- Mr. Stark?
- Hey
- How was your flight?
- It was excellent.
- Oh it's nice to see you.
- We have one photographer from the ACM if you don't mind.
- When did this happen?
- You made me do it.
- I made you do what?
- Smile and you. Look there.
Stop acting constipated.
- You are so predictable.
- Do not inflate your nostrils.
- Right this way.
- Thanks, you look fantastic.
- Why thank you very much.
- But that's unprofessional. What's on the docket?
We have a 9.30 dinner.
- Perfect I'll be there at 11. Is this ours?
- It can be.
Great, make it ours.
Mr. Musk, how are you?
- Congratulations on the promotion.
- Thank you very much.
Elon, those Merlin engines
are fantastic.
Thanks. I got an idea
for an electric jet.
You do? Then we'll make it work.
- You want a massage? - Oh god no I don't want a massage.
- I'll have Natalie make an appointment.
I do not want Natalie to do anything.
- By the way I didn't mean to spring this on you.
- Thank you very much.
Green is not your best color.
Anthony, is that you?
My least favorite person on earth,
Justin Hammer. - How you doing?
You're not the only rich guy here
with a fancy car.
You know Christine Everhart
from Vanity Fair? You guys know each other?
- Hi.
- Yes.
- Yes!
- Yes, roughly.
BTW, big story,
The new CEO of Stark Industries.
- Congratulations.
- My editor will kill me...
if I don't grab a quote
for our Powerful Women issue.
- Oh.
- Can I?
- Sure.
She's actually doing a big spread on me
for Vanity Fair.
- I am.
- I thought I'd throw her a bone, you know.
She did quite a spread on
Tony last year.
- And she wrote a story as well.
- It was very impressive.
- That was good.
- Very well done.
- I'm gonna go wash.
- Do not leave me.
- How you doing? You look great.
- Please, this is hard.
- So is this the first time that...
- Oh, god that's so awful.
Listen, it's the first time you've
seen each other since the Senate?
- Since he got his contract revoked.
- Actually, it's on hold.
That's not what I heard.
What's the difference between
on hold and canceled? The truth?
No. The truth is, oh put that away,
The truth is I'm actually hoping to
present something at your expo.
Well, if you invent something that works,
I'll make sure I get you a slot.
- Mr. Stark?
- Yes.
- He's kidding,...
- Your corner table is ready.
- I actually have a slot, yes I do.
- Hammer needs a 'slot.'
- We'll give him. - We kid, we're kidders.
Got any other bad ideas?
Tony and I, Tony,
I love Tony Stark.
Tony loves me.
We're not competitors.
Him being out of the picture created tremendous
opportunity for Hammer Industries you know.
Everything that Tony and
I do is a healthy...
What's the use of having and owning
a race car,
competition.
if you don't drive it?
Is he driving?
Natalie! Natalie!
- Yes?
- Did you know about this?
This is the first time I hear it.
- That cannot happen.
- Absolutely, I understand. How can I help you?
- Where is Happy?
- He's waiting outside.
- Ok get him, I need Happy.
- Right away.
Tony is, we're, you know...
We're not competitive.
You know what I mean?
You know what?
Can you excuse me just one second?
- Why don't you just read me what you wrote?
- I will.
- After I make one quick phone call.
- Where are you going?
- I got some caviar coming.
- This is great stuff, I'll be right back!
That asshole just goes inside the track!
God!
Go, go!
Hang on!
- Give me the case.
- Here, take it.
- Where is the key!
- It's in my pocket.
Car!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Were you heading for me or him?
- I wanted to scare him.
- Cause I can't tell!
- Are you out of your mind?
- Better security.
- Get in the car!
- I was attacked!
- You're a jerk!
- We need better security.
- Get in the car!
Better security measures!
God it's embarrassing.
First vacation in two years.
Oh my god!
- I got him!
- Hit him again, hit him again!
Give me the case.
- I hit him!
- Give me the case!
Give him the case!
Oh, god!
Give me the case! Please!
Come on!
You'll lose!
You'll lose. You'll lose, Stark.
We've checked his fingerprints. Nothing.
Not even a name.
- Where are we going?
- There.
He may not understand us.
In fact, he has not even spoken.
Five minutes.
Pretty decent tech. Cycles
per second were a little low.
You could double up your rotations,
You focused the Repulsor energy
through ionized plasma channels.
Effective.
Not very efficient.
But it's passable enough though.
I don't get it. With a little fine tuning
you could've made a solid paycheck,
if you sold it to North Korea,
China,
Iran, or gone right to
the black market.
You look like you got
friends in low places.
You come from a
family of thieves and butchers.
And now, like all guilty men,
try to rewrite your own history
and you forget all the lives
that Stark family has destroyed.
Speaking of thieves,
where did you get this design?
My father.
Anton Vanko.
Well I've never heard of him.
My father is the reason you're alive.
The reason I'm alive is cause you had
a shot, you took it and you missed.
Did I?
If you can make god bleed
people will cease to believe him.
And there will be blood in the water.
And the sharks will come.
The truth, all they have
to do is sit and watch
as the world will consume you.
Where will you be watching the world
consume me from?
That's right.
A prison cell.
I'll send you a bar of soap.
Hey Tony, before you go,
palladium in the chest,
painful way to die.
It's just unbelievable it proves
the genie is out of the bottle
and this man
has no idea what he's doing
He thinks of the Iron Man
weapon as a toy.
I was at a hearing where
Mr. Stark in fact was adamant
that these suits can't exist,
anywhere else, don't exist anywhere else,
never will exist anywhere else
at least for 5-10 years
and here we are in Monaco
realizing, uh-oh, these suits exist now
Mute.
He should be giving me a medal.
That's the truth.
What is that?
This is your in-flight meal.
- Did you just make that?
- Yeah.
Where do you think I've
been for three hours?
Tony...
What are you not telling me?
I don't want to go home...
at all.
Let's cancel
my birthday party and
We're in Europe.
Let's go to Venice, Chipriani.
- Remember?
- Oh yes.
It's a great place to...
be healthy.
I don't think this is the right time.
We are in a kind of a mess.
Yeah but maybe that's
why it's the best time.
Wow, I think as the CEO I need to
show up. - As CEO
you are entitled to a
- leave?
- Company retreat.
A retreat? During a time like this?
I'm just saying to recharge our batteries
and figure it all out.
Not everybody runs on batteries, Tony.
Have fun with the Püree
Prisoner stop!
What are you doing?
Hey, here he is!
There he is!
What an absolute pleasure.
Welcome.
Goodness gracious, can we get the handcuffs
off my friend here?
Forgive me, I'm sorry.
I'm such a huge fan of yours.
I didn't wanna...
make a first impression like this.
He's not an animal. Come on.
He's a human being.
Thank you.
Leave us.
Oui, oui, I'm fine.
My name is Justin Hammer.
I'd like to do some business with you.
Please sit.
Dig in.
What do we have today, Jack?
Some salmon carpaccio, sir.
Salmon carpaccio?
Anything you want here, we got it.
I like my dessert first.
I had this flown in from
San Francisco.
It's Italian though.
Organic ice cream.
I got a sweet tooth.
Apparently you do too
for Tony Stark.
When I saw what you do to
Tony Stark on that track
how you stepped up to him in front of
god and everybody,
that was wow!
You spoke to me was what you did.
And I know that you knew that
I'd be listening.
This is why I couldn't bear to have
you shipped off to god knows where.
It would've been such a waste of talent.
But if I might make a suggestion you know
you don't just go
and try to kill the guy. I think...
if I may,
you go after his legacy.
That's what you should kill.
You and me we're a lot
alike in a lot of ways.
The only difference between you and I
is that I have resources.
I think, if I may,
you need my resources.
Someone behind you.
A benefactor.
I'd like to be that guy.
Okay.
Do you speak English,
because I can get a translator.
I don't know if you've been understanding
everything I'm saying.
- Very good, man.
Very good, man.
- Yes.
- I want my bird.
A bird?
- You want a bird?
- I want my bird.
I can get you bird
I can get you ten birds.
- I want my bird.
- Okay,
nothing's impossible.
I could, are we talking about...
is this a bird back in Russia?
Yes, but the fundamentals of the company
are still very, very strong.
Despite the events in Monaco.
Oh, oh, fax them.
- Where is he?
- He doesn't wanna be disturbed.
He's downstairs.
His continuing erratic behavior
may lead many people to ask themselves
can this man still protect us?
Iron Man never stopped protecting us.
The events in Monaco prove that.
Query complete, sir.
Anton Vanko was
a Soviet physicist
who defected to the United States
in 1963.
However, he was accused of espionage
and was
deported in 1967.
His son, Ivan, who is also a physicist,
was convicted of selling
Soviet-era weapons-grade plutonium
to Pakistan and served 15 years
in Kopeisk prison.
No further records exist.
Tony, you gotta get upstair
and get on top of this situation right now.
Listen, I've been on the phone with the
National Guard
all day
trying to talk them out of
rolling tanks and the PCH
knocking down your front door
and taking these.
They're gonna take your suits, Tony,
they're sick of the games.
You said nobody else would possess
this technology for twenty years.
Well guess what,
somebody else had it yesterday.
It's not theoretical anymore.
Are you listening to me?
Are you okay?
Let's go.
- Are you alright?
- Yeah I should go to my desk.
- See that cigar box?
- Yes.
It's palladium.
Is that supposed to be smoking?
If you must know
it's neutron damage.
It's from that reactor wall.
You had this in your body?
And how about the high-tech
crossword puzzle on your neck?
Rogue rash.
Thank you.
- What are you looking at?
- I'm looking at you.
You wanna do this whole lone gunslinger act
and it's unnecessary.
You don't have to do this alone.
You know I wish I could believe that.
I really do.
But you gotta trust me.
Contrary to popular belief,
I know exactly what I'm doing.
This is where we do it
This is my humble abode.
You can work in absolute peace.
Must be kinda fun to be dead, right
No pressure.
Ah, here they are.
They're excited, they're combat ready.
I may have done a few miscalculations and
rushed the prototype, but sue me,
I'm enthusiastic.
Go ahead, take a look around.
Oh, you don't wanna do that.
You'll be able to access that as soon as
we generate some encrypted passcodes.
Can we generate some encrypted passcodes?
Let's get some of those...
encrypted passcodes, Jack.
Nevermind.
Wow, okay. Good stuff.
- Sorry?
- Software shooot.
You're good.
You really blasted and
passed the firewall there.
Let me show you where
you're gonna be working primarily.
Go ahead, take a look.
Take a good look at that.
That's something, isn't it?
You know they're really
just for show and tell.
They're 125.7 million a pop.
Jeez, could you get somebody to help?
That's where the pilot goes.
I'm having a tough time finding volunteers.
I'll take care of that just leave it.
What you want them do?
Long term
I want them to put me in
the Pentagon for the
next 25 years.
I wanna make Iron Man look
like an antique.
I wanna go to that Stark Expo
and take a dump on Tony's front yard.
- You know what I'm talking about?
- Ya I can do that.
- Yes?
- No problem.
Hey, fabulous I love it.
This is our guy. Didn't I tell you?
I had a feeling.
Do you know which watch you'd like
to wear tonight Mr. Stark?
I'll give them a look.
I should cancel the party now?
- Probably.
- Yeah, cause it's, um...
- Ill-timed.
- Right, sends the wrong message.
Inappropriate.
Is that dirty enough for you?
Gold faced with the brown band...
The Jaeger.
I'll give that a look.
Bring them over here.
I'll take that.
Why don't you...
I gotta say it's hard to
get a read on you.
- Where are you from?
- Legal.
Can I ask you a question hypothetically?
It's a bit odd.
If this was your last birthday party you're
ever gonna have how would you celebrate it?
I'd do whatever I wanted to do.
With whoever I wanted to do it.
Yes, sir, I understand.
No, sir, that will not be necessary.
I'll handle it.
Sir, I personally guarantee that
within 24 hours
Iron Man will be back on watch.
Hey, Pepper...
- I'm gonna go get some air.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know what to do.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- That's it, I'm gonna make a...
- No, no, don't call anyone.
This is ridiculous I just stuck my neck up
for this guy.
I know. I get it. I'm gonna handle it okay,
just let me handle it.
Handle it, or I'm gonna have to.
You know the question I get asked most often is
Tony how do you go to the bathroom with the suit?
Just like that.
Does this guy know how to throw a party
or what?
I love you.
Unbelievable. Thank you so much
Tony, we all thank you so much for such a
wonderful night. We're gonna say
Good night now
and thank you all for coming.
No, no, wait, we can't, we didn't bring out
the cake we didn't blow out the candle.
- You're out of control okay
- I'm out of control?
- Trust me on this one okay?
- You're out of control gorgeous
- It's time to go to bed.
- Give me a little smooch.
Come on you know you want to.
You just peed the suit.
- I know, has a filtration system.
- It's not sexy.
- You can drink that water.
- Just send everybody home, okay.
- It's time to...
- If you say so.
Okay, I'll take this.
You take that.
Pepper Potts.
She's right.
The party is over.
Then again the party was over for me
like an hour and a half ago.
The after party
starts in 15 minutes!
And if anybody, Pepper, doesn't like it,
there's the door.
Shoot!
Me!
I think she wants the Gallanger!
There you go!
I'm only gonna say this once.
Get out!
You don't deserve to wear one of these.
Shut it down!
Goldstein.
Yes, Mr. Stark?
Give me a fat beat to beat
my buddy's ass to...
I told you to shut it down.
Now, put that thing back where you found it
before someone gets hurt.
Really?
Sorry pal, but
Iron Man doesn't have a sidekick.
Suck at this!
Had enough?
- Natalie!
- Ms. Potts...
Don't you Ms. Potts me. I'm on to you.
You know what, ever since you came here...
Pepper!
Let's get out of here!
You want it?
Take it!
Out!
Put your hand down.
You think you got what it takes
to wear that suit?
- We don't have to do this, Tony.
- You wanna be a war machine?
- Take your shot.
- Put it down!
- You're gonna take your shot?
- Put it down, now!
- Drop it Tony
- Take it!
Tower this is Lt. Col. James Rhodes
eastbound for 3 miles,...
Colonel.
Major.
Yeah.
Let's take it inside.
Clear the area.
Sir! I'm gonna have to ask you
to exit the donut.
I told you I don't wanna
join your super secret boyband.
No, see, I remember, you do
everything myself.
How's it workin out for you?
I'm sorry, I don't wanna get off on the wrong
foot, do I look in the patch or the eye?
Honestly I'm a bit hungover
I'm not sure if you're real or if...
I am very real. I'm the realest
person you're ever gonna meet.
- Just my luck. Where is the staff here?
- Oh, that's not lookin too good.
It's getting worse.
We've secured the perimeter, but I don't
think we should hold it for too much longer.
- You're fired.
- That's not up to you.
- Tony... I want you to meet agent Romanoff
- Hi
I'm a Shield shadow
and I was tasked to you by Dr. Fury.
I suggest you apologize.
You've been very busy.
Made your girl your CEO,
you've given away all your stuff.
You let your friend
fly away with your suit.
- If I didn't know better...
- You don't know better.
I didn't give it to him.
He took it.
He took it? You're Iron Man
and he just took it?
Little brother walked in there
kicked your ass and took your suit?
Is that possible?
According to Mr. Stark's database
security guidelines
There are redundancies to prevent
unauthorized usage.
- What do you want from me?
- What do we want from you? No, no, no!
What do you want from me.
You have become a problem, a problem
I have to deal with.
- Contrary to your belief, you are not
the center of my universe. - Yeah I get it.
I have bigger problems than you in the
Southwest region to deal with. Hit him.
Are you gonna steal my kidney and sell it?
Could you please not do anything
awful for 5 seconds?
What did you just do to me?
What did we just do for you.
That's lithium dioxide. It's gonna take the edge off.
We're trying to get you back to work.
- Give me a couple of boxes and I'll be right as rain.
- It's not a cure, it's just to break the symptoms.
- Then the lag is gonna be an easy fix.
- Trust me I know I'm good at this stuff.
I've been looking for a suitable
replacement for palladium.
I've tried every combination, every
permutation of every known element.
Well, I'm here to tell you
you haven't tried them all.
Hey, hey, hey.
Special delivery.
Candygram!
I brought you something.
- We got you the bird, pal.
- This is not my bird.
What do you mean?
That's the bird.
I pulled a lot of strings
to get this bird.
- It's a great bird.
- It's a beautiful bird.
- We got this all the way from Russia.
- Hey man, it's not my bird.
Well listen, even if it's not the bird,
I mean this is a gorgeous bird.
I mean, look, don't get so attached to
things, learn to let go.
Wait a minute.
Jack, what is that?
Is that...
That's not a helmet. What is that?
Ivan... What's this?
Jack?
Is that a helmet? It doesn't look like a helmet to me.
How are you supposed to get a head in there?
- Jack, could you put your head in there?
- No. - Try to put your head in there.
Go ahead, try to put your head in there.
See Ivan, he can't put his head in
there. That's...
That's not a helmet, it's a head.
I need to put a guy in there.
I need to fit a person
in that suit, you understand?
Drone better.
What? Drone better?
Why is drone better?
Why drone better?
People make problem.
Trust me, drone better.
Ivan, you know I like you.
I got you the bird.
You said no problem. That's what you
said to me, you said no problem.
Now I need suits.
The government wants suits.
Like Iron Man, you understand?
That's what the people want.
That's what's gonna make them happy.
Hey, man...
Don't get to attached to things.
Learn to let go.
These drones better steal the show, Ivan.
You understand? They better
rock my world, Ivan.
Unbelievable.
This ought to get the Senate off my ass.
- It's functional?
- Fully mission-capable.
Good. Get Hammer down here
to weaponize it.
Sir?
Justin Hammer's making a weapons
presentation at the expo.
We'd like this to introduce it.
Sir, I don't believe that the expo is...
Colonel, the world needs
to see this fast.
We've got to make this happen.
- Yes general, but the...
- It's also an order.
Yes, sir.
Good work, Colonel.
You've made your country proud.
Thank you, sir.
That thing in your chest is
based on unfinished technology.
No it was finished, it's never
been particularly effective until
I've miniaturized it
and put it in my...
No, Howard said that the arc reactor was
a stepping stone to something greater.
He was about to kick off an energy race
That was gonna dwarf
the arms race.
He was on to something big,
something so big
that it was gonna make the nuclear reactor
look like a AAA battery.
Just him? Or was Anton
Vanko in on this too?
Anton Vanko is the other
side of that coin.
Anton saw it as a
way to get rich.
When your father found
out he had him deported.
When the Russians found out he couldn't
deliver they shipped his ass off to Siberia
and he spent the next 20 years on a vodka
fuel rage.
Not quite the environment you wanna raise
a kid in.
His son you had the misfortune of
crossing paths with in Monaco.
You told me I hadn't tried everything. What
do you mean I haven't tried everything?
What haven't I tried?
He said that you were the only
person with the means and knowledge
to finish what he started.
He said that?
Are you that guy?
Huh? Are you?
Because if you are then
you can solve the riddle of your heart.
I don't know where you get your
information, but he wasn't my biggest fan.
- What do your remember about your dad huh?
- He was cold, he was calculating...
He never told me he loved me
he never even told me he liked me.
So it's a little tough for me to digest what're you
telling me he said the whole future is riding on me
and he's passing it down...
I don't get that.
We're talking about a guy
whose happiest day
was when he shipped me
off to boarding school.
That's not true.
Well, then clearly you know my dad better
than I did.
As a matter of fact I did.
He was one of the founding members
of The Shield.
- What?
- I got a two o'clock.
Wait, wait, what's this?
- Okay, you're good, right?
- No I'm not good.
- You got this, right? - Got what? I don't
even know what I'm supposed to get.
Natasha will remain
a floater at Stark with her cover intact
and you remember
Agent Colson right?
Yeah.
Oh, and Tony...
Remember, I got my eye on you.
We've disabled all communications,
no contact with the outside world.
Good luck.
Please...
First thing I need a little body work.
I'll put in a little time at the lab.
If you could send of your goon squad down to the Coffee
Bean across the street or Starbucks, that'll be nice.
I'm not here for that.
I've been authorized by
Director Fury to use any means necessary
to keep you on premises.
- If you attempt to leave - Right
- Or play any games
I will taze you and watch
Supernanny while you
drool into the carpet. Okay?
- I think I got it, yeah.
- Enjoy your evening's entertainment.
Think this is the power source?
Major, this is not a scientific exercise.
Let's just focus
on arming it, alright?
Yes, sir.
Oh, yes!
Oh, yes, yes, yes!
Is it my birthday?
You gotta.. what did you do?
What did you do?
- Is this what I think it is?
- Yes it is.
Hammer, I want to know
what you're gonna do for us.
What am I gonna do for you?
First thing I'm gonna do for you is
I'm gonna upgrade your software,
I'm talking about firepower.
Well you're talking to the right guy.
Claridge Hi-Tec semi-automatic 9 mm pistol.
Too downtown?
I agree.
M-24 shotgun pump action.
5-round magazine, but
you know what, you're not a hunter.
What am I talking about?
I'm getting rid of it.
This is the FN-2000 from Belgium.
They do make something better than waffles.
It's beautiful, but I can tell this isn't
disco enough for you
so I'm gonna put it right here.
You're looking at a Milkor 40 mm
grenade launcher. Tear gas, smoke.
Hippie control.
You're tough.
Let me tell you something,
Size does matter.
Don't let anyone tell you different.
This is an M134 7.62 minigun.
Six individual barrels.
The torso taker, powder maker.
Our boys in uniform call it Uncle Gazpacho
or Puff the Magic Dragon.
Okay.
These are the Cubans baby.
These are the Cohibas, the Montecristos...
That's a kinetic-kill sidewinder vehicle
with a secondary
cyclotrimethylenetrinitramine RDX burst.
It's capable of busting a bunker under
the bunker you just busted.
If it were any smarter
it would write a book.
A book that would make Ulysses look like
it was written in crayon.
And would read it to you.
This is my Eiffel Tower,
This is my Rachmaninoff's Third.
My Pieta. It's completely
elegant, it's bafflingly beautiful.
And it's capable of reducing the population
of any standing structure to zero.
I call it the Ex-Wife.
That's the best I got.
How are you gonna do this? Give me something.
You're like a sphinx.
I can't read you.
I think I'll take it.
- Which one?
- All of it.
All of it?
Action.
Everything is achievable
through technology.
Better living, robust health.
And for the first time
in human history...
the possibility of world peace.
I'm Howard Stark. And everything
you'll need for the future,
can be found right here.
City of Future, City of
of Tomorrow? Hang on.
I'm Howard Stark.
And everything you'll need in
the future can be found right here.
So, from all of us in Stark Industries
I would like to personally...
Tony? What are you doing back there?
What is that?
Put it back.
Put it back where you got it from.
Where is your mother?
Maria...
Go on, go, go, go...
Sorry I think we got the...
I'll come in in there...
Are you waiting on me?
So from all of us in Stark Industries
I'd like to personally show you...
my ass.
I'd like to... This...
I can't... We have this don't we?
That looks ridiculous.
Everything...
is achievable...
through technology.
Tony...
You're too young to understand this right now
so I thought I would put it on film for you.
I built this for you.
And someday you'll realize that it represents a
whole lot more than just people's inventions.
It represents my life's work.
This is key to the future.
I'm limited by the technology
of my time.
But one day you'll figure this out.
And when you do...
you will change the world.
What is and always will be
my greatest creation...
is you.
Hi, sir.
- $6.
- I don't have any...
- No sir, that's too much.
- No it's fine, take that.
Take it, take it.
I don't like people hand me things so if you
could just drop that there that would be great.
- Are you Iron Man?
- Sometimes.
We believe in you!
It was an illegal seizure
of trademarked property.
- Ms. Potts, Mr Stark is...
- Here.
- He refuses to...
- I don't. It's fine. I'll just be a second.
It's our position that Stark has the means to maintain
proprietary ownership of the Mark II platform.
When Mr. Stark announced
he was the Iron Man
he was making a promise to America.
Obviously he did not.
Now we learn that his secretary,
a woman named
Virginia "Pepper" Potts,
has been appointed CEO
of Stark Industries executive.
What are her qualifications?
No.
- Ms. Potts is doing nothing to manage
the terrible situation... - Mute.
Bert, don't tell me that we have the
best patent lawyers in the country
and then not let me pursue this.
I'll get this stuff out of here.
Well then, tell the President
to sign an order.
We'll talk about it at the expo.
Hammer's giving some presentation
tomorrow evening.
- Will Tony Stark be there?
- Will I?
- No, he will not.
- I'd like to be.
- Got a minute?
- No.
Come on, you just got off the phone.
30 seconds.
29... 28...
I was driving over here, and I thought I was
coming basically to apologize, but I'm not.
- You didn't come here to apologize?
- That goes without saying, and I'm working on that.
But I haven't been entirely up front
with you
and I just wanna try to make good,
Can I move this?
This is crazy I got ferris wheel...
No.
Do you know how short life is?
And if I never got to express...
and by the way somewhat revelatory to me,
I don't care... I mean, I
care, it would be nice,
I'm not expecting you to...
Look, here's what I'm trying to say.
Let me just stop you right here, okay,
because if you say "I"
one more time, I'm gonna actually hurl
something at your head, I think.
I am trying to run a company. Do you
know have any idea what that entails?
Yes.
People are relying on you to be
Iron Man, and you've disappeared.
All I'm doing is putting out your fire
and taking the heat for it.
I am trying to do the job that you
were meant to do.
Did you bring me strawberries?
Did you know that there is only one thing
on earth that I am allergic to?
You're allergic to strawberries, uh-uh.
This is progress, Pepper. I knew there
was correlation between you and this...
- I need you...
- And I need you too, that's what I'm trying to say.
To leave now.
Ms Potts.
- Hi, come on in.
- Wheel's up in 25 minutes.
Thank you.
Anything else, boss?
- I'm good Hap.
- I'll be just... another minute.
I lost both the kids in the divorce.
No.
Are you blending in well here, Natalie?
Here at Stark... Enterprises.
Your name is Natalie, isn't it?
I thought you two
didn't get along.
- No, that's not so.
- It's just me you don't care for.
No? Nothing?
Actually while you're here maybe you and Natalie
could discuss the matter of personal belonging.
Absolutely.
- I'm surprised you could keep your mouth shut.
- You're good. You are mind-blowingly duplicitous.
How do you do it?
You're a triple impostor.
I've never seen anything like it.
Is there anything real about you?
Do you even speak Latin?
Fallaces sunt rerum species.
Which means?
What did you just say?
It means you can either drive yourself home
or I can have you collected.
You're good!
Jarvis, could you kindly
backform a digital wireframe?
I need a manipulable projection.
1974 Stark Expo model scanning
complete, sir.
- How many buildings are there?
- Am I to include the Belgian waffles stand?
It was rhetorical, just show me.
What does that look like to you, Jarvis?
Not unlike an atom.
In which case, the nucleus...
would be here.
Highlight the Unisphere.
- Notice the footpaths. Get rid of them.
- What is it you're trying to achieve, sir?
I'm discovering,...
correction, rediscovering...
a new element.
Lose the landscape and the shrubbery there,
trees,
parking lots, exits, entrances.
Structre protons and neutrons
using flags the pavillions
as the framework.
Dead for almost 20 years...
still taking me to school.
The proposed element should serve
as a viable replacement for palladium.
Thanks, Dad.
Unfortunately,
it is impossible to synthesize.
Get ready for major remodel, fellas!
We're back in hardware mode.
How did you break the perimeter?
That was like three years ago.
Where have you been?
- I was doing some stuff.
- Yeah, well, me too and it worked.
Hey, I'm playing for the home team, Colson You
and all your Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers.
Let me work, or break my balls?
What's this doing here?
That's it.
Bring it to me.
- You know what this is?
- It's exactly what I need to make this work.
Lift the coil.
Go, go! Put your knees under it.
There you go.
And...
- Drop it. - Okay.
Perfectly level.
- I'm busy. What do you want?
- Nothing.
Good bye. I've been reassigned.
Director Fury wants me in New Mexico.
- Fantastic, the land of enchantment.
- So I'm told.
- Secret stuff.
- Something like that.
- Good luck.
- Bye.
- Thanks.
- We need you.
- Yeah, more than you know.
- Not that much.
Initializing
prismatic accelerator.
Approaching maximum power.
That was easy.
Congratulations, sir.
You have created a new element.
Sir, the reactor has accepted the
modified core.
I will begin running diagnostics.
Hey, Ivan.
I got Senator Stern here. Thought we'd swing
over and look at some of the drone designs.
- The drone is not going to be ready.
- Not ready... What do you mean?
It can make presentation
not demonstration.
- What the hell is the difference?
- Presentation, no fly, no shoot.
Wait. What can we make 'em do, I mean,
This is a weapons demonstration.
I can make salute.
You can make salute, what do you mean
make salute?
What the hell does that mean, Ivan?
It's not what we agreed to, okay.
You promised me suits, and
then you promised me drones.
- Hey man, everything will be okay.
- This is not what I wanted.
Hey, there he is, the bird man.
Oh, now you like the bird, is that right?
Is that your bird?
I'm confused.
You said it wasn't, but now
it's like you're best of pals.
You love that bird, don't you?
You know what? Take the bird.
Take his pillows too. Both of them.
And shoes, take his shoes.
I took your stuff.
How does that make you feel?
You feel bad?
Good. Cause that's how I feel!
We had a contract!
I saved your life
and you give me suits.
That was our deal.
And you did not deliver.
I don't know if you're a genius
or a fraud.
I don't know what you are!
Something really, really
great fell into my lap.
If it hadn't, I'd be at your mercy tonight.
Now I have a piece of Stark
tech, and I pimped out myself.
Now your overpriced paperweights are gonna
look like a backdrop to my demonstration.
You dig what I'm gettin' at here?
I don't know if you noticed,
but I don't speak Russian!
I'm gonna leave now. I'm gonna go to the expo.
Maybe I'll even get laid.
See these guys? They're your babysitters.
They are not to be trifled with.
When I get back, we're gonna renegotiate
the terms of our agreement.
And you're gonna make
good on our arrangements.
Because if you don't, you're gonna be
exactly what you were when I found you,
a dead man.
You got that?
Maybe you can watch me on TV.
Dummy. You.
Can we clean up this mess?
- Incoming call with a blocked number, sir.
- Phone privileges reinstated.
Lovely.
- Colson, how's land of enchantment?
- Hey, Tony, how you doin'?
- I doubled cycle. - You what?
You told me double cycle's
more power. Good advice.
- You sound pretty spitely for a dead guy.
- You too.
- Trace it. - Sir.
Now the true history of
Stark name will be written.
- Jarvis, where he is?
- Accessing the Oracle grid.
Eastern seaboard.
What your father did to my family
over 40 years
I will do to you in 40 minutes.
Sounds good, let's get together
and hash it out.
Tri-state area.
Manhattan and outlying boroughs.
I hope you're ready.
Call trace incomplete.
- Sir.
- You wanna run some tests, run 'em.
And assemble the suit while you're at it
put it together now.
- We are unclear as to the effects...
- I don't wanna hear it, Jarvis!
It tastes like coconut...
and metal.
I'll keep the car down here, alright.
- Thank you Happy.
Justin Hammer, his presentation will
begin shortly in the main pavilion.
That's what I'm talking about!
Thanks for coming.
Ladies and gentlemen,
for far too long
this country has had to place its brave men
and women in harm's way.
But then the Iron Man arrived
and we thought that
the days of losing lives were behind us.
Sadly that technology
was kept out of reach.
That's not fair. That's not right.
- And it's just too bad.
- Oh, lord...
Regardless it was an impressive innovation
one that grabbed headlines the world over.
Today, my friends, the press
is faced with quite a different problem.
They are about to run out of ink.
Get that out of here.
Ladies and gentlemen...
today I present to you
the new face of the
United States military!
The Hammer drone!
Army!
Navy!
Air Force!
Marines!
That's a hell of a lot better than some
cheerleaders, let me tell you.
But as revolutionary
as this technology is,
there will always be a need for a man
to be present at the theater of war.
Ladies and gentlemen, today I am proud
to present to you the very first prototype
the variable threat response battle suit
and its pilot Air Force Lt.
Col. James Rhodes.
What?
For America and its allies,
Hammer Industries, is reporting...
We got trouble.
Tony, there are civilians present.
I'm here on orders.
Let's not do this right now.
Give them a wave.
All these people are in danger.
We gotta get them out of here.
You gotta trust
me for the next five minutes.
I tried that and
I got tossed around your house, remember?
I think he's working with Vanko.
Vanko is alive?
- Where is he?
- What?
Where is Vanko?
- Who?
- Tell me.
What are you doing here, man?
- Is that you?
- No, I'm not doing that, it's not me.
I can't move.
I'm locked up, I'm locked up.
Get out of here! Go!
The whole system's been compromised!
Let's take it outside.
No!
- Jarvis, break in, I need to own him.
- Yes, sir.
Tony, I'm locked on I have target locked.
- On what?
- On you.
Tony on your six.
- What's going on, what's happening?
- The software's been overwritten.
What?
What do you mean it's been overwritten?
- I think he slaved the drones.
- It is impossible.
- Call the guards
- All the phones are down, sir.
- Then call their cells.
- Their cell phones are not working either, sir.
- He's locked us out of the mainframe.
- Who's locked you out of the mainframe?
Please, please, go away.
I got this handled.
- Have you now?
- Yes I do.
In fact, if your guy hadn't showed up
This wouldn't be happening
Please now, go away!
Thank you.
Listen we gotta get these
bitches outta here.
You're gonna tell me who's behind
this.
Who's behind this?
Ivan. Ivan Vanko.
- Where is he?
- He's at my facility.
- I need NYPD please.
- No, no, no honey.
Don't call the authorities!
Step aside.
Tell me everything you know. Go.
- How we doing Jarvis?
- Remote reboot unsuccessful.
- No one's answering the phone, what's going on?
- Get in the car. Take me to Hammer Industries.
I'm not taking you anywhere.
- Fine. You want me to drive?
- No, I'm driving. Get in the car.
Nice work, kid.
- You got multiples coming down on you.
- Let's get this away from the expo.
When we arrive I need you
to watch the perimeter.
I'm gonna enter the facility
and take down the target.
- Watch the road.
- I got it.
Listen, listen, a pack has peeled
off and headed back to the expo.
Got it.
I'm closing on you!
It's coming in hot, Tony! Watch it.
- Stay in the car!
- I'm not staying in the car.
- I said stay in the car.
- What are you wearing?
Look, I'm not letting
you go in there alone.
- You wanna help? Keep the car running.
- Okay.
Hey, you can't come in here!
Each set of drones is communicating
in its own unique language.
- Choose one and focus on that.
- Have you tried Russian? Why don't you try Russian.
I got 'em!
- Rhodey, you're still locked on? - Yeah.
Drop your socks and grab your
crocs, we're about to get wet on this ride.
Wait, wait!
He's gone!
Sorry buddy, had
to thin out the herd.
What's your twenty?
- What are you doing?
- I'm rebooting Rhodey's suit.
Tony!
Reboot complete.
- You got your best friend back.
- Thank you very much, Agent Romanoff.
Well done with the new chest-piece. I'm reading significantly
higher output and your vitals all look promising.
Yes, for the moment I'm not dying.
Thank you.
- What do you mean you're not dying?
Did you say you're dying? - That you?
No, I'm not. Not anymore.
- What's going on?
- I was going to tell you. I didn't want to..
- You're gonna tell me you really were dying?
- You didn't let me.
- Why didn't you tell me that?
- I was gonna make you an omelette and tell you!
Hey, hey, save it for the honeymoon.
You got incoming, Tony.
Looks like the fight's coming to you.
- Great. Pepper?
- Are you okay now?
- I'm fine. Don't be mad. I will formally...
- I am mad.
apologize when I'm not
fending off a Hammeroid attack!
- We could've been in Venice.
- Oh, please...
Rhodes!
Snap out of it, buddy!
I need you.
They're coming. Come on let's roll. Get up.
Oh man, you can have your suit back.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, thanks.
- Tony, look... I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
- No I should've trusted you more.
- I'm the one who put you in this position. Forget it.
No it's your fault. I just wanted
to say I'm sorry.
Thank you.
That's all I want to hear, partner.
They're coming in hot. Any
second. What's the play?
Well we wanna take the high ground, okay.
So let's take
the biggest gun up on that ridge.
- Got you.
- Where do you wanna be? - Where you going?
- What are you talking about?
- I mean me.
- I have a big gun, you are not the big gun.
- Tony, don't be jealous.
- No it's subtle with all the bells and whistles.
- It's called being a bad ass.
- Fine.
- Alright. You go up top. I'll draw 'em in.
- But don't stay down here
it's the worst place to be.
- Okay you got a spot. Where's mine?
- It's the kill box, Tony, okay, this is where you go to die.
- See that?
- Yea, yea, nice.
Rhodey...
Get down!
Wow. I think you should lead with that
next time.
Yeah, sorry boss, I can only use it once.
It's a one-off.
I told you that five minutes ago.
That's your guy here.
- Excuse me?
- Sir, you're placed under arrest.
Hands behind your back, sir.
I'm trying to help here.
I get it. I see what you're doing. Trying
to pin this on me, huh?
That's good. You start to think like a CEO.
Taking out the competition.
I like that.
You think you're making a problem for me?
I'm gonna make a problem for you.
I'm gonna be seeing you again, real soon.
When they get here, I think you should station
them at the Southeast and both West exits.
We shut down the seven train in and out of
Willets Point already.
Well, have city buses there to ferry people
to operating lines.
You coming with us?
No, I'm gonna stay until the park is clear.
Heads up you got one more drone incoming.
This one looks different.
Repulsor signature
is significantly higher.
Good to be back.
This ain't gonna be good.
I got something special for this guy.
I'm gonna bust his bunker with the ex-wife.
The what?
- Hammer tech?
- Yeah.
We got this.
Rhodes! I got an idea.
You wanna be a hero?
- What?
- I can really use a sidekick.
- Put your hand up.
- This is your idea?
- Yup.
- I'm ready, I'm ready, go go go.
Hit him!
You lose.
All these drones are rigged to blow
We gotta get out of here man.
Pepper?
Oh my god, I can't take this anymore!
- You can't?
- I can't take this.
What do you mean, look at me!
My body literally cannot handle the stress. I
never know if you're gonna kill yourself...
or wreck the whole company...
I think I did okay!
I quit.
I'm resigning.
That's it.
What did you just say?
You're done?
Surprising, I mean not
surprising.
I get it.
You don't have to make any excuses.
- I'm not making any excuses.
- Well you actually were just making excuses.
I wasn't making an excuse but
I'm actually very justified.
You deserve better.
You've taken such good care of me.
I've been in tough spot
you got me through it, so.
- Right?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Thank you for understanding.
- Let's start clean up.
- I'll handle the transition. It'll be smooth.
What about the press? Because you only had
the job for a week. That's gonna be...
- With you it's like dog years.
- I know.
I mean it's like the President.
Weird.
No it's not weird.
- It's okay, right?
- Yeah.
I think it was weird.
You guys look like two seals
fighting over a grape.
- I had just quit
- You don't have to do that.
- I heard the whole thing.
- You should get lost.
I was here first.
Get a roof.
- I thought you were out of one-liners?
- That's the last one.
- You kicked ass back there, by the way.
- Thank you. You too.
Listen, my car got taken
out in the explosions
so I'm gonna have to hang on to
your suit for a minute, okay?
Not okay with thats.
It wasn't a question.
I don't understand...
I don't think I want you looking at that.
I'm not sure it pertains to you anymore.
Now this, on the other hand, is agent
Romanoff's assessment of you.
Read it.
Personality overview:
Mr Stark displays compulsive behavior.
In my own defense, that
was last week.
Prone to self-destructive tendencies.
I was dying.
I mean, please, aren't we all?
Textbook narcissism?
Agreed.
Recruitment assessment for Avenger
Initiative, Iron Man, yes.
- I gotta think about it.
- Read on.
Tony Stark not recommended?
That doesn't make any sense. How can
you approve me but not approve me?
I got a new ticker, I'm trying to do right
by Pepper.
I'm in a stable-ish relationship.
Which leads us to believe at this juncture
we'd only like to use you as a consultant.
You can't afford me.
Then again I will waive
my customary retainer
in exchange for a small favor.
Rhodey and I are being
honored in Washington
and we need a presenter.
I'll see what I can do.
It is my honor to be here today
to present these distinguished awards
to Lt. Col. James Rhodes
and Mr. Tony Stark
who is of course
a national treasure.
Thank you Lieutenant Colonel for such an
exceptionally distinguished performance.
- You deserve this.
- Thank you, sir.
Mr Stark, thank you for such an
exceptionally distinguished performance.
You deserve this.
Oh sorry.
Funny how annoying a little
prick can be, isn't it?
Let's get a photo.