Five, four, three..
two, one.
Ready or not, here I come.
Hey.. Dad?
Dad..
You will stay with Aunt May and
Uncle Ben for a little while.
- I want to go with you.
- No.
Doesn't like crust
on his sandwiches..
and he likes to sleep
with a little light on.
Mary. Come on, come on. Oh, God.
Dad.
Be good.
- Sorry.
- Morning, Flash.
Good morning, Parker.
Hey.. It's Peter, right?
I really like your photos.
Oh, thanks. Thanks.
Listen are you
busy Friday night?
Cool. Can you take pictures
of my boyfriend's car?
I just you know, I really want to
frame a good one for his birthday.
That's really nice of you. Wow,
that's such a nice thought.
Yeah, I will have a look at the old..
The old schedule. Okay.
Parker.
- Yes, sir?
- You want to keep that skateboard?
- Yeah. Keep it off the ground.
- Sure. Yeah. Wheels up.
Like that? That's it. Okay.
Eat it. Eat it. Eat it. Eat it.
Eat it. Eat it.
Eat your vegetables, Gordon.
Come on. Eat it.
Come on. Eat it. Eat it.
Hey, Parker, come on. Eat it.
Get a picture of this. Come on.
No, I am not going to take a picture of it.
Come on. Put him down, man.
- Come on.
- Gordon, don't eat it.
Take the picture, Parker.
Put him down, Flash.
Take the picture.
Put him down, Eugene.
Hey, man.
Come on. Get up, Parker.
- Get up. Come on.
- Come on. Get up.
Still not taking the picture.
Stay down, Parker.
Who wants one more?
One more. Flash.
Flash..
we still on for
after school today?
My house, 3:30?
I hope you been doing your homework.
Last time, I was..
very disappointed in you. Okay. Move.
No, how about we go to class?
How about it?
Whatever.
I thought that was great
what you did out there.
It was stupid..
but it was great.
You should probably go to the nurse.
You might have a concussion.
What's your name?
You don't know my name?
No, I know your name.
I just want to know if
you know your name.
Peter.
- Parker. Peter Parker.
- Okay. Okay, good.
I'd still go to
the nurse though.
- You're Gwen, right?
- Gwen Stacy. All right.
Hey.
I am making spaghetti
and meatballs tonight.
You're serious? Spaghetti
and meatballs.
Since when don't you like
spaghetti and meatballs, huh?
- Oh, my God. What's up?
- What happened to your face?
I am all right. Just.. I fell.
Skating. It's all right.
Ben Parker, don't you even..
think about leaving that
filthy box in my kitchen.
These are my bowling trophies.
Oh, well, then, by all means..
please leave that filthy
box in my kitchen.
- What happened to you?
- He fell.
Why you kids ride those
things, I will never know.
Because it's stupid
and dangerous.
Remember when we were
stupid and dangerous? No.
- Trust me, we were.
- All right. Good to know. Hey.
- Where's the flood? Follow me.
- I will show you. You serious? Yes.
All right.
I think it's the condenser tray.
No. Too much water for the condenser
tray or the heat exchange tubing.
This has got to
be the fill line.
That's the only thing
that makes any sense.
Can you fix it?
No, not tonight. I will go by
the hardware store tomorrow.
Good deal. And meanwhile,
put this on your face.
How's the other guy look?
Come on. I know a right
cross when I see one.
Yes or no? Do I have to
call somebody's father?
No, no.
All right.
Well, I wouldn't
tell your Aunt May.
I pity the poor kid who'd
have to suffer her wrath.
Hey, before you come up, see if there's
anything else worth saving. Okay.
Plumbers don't fix appliances.
Oh, yes, they do.
They fix pipes and pump things.
If you ask them to..
I forgot all about that thing.
It was your dad's.
- Yeah.
- He asked us to keep it safe one.
He saw it in the window of that
leather shop over on 9th Avenue.
He was 19. What does a 19-year-old
kid need with a briefcase?
And guess who sold it to him.
- I don't know.
- Your mother.
That's how they met.
He asked you to keep this safe?
Why? There's nothing in here.
Have you looked in here?
There's nothing here.
Your father was a very
secretive man, Peter.
Yeah, I know.
Who's that?
Do you know who that is?
Some guy who worked
with your dad, I guess.
Just take this off the
table, all right?
We're going to eat. Off.
And wash your hands.
Now. All right. Go on.
I need you to be a good boy.
Where are you going?
There's something..
something your mom
and I have to do.
What is this?
"Zero, zero, decay
rate algorithm."
Yeah, one sec, one sec.
Come in.
- You okay? Yeah. What's up?
- Oh, my God.
- You look just like him.
- Can I come in? Yeah.
Listen..
I don't have much education.
You know that, Peter.
Hell, I stopped being able to help
with your homework when you were 10.
What I am trying to say is..
I know it's been rough for
you without your dad.
And I know we don't
talk much about them.
- Yeah, it's all right.
- No, it is not all right.
I wish I could change
it, but I can't.
Curt Connors.
That's the name of the guy in
the picture with your dad.
They worked together for
years and they were close.
But after that night,
we never saw him again.
He never even called.
Not once.
Go figure.
She's pretty.
- Uncle Ben.
- What?
You're a pretty great dad.
Alright.
Excuse me.
What?
Can I help you?
I don't know. I am here to
see Dr. Connors. Right.
You will find
yourself to the left.
You are here for the internship?
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
You will find your
badge to the left.
Are you having trouble finding yourself?
No. Yeah, I got it.
Okay. Mr. Guevara. Gracias.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Welcome to Oscorp.
Born from the mind of our
founder, Norman Osborn..
the Oscorp Tower houses
108 floors of innovation.
Our scientific minds are pushing the
boundaries of defense, biomedical..
and chemical technologies.
The future lies within.
Welcome to Oscorp.
My name is Gwen Stacy, I am
senior at Midtown Science.
And I am also head
intern to Dr. Connors.
So, I will be with you for
the duration of your visit.
Where I go, you go.
That's the basic rule. If you remember
that all will be fine. Come on.
- If you forget that, then..
- Listen. Look, listen.
Tell them Rodrigo
Guevara is down here.
Please. Just tell them Rodrigo Guevara
is down here. My name's Rodrigo.
Well, I guess I don't need to tell
you what happens if you forget.
Shall we?
Come around this way.
Good afternoon, Gwen.
Dr. Connors.
Welcome.
My name is Dr. Curtis Connors.
And yes, in case you're
wondering, I am a southpaw.
I am not a cripple..
I am a scientist, and the world's
foremost authority on herpetology.
That's reptiles, for those
of you who don't know.
But like the Parkinson's patient who
watches on in horror as her body..
slowly betrays her, or the man
with macular degeneration..
whose eyes grow dimmer each
day, I long to fix myself.
I want to create a world
without weakness.
Anyone care to venture
a guess just how?
Yes.
Stem cells? Promising. But the solution
I am thinking of is more radical.
- No one?
- Cross-species genetics.
Person gets Parkinson's
when the brain cells
that produce dopamine
start to disappear.
But a zebra fish has the ability
to regenerate cells on command.
If you somehow could
give this ability..
to the woman you're talking
about, that's that. She's..
She's curing herself.
Yeah, you just have to look
past the gills on her neck.
And you are..?
He's one of Midtown Science's
best and brightest. Really?
He is second in his class.
Oh. Second? Yeah.
You sure about that?
I am pretty sure.
I am afraid duty calls. I will leave you in
the more-than-capable hands of Miss Stacy.
Nice meeting you all.
If you'd like to gather round.
Welcome to Oscorp's tree of life.
Our planet's tree
of life is immense.
- At Oscorp's Cross-Species Division..
- Hi.
We endeavour to explore
exciting new methods..
What are you doing, "Rodrigo"?
Oh, yeah.
What are you doing here?
I work here. I don't work here. I
was going to say I work here..
but it seems like you in fact do work here.
So you know that I don't work here.
You following me?
No, I am not following you, no. I am not.
I had no idea you worked here.
Then why would you be here?
I just snuck in because..
I love science.
- You love science.
- I am passionate about it.
So you snuck in..?
I have to lead this tour group. I know.
I will ask you more about this later.
Do not get me in trouble.
Stay with the group.
I promise you I won't.
All right, guys? I am going to take
you to the bioreactor room now.
Sorry. Yo.
Sorry.
We received the results from the
mRNA sequences this morning.
They were.. disappointing.
Define "disappointing."
Another dead end.
It's the decay rate algorithm.
- And this is to be expected.
- Expected?
You said you were close.
We are close, but it's
going to take time.
He doesn't have time.
Norman Osborn is
dying, Dr. Connors.
Save him.
Or we will both lose our heads.
All right, give me the badge.
Give it to me.
Sorry.
Disgusting. Now I
smell like beer.
All right, I am sorry. I
didn't mean to do that.
I didn't mean to..
I didn't.. I didn't..
Get your hand off her. I am
trying to get my.. Yo man.
Are you kidding? I am sorry.
Are you freaking kidding me?
- Hey, get him, Rudy.
- Hey.
Man. I am sorry. Help him..
Man, are you all right?
- Take him down.
- Come on.
Get him, man. Get him.
No, man, no. Not my board.
Please, dude, don't..
Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry.
I am so sorry.
Coney Island, next stop. Next
and final stop, Coney Island.
Hey.
Hey. Hey.. Sorry. I am late.
- I got..
- We have been so worried.
I know. I am sorry.
Watch out.
That's a fly, Peter.
Yeah.
I am so sorry..
I kept you guys up..
I am insensitive, I am irresponsible..
and I am hungry.
Meatloaf.
Drinking?
What's this?
I don't think so.
This is your meatloaf.
This beats all other meat loafs.
Something is very wrong.
Yeah. Nobody likes
your meatloaf.
I got it.
He took the frozen
macaroni and cheese.
I noticed that.
Why didn't you tell me you
didn't like my meatloaf?
You could have said that
to me 37 years ago.
How many meat loafs
have I made for you?
Peter.
What are you doing up there?
I am..
Homework.
Be careful.
Sure.
Dr. Connors.
You don't remember me. I.. The
intern from the other day.
Yeah, yeah. That's right, yeah.
I am sure you're very nice
young man, but this is a home.
I ask you to make an
appointment with my office.
I am Richard Parker's son.
Peter?
I am afraid..
I can't help you much, Peter. I don't know
why they left or where they were going.
Good reflexes.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- I read your book. Yeah.
It's something, you know.
So you really think it's..
possible, cross-species genetics?
Yes, of course but.
For years your father and I
were mocked for our theories.
Not just in the community at
large, but at Oscorp, as well.
They called us mad scientists.
And then your father bred the
spiders and everything changed.
The results were
beyond encouraging.
They were spectacular.
We were going to change
the lives of millions.
Including my own.
Then it was over.
He was gone.
Took his research with him.
And I knew without him, I..
I..
I was angry.
So I stayed away from
you and your family.
And for that, I am truly sorry.
Say..
Say it worked. Say
you got it to work.
Like, how much would the
foreign species take over?
What could the side effects be?
It's hard to say, considering
no subject survived.
The problem was always..
The decay rate algorithm?
- Right.
Can I..?
Of course.
- Extraordinary.
- How did you come up with this?
Peter, how about you
feel about coming to see
me at the Tower one day
after school? Yeah.
Thank you.
Number one, Reggie. Run it, buddy.
Let's go. Reggie.. Yeah.
Rejected.
You did that on purpose, Flash.
No, but I should have. You
better watch your back.
Hey.
All right?
Give it up, Parker.
Come on, man.
One sec.
- Come on, man.
- Why don't you take it from me?
That's right, Flash. Take it, man.
Go ahead. Take it.
Just take it.
All right, how about this?
All right?
How about that? Come on, Flash.
- Come on, Flash.
- Flash, stop playing, man.
- Take it from him.
- Come on, Flash. Take it.
Yo, Flash, let's go.
- Let's go.
- Do it, Flash.
- Stop playing, man.
- Let's go, Flash. Come on.
- What are you doing?
- What's up?
What you doing, man?
All right, bring it. Come on, Parker.
Come on.
Peter's behaviour is
just unacceptable.
They are not going to make us pay
for the backboard. You know that.
I don't care about
the backboard.
- Was that true?
- What?
What I heard in there just now.
Did you humiliate that boy?
Yeah, I did.
But.. But what? This guy deserved it.
Did he?
- Yeah.
- Is he the kid that hit you?
Is he?
Yeah, yeah, but.. So all
this is about getting even.
If so, I guess you must feel pretty
good about yourself now, right?
Am I right or wrong?
Yeah, I thought so.
Well, thanks to this
little escapade of yours..
I had to change shifts at work..
so you have to pick up Aunt May
tonight at 9:00. Understood?
- Is that understood?
- Yeah. Yeah. Okay, good.
She looks familiar.
She is the girl
on your computer.
Yeah. He's got you on his computer.
I am his probation officer.
Don't forget Aunt May.
Okay.
He's a character.
That's my uncle.
He's a pathological liar.
He thought you
were someone else.
Oh, man, you don't have
me on your computer?
Yeah. I mean, like I have.
I took a photo of the debate team, and
you're in the debate team. So. Right. So.
He must have seen.. I
was touching up stuff.
- Touching up stuff?
- Come on.
I was.. I am not going
to answer that.
- Did you get expelled?
- No, no.
I didn't get expelled. I
got community service.
So you want to.. I don't know..?
Want to what?
I don't know.
Just..
I don't know.. We could..
We could do something
else, or we could..
If you don't feel like, we could..
Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, either one.
- Really?
- Sure.
- Okay. All right, good.
- Sounds good. Cool.
Okay. I can't right now.
I can't right now. Yeah.
- No. I am so busy right now.
- I know, me too.
But maybe..
- Yeah, just, you know..
- Some other..
time, all right. Okay.
Bye. All right.
We've protein structure,
rDNA, chromatography,
transgenics testing,
that's X-ray video.
That's the only one on the planet.
We have..
- Human line testing over..
- I remember that.
I have seen that before.
The Ganali device.
Yeah, I remember a picture
of that in my dad's office.
The idea was so simple. You
load it with an antigen.
It creates a cloud which can be dispersed
over a neighbourhood, even an entire city.
Theoretically, you could
cure polio in an afternoon.
That's incredible. Well,
others disagreed.
What if the device were
loaded with a toxin?
What if you wanted to opt out? You
can't run away from a cloud..
after all, so here it
lies, gathering dust.
What you see here is a
computer model of a lizard.
Many of these wonderful creatures
have so brilliantly adapted..
that they can regenerate
entire limbs at will.
You can imagine my envy.
We're trying to harness this capability
and transfer it into our host subject:
Freddy the three-legged mouse.
Enter the algorithm now.
You need to take that?
System ready for gene insertion.
Okay.
Check.
See what I am trying to do?
- Preempt the proteins.
- Preempt the immune response.
- Beginning trials.
- Pending. Pending.
Failed. Subject deceased. Come on.
Come on, come on. Pending.
Failed.
Pending. Failed.
Subject deceased. Pending.
Peptide algorithm accepted.
- Regrowth complete. Hey.
- Vitals normal.
Blood pressure normal.
Limb regeneration successful.
Extraordinary.
And thank you.
Meet Fred and Wilma..
our three-legged mice.
Here you go.
Hey, buddy. I got you.
Okay. Careful, don't want
to stick you by mistake.
Human trials aren't
until next week.
There.
Hey.
Hey, I thought you..
Didn't you forget something?
What?
Now, don't answer that, but I
am glad to know it's working.
You owe your aunt
an apology bigtime.
Be a man. Get in
there and apologise.
I am sorry, Aunt May, I..
Honestly, you don't have..
to apologise to me. It's your..
The hell he doesn't. Ben.
Look, I am sorry, uncle
Ben I got distracted.
Oh, he got distracted. Yeah.
Your aunt, my wife, had
to walk 12 blocks alone..
in the middle of the night and then
wait in a deserted subway station..
because you got distracted.
Ben, sweetheart, honestly..
I am completely capable of walking home..
You will not defend this boy.
I am not defending.. You are defending him.
Listen to me, son. Yeah, go ahead.
You're a lot like your father.
You really are, Peter, and
that's a good thing..
but your father lived by a
philosophy, a principle, really.
He believed that if you could do
good things for other people..
you had a moral obligation
to do those things.
That's what's at stake here.
Not choice.
Responsibility.
That is nice. That's great.
That's all well and good.
So where is he?
- What?
- Where is he?
Where's my dad?
He didn't think it was his responsibility
to be here to tell me this himself?
Oh, come on, how dare you?
How dare I? How dare you?
Where you going?
Peter, come back here, please.
Ben, leave him alone for a little while.
He will be all right.
Peter.
Peter?
It's $2.07.
- All right. It's $2.07.
- Yeah. No, I know.
Yeah, you're holding up the line.
No.
You can leave a penny.
You can't take a penny.
What? You can leave a penny anytime,
you have to spend 10 dollars..
to take a penny.
It's store policy.
You are going to pay.
You're holding up my line.
I don't have 2 cents.
You can't afford milk,
just step aside.
Daddy didn't give you
enough milk money today?
It's 2 cents. We're talking about 2 cents.
Just step aside, kid.
Really?
Yo, not cool, bro.
Hey, man, stop.
Somebody stop that guy.
Hey, kid, little help?
Not my policy.
Somebody stop that dude.
Hey.
Hey, stop.
Somebody stop that dude.
Hey.
Oh, God, oh, God.
Uncle Ben, Uncle Ben.
Call an ambulance.
Someone call an ambulance.
Uncle Ben, Uncle Ben.
Oh, God, oh, my God.
Oh, God.
No..
Oh, Jesus.
Witnesses gave a description
to the sketch artist.
I need you to take a look.
No, I don't know him.
I didn't expect you would, ma'am.
Homicide detectives..
are on it. We will see
what they turn up. Okay.
Can I.. Can I have that? Sure.
There's one other thing. He has a
star tattooed on his left hand.
Peter, I know things have
been difficult lately..
and I am sorry about that.
I think I know what
you're feeling.
Hey, Parker.
- Not today. Flash.
- Hey come on, man. I just want to talk.
It feels better, right?
Look, your uncle died.
I am sorry.
I get it.
Okay?
Peter.
Listen to me. Stay
away from him.
You understand me? Hey.
Stay away from Joey.
You like beating on girls?
You like beating on old men?
Hey, pal just keep on walking.
- You're in the wrong place, buddy.
- When were you in Queens?
I asked you a question, man.
Nicky, no.
That the gun?
You going to kill me too?
- Hey.
- Stop it.
- Get off.
- Wait, oh, don't hit Nicky.
- Back up.
This guy is crazy.
Get him.
Get back here, man. Get him.
Follow him.
- Go around, man.
- I will follow you.
Go, go, go.
There he is.
Can't get away.
He has a star tattooed
on his left hand.
Oh, yeah? Come on.
I know what you look like.
You hear me?
I have seen your face.
Is that all you got?
Just take it, take it.
Engineered from genetically
enhanced spiders..
Oscorp's BioCable tensile
strength is unparalleled.
We're just beginning..
to understand all the potential
industrial applications.
A single pellet can safely store several
hundred meters of the lightweight cable.
Mother..
Attention, all units in the confines
of Precinct 13, receiving a 10-30..
on West 19th Street
and Broadway.
Assailant is Caucasian
male, mid-30s..
170 to 180 pounds
shoulder-length blond hair.
Last seen on foot heading
eastbound on 19th Street.
Hey.
You got a description?
Well, no, he wears a mask.
A mask?
Yeah. And most of his victims..
are suspects. Some of them
with serious rap sheets.
They're calling him a vigilante.
Okay, he's not a vigilante,
he's an anarchist.
Help me, somebody. Arrest me.
Please. Get me out of here.
Hey, look.
Spandex. Spandex.
Everything..
spandex.
Extraordinary velocity vector is a
function of both mass and acceleration.
Oh. Come on, you know
better than anyone..
the weight on any pendulum has
no effect on swing speed.
It doesn't affect frequency, but
it's totally a factor in momentum.
Hey, Aunt May.
Yeah. Eggs? Organic, got it.
You know, in the future, if
you're going to steal cars..
don't dress like a
car thief, man.
What are you? You a cop?
Really? You seriously think I am a cop?
Cop in a skin-tight red-and-blue suit?
You know, you're, you're..
You have got a mind of
the true scholar, sir.
I was going more for the
guys who do the luge.
Good thinking. Good thinking.
Get out the window.
There you go. You got it.
Crotch.
Just let me go. Is that a knife?
Is that a real knife?
Yes, it's a real knife.
My weakness, it's small knives.
Just let me go. Anything but knives.
Oh, it's so simple.
- That was cool.
- What the hell is this?
Webbing that I developed myself. I
don't think you really want to know.
Come on. Let me go.
Okay, one second. Hold on, one second.
Knock it off, man. No.
Come on, let me go. Stop it.
That isn't funny. It is kind of funny.
Come on. Help.
This could have
gone a lot worse.
Now hold still.
Boys in blue here.
Yo, I got him.
- Freeze. He's not going anywhere.
- You in the tights, don't move.
You serious?
Who are you?
No one grasps the
concept of the mask.
Freeze.
I just did 80 percent of your job.
And that?
That's how you repay me?
Hold it right there.
All right. Well, that was fun.
Bus. Hey there, everybody.
What are you doing?
Hey, watch out.
I am swinging here.
So 38 of New York's finest
versus one guy in a unitard.
Am I correct?
You don't have to wait up for me, you know.
Yes, I do. No, you don't.
Yes, I do.
- Okay.
- Where were you?
I was out.
Did you get the eggs?
Nope. Forgot the eggs.
I am going to get them now.
No, you most certainly will not.
Not at this hour.
Look at me, Peter.
Take off the damn
hood and look at me.
Peter. Where do you go?
Who does this to you?
Please go to sleep, Aunt May.
Please tell me. Aunt May, please,
please, please go to sleep.
I can't sleep. Don't you understand?
I can't sleep.
Peter, listen to me.
Secrets have a cost.
They're not for free.
Not now, not ever.
Cross-species genetics
is finally working.
I have used the lizard DNA to help
Freddy regrow that limb. It's a miracle.
No, it's hard work and promise.
And it's a step closer
to the primate lab. But
he doesn't have time
for every little step.
Little? I just mean
he can't wait.
Well, he will have to.
Unless he wants to be a lab rat.
That's not what I am saying.
So, what are you saying?
You have to start human trials.
Now.
No, I don't, and no, I won't. Well,
then he's going to die. People die.
Even Norman Osborn.
We are not finished.
Human trials?
Where enough are you going to find
the people to volunteer? For what?
As far as anyone's concerned,
it's for a winter flu shot.
I might think the Veterans
Hospital is a place to start.
You have got to be kidding me.
I don't think I am.
It's a little late for shock
and indignation Curt.
About 15 years late.
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Richard Parker wore it well.
On you, it's a cheap
suit, as it was then.
I had nothing to do with that. Is
that what you told his son? Peter.
I don't know what you're saying.
You don't know, or you
don't want to know?
I will remind you what happened.
Richard Parker said just about the same
thing then that you are saying now.
The clock is ticking,
Dr. Connors.
I..
I won't.
Fine.
The formula is ours now anyway.
Say goodbye to that arm
you have dreamed of.
I am shutting you down.
Have your office cleared
out by the morning.
Your toys can be taken
away too, you know.
Right, Freddy?
- Hey.
- Hi.
How's it going?
Where you headed?
- Monday, B track.
- Oh, it's Thursday.
- It's Thursday?
- What happened to your eye?
What? Your eye, it looks bruised.
Oh, yeah, no, I don't..
Maybe I got a rash or..
It's pretty bad. Have
you gone to the nurse?
Do you like branzino?
Like, a fish. No, no. I know.
I know. Well, if you want..
you can come to this
address at 8:00 tonight.
My mom's making branzino.
So..
It's apartment 2016. I
didn't write that part down.
I don't know why I..
- I will remember it.
- Oh, okay. 2016.
Hi.
How did you get out there?
The fire escape.
Your doorman's intimidating.
It's 20 storeys.
Yeah. It's all right.
- This is your room.
- Yes, this is my room.
Books.
Shoes.
Oh, hey..
I got your mom.. these.
Oh, lovely. Beautiful, right?
Beautiful.
They were nice. No, they're beautiful.
I am sorry.
No, it's impressive. They
actually held together very well.
I am going to keep these.
You have your suit in there?
My suit?
It's for dinner. Are you going to..?
Are you going to wear that?
That's.. Hey, hon.
You must be Peter.
Dad, this is Peter.
Nice to meet you, sir.
Nice to meet you.
Dinner's ready.
Hope you like branzino.
Who doesn't?
Emma, it's Curt.
- Is he there?
- I am afraid not, doctor.
The car is taking him to the
Veterans Hospital in Brooklyn.
No. No. No. He can't, Emma.
You have to stop him. He..
I would, but I always lose him
when he is on the bridge.
I will make sure Dr. Ratha returns
your call as soon as possible.
I am going to Holton
Avenue, across the river.
I am in a hurry.
Okay. You want me to take
the tunnel or the bridge?
Bridge. Take the bridge.
All right, we will do that.
Hey, man, you all
right back there?
You tweaking man?
Just drive.
Okay.
You're having trouble there? The
head goes on the other.. Simon.
Help Gwen's friend
with his fish.
Oh, I..
I got no idea.
First time.
- Branzino.
- George.
Why don't you tell us about your day.
Oh, yeah.
Dad, did you catch
that spider guy yet?
No, we didn't catch him yet.
But we will. He's an amateur..
who's assaulting civilians
in the dead of night.
He's clumsy, he leaves clues
but he's still dangerous.
He's assaulting people?
I am not sure. I mean,
I saw that video..
with him and the
car thief, and..
I think most people
would say that he was..
providing a public service.
Most people would be wrong.
If I wanted the car thief off the
street, he'd already be off the street.
So why wasn't he then?
Let me illuminate you. See, the car thief
was leading us to the people who run..
the entire operation. It's
been a six-month-long sting.
It's called strategy. I am sure you
are aware of the term strategy?
You probably heard about that in school?
Yeah. Good. I know. Obviously..
he didn't know you had a plan.
You seem to know..
an awful lot about this case. You
know something that we don't know?
- I mean, whose side are you on here?
- I am not on anyone's side.
I saw a video on the internet.. You
saw the video on the Internet.
- Well, then the case is closed.
- Well, no.
I am just saying if you watch the video..
Maybe send you a link?
It looks like he's trying to help.
Stop, stop, stop.
Yeah, sure. On the Internet
he's being made out
to look like some kind of
mask hero or something.
No, no. I am not saying he's a hero.
I don't think he is hero at all.
What are you trying to say? I am saying
he's trying to help. But it looks like..
he's trying to do something
maybe the police can't.
Something the police can't?
- I don't know.
- What do you think we do there?
We just sit around eating doughnuts with
our thumbs planted firmly up our asses?
George. George. Daddy. You
think that we do down there?
Up your what, dad? Howard.
I think he stands for
what you stand for, sir.
Protecting innocent
people from bad guys.
I stand for law and order, son. That's
what I stand for. Okay? I wear a badge.
This guy wears a mask like a..
you know like an outlaw.
He's hunting down a bunch of
criminals that all look the same..
like he's got some sort
of personal vendetta.
But he's not protecting
innocent people, Mr. Parker.
Let's get some air, Peter.
- Dad, we need to talk.
- Yes, we do.
Thank you for having me. I
am sorry if I insulted you.
It was not my intention.
- You're welcome.
- Branzino was real good, Mrs. Stacy.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Dad.
- Yeah?
Well, that was something.
I am sorry. You know I thought he was
going to arrest me at one point.
No, I wouldn't have
let him arrest you.
- What happened to your face?
- I want to tell you something.
Okay.
I have been bitten..
So have I.
Okay.
Okay, okay, okay. Okay. Okay. I
got to tell you this one thing.
I got to tell you this
thing about the vigilante
and the car thief. Alright.
Oh, okay.
What?
- No, no, no.
- I don't want to talk about that.
Okay, no. Forget that. I am
not going to talk about that.
- I am going to talk about me, okay?
- What about you?
It's important. I
wish I could just..
I can't. It's hard to say.
Just say it. I don't know.
Say it.
What? What?
What?
Okay, then forget it.
You..?
- You're Spider-Man.
- Shut up.
Gwen?
Gwen..
Your father wants you to come inside.
Right away. Okay. Okay? Yeah.
Gwen.
I am coming.
Oh, I am in trouble.
Will you please go and find
out what is going on, Alfred?
Excellent.
Hey.
Hey. What is that? Oh, my God.
I don't know.
Get back in the car.
Help.
Incoming..
Somebody help.
Help me. My kid is trapped.
I want my dad.
Dad. Hey, hey, hey. Help.
Hey, buddy. It's okay.
Get away. It's all right.
- Help..
- Hey, look.
Just a normal guy, all right?
Want to hold this?
Hold my mask.
All right.
What's your name?
Jack?
- Yes.
- Let's get you out of here.
Okay, stay very still.
All right.
Okay, I got you.
Okay, now look. I am
going to undo the belt.
You hold on..
to that seat in front of you.
Okay. On three?
- All right.
- Okay, one, two, three.
See how easy that was?
You did a great job.
All right, okay.
Jack, climb now. I can't.
Yes, you can.
Put it on, the mask.
It's going to make you strong.
Jack, trust me.
Put it on.
There you go. That's it. That's it, buddy.
That's it. Okay, now, climb.
Come on, Jack.
Do me a favour. A little
faster, okay, bud?
You're doing great, buddy.
You're doing great.
That's it. Keep coming.
Keep it coming.
Keep coming.
No..
Jack. Oh, God.
Thank God.
You okay?
- My son.
Oh, my son.
My son.
Who are you?
Spider-Man.
Beautiful.
Settle down, guys.
Settle down, boys. Settle down.
- Come on.
- Listen. At approximately..
9 p.m. last night, an incident took
place on the Williamsburg Bridge.
Much of what occurred
is merely speculation..
at this point. However,
several eyewitnesses..
to the crime, as well
as our own preliminary
findings, have
positively placed one..
individual at the scene.
Which is why, this morning..
I am issuing an arrest warrant..
for the masked vigilante
known as Spider-Man.
And lastly, city council members met
with homeowners and airport officials..
in the first of four
meetings scheduled..
It's so beautiful.
Knows how to bite though.
Who else knows about this?
Just you.
Really?
Hey, you don't, you don't..
You don't believe what the
police are saying, do you?
Of course not.
Does it scare you?
What you can do?
No.
What did that thing on
the bridge look like?
It was real big. Too
big to be human.
You got to lay low.
No, can't do that.
You have got to.
I mean, why..?
Because of last, last night.
Those people on the bridge.
Whatever was attacking them
would have killed them.
So.. I got to go after it.
That's not your job.
Maybe it is.
I really liked kissing you.
And you're an amazing kisser.
Well, you know, it was..
It was good for me too.
Yeah?
Who did that?
Hello.
It's not nice to snoop.
I gave everyone the week off.
Yeah.
Shouldn't you be at school?
No, I got a free track. I
wanted to ask you a question.
How would a predator
track a reptile?
Oh, they don't. Most reptiles are at the
top of their respective food chain.
Kings of their domain.
They got to have
vulnerabilities, right.
Why the sudden interest
in the cold-blooded?
Just asking a question.
I got school stuff.
Biology profiles to do.
So because of the cold blood would they
react to sudden changes in temperatures?
You'd have to catch one first.
Did you know there's a rumor
of a new species in New York?
Beautiful and quite large.
What do you know about it?
You seen it?
No, it's not yet classified.
But it can be aggressive..
if threatened.
Doc, you all right?
Never been better, Peter.
Never been better.
Now, if you will excuse me. Afraid I have
to ask you to leave. I have a new project..
I am working on. I
need to be alone.
- Good. Good, good.
- Good.
Don't worry, Mr. Parker.
I will be back.
Wonderful things are coming.
Wonderful things.
Fred?
Mr. Mayor, I can assure you
if there was a giant dinosaur
running around the streets of Manhattan
you would be the first to know.
So tell your son he can
rest easy, all right?
Yeah. You and me both, sir.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Mr. Parker, why are you not in school?
Got a free track.
Okay, well, I do not have a free track.
So make your point quickly.
Okay. Fine, there may not be a
dinosaur running around Manhattan.
But there is something more
dangerous, and I know who it is.
You know who it is? Dr. Curtis Connors.
Of Oscorp? He's a biochemist.
That's right. Okay. Dr. Curtis
Connors who's also my
daughter's mentor. Is that
who you're talking about?
- That's the one.
- Okay.
You know recently, Dr. Connors gave
Gwen a glowing college recommendation.
It was beautiful. When
I read it, I cried.
But you would have me believe
that he in his spare time..
is running around dressed
up like a giant dinosaur?
Not dressing up and not a dinosaur. He has
transformed himself into a giant lizard.
Let me ask you a question.
Do I look like the
mayor of Tokyo to you?
I am telling you the
absolute truth.
This man has worked for his whole
life on cross-species genetics.
He lost one arm, he tried
to grow it back, but
there was something imbalance
about the equation.
And he has turned into a full lizard.
He's using lizard DNA.
He is dangerous, and he is planning
something horrific. I know. I know.
Okay. All right, I get it.
Here's what we are going to do.
You are going to go back to hanging
out with the citizens of Tokyo.
And I am going to go back to protecting the
citizens of this fine, fair city of ours.
Sergeant Butler, would you
please escort Mr. Parker..
back to school. Captain Stacy,
I am not messing around.
Just bring him in. Just call him in.
You have to call him in.
He is a danger to everybody. Just,
please, listen to me. Let's go.
Jimmy.
Get me everything we have
on Dr. Curtis Connors.
Okay? Right away. Yeah.
Subject: Dr. Curtis Connors.
Current temperature: 89.7,
steady for 48 hours.
Blood panels reveal lymphocyte and monocyte
readings consistent with subject's past.
Clotting rate vastly improved.
Marked enhancement..
in muscle response..
strength and elasticity.
Eyesight similarly improved.
Subject no longer requires
corrective lenses.
This is no longer
about curing ills.
This is about
finding perfection.
In attempt to redress
regenerative relapse
dosage has been increased
to 200 milligrams.
You stopped me once.
You won't stop me again.
I am getting stronger every day.
Oh, that sucked.
Peter Parker.
Come in.
You should maybe consider
coming in through the lobby.
Also, my father is
under the impression..
that you require psychiatric attention.
Oh, really? Peter.
What happened? What happened?
You should see the other guy.
The other guy, in this instance,
being a giant mutant lizard.
Hey, Gwen, honey. Do you want cocoa?
Howard's making some cocoa.
No, Dad, I do not want cocoa.
Honestly, I am 17 years old.
Okay.
I just thought, I remembered
somebody saying last
week her fantasy was to
live in a chocolate house.
Well, that's impractical.
And fattening.
Chocolate house.
Sorry, Dad. It's good. I just, I can't..
have cocoa right now because I am working..
I am doing this..
I have cramps.
I feel kind of pukey and just
sort of like, emotional.
It's okay. I keep crying.
Good. Good.
It's brutal.
You don't want to know. I got it.
Trust me, it's, like, bad.
- Thanks, Daddy.
- All right.
Easy, Bug Boy.
What'd you call me?
I am going to be all right.
No. No. Yes. Yes.
I know what this is.
What is it?
Every day, for as long as I
can remember, my father..
has left every morning and he's
put a badge on his chest..
and strapped a gun to his hip.
And every day, for as
long as I can remember..
I haven't known if he was
going to make it home.
I got you.
Okay?
I got to stop him, though.
I have to, because
I created him.
What do you mean?
I gave him an equation..
that made all of this possible.
Something my father had
been working on, you know.
Secretly. Now I realise
why he kept it a secret.
Point is, this is
my responsibility.
I have to fix it.
Peter.
Hey.
Let's get out of here.
Let's just get out of here.
Just for a minute. Can we?
No. No. Yeah. Yes.
Yes. No. Yes. If my parents
see me leaving, I am dead.
Your parents aren't going
to see you leaving.
Peter Parker.
Spider-Man.
I am not the one who needs help.
There will be no more
loneliness no more outcasts.
Species-wide distribution could enhance
humanity on an evolutionary scale.
One has to adapt to survive.
"That, changing like the
snake, I might be free..
to cast off flesh wherein
I dwell confined."
Would you give it all up after
all you know you can do?
All the power you feel.
I can save them.
You are not going to get in the
way of my plan Peter Parker.
Go. Go.
Nowhere to hide, Peter.
All these souls lost and alone. I
can save them. I can cure them.
There's no need
to stop me Peter.
You're not thinking
straight, doc.
Stop this. This isn't you.
Let's talk this out.
Doc.
Oh, boy.
Alright. You don't want to talk?
There you go.
Don't..
make me.. have to..
hurt you.
That is disgusting.
Gwen.
I am going to throw you out
the window, now. What?
Somebody's been a bad lizard.
This is Lieutenant Williams
from the New York City..
Police Department. We have got
this building surrounded.
Alpha, let's move ahead. Go.
- Hey. Where are you?
- I am fine. I am okay.
I am down the sewer. I am tracking him. I
got to stop him before anyone gets hurt.
But we need an antidote.
Do you know how to run a serum?
Yeah, I do it
for Connors all the time.
OK, great, great. OK.
Listen, I need you
to go to Oscorp.
I need you to access the
cross-species file.
It's a blue serum.
File 12389. Okay, got it.
On my way.
I spent my life as a scientist trying
to create a world without weakness..
without outcasts.
I sought to create a stronger human
being but there's no such thing.
Human beings are weak, pathetic,
feeble-minded creatures.
Why be human at all when
we can be so much more?
Faster. Stronger. Smarter.
This is my gift to you.
Oscorp.
- Captain Stacy.
- What?
We have a confirmed sighting, sir.
The Lizard's headed..
toward Canal Street Station.
What about Spider-Man?
Inside the high school. I want
that Spider-Man off the street.
The lizard creature has
released a biological agent.
All efforts to stop him
have failed and he
is now proceeding north
on 7th Avenue. Over.
- Hi. Hey. Where are you?
- Peter, hi. I am at Oscorp.
You have to get out of
there right now. Okay.
- The antidote is cooking.
- No, no, no. Connors..
is on the way. He's
coming to you right now.
He needs the device. He's going
to infect the whole city.
Eight minutes left.
You're going to wait there
for 8 minutes after
what I just told you?
People are going to die.
You leave right now.
That is an order, okay?
I will get everybody out.
Did you hear what?
Gwen. Gwen. You Mother Hubbard.
Are you serious?
He's heading south.
Stand down now, or
we will open fire.
You are surrounded.
There is no escape.
Go, go.
Clear.
Clear up top.
Clear, sir.
All clear here, sir.
Freeze.
Down on the ground.
Your hands behind your head.
Now.
Parker.
It's headed to Oscorp. And your
daughter's there right now.
You got to let me go.
Hold your fire.
Well, Paul, if I didn't see
it, I wouldn't believe it.
I won't venture to say exactly
what it is that's crawling up..
the north side of
the Oscorp Tower..
but clearly it is not human
and it is very, very strong.
Time remaining: one minute.
Antidote complete.
Oh, man. We're now getting
the latest details.
This is just coming in.
The New York Police Department has
called for a city-wide evacuation..
everything south of 54th Street.
If you are south of 54th Street, you have
to move out of the area immediately.
Spider-Man appears to be
heading towards Oscorp.
He looks injured and it's really not
clear if he's going to make it.
That's the guy who saved
my boy on the bridge.
Troy, they're clearing us out.
Something bad's going
down in Midtown. Hey.
You still friends with Matthews, that
crane operator down on 6th Avenue?
- Yeah.
- Get him on the phone for me.
The cops are evacuating everybody.
Who the hell cares?
Get him on the phone for me.
Hey, Charlie, get me
Enrique: on 54th Street.
- You got it.
- Angelo, get your mug over here.
Wolski. You're getting
some overtime.
All tower cranes on 6th..
swing your jib arms over the avenue.
Boom angles at 90 degrees.
Spider-Man needs those big
boys high and lined up.
Let's give him a clear approach.
Over.
Come on, Parker.
Hey.
Dad. I have to get this to Spider-Man.
Get in the car. Let's go.
- No, no. It can stop the Lizard.
- Get in the car.
- You don't understand.
- Yes, I do.
Your boyfriend is a
man of many masks.
I get it.
Give me this.
Get in the car.
Please make sure he's okay.
Initializing Ganali device.
Detonation in T-minus
two minutes.
Poor Peter Parker.
No mother, no father..
no uncle.
All alone.
He's not alone.
Detonation in
T-minus 45 seconds.
Hey. Gift from Gwen.
- I got this, Peter.
- Go.
T-minus.. 30 seconds.
Detonation in
T-minus 10 seconds.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
No..
The captain.
Captain.
The Lizard.
It's okay.
We stopped him.
Okay. Let's get you out of here.
Come on.
Okay, okay, okay.
Look at me. Stay with me.
- Help's on the way, okay?
- You need to..
You need to be gone
when they get here.
Okay?
I am not going anywhere.
I was wrong about you, Peter.
This city needs you.
Here.
You're going to need this.
You're going to make enemies.
People will get hurt.
Sometimes the people
closest to you.
So, I want you to promise
me something, okay?
Leave Gwen out of it.
Promise me that.
You promise me.
An eerie calm has set
in over New York City.
Apparently, some sort of aerosolised
antidote was launched from Oscorp..
Tower, which seems to have
counteracted the biotoxins.
Residents of Lower Manhattan
can rest peacefully..
knowing that the alleged
mastermind of this terror..
plot, Dr. Curtis
Connors, is behind bars.
We have got John Niles on the street
for a report in Lower Manhattan.
John, what do you see?
[INDISTINCT TV CHATTERING]
[INDISTINCT TV
CHATTERING CONTINUES]
Sweetheart, it's all right.
It's all right.
Rough night.
It's going to be all right.
Where have you been?
Hi.
My father died.
There was a funeral.
They shot off..
rifles and they made speeches.
Two of my teachers showed up.
And Flash showed up.
Everyone was there but you.
Can't do this. Can't do this.
I am sorry. I can't..
What are you saying?
I can't see you anymore.
I can't.
He made you promise, didn't he?
To stay away from
me, so I'd be safe.
- What a pretty girl.
- Yeah.
That's what Uncle Ben said.
Did you ask her out?
Why?
Can't.
I am just no good for her.
Peter Parker, if there's one
thing you are, it's good.
Anyone has a problem with
that can talk to me.
Peter, I know things have
been difficult lately..
and I am sorry about that.
I think I know what
you're feeling.
Ever since you were
a little boy..
you have been living with
so many unresolved things.
Well, take it from an old man:
Those things send
us down a road.
They make us who we are.
And if anyone's destined for
greatness, it's you, son.
You owe the world your gifts.
You just have to figure
out how to use them.
And know that wherever they take
you we will always be here.
So come on home, Peter.
You're my hero.
And I love you.
- What's up, Parker? What's up?
- Hey. How's it going?
You coming along, man?
Cool shirt.
Yeah.
Dude's crazy.
But chicks dig him.
Come on, guys, you heard the bell.
Get to class.
I had a professor once who liked
to tell his students that..
there were only 10 different
plots in all of fiction.
Well, I am here to
tell you he was wrong.
There is only one:
"Who am I"?
Mr. Parker.
Tardy again.
Well, at least we can
always count on you.
Sorry, Miss Ritter, won't
happen again, I promise.
Don't make promises you
can't keep Mr. Parker.
Yeah, but those are
the best kind.
Okay, class, open your books.
Let's begin on page one.
Hello, doctor.
Did you tell the boy?
Tell him what?
Did you tell the boy the
truth about his father?
No. Well, that's very good.
So we will let him be for now.
You should leave him alone.