Outside of the world you know...
There exists the realm eternal.
Asgaard.
The shining light of the
nine worlds.
Asgaard is home to the gods.
All of them who bow down before the all father...
Odin.
Odin's life blood flows through Asgaard,
And Asgaard is Odin.
His power is all and
he keeps the Asgaardian realm safe.
But once each winter the all father
must rest...
and enter the Odin sleep.
While Odin slumbers his absence
leaves Asgaard vulnerable.
And this is when the wicked
descend upon his kingdom.
For seven days an onslought of trolls,
giants, dark elves and demons...
seek to take control of the nine worlds.
But they are eternally defeated
By Him!...
My arrogant, Oafish, brute of a step brother...
Thor.
I don't understand.
Where am I?
Here me, Human.
You have been brought to Asgaard
Because in all the Universe...
Only you have ever brought near defeat
to the mighty Thor.
What?
I couldn't.
Not thee, Bruce Banner.
You are but a snivelling, sad creature.
I speak of your other half.
I speak of the Hulk.
There is one day left in Odin-sleep.
The cycle is nearly complete.
As always the Asgaardians will emerge
victorious against the seige of darkness.
My brother will seek peace,
And then,Then I shall destroy him.
Verily we must say that was
far better than the last winter.
Tell us, Volstagg, are you going
to dispatch that troll beneath you...
or are you saving it for dinner?
That all depends on how much need I partake in.
Did my ears deceive me?
Did Hogan the grim make a joke?
And here we thought you were in a foul mood
because you didn't get to slay a frost giant.
I've still slain more than thee, Fandral.
Well we shall see who the
maidens reward more.
In a mere hours the all father will awaken
then we may all rejoyce.
Your lady Siff, would know what vexes thee.
Aye, we won the day.
All is well in the realm of Asgaard.
But only untill the next Odin-Sleep.
-It is as it has always been.
We must learn to savour
the moments of peace.
And accept the cycle of death?
How many of our brothers and sisters
have fallen to this madness?
Must we be chained to
this eternal struggle?
Be careful what you wish for my love...
But when the cycle does break,
when things do change...
then comes the end of days.
Then comes Ragnarok.
Perhaps our fates are not ours to choose.
Then come, let us return to
my fathers palace...
prepare for his awakening.
Please I'm begging you.
Don't do this.
I've fought all my life
to keep the Hulk inside.
You don't know the destruction he can cause.
Don't know?
You fool.
I'm counting on it.
Look at you.
so weak.
Were it not for you inside the Hulk's mind
suppressing his power...
He would rule Midgaard
with his rage.
I won't let him out.
I won't let you do this.
You won't let me?
How amusing you mortals are.
Now let me see if I recall correctly.
It is anger that unleashes the beast?
I seem to have forgotten the
frailty of mortals.
Look Amora I do believe he's going to...
No.
That is impossible.
Now.
And so begins the end of Thor.
You wouldn't thing thee, Balder?
One last troll with dreams of conquest?
Perhaps.
Come Hogun, Fandral.
Let us give it to this scoundrell the gift of battle.
The creature's power is incredible.
Take care Loki.
My spell bonds you to the creature...
and while you are master to it
I can feel him fighting you.
You have to listen to me.
It can't be controlled.
Do not try my patience worm.
Must I turn my attentions to thee.
You are no troll, monster.
That is Balder's horn.
But this is not right.
Asgaards enemies are all defeated.
- And yet the alarm has sounded.
Stay at Odin's side.
Should I fail to meet this threat
You must protect him.
If Thor should fall,
What Hope has Asgaard?
You will have to kill me monster...
For I shall not yield.
Thor, the creature like nothing
I've ever seen.
Aye, my friend.
This is no immortal evil that we face now.
The Hulk has come to Asgaard.
Dr. Banner, can you hear
me inside the beast?
Why have you come here?
Why to kill you of course.
Dear step brother.
I have waited an eternity for this.
To crush you with my bare hands.
To match your might.
To feel your life fade away as my hands
wrap around your throat.
Never.
Come to your new master, Mjolnir...
And let us smite my step brother.
For there are none stronger than Loki now.
Rise Cussed hammer.
Loki enough.
Your own rage fuels the beast.
I can feel the spell breaking.
I will, have this hammer.
Neh, you will have its thunder.
For Odin.
For Asgaard.
The monster, it is raging carnage.
It has shattered the spell.
The Hulk is free.
Will thou yield, Loki?
Truly this is the best of both worlds.
I need not control the beast
to enjoy it's wrath.
Goodbye, brother.
This...
This is not what I wanted.
There's no going back Amora.
After all, if not for your black broken heart
none of this would have been possible.
You don't know what you've done.
With no one to bring the Hulk in,
he'll tear down your entire world.
I find your prattling useless mortal,
just as you are now useless to me.
For Odin.
For Asgaard.
Thor,
My love.
I...I was angered,
When you chose Siff over me, I did not.
I wanted thy love, not your death.
Please,
Please come back to me.
Amora,
- Yes my love?
Where, is Loki?
What is that monster doing?
He travels towards Odin.
Loki,
I would have words with you.
No, You were at Hela's door,
I defeated you.
You,
You dare cross the god of...
The Hulk will be sent back to Midgard
and then you will answer to Odin.
Fine, Take the creature,
It provided me with amusement enough...
Seeing it pummel you nion to death.
Loki you fool,
You killed him.
Do you know what you've done?
Because the mortal died here
Hela claimed his soul.
Without his soul I cannot
return him to Midgard.
Without Bruce Banner, The Hulk
cannot leave Asgaard.
Valkeries, Wariors...
Your seats in Walhalla are promised.
Protect Odin with your lives.
For Asgaard.
I saw the beast's eyes brother.
It will not stop untill all of Asgaard is destroyed,
Untill Odin is broken.
You have bought a new Ragnarok down
upon us all.
It's possible I made
a poor choice.
Amora, I need you by Odin's side.
Protect him along with Lady Siff.
As you wish.
Loki, you will send whatever dark forces you have left
to battle the Hulk.
Then you and I,
we go out to help destiny.
Rest your weapons, Shieldmage.
I've come to aid thee at Odin's defence,
At Thor's request.
His request You say?
More likely his penance, witch.
No doubt he saw your hand in this attack.
A punishment more cruel than you can imagine cow.
Loki, The god of mischief bids
you death mortal creature.
Long have I wished never
to see this realm.
I always forget what a busy time the
Odin sleep is for my daughter.
Does thou see any newly arrived
friends here, brother?
Have a care, Loki.
Unless yee stay here.
Where am I?
No, this
Doesn't make any sense.
Bruce?
Are you OK?
Betty?
I thought...
I don't understand.
I was alone, and then...
- Your not alone Bruce.
Not any more.
Daddy.
Come play with me.
Hail, Hela,
goddess of the dead.
We seek an audience.
The sons of Odin risk much
entering my realm.
The nine worlds of Asgaard are in
great peril, mistress...
including Hell and Niflheim.
A new Ragnarok is upon us
and we need your help.
We need Bruce Banner.
The mortal soul is mine, Asgaardian.
As yours nearly was this very day.
and may well be again
You would risk everything for the sake of one soul?
- Just as you would, Odin's son.
But you do not have one soul daughter.
you have half a soul.
You have Bruce Banner.
You'll need the Hulk to
complete your prize.
Are you alright?
I feel...
I feel great.
I can't imagine anything better.
Bruce Banner.
Awake from this dream.
Betty?
Where are you?
The world of the living has need of you.
Who are you?
What do you want with me?
Not I.
He.
Friend Banner, for the sake of all Asgaard
you must become the Hulk once more.
Betty?
Where is...
No.
No. you can't ask me to do that.
I finally had peace.
You don't know what your asking.
Your time in Hell
certainly has not made you less of a worm, mortal.
Bruce Banner, I know thee to
be a man of honour, I know.
Thee to be a hero, the lives at stake are
not your concern, not even human.
But I ask you anyway, be that hero now.
No, I can't.
Die beast.
The Hulk's soul is rightfully yours, daughter.
Take it bring the Hulk to hell merge the
two halves of his soul and claim him.
I will not force you to forsake me
the rewards of the after life
But you must be whole.
- No. I won't, you don't understand.
No.
Curse you Loki, for convincing me
to bring this creature to my realm
stay thy hand Hela.
We shall retrieve the Hulk.
We? the Hulk's fists have Addled
your mind thunderer.
Fight with me brother, or die alone.
Not much of a threat,
considering we're already in hell.
Have that thee.
My apologies.
I was enjoying the performance.
Let them go.
I'm the one you want.
Come on.
Hulk...
Tired.
You called him weak, Loki.
But there is more strength and
courage in that man than you will ever know.
This soul is too dangerous to keep in Hell...
And to valuable to lose to Walhalla.
I will return him to Midgaard.
Enough of this Ridiculousness.
To think that loki, prince of darkness, should
waste his time defending Asgaard.
Nay brother, we leave together...
For you still have much to answer for.
Indeed you both do.
For today Hela has Relinquished a soul...
And she demands one in exchange.
You may try to take my soul death Goddess,
But I will make you fight for it.
And your realm has suffered
much already this day.
You speak the truth.
so I shall take his soul instead.
Thor.
I'v helped you.
I could fight you for Loki's soul.
- will you?
He is my father.
His day will not be eternal.
But know this Odin's son:
your soul will be mine.
And I will keep it forever.
Your fate is Inescapable.
We shall see.
Thus the cycle begins anew.
Asgaard is safe once again,
defended to the end by it's heroes...
I am proud of each of you that stand before me..
The day was saved by loyalty and sacrifice.
We honour those who fought beside us.
Those who are know longer with us.
and we defy those who would
see us brought to ruin.
And while the rewards of Walhalla await all of Asgaard's
heroes, this day we honour a hero of Midgaard.
A mortal who sacrificed everything
for a land not his own.
This day a human showed
the gods what legends are made of.
Hail the mortal,
Bruce Banner.