One must be a sea to receive a polluted stream
without becoming impure.
Lo, I teach you the Overman.
He is that sea.
What's the problem?
Did you drink too much last night?
I can hold my liquor much better
than you, servicemen.
That's just the rookies,
and if you're not careful,
you might end up like them,
barfing your guts out inside your suit.
Watch and learn!
I'm about to do some
maneuvers only big boys can pull off!
You'd better give up and admit defeat, Rhodey!
Your War Machine is all about firepower,
not speed. It's too heavy!
You might as well admit it.
You're never going to catch me!
Just watch me!
Gotcha!
You keep forgetting one thing, Tony.
It's not just speed that counts here,
I'm an Air Force pilot
with a whole lot of experience.
I have years of training under my belt,
in actual combat conditions!
You're a novice who only just got his license!
No fair, shooting repulsor rays!
You said you were experienced in tactics!
You didn't see that coming?
Imagine if outbreaks of violence,
murder, and terrorism could all be
detected and prevented
before they ever took place!
It sounds like science-fiction,
but it's not.
We're here to introduce
the new Howard satellite,
developed by Stark Industries.
This technology will enable the
S.H.I.E.L.D. detection program
to monitor every event and the full range
of human activity, all over the planet.
But there are those who are already
calling it the ultimate spy satellite.
Privacy-rights
advocates have demanded
that Stark Industries scrap its deployment.
Tony Stark responded to those accusations
in his presentation last night...
I named this satellite "Howard" after
my Dad, who always watched out for me.
It's a tribute to him.
And for a particular reason.
He believed in the concept of personal freedom.
The Howard satellite has not been designed
to infringe upon that right.
Instead, it's an all-seeing
eye in the sky with one job,
to identify and prevent trouble before
it occurs, 24 hours a day.
Once it's launched and activated,
it will provide relief to the victims of crime,
and protect countless lives all over the world.
Tony Stark, the CEO of Stark Industries,
who is also known as Iron Man,
is claiming the launch of his new satellite
will provide endless benefits
to ordinary citizens...
With many questions unanswered, there is
much anxiety over potential
violations of privacy...
People are wondering whether they're
able to trust this man, who has
a background as a weapons dealer.
There is an undercurrent of anxiety that
the satellite was developed for some
secret purpose.
There are those who say there is
great danger in putting all of
our faith in technology.
Who will be in control, man or machine?
Here comes Tony Stark in his Iron Man armor,
and Colonel James Rhodes,
flying his War Machine!
Obviously, they are
both here to reassure the public.
Glad you're still alive.
Not as much as me.
Who the hell are these guys?
They're targeting the Howard.
I've run into these bastards before.
They're armored mercenaries who call
themselves the "Raiders."
They must be paranoid that we're gonna be
able to track their activities.
They're jamming the radio waves!
Data interrupt!
We've lost communications!
Scramble our lnterceptors
and get them out there.
Rhodey! Great work!
It's time for us to have
a little chat, my friend.
If you answer nicely,
you might survive this interview.
You'll be in prison, but at least
you'll still be alive.
Am I supposed to be scared?
My boss is more powerful than you.
He's far surpassed your capabilities.
He's that good, is he?
Maybe I can find a job for him in my company.
We'd have to settle a few things first,
like a claim for damages.
We've only just begun.
My boss is going to smash
your satellite into pieces before
you have a chance to play with it!
If he's that powerful,
why is he so afraid to show himself?
Oh, he's here.
Rhodey!
Take care of this guy, will you?
Hey!
Have all staff except necessary
personnel evacuate immediately!
We're about to launch the satellite!
Yes, sir!
Who's there?
Only authorized personnel are allowed in here!
Fuel update!
Complete, sir!
Launch pad status!
Ready to go!
Fire flow complete!
Countdown continuing.
25...24...23...
22...21...20... 19...
Wind speed, eight miles per hour!
Purging energy supply pipe!
- All systems are green!
- Acknowledged!
Good morning.
Huh?
And goodbye.
Huh? What the heck?
Unknown phenomenon.
No reference in the database.
Possible presence of erosive biological cells.
No one escapes.
I won't let you do it!
Power is down.
Energy reserves at 55%.
Who is this guy?
Insufficient data.
Genome DNA extract impossible.
Cannot read base sequence.
Unknown gene region.
Centrifuge is required to continue analysis.
You must be some kind of monster!
How could you sacrifice so many lives
for a single satellite?
Hey, you! Say something!
The leaders of all fascist companies
appear to have similar eyes.
The eyes of smartass kids also seem the same.
People who place their faith in
high-technology, like you,
should be placed in museums
with the rest of the fossils.
Actually, coffins would be better.
And kids who are all mouth, like you,
should be sent to the Stark School
of Re-Education.
I am Ezekiel.
Ezekiel?
I promise you, I will be dancing
around your coffin as they
drive in the final nail.
I will then hold a wake in
the offbeat style you so favor.
I'm not done with you yet!
Goodbye.
Shoot! What the hell is this?
Tony, where are you?
What happened down here?
What's going on in this place?
I'm done on my end!
Tony, are you down here somewhere?
Don't come any further!
What? Are you in trouble?
What's that? Tony!
I don't believe this.
The control tower's gone!
Any signs of life?
I'm afraid not.
Wait! I see some movement
down in the rubble!
It's Tony Stark!
He made it out, sir!
Iron Man is alive!
Send Black Widow to pick him up!
And hurry! We need to
debrief him immediately!
Come on!
Where are you, Rhodey?
Come on! You've got to be here somewhere!
I'll find you,
no matter how long it takes!
If you're alive, answer me!
Natasha!
Help me find Rhodey! Please!
Stark! There's no time to waste,
we have to get out of here.
Fury has ordered me to escort you
to the helicarrier.
The medical team will continue
to search for survivors,
but casualties are expected to rise
to more than 300 people.
Nick! Rhodey died!
Right in front of me!
And so did a lot of other people.
Who the hell were these guys?
All their signals were blocked
by a very powerful electromagnetic field.
I was hoping you could give us some guidance.
He was a smartass kid.
His armor was weird.
It was very advanced,
I'll tell you that is something
I've never seen before.
It was techno bio-organic matter,
combined with manmade mechanisms!
Techno bio-organic armor?
I'm gonna find that guy.
And when I do,
I'm gonna make him pay for Rhodey!
Nick! What's going on here?
What are you up to?
You're not leaving this complex, Stark.
Not until S.H.I.E.L.D.
has worked out exactly what's going on.
Are you suggesting
I had something to do with this?
We have more questions.
What happened just now
is being broadcast everywhere.
It's being played out on every news channel
on every television across the planet.
If we don't provide an explanation
some high-up heads at the Pentagon
are going to roll.
Just routine procedure, of course.
Business as usual.
They have enough heads.
Believe me, they can afford to lose a few.
That's not the most important thing now.
We need to get hold of that kid before
he causes any more damage.
And that's exactly what I'm gonna do!
Go after him.
Nick! Will you call
off your pit-bull?
For God's sake!
I don't have time to mess around!
That's too bad.
I'm the only one who has a chance
against that
smart-ass kid's technology!
You probably won't believe it,
but I'm telling you the truth,
I'm not enjoying this one bit.
There are rules.
And whether you like it or not,
I happen to be duty-bound to obey them.
There'll be hell to pay if I let
our only witness get himself killed.
You government workers sure have a tough job.
Homing missiles locked on and tracking.
Thanks a lot for the update!
Wanna play?
Commander, he's gone!
We've lost him!
Natasha?
Sorry, Natasha.
Stark!
I need to teach that kid
the greatness of technology.
I'm going to have to find out
where its weaknesses are.
How's the art coming?
I'm still working on it.
I love art, but I don't
intend to become an artist.
After all this time playing around,
I realize I don't have the talent
for it like my uncle.
You shouldn't give up in frustration.
Your body has the DNA for it.
There's something I've finally come to realize.
Even with talent, you need chaos
to give birth to a dancing star.
I'm not sure I have it.
Someday, man will no
longer give birth to any star.
By the way, I see they managed to launch
the satellite after all.
The Raiders couldn't control
the reinforced functions I gave them.
However, it's still early in the game.
I'll be preparing another offensive.
Tony Stark.
He seems to be in possession of
a wide range of technological icons.
And one of the high-tech graven images
these people
place on an altar to worship,
is his new satellite.
He's the high priest of technology.
Yes.
But it's a conceited and foolish
misunderstanding.
Technology and the people who give birth
to it are nothing more than false idols,
leading society to disaster.
It's a tiresome task.
But these people must be taught the truth.
Huh?
I need your help!
Excuse me?
Check the black market
for bio-related products.
You promised me a full week's vacation!
And anyway, aren't you supposed to be in Utah
for the launch of that new
satellite you developed?
I'll make it up to you, Pepper.
I'll tell you what.
This year, you can
have the villa and a whole support staff.
Thanks, but you already gave me that to
make up for losing last year's vacation.
I did?
Okay, then how about I rent you
an entire village or something?
Please, Pepper. It's urgent.
What's going on here?
I'll tell you inside.
How long is it before the Howard goes online?
Everything should be active within four hours.
We're going to use
that satellite to find its maker.
As of now, priority one is capturing
the fugitive Iron Man.
Poor Rhodey.
I can't believe it.
I can't believe he was such an idiot for
letting that kid get him.
I could've taken care of myself.
He didn't need to come looking for me.
You're saying the killer was a child?
Yeah, some know-it-all kid!
There was something about him, though,
that was very intriguing.
The bottom line is,
if he was able to create a technology
that I've never seen or heard of before,
he deserves a little respect.
His sense of design isn't really my cup of tea.
But his results are.
As you know, I've dealt with some
shady vendors in the past.
But Rhodey was the exact opposite.
He was a straight arrow.
All the time
I knew him, he never broke the rules
or left the straight
and narrow. I admired him.
He really believed in the dream.
Rhodey was a government worker
and a normal person.
I'm nothing but a rich genius.
The worlds we lived in were so different,
it's amazing we got along at all.
He was a good friend,
but I'm not sad about it.
I'm fine, really.
It's a shame, though,
that I lost someone to race against.
I guess I should have let him win
some of the times.
Tony.
That suit was made of technology
I've never seen before.
Nanotechnology? Biotechnology?
No.
It was nowhere near as simple as that.
He had inserted the integral DNA
of living organisms
into a material based on the functions
of a human body.
It couldn't be done in
a normal research facility.
Could he somehow be using mutated cells?
No!
He's synthesizing them in a molecule assembler!
If not, it wouldn't be stable.
Tony. I need you
to authorize access.
Stark, vocal authorization.
Nanomachines, nanotechnology.
Here's something on human-mech hybrids.
There's research being done all over the world,
but no one has announced
a practical application.
I haven't heard of any successes, either.
But I have to believe my own eyes.
What I saw was a definite breakthrough.
It merged biotechnology and mechatronics.
Customized artificial neurons were
working in conjunction
with the human nervous system.
He was controlling them perfectly.
A.I.M!
It's a company called Advanced Idea Mechanics
and they're the largest
supplier in the black market.
They've been researching
biotechnological hybrid armors
for a long time, in secret.
In recent years, they've continuously
invested vast amounts of capital.
Does your data indicate where their
research facility is located?
Let me see.
Karachi, Pakistan!
There's a secret lab there!
The facility is being fronted
as a warehouse for medical supplies.
But actually, they're involved with
chemical warfare research and the sales
of illegal weapons.
I've downloaded map coordinates
in case you plan to pay them a visit.
Thanks, Pepper.
You can return to your vacation now.
Are you going to be okay on your own?
A kid misbehaved.
An adult needs to discipline him.
You're a kid yourself, Tony,
an obstinate, stubborn kid.
Are you going to scold me, Pepper?
Why do you keep putting me in that position?
I don't want to be the only adult
in this relationship.
It's intriguing, though.
I find I'm drawn to more mature women.
Especially when they're beautiful.
Darn it.
Tony.
Iron Man is not responding.
All signals are being blocked.
Damn it! Teams Blue and Gold,
cover all escape routes!
Team Red, move in on my
command. Capture and contain!
It's S.H.I.E.L.D.
What did you do this time?
Something awful, I imagine.
I suppose it's too late to apologize.
Confirming
as our target, Mr. Tony Stark.
Checking profile.
Target identified.
Mr. Stark, please throw away your weapons
and surrender immediately.
Please comply.
You can leave your belongings with us.
Sorry, Nick.
I don't have time to waste right now.
I'll pay for the damages.
I have to go.
Fire.
There goes my vacation.
Predictable.
Don't you ever knock
before you enter a room?
All Mandroids have lost position of Iron Man.
Visual monitors are disabled.
Switching to motion sensors.
Hey, boys, I'd love to keep playing.
But I think it's time to excuse myself.
Sorry, Nick, but I had to do
what I thought was necessary.
I think you need to improve
the A-One on the Mandroids.
After facing off with them, I have to say,
they seem a little vulnerable to me!
All Mandroids have been annihilated.
Get me special agents Barton and Romanova.
Right away, sir.
So, Miss Potts.
Is your boss free any time in the near future?
I'm afraid he's fully booked
for the next three years or so.
Of course. Being Tony Stark,
he never follows his schedule.
Then he blames me
when he misses his appointments.
There's something I want to show you.
I was trying to tell your crazy boss about this,
but he appears to be
blocking all communications.
One day he's going to
go off half-cocked,
and run into something
unexpected he can't handle.
They herald the coming
of the lightning, and perish as heralds.
Lo.
I am a herald of the lightning.
I feel good today.
It's so beautiful.
With the Technovores, I will have great power.
I will be able to control any machine,
using the interface built into this armor.
So. Are you ready to go?
Yes. I will now be able to infect
the satellite and bring it down.
We will grind these oppressors
and their techno gods to dust.
It's up to you, however,
as to where you want to use it.
Obviously.
Excellent.
We have a deal, my friend.
Tell your associates
A.I.M. says hello.
What's wrong?
shooot! It's the Punisher!
How did he track me?
We're being blown to bits over here!
You need to send reinforcements right away!
What do you mean, 10 minutes?
Nobody's gonna be alive here in 10 minutes!
We need them in 10 seconds!
What do you think you're doing?
Let me handle this, Punisher.
I don't need help from a company president
who can't stay out of the limelight.
These guys are scum.
They don't deserve to live.
Punisher, I don't disagree with your feelings.
But I need some answers before you wipe 'em out.
I have all the answers I need.
Get out of the way.
If you shoot, I'll blast you from here to Tokyo!
Fine, go ahead.
I appreciate it.
All right. Let's get
this over with while
Punisher's still in a good mood.
I need to know about the men who hired you.
Do you think an A.I.M.
man would give up
the identity of his clients?
Come on, Stark!
You of all people
should know what would happen
if I were to do that!
Let me guess.
You'd never be able to do business again.
Permanently!
I figured.
But thanks for the directory anyway.
Nice work.
So, neo-terrorists.
Techno-organisms, buyers of body armor.
Let's see who you've been dealing with.
Ezekiel?
Ezekiel. Wait a minute!
I know that name!
But I've got a dossier on him,
if it's any use to you.
You're sure about that?
I remember that name, too.
As a friend, you'd let me read that dossier?
Huh! Now you're a friend?
The same friend who threatened to blast me
from here to Tokyo?
I guess our job is done.
Let's get out of here.
How can you drink this coffee?
It's like sludge.
It's military issue.
Drinking it at night in the jungle
used to calm me down.
Actually this place kind of
reminds me of a jungle.
Here's the file. I found it.
Ezekiel Stane...
Stane! Wait!
Obadiah Stane's son?
That would be pretty disgusting.
This nutcase turns out to be
the son of your old partner?
Obadiah went crazy.
I had no choice at the time.
I had to kill him.
Are you telling me he's that Ezekiel Stane?
But he's supposed to have died
in an aircraft accident!
At the age of 16!
His father had a lot of assets
hidden around the world.
Having inherited all that,
I'm sure a clever kid like him
would know how to put it to very good use.
Nowadays, a little cash
can make the impossible possible.
You're right.
There's no denying that.
Looks to me like this kid has been
burying his trail for a lot of years.
And now he shows up in the form of
a sociopathic super-genius.
There are rumors he injected his brain
with nanobots to make himself smarter
than he already was.
According to this, he's involved in
a wide range of shady research.
From synthetic drugs to nanotechnology.
One of his interests
is techno-organic armor.
What a surprise.
He won't be an easy opponent to handle.
I've been after him for six months
and I haven't been able to pin him down.
Let me try something.
What are you looking for?
I'm hacking directly into the S.H.I.E.L.D. network.
I figure if
I cross-reference your dossier
with the data in the network
I might be able to find out where he is.
Computer geeks are something else.
Thirty miles to Karachi.
Log note, I'm briefing Agent Natasha
Romanova, and Agent Clint Barton.
Here's the update, it's been confirmed that
Stark has joined forces with Frank Castle,
known as "The Punisher."
That weapon-crazy lunatic?
Although I hear he's not very good
with a bow and arrow.
I want to get out of this country as
quickly as possible.
If it's discovered
that we're violating the airspace
of a sovereign nation,
it'll cause an international incident.
You have 40 minutes to complete
the mission and get back to the ship.
Shanghai?
I don't get it.
What would he know about a place like that?
We had a weapons research center there,
until I decided to close it down
a few years ago.
Then someone bought the property
and built a luxury hotel there
with a penthouse suite for wealthy VIPs.
The hotel's privacy is as tight as a Swiss bank.
The land itself was apparently purchased
by Obadiah Stane.
You see how effective
a little bit of cash can be?
Thanks for everything, Frank.
The next time I come,
I'm gonna bring you a bag
of the best coffee in the world.
Hello, we've got company!
Oh, boy! I knew
they'd come, sooner or later.
They sure seem to have
a lot of time on their hands.
See you.
Wait!
There is an object approaching from behind.
Is it a missile?
Negative.
Bulls-eye!
Some freakin' arrows caused this much damage?
Conducting system check.
So glad I installed a protective force field.
Give up, Stark, and come with us
to see the Director.
You really think he's going to
come along willingly?
System interrupt.
Initiating forced shutdown.
Hold on, wait a minute!
Stop fighting.
There's no way you can get loose.
You might as well accept it.
The game's over, buddy.
We're taking you in.
Listen, Stark!
In the helicarrier's medical bay is...
Watch out! You're not
too good at this, Stark!
Crap, he's getting away!
Tell me something.
Are you trying to be as obvious as you can?
What do you mean, Stark?
I thought you liked the attention.
Not when I look like five miles of bad road!
Well then, hang on, buddy!
What's your problem, mister?
It's over, Stark!
If you join forces with a crazed
vigilante killer,
no-one's gonna take you seriously
as a hero, buddy!
That son of a gun!
Don't do it, Frank!
They're just following orders!
I'm not trying to kill them!
I just want them to know we're not
about to surrender!
shooot!
You ready?
Leave it to me!
Bingo!
All right, guys!
If you don't want to get hurt any further,
you'd better come out!
We hear you. But before we do,
here's a little gift!
You bastard!
Thanks for the compliment.
Now throw down your weapons
and raise your hands!
Did you hear me?
Good girl.
You, too!
Fine. You jerk.
Don't think you're gonna get away with this.
Bunch of bleeding-heart
S.H.I.E.L.D. weaklings!
If you disrespect me again, I'll...
If you don't want a tunnel bored in your head,
throw your guns away!
Whatever. I don't
need them now, anyway.
I guess I was able to buy enough time.
Power reserves now recovered to 40%.
Good, now go ahead and re-route
force field reserves to thrusters.
Affirmative.
Come back here!
It's no use.
Your arrows won't reach him.
Darn it!
Power reserves fully recovered.
All systems are now optimal.
I've wasted too much time.
I can already hear the boss
dismissing us, sarcastically.
Yeah. It makes me want to bore
a hole into my own head.
You owe me, Stark.
Payback won't be cheap.
I hear a soft breeze.
And that wind gathers another soft wind.
I can sense our destiny.
We come together with that wind.
Listen carefully, Sasha.
Can you hear it, as well?
Jarvis, have you got anything?
Readings are unclear.
There's interference.
Wait, there is a slight reaction.
It could well be a living organism.
That doesn't help me much.
Hey, boy! I came to see you.
Why don't you turn the lights on for me?
When I was young, I played hide and seek.
I hid in the dark garage for so long,
I fell asleep.
After a while, my mom, Maria, came
to look for me.
She was worried sick.
Did your parents do the same for you?
I've never played hide and seek.
Five meters behind you, the air shifted.
And the room temperature changed slightly.
Where did you come from?
Did you use magic?
My mom was very upset by my behavior.
I worried her
with my appearances and disappearances.
If you keep this up,
your Mom will get upset, too.
Or your Dad, if he's still around.
I don't hide from anyone.
You're simply not looking in the right place.
Really?
This is starting to feel
more and more like a kid's game to me.
I told you before,
I've never played hide and seek.
And my Dad that you speak of,
I suspect you know who he is.
You might as well say his name.
Obadiah!
That is correct.
He can summon up a hologram, just like that!
You want revenge?
Revenge?
Why would I want that?
Because I killed him.
You knew that.
Wait, that's right.
You were involved, weren't you?
I remember now.
You'd forgotten that?
It wasn't as important an event in my
life as you might imagine.
We weren't actually that close.
Then why are you targeting me?
Don't be so conceited.
What?
I wasn't targeting you specifically.
It's just that you were standing in my way.
I don't understand.
What are you saying?
But he killed Rhodey.
Even if it was just a prank,
some things cannot be forgiven!
Rapid power decrease.
System error detected.
What's going on?
Synthetic alloys and unknown biological entities
have invaded the system.
Technovores.
Power source and all sensors
have been compromised.
Technovores?
This armor is pretty well made.
Who do you think made it?
I'm impressed.
For someone like you, it's good.
I realize you can't move.
But believe me, Sasha will still be impressed.
Sasha?
This must be your pride and joy.
The arc reactor.
Don't you have anything to say?
Like how you think Tony Stark is a genius?
I must say, it's very well made.
For you people, that is.
What does that mean "you people"?
I'll have you know...
Adam and Eve ate the forbidden fruit,
and as a result, they were expelled
from the Garden of Eden.
And 160,000 years ago in Africa,
Mitochondrial Eve was born.
The ancestor of humankind.
Very impressive.
Did you study the history of mankind in college?
Now there are over
seven billion people on Earth.
What does that have to do with anything?
You asked what I meant when I said
"you people."
That's what I was referring to.
You talk as though you're not
a part of the human race.
That's exactly how I feel.
I think I'm different from the rest of you.
Then what are you?
It's somewhat hard to describe, really.
But if I were forced to explain it in words,
I guess I would be a breeze.
A breeze?
I'm a little confused, can you elaborate on that?
Sasha would also be a breeze.
Who is this "Sasha" you keep referring to?
A girlfriend?
A gentle breeze that caresses your skin.
And ruffles up the grass and trees.
I see.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
But I'm beginning to understand one thing.
Obadiah wasn't a very attentive father.
He let you get lost in a world of dreams.
You represent the dinosaurs of the past.
I, however, represent the future.
Dinosaurs of the past?
You should consider retirement.
That sounds pretty good to me.
I could relax in a nice, quiet place.
In fact, I actually tried that once.
But my personal assistant just won't let me.
This time, I'm afraid I'll have to override her.
You'll retire for sure.
You understand the situation, don't you?
New wind, new future.
A brand new world is created
to go with the brand new future.
A completely new technology will be created.
The old will die out, and the new will be born.
That is the providence of nature.
A superior technology to that of man.
Howard will be the whistling arrow
that announces the new reality.
You should be honored.
The wind that follows is going to blow away
your most advanced technology.
Howard will be the shot that leads the way.
Hey. Obadiah was lucky he didn't hang around
long enough to see this.
New technology, you say?
Technovores, you called it?
Don't make me laugh.
The birth of mankind.
Refinement of steel.
Computers, biotechnology.
The things you call old technology
have all been linked and accumulated
to create your "technovore."
It's not new at all.
The truth is, it's only been born and exists
because of the past.
You think you represent
a brand new form of existence?
You're mistaken, kid.
You're no more advanced than the rest of us.
You were born from human parents.
So?
You're just a petulant child
throwing temper tantrums.
And just like a child, if you've been bad,
it's an adult's responsibility to correct you.
You would do that?
I don't think so.
Be quiet for a second.
Part of the system has been restored.
Where? Search for
the area that's functional!
The missile!
Locked on target.
Foolish man.
Do you know what will be written
on the brass plate
that gets installed on your
exhibit in the museum?
"Here lies
a fragment of Iron Man."
But only if someone is able to identify
those fragments after I blow you up.
You spoilt kid.
I don't want to put the curators of
the museum to that much trouble!
Perhaps if we had had more time,
I could have taught you a few things.
Well, it's time for goodbye, Tony Stark.
There's still quite a bit of work to do.
What's wrong, boy?
Invading technovore now being removed.
Restarting system, restoring circuits.
Energy charge in three, two, one, complete.
What's the matter, boy?
You look like you're in trouble.
Do you need the hand of an adult?
I don't believe I do.
The future is full of uncertain elements.
It's okay for a child to rely on adults.
Send energy to the reactor!
Force field deployed!
Hey, where did you go, boy?
Hide and seek time is over!
You went too quickly.
You can't break me...
And you're unable to change the future
because that timeline's already written.
It's a blessing your father's not here
to witness this all play out.
That's enough, Stark!
It took long enough
but we finally caught up with you!
You're coming in with us to see the Director
or I'm gonna add an extra hole in your head!
All right, William Tell.
You made your point.
I'll go, but only if she takes me in.
You only got 98 on your test?
Without a perfect score,
you're the same as the other idiots!
Go to your room and reflect on your
shortcomings until dinner.
I thought you were much better than this!
You're a disappointment!
Did you listen to me?
I told you never to touch my Monger!
You little fool!
This Monger is worth 10 times as much as you!
My God!
I can't believe what I'm seeing!
Rhodey survived that attack?
Has he woken up at all?
He's being kept alive
by the life-support system
but so far we haven't seen...
Hey, Rhodey!
Rhodey, can you hear me?
If you don't wake up you're gonna die a loser!
You can't die without beating me
in a race at least once!
That would be shameful!
Tony...
Wait a minute! How 'bout this?
If you wake up,
I'll concede the next race to you!
I'll introduce you to a beautiful woman, too!
You just tell me which model on which page
of that magazine you were looking at!
Anyone at all!
Except the girl on page 10.
I've got dibs on her.
Just don't tell Pepper!
Other than that, anybody you want!
Hmm?
All stations!
An unknown program is hacking into our system!
Shutting off communications!
Starting antivirus program!
Initiating defense protocols!
How are the main servers?
We can't stop it.
Someone breached our security
and is invading our systems.
Technovores.
Ezekiel's Technovores are the invaders.
What?
I'm sure the servers have been taken over by now.
It's too late.
Damn it!
He's gone!
Where did he go?
The Howard is under attack!
What's happening?
Initiate Guardian program!
It won't start!
The firewall is about to be breached!
If we don't do something immediately,
all the systems in Howard will be taken over!
I'm right here.
Look around for me.
My, my.
You're not very observant.
I'm right beside you.
Above us!
Are you okay?
Yeah, here's the problem.
Howard has the power to access
every computer in the world.
Including military satellites.
Exactly.
He's planning to make Howard
the source to hack into the world's
military satellites and control them.
Ezekiel called that the wind.
The wind?
He's planning to wipe out
everything that lives on this planet!
What happened to the server room?
I haven't been able to get a response.
Hmm.
Mmm?
Stark!
What are you planning to do?
I'm going to fix the computer so we can use it.
If I can divert the power of the arc reactor
and aim it at the Technovores,
I can annihilate them.
I'm pretty sure I can survive for five minutes
without this old heart of mine.
After that,
I guess it's straight to heaven!
I can't tell the situation from here.
What do you want to do?
I guess we should return to the bridge.
Ezekiel is definitely coming here to target us.
Warning! Warning!
Power reserves decreasing rapidly!
Ezekiel!
He's here!
Hi there, "Old Man" Tony!
Stop this, now!
Where are Clint and Natasha?
They're tucked away safe and sound.
What?
Don't worry about them.
Connect it.
Good, Maria.
Now re-boot the Howard.
Rebooting Howard, sir!
The Guardian program has also been initiated!
You people are determined to try
and get in my way somehow.
Come here. Sit down.
You and I are gonna
have a talk! Right now!
No matter what you think about your father
I can tell you Obadiah loved you very much.
It was a pretty straightforward bargain.
He was human and you were his son!
Was that all?
Isn't that enough?
You'll achieve nothing
if you throw away your history.
I have personal experience.
I was only able
to move forward by accepting my father.
And you'll only create a new world
by accepting the past and building on it.
A relic like you is lecturing me
about the future?
How amusing...
Why should I listen to someone irrelevant?
The Technovores!
Why...
Why are you betraying me?
Together, we could have defeated them.
I can't see anything, feel anything.
Sorry, Ezekiel.
The wind...
...has stopped.
I've lost all instruments!
I have no control over the helicarrier!
It's losing altitude!
Shoot him!
Come over here!
This way, you bastard!
Hurry up, Maria!
Reactor detected.
Power reserve at 15 percent.
I have that much?
That's it, pal.
Playtime is over!
Propulsive force still inoperable!
Too many engines are offline!
Where are we going to land?
Shanghai, China!
Contact the Chinese government!
Have them evacuate everyone!
Tony, what's going on up there?
Power dropping rapidly!
Now entering red zone!
Emergency! Emergency! Emergency!
Well, that's it!
This kid needs some serious disciplining!
System error! System error! Danger!
Is it really going to end here?
Am I done for?
My body won't move.
Rhodey, is that you?
Rhodey...
Guess I must have overslept!
Remind me to reward you later
for waking up, old friend!
Rhodey...
How did he...
Rhodey!
What in the...
Wait, Rhodey!
What the hell...
What's happening?
Whatever it is, we're gonna have to
put an end to it, right now!
Let's go!
Peace to everything.
Fear... Leave it to me,
you powerless immature beings.
I will bring prosperity to all.
I will proceed with salvation for all.
I will break free.
I will realize the salvation of all.
I will merge.
Repeat, technology has already been released.
Stupid...
...has been closed.
Ezekiel!
Power reserves at seven percent!
Red zone!
Re-charge immediately! Re-charge immediately!
What is this guy saying?
Rhodey!
Do you understand what's going on?
We have to conserve our energy resources!
But we can't just let him destroy everything!
Stop wasting bullets!
What are you talking about?
What are we supposed to do then?
I don't know what we can do!
I'm trying to think of something!
...final... universe... reincarnation...
We've lost control of the Howard!
Powerless and immature beings...
Prosperity...
I will proceed with the salvation of all.
He's replicated it!
He's using the Howard to control
all the other military satellites in orbit!
I'm confused!
What's this all about?
Is he planning an attack?
Ezekiel, you said that a new wind
would create a new future.
Is this how you plan to reset the world?
Destroy everything and start all over?
All of the military satellites have been
repositioned!
He's preparing to attack!
... world... technology... I will start...
He's completely insane.
He's going to destroy the world.
Tony, we should save our nail clippings.
What?
To be filed
with our wills. As keepsakes.
I hate to bring this up
but why would we do that?
There won't be anyone left to give them to.
I thought it might be something
Pepper could remember us by.
Wait a minute. Pepper!
Wills...
Leaving something behind...
Of course!
Pepper!
Pepper, can you hear me?
Yes, sir.
Are you focused enough to help me one last time?
Anything but dictation.
You're an amazing secretary
but it's a little more complicated than that.
I'm not surprised.
You can't do anything without my input.
I want to give you a present before I die.
Huh?
What's the one thing
you've never had since I've known you?
What do you truly want, more than anything else?
What do I want more than anything else?
That's easy.
What I want is a vacation!
Vacation. Vacation.
Vacation. Vacation. Vacation.
We're starting to regain control of the Howard!
Good job, Pepper!
I was able to get through Howard's back door!
What back door?
I'm not all-powerful.
I'm an imperfect human
and I realized a while ago
that I had to be careful.
I programmed a back door into the satellite
to protect it from unauthorized users.
When did you set up my voice as the password?
You talked in your sleep
when you passed out at your desk.
I don't remember that.
You wouldn't.
But I was able to uplink my armor
to the Howard at the time.
You've earned that vacation twice over.
Thank you very much,
Mr. President.
The particle-beam
cannon on the Chinese
military satellite is about to shoot!
I'm only able to control one satellite
and I won't have control for long!
I want to show this guy something
I have that he doesn't!
Are you out of your mind?
What are you gonna do?
This is gonna be our last chance,
so listen carefully!
The Technovores are trying to
take over the Howard by hacking in!
How much time do we have?
Tens of seconds, that's all.
I'm counting
on you Rhodey. Okay?
All right, Jarvis, pull the trigger!
Affirmative!
Tony!
Here we go!
Hope your little nap didn't affect your aim!
Aim at what?
All right, it's aligned.
Rhodey! This is it!
You've only got one chance!
Let's do it!
Release the energy of the arc reactor!
The Technovores reacted.
Aim for the crack!
Careful...
All missiles are ready to launch!
Rhodey, we have no time!
You have to shoot!
Do it now!
It's our last chance before the world ends.
Shoot!
All missiles, armed and ready!
Rhodey!
Bear down and shoot!
Everything should work now!
Launching!
Tony!
Yeah, the last thing I can remember
is watching the bombs go off.
I guess the Technovores decided
they needed to repair you
before they could override your system.
And in the process, it looks to me
like they saved your life.
That was fortunate.
Now it's your turn to recover!
At least you'll be taken care of
by a bunch of hot nurses!
I'm glad you're okay, Tony,
but if you do anything like that again,
I'll kill you myself.
I hear you, Pepper.
When a child is bad, you need to scold him.
So, you're finally getting it.
You're an obstinate child...
...who needs discipline.
And it's an adult's duty
to provide that discipline.
Do you hate women who scold?
Not really.
All boys look up to authority figures.
Especially when they're as beautiful as you.
Don't forget, now.
You promised me a vacation.
Of course.
So where do you want to go?
I'll take some days off, too.
What?
Let's take a vacation.
Just the two of us.
How 'bout it?
Is that an order, sir?
No.
It's more like a suggestion.
Well then, I suggest you and I pack up.
The insane man shut up
and looked at the audience.
The audience also shut up and looked at him.
He regained consciousness last night.
He has a visitor today but there's been
no change. He's still
mentally deranged.
He finally threw his light against the ground.
The light shattered and died out.
This tremendous event is
still on its way, still wandering.
It has not yet reached the ears of men.
Deeds, though done,
still require time to be seen and heard.
This deed is still more distant from them
than the most distant of stars.
Still, they were able to do the deed.
According to the people, this insane man
forced his way into various churches
that day singing, "Requiem."
The wind!