MAN: The Incredible Hulk.
Strength, invulnerability,
and a temper that has
made him infamous.
Created by the accidental exposure to
an exploding gamma bomb,
the Hulk is, without question,
the strongest being on Earth.
The power coursing through
his raging body
is exactly what we need.
(GROWLlNG )
But that raging quality
will not make it easy to
bring the Hulk in, Dr. Cruler.
Which is why we´ve employed
the Abomination.
His exposure to gamma energy
endowed him with not
only charming looks,
but skin said to be stronger
than the Hulk´s.
I contest that the Abomination
is just as powerful as his old enemy.
DR. CRULER: I suppose
we will soon test that theory,
won´t we, Dr. Fump?
(OMlNOUS MUSlC PLAYlNG )
(GROWLlNG )
(ROARlNG )
HULK: Hey, fin head!
Hulk...
About time you showed up.
Your ugly mug
scared off everyone, Abomination.
But you don´t scare me.
Time for you to leave.
That´s no way to talk to
an old gamma-powered pal.
l´m not leaving until
l crush you under my scaly fist!
l was hoping you´d say that,
so l can smash you out of town!
(ROARlNG )
l come here for peace and quiet.
What are you doing here?
Just came for the fresh mountain air.
And some mass destruction!
Good people of this town
don´t deserve this.
You´re gonna pay.
DR. FUMP: Abomination, do you copy?
Where is our specimen?
The Hulk just showed his big, ugly face.
Give me five minutes.
Better make that 1 0.
JARVlS: The Mark VI
Hypervelocity Iron Man Armor.
Powered by an arc reactor,
this suit features a gold
titanium composite shell,
quad repulsor projectors,
and various energy weapons
as built and worn by
its prolific inventor, Tony Stark.
You forgot the part about how
l´m a billionaire philanthropist
and ladies´ man, you lousy scrap heap.
JARVlS: Insults are entirely
unnecessary, sir.
They neither motivate me with anger,
nor hurt my feelings.
You´re no fun, Jarvis.
JARVlS: You did not program
my artificial intelligence for fun, sir.
Next system update,
l´m programming less backtalk.
(GROANlNG )
JARVlS: Perhaps it is your armor
that needs a system update.
This training exercise is
nearing its inevitable end.
Yeah, how do you figure?
JARVlS: I´ve completed
my calculations.
Your armor may be faster,
but the Hulkbuster suit is far stronger.
And, in a one-on-one battle,
power overcomes speed
69% of the time.
Don´t worry, my tech has overcome
worse odds than those before.
Not this time, sir.
(GRUNTS ) Ow!
You are incapable of escape, sir.
Please surrender.
Not this time.
Charging the E.M.P.
(EXPLOSlON)
JARVlS: Explosion.
Technical difficulties.
The Hulkbuster systems
have been immobilized.
l think you´ll live, Jarvis.
Yes, if you say so, sir.
Congratulations, your technology
did prove superior to...
Well, your other technology.
Jarvis, nobody outsmarts me
like me.
(GRUNTS ) You´re making me mad,
and the madder l get,
the stronger l get!
And you get sloppy
when you´re angry, too.
Now, you listen to me.
Here´s how we´re gonna do this...
(GRUNTS )
Ouch.
HULK: What, now?
Couldn´t hear you with
your mouth full of my fist.
(EX CLAlMS ) Maybe l overdid it.
Yep.
All that fighting made me hungry.
Then why don´t you chew on this?
(GRUNTlNG )
Now that is homerun.
Now l´m hungry and mad.
Robots? Those war drones?
Hydra. Got a feeling
it ain´t a coincidence.
This town is suddenly bad guy central.
But l didn´t have enough to smash.
(GRUNTS )
(GAS HlSSlNG )
(COUGHS )
So cute. Sleeping like baby.
That wasn´t so hard after all.
DR. FUMP: Especially when you didn´t
have to do the hardest part of the job.
Hey, l got him here.
DR. CRULER: Regardless,
the cost of those war drones
is coming out of your pay.
Now, the least you can do
is bring him inside.
ABOMlNATlON:
l hate working for Hydra.
DR. FUMP: We heard that.
(GROWLlNG )
ABOMlNATlON: This place
need dog catcher.
(SNARLlNG )
Honey, l´m home.
Stand down. Stand down!
Dr. Cruler, the specimens.
Our fuel supply has finally arrived.
Excellent.
The arc reactor
has completed its target phase.
All right, you ghouls,
where´s my reward?
Oh, it´s coming. We assure you.
You can put the Hulk
in the fuel containment cell.
What´s the other one for?
Why, you, of course.
(GRUNTS )
(COUGHlNG )
Put him in the other cell.
l still don´t believe
we have enough shielding, Dr. Cruler.
My calculations are correct, Dr. Fump.
The reactor core was built to
absorb enormous green energy.
We had a deal!
Brought you the Hulk!
What do you want with me?
Why, you´re special, too.
The rare gamma in you two monsters
has the potential
to supercharge our new arc reactor.
Thanks to you,
Hydra will have the power
to create a weapon
capable of destroying
all our enemies.
Yes, the siphon is working.
Prepare to charge the reactor coil.
Prepared and standing by, Dr. Cruler.
On my mark.
Now.
(REACTOR POWERlNG UP)
(GRUNTlNG )
DR. FUMP: lt´s working. lt´s working!
Energy levels have already
surpassed our expectations.
lt´s more powerful than we imagined.
(MACHlNE BEEPlNG )
Oh, no! We´re losing containment.
ls that a reactor?
What are you eggheads doing?
You´re gonna cause a meltdown!
DR. CRULER: He´s right.
We´ve got to power off, now!
Failsafe shutdown circuit isn´t working!
lmpossible. The polarity has reversed.
lt´s not generating electricity, it´s,
it´s draining it!
DR. FUMP: From where?
DR. CRULER: Everywhere!
JARVlS: Another suit of armor
in need of repair.
What a surprise.
TONY: Well, your sarcasm
is working just fine.
Why don´t you make yourself useful
and check for emergency alerts?
Sir, there´s been a power outage
you should be aware of.
There´s blackouts all the time, Jarvis.
The more energy people use up,
the less there is to go around.
The source of this blackout triggered
your regional gamma energy monitors.
Gamma? Get me a satellite view.
That power plant is emanating enough
gamma energy to wipe out the state.
So, you were right.
Of course I am.
Yeah, you´re right, but l built you,
so that makes me righter.
Put that in your next update.
Hey, Jarvis,
you better pack up and follow me.
l might need our radiation
containment gear when l get there.
Cross your fingers l won´t.
JARVlS: Virtual fingers crossed.
I´ll be right behind you, sir.
(ALARM SOUNDlNG )
DR. FUMP: lt´s building
to critical mass, Dr. Cruler!
DR. CRULER: l´ve tried everything.
There´s no stopping it now, Dr. Fump.
Don´t give up, Dr. Cruler.
Dummies! l told you so!
Let´s go.
Sorry.
(GRUNTS )
(EX CLAlMS )
(GRUNTlNG )
Let´s get you out of there.
You´d do the same for me, right?
-(GROANlNG )
-Yeah, right.
(SCREAMS )
(BOTH GROANlNG )
How... How are we still alive?
Because there was no explosion.
Then where did all that energy go?
lt must have imploded
back into the core.
lt almost looks alive.
(SCREAMS )
Do you realize what we have here?
Yeah. A rather unfriendly pet
comprised of 1 00 gigawatts of power.
We also have a living energy weapon.
We must capture it.
l knew there was some reason
l enjoyed working with you, Dr. Cruler.
l´ll fetch the energy guns, Dr. Fump.
Yes, and hurry.
(GRUNTlNG )
Still breathing, scale-face?
Get off of me.
(GRUNTS )
Where are your manners, creep?
l just saved you.
(GRUNTS ) Well, aren´t you
the boy scout.
(GROANlNG )
(SCOFFS ) Ought to get a badge for that.
Hulk.
l said, leave me alone.
(ROARlNG )
-lron Man?
-Of course.
Fly all the way over to
investigate a gamma surge,
and what do l find?
My favorite big, green anger problem.
What do you want, lron Man?
And l didn´t do anything. lt was...
lt was the invisible man.
Aw, nuts.
Hey, now.
Where do you think you´re going?
Get out of my way.
Listen, Hulk, l know we´re friends,
but you need to relax, or l´m...
Or nothing, Stark. (GRUNTS )
That was just a tap.
You gonna calm down so we can talk,
or do l need to turn it up to 1 1 ?
Maybe, after l turn
your armor into a soup can!
(GROANS )
You may be strong, but l can fly,
shoot repulsor beams and, yeah,
l own a flying fortress.
Anything you do, l do better!
Let´s put that to the test, shall we?
(SONlC DlSRUPTOR SOUNDlNG )
(GROANlNG )
l can make loud noises, too.
(GRUNTlNG )
(GROANS )
Ha! All those gadgets and doodads
and still you´re not so tough.
(GROANS )
l can do this all day, green.
Too bad you can´t fly.
Oh, too slow.
Get down here!
No thanks.
l can smell your Hulk breath from here.
(GRUNTlNG ) Uh-oh!
Oh, what? Nothing funny to say?
Okay. l´ll talk.
You´re always ready to blame the big,
green guy when things blow up,
but l didn´t even
cause the problem here, Hydra did.
Hydra? Those guys are always
trying to take over the world.
What would they want with a tiny
energy plant in nowhereville?
Hmm, still registering
a lot of gamma energy inside the plant.
Okay, okay, timeout.
l said timeout.
l heard you.
Like l was saying,
my power and all the other power
was drained into the plant.
Why didn´t you
just tell me that in the first place?
Whoa!
l was trying.
Oh, l wanna punch you right now.
Hey, big green,
why don´t we ask
questions first this time? Smash later.
You´re one to talk.
DR. CRULER: There it is. Blast it.
DR. FUMP: lt´s just too fast
and powerful.
Quick, activate your grounding circuit.
Whoa!
lt discharged my energy gun.
(EX CLAlMlNG )
HULK: Okay, the spark ball´s new.
TONY: Jarvis, what are we dealing with?
JARVlS: I have no record of this energy,
however, its composition
is consistent with a primitive life form.
Those things aren´t flying on their own.
These robots will be fun to break.
l´ll just pretend they´re you.
Yeah, well, good luck with that.
(ROARlNG )
Hear that roar?
That´s my stomach.
You´re getting in the way of me filling it.
Back off.
(GRUNTlNG )
Looks like you could use a hand.
l don´t need a hand, chrome dome,
but l´ll take a leg.
Whoa!
Not what l had in mind.
Works for me.
Come closer, so l can smash you.
Hulk, behind you.
Be quiet.
Ow!
You´re welcome.
Uh-oh, looks like
they got their act together.
Don´t worry, l´ll take them apart.
(GROANlNG )
Do something, Stark!
lt´s draining my power.
Jarvis, charge the E.M.P.
JARVlS: Sir?
An electro-magnetic pulse
will release energy.
This creature feeds on energy.
So, if we overfeed it,
maybe we can give it a stomach ache.
(E.M.P. SOUNDlNG )
So much for the spark ball.
See? You do need me.
lt´s true. You make a good club.
Looks like those two
Hydra goons escaped.
l´ll find ´em.
This reactor is based on my design.
Of course, their big mistake,
trying to power it with
the energy out of you.
What´s the matter with that?
Gamma is a dangerous,
unpredictable energy source.
Made me the man l am today.
Exactly my point.
JARVlS: Sir, your facility has arrived.
Your timing is perfect, Jarvis.
We got a lot of work to do.
Hulk, l´d say it was
nice seeing you again,
but it really wasn´t.
Jarvis, the armor´s acting up.
JARVlS: Shall I run a diagnostic?
Hold on.
And we´re back.
You know what never glitches?
Fists.
Let me know when
your fists can do this.
Jerk.
Jarvis, clear your calendar.
JARVlS: At your service, sir.
First order of business,
we use the ship´s arc reactor to
get the power grid back online.
At least we can light up
a few thousand homes.
Very good, sir.
Shall I employ the mandroids?
You read my mind.
Have them salvage what they can
out of that reactor on the ground.
Hulk is hungry!
Oh, great.
So, where´s the kitchen
in this flying cruise ship?
You can have dessert
when you finish your chores.
l need you to clear
the debris down there.
The only thing l´m looking to clear is
the food out of your fridge.
This is the fridge, right?
Oops.
No, it was part of the computer
systems that handle my security.
Nice, Hulk.
Hey, l can´t help that
it looks like a fridge.
Well, guess l´m outta here.
Hulk, look.
You´re supposed to be a hero.
You can´t be on the run,
alone, all the time.
Better than floating up here
in your iron castle, alone.
Not the same thing. Trust me on that.
l need time alone,
to invent, to build things.
Next time, build a kitchen.
Fine, if you´re not gonna help,
don´t let the door hit you in your big,
green butt on the way out.
Have fun cleaning up after Hydra.
JARVlS: Warning, computer systems
have been compromised.
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
Jarvis, shut down all the systems now.
Jarvis! Shut them down now.
I´m sorry, sir.
I´m afraid I can´t do that.
What?
Huh? Uh-oh.
Huh?
Human creatures!
I am Zzzax!
Nice one, bolts for brains.
You let the spark ball in the machine.
Hey, hey, it´s not my fault.
Tricky little zapper stowed away.
Now it´s teaching itself
at an exponential rate.
Zzzax must feed
on energy!
All energy!
Listen, sparky... Or Zix, Zzzax.
Whatever your name is.
Humans rely on energy, too,
and we can´t survive without it.
Humans not worthy.
Humans waste energy.
We don´t want to waste energy.
We´re trying to conserve, to get better.
We´ve even created
renewable power sources.
Now, come out of there,
like a good little spark,
and l´ll give you a couple of nine
volt batteries to chew on.
Less talk, more smash.
Hulk, wait, it´ll just stow away
somewhere else!
Like my armor. Shields up!
Hulk, it´s coming your way!
(BEEPlNG )
I see you.
Gotta squash that spark fast.
Ow!
Humans not stop Zzzax!
Hulk, don´t let that mandroid escape.
This thing gets any more power,
it could end up unstoppable.
Only l´m allowed to be unstoppable.
Maybe l shouldn´t
have built so many mandroids.
You think?
(ROARS )
Stupid dome heads.
(GRUNTS )
How is this fair?
Oh, man.
Hulk, could use a little smash
right about now.
Smash your toys?
You don´t have to tell me twice.
(ROARlNG )
Oh! Puny robots.
Hulk smash!
TONY: Green, behind you.
(ROARlNG )
Stay cool, buddy.
Only one left.
Need more power.
Zzzax must feed.
Sparker´s making me mad.
Spark won´t like me when l´m mad.
Jarvis, you back online?
JARVlS: Bit of a job, sir,
but right as rain now.
Zzzax is trying to get to my suits.
Defense mode now.
JARVlS: Working on it, sir.
Jarvis, seal them up.
Last one. Get the last one, Jarvis.
Oh, man, it got into the Mark ll.
That´s, like, my third favorite suit.
ZZZAX: This shell
will serve Zzzax!
JARVlS: Remote power down failed, sir.
l don´t know
how many of these things you need,
but one less ain´t gonna matter.
(ROARS )
(GRUNTlNG ) Get off me,
you big, green ape!
Thanks.
l think you only broke two or three ribs.
That thing can´t get enough power.
Gotta be going after the reactor.
Can´t you shut it down?
JARVlS: Shutting down the arc reactor
would also shut down
the turbine engines,
sending the entire craft
plummeting to imminent destruction.
Then lock it down, now.
Engaging arc reactor force fields.
l´ll make a short cut.
TONY: Do not let it past us.
(SCREAMlNG )
lron Man, blast him!
You know,
that suit´s kind of a collector´s item.
Shellhead!
All right, firing unibeam.
Phew, nice save, Hulk.
lf that thing would´ve
gotten into the reactor,
we would have been in a world of hurt.
HULK: Oh, l would´ve
smashed us out of it.
TONY: Wait. What´s that sound?
No!
Jarvis, power down the reactor!
TONY: Ah!
l got this.
(STRAlNlNG )
What´s it doing now?
lt´s evolving.
lt´s copying us.
Which means we´re probably
in deep trouble.
Hey, electric breath!
Let´s see what you do with repulsors.
(GRUNTlNG )
You eat them, apparently.
Zzzax
destroy!
Jarvis, tell me you got something.
JARVlS: The creature is pure energy.
I´m afraid it has no weakness.
lt must.
Wait, what´s this thing´s frequency?
JARVlS: Zzzax´s frequency
is 96.2 megahertz.
l´ve got an idea.
Retune the repulsors
to a matching modulation.
lt´s time we kicked
that creep´s high voltage butt.
(ZZZAX GROANlNG )
(SCREAMlNG )
(GRUNTS )
(GROANlNG )
lron Man!
Jarvis?
Stark, you okay?
JARVlS: Power at 1 2%, sir.
Recommend immediate recharge.
TONY: Duly noted.
Hulk! Here he comes.
(GROANlNG )
Hulk.
(GROANlNG LOUDLY)
Now,
Zzzax destroys!
BOTH: Whoa!
(GRUNTlNG )
Hulk, you... (COUGHS )
You okay?
(GROANlNG )
Everything is dark.
l can´t see.
lt´s okay.
lt´s only... lt´s only temporary, green.
lt´s UV damage to your cornea.
They call it welder´s blindness.
Me,
my armor´s leg servos are damaged.
l can´t move.
Looks like we´re in a cemetery.
A creepy, disturbing cemetery.
Good thing l don´t believe in omens.
(GROWLS )
(SNARLS )
(GROWLlNG )
Guess l spoke too soon?
(GROWLlNG CONTlNUES )
(SNlFFlNG )
What´s that smell?
What´s going on, Stark?
You´re not missing much.
We´re just about to get eaten
by a few hungry something or others.
Jarvis, what are we up against here?
JARVlS: Based on my scans,
these creatures appear to be
the Wendigos, sir.
A legendary cursed beast
rumored to consume
anything in its path.
No need to fret.
The Wendigo tale
was created to frighten children.
They do not actually exist.
(SNARLS )
That´s not helping, Jarvis.
(WENDlGOS GROWLlNG )
Get behind me.
l´m not exactly going anywhere.
(REPULSOR FAlLlNG )
Hulk, duck!
Punch, right.
-Behind you.
-(GRUNTS )
Dodge, back!
Where are you, Stark?
Under your big, honking foot.
You mind?
l´m not crazy about organ failure.
Got an idea.
You can be my eyes.
l´m not a backpack, Hulk.
All right, here they come.
-From where?
-From everywhere.
(WENDlGOS SNARLlNG )
Hulk...
Smash, left. Forward... No, duck!
Big uppercut.
This is better than a video game.
Help, Stark.
Okay, okay. Grab, right.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
(ROARlNG )
TONY: That´s right.
Good, good, just scream it all out.
The Wendigos are gone?
TONY: My armor scanners are down,
but yeah, l think so.
You know,
we don´t make such a bad team,
when we´re not
smashing the snot out of each other.
Hmm, maybe.
(ENGlNES POWERlNG UP)
Hold up. My facility´s on the move.
What´s going on, Stark?
TONY: Zzzax is pretty clever
for living electricity.
He´s positioning
the ship right over the power plant.
His creation caused a blackout,
so l figure he´s going to use the plant
to reach the power grid to somehow
suck up all the power he can,
like a giant electric leech.
But why not just come down?
Drain it straight from the generator.
Zzzax has to stay in the air.
What?
What happens to a lightning bolt
when it hits the ground?
lt hits the ground and loses its charge.
Hulk, you´re a genius.
Or, well, definitely, you know,
smarter than you look.
Yeah?
(GRUNTS )
But then again,
you´d kind of have to be.
Don´t make me step on you again.
So, you got a plan, metal britches?
l´m thinking, l´m thinking.
We gotta get up there somehow.
HULK: Can hear him buzzing.
He´s not far.
You think you can Hulk-jump us
back up onto the ship?
lf you can be my eyes.
Oh, great. (GRUNTS )
Whoa! Easy, green.
All right, we´re gonna leap straight up
into the facility, you got me?
Angle yourself 40 degrees left.
Forty degrees, what?
Even if l wasn´t blind, l wouldn´t know
what you´re talking about.
Just turn left.
A little more.
That... No, too much. There you go.
Okay, steady.
Launch!
(HULK GRUNTlNG )
TONY: Okay, all right.
What do you say
we try that one more time?
(BOTH EX CLAlMlNG )
(STRAlNlNG )
Close enough.
You know those planes cost me
50 million bucks, right?
They´re not worth it.
Now just tell me where to go.
All right, all right.
About 1 00 paces left.
(GROANS )
Your other left, genius.
And try not to make a racket.
(CRASHlNG )
You know, you´re about
as stealthy as a T. rex.
Little help.
Okay, you´re gonna want
to turn left up here,
in three, two, one...
Ow, ow!
Okay, l think we´re finally here.
lt only took half the night,
but we made it.
Yeah, next time, you get
zapped in the face and carry me.
Okay, l get the point.
All right, look, there´s a cable to
recharge my arc reactor with
beside you.
You´re gonna want to plug it into
the unibeam projector in my chest plate.
That´s my head.
Lower, a little lower.
Okay, l think you got it.
Now go to the left.
Ow! My left.
Ow! Right. Okay, your left.
(ARC REACTOR POWERlNG UP)
l´m gonna slip into some work clothes.
Just, uh...
Take it easy, Hulk.
Stark, can you fix my eyes?
l´ll do my best, big guy.
Just give me 30 seconds
to armor up, okay?
(ELECTRlC ZAPPlNG )
The Mark Vll armor.
What do you think, Hulk?
Did you forget l can´t see?
Right. Well, l´m wearing a new suit.
lt´s untested and probably a little buggy,
but it´s got better shields
to keep Zzzax out.
Jarvis, you remodulate the repulsors?
JARVlS: All energy weapons
have been tuned to 96.2 megahertz,
which will repel the
creature´s frequency.
All right.
Now it´s time to fix you up, big green.
How´s the vision?
Uh...
Everything´s still kind of blurry.
You´re familiar with laser eye surgery?
Now hold still. This won´t hurt a bit.
Easy as one, two...
(GRUNTS )
Hey!
Eyes work good enough to see.
l don´t need a laser zapping them.
l´m trying to help.
Look, l know we got off on
the wrong foot today,
with me blasting you and all,
but we´ve got to work together on this.
Comprende?
This is bigger than both of us, Hulk.
l know that, Stark.
Thanks for trying to help.
No problem.
All right, so here´s what
l figure´s happening.
(HULK CLEARS THROAT)
Zzzax is gonna use my ship
like an antenna
and drain all the power from Earth.
We can´t destroy the grid.
We´ll leave millions of people
in the dark.
But we can bring Zzzax down
and ground him
if we take out my ship.
Crash your iron castle, huh?
l like it.
So, what are we waiting for?
Let´s get smashing.
Ho, hold up, Hulk.
You want sparky to
zap your eyes again?
We need to insulate you somehow.
You got something Zzzax can´t fry
in my size?
l think we do, with a little tailoring.
l named it the Hulkbuster, after you.
Well, what do you think?
(ELECTRlC ZAPPlNG )
(ROARlNG )
Zzzax consume all!
TONY: Consume this!
l don´t think so.
Smash?
Smash.
Stupid gizmo! (GRUNTS )
Easy there, cowboy.
Gotta steady yourself.
Not as good as smashing,
but not bad either.
Let´s see you drain Earth dry
when l bring down your condenser.
Shields.
Sparky doesn´t miss a thing.
Humans inferior!
Zzzax superior!
He´s tricky for living lightning,
l´ll give him that.
Hulk, use your gauntlets.
Smash him back to sparksville.
How?
Your gauntlets are tuned with the same
frequency as Zzzax, so punch away.
Ah, with pleasure.
Finally, time for some Hulk smash.
Keep it up, mean green.
l´ll take out the turbines.
Full power to unibeam.
One down.
JARVlS: Unibeam recharge
in 90 seconds.
Speed up the process, Jarvis.
Redirecting power from
the repulsors now, sir.
(BEEPlNG )
l´m gonna go check on big green,
see how he´s doing.
Quit standing around
and crash this thing, Stark!
l´m working on it!
None may stop Zzzax!
TONY: How we doing on that unibeam?
JARVlS: Thirty seconds, sir.
Humans are all parasites!
Turn my ship against me, huh?
JARVlS: All threats eliminated,
and the unibeam is back online, sir.
Huh?
JARVlS: My mistake, sir.
More missiles incoming.
(GRUNTS ) Outsmarted by
a 50-foot ball of static.
(ROARlNG )
(SCREAMlNG )
That´s cutting you down to size.
Stupid bolt!
(GRUNTlNG )
ls that all you´ve got, sparky?
TONY: Hang on, Jarvis, we´re going in.
JARVlS: But, sir,
all weapons are targeting us.
l know, but we´ve gotta
take out that second turbine.
That´s it.
That´s it. Just a little closer.
(GRUNTlNG LOUDLY)
Two turbines down, one to go.
JARVlS: Sir, I feel compelled
to remind you...
That there´s still a missile chasing us?
l know. l´m gonna use it.
JARVlS: The odds of this
risky maneuver
successfully working
a second time are extremely low.
l told you, Jarvis,
l always beat the odds.
And there´s Zzzax,
frying off Hulk´s face again.
Time to shut off the power.
Hey, sparky.
You didn´t pay your electric bill.
No!
Yes!
TONY: What have we gotta do?
We´re going down.
Hulk, we´re gonna smash into the dam.
You gotta turn this thing.
l´m on it.
Not what l had in mind, Hulk.
How we doing, Jarvis?
Sir, the facility´s
trajectory has changed.
The dam is safe,
but the ship will be destroyed.
l can live with that.
There´s my green pal.
You okay?
(GROANS )
We get him? Zzzax finally gone?
Maybe. l don´t know.
HULK: We gotta find him.
That thing needs
to constantly feed on energy.
Hear that?
Hmm, what´s this?
Hulk, get away from there.
Gotcha.
(ROARS )
Stop him.
Zzzax!
You´re grounded.
Hulk!
l got him, lron Man. Stay back!
Yeah, right.
Hulk!
(GROANlNG )
Zzzax...
Hulk, are you...
l´m okay, lron Man.
Been through a lot worse.
(COUGHlNG )
Lights out for spark man, huh?
Hulk, that was the stupidest, craziest,
bravest thing l´ve ever seen anyone do.
The town is still dark.
Not for long.
l´m gonna power the entire seaboard
with green Stark reactors.
At least until this mess
is straightened out.
Free of charge from Stark lndustries.
Jarvis, ship out a dozen mobile facilities
to key locations
throughout the tri-state area.
JARVlS: Anything else I can attend to
while you relax?
No. l´m good.
Hulk? You need anything, big guy?
Well, since you asked...
Look, l know what you´re gonna say.
Teaming up with you made me realize
l can´t always rely on tech.
No, l was gonna say, l need...
To be alone. l know.
You say it all the time.
But you also need
to keep in touch, okay?
Any time you need a friend,
big guy, l´m here.
(GRUNTlNG )
Why are you staring at me like that?
´Cause you never listen!
l´ve been trying to say l´m hungry.
l want food.
Oh... Right.
Uh... Well, l know this little diner
30 miles down the road.
Best cherry pie in the state.
Best idea you had all night.
Last one there pays the check.
(YELLS )
(ROCK MUSlC PLAYlNG )
Dr. Fump, Dr. Cruler,
your catastrophic failure is inexcusable.
The Commander will
have your heads for this.
(HATCH OPENS )
COMMANDER: On the contrary.
Their expertise is necessary for a much
more ambitious plan.
HYDRA is going to force
the world to its knees.
And Captain America
and lron Man are going to help us.
Or be destroyed.