Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
It's me, Peter Parker.
The helpful neighbor...
I have a long way since
I was bitten by a spider...
When nothing seemed to go right,
but now... people love me.
It starts soon!
Everyone feels safe.
I think I have a part in it.
Uncle Sam would be proud.
- I go to school yet. Top of the class.
- This shows us-
- The energy levels are disturbed
of tension...
The shape of this
matrix, we can see...
- Ms. Stacy.
- The only M = 0 quantity has impact.
Right! Good job, Ms. Stacy.
- Do you have something to add, Parker?
- No, sir.
I'm in love with my dream girl.
AVAILABLE FOR INSTALLMENT
Ms. Watson put aside a
ticket for me. Peter Parker.
I'm so nervous.
She is my girlfriend.
- I thought she was good.
- Yes.
Harry... Harry!
I have to talk to you.
So that I can explain.
Tell that to my father.
Revive him.
I am your friend, Harry...
I cared about your father.
- MJ Congratulations!
- Peter.
- Was I good?
- You were great.
I love flowers.
Those are from Harry. Was he here?
- I ran into him.
- What is it with you?
- It's complicated.
- Tell me again that I was great.
I was so nervous that my knees were shaking.
The applause was not as high.
Well, it depends on the acoustics. Diffusion
prevents Ijudvågorna to propagate.
- When Ijudvågorna moves forward...
- You're such a dork.
Did you see it?
I would like to sing in the rest of
my life with you in the front row.
I will be sitting there.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
I love you so much.
I've always done.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
RETURNED MAIL
- You can not hide here, Flint.
- I just want to see my daughter.
You are a prisoner on the run.
Police are looking for you.
You will not be near her.
You are simply a thief.
- You may have murdered a man.
- It was not so.
I had good reason. It's true.
You and the truth is in prison
and get three meals a day MAI.
I live a life of genuine truth.
The truth did you leave behind you.
Inside the bedroom.
- I missed you, Betty.
- I missed you too, Dad.
I promise that I will
to make you healthy.
- I'll get the money.
- Get out of here right away.
I'm not a bad person.
I've just been unlucky.
- What is it, Peter?
- It's MJ
I intend to marry him.
I was so scared and excited
When Ben proposed to me.
And very young.
But I loved him so much.
- You said well yes?
- No. We were not ready.
So we took our time. Looked forward to it.
We could not just rely on charity.
A man must be understanding.
His wife should come before anything else.
- Can you do that, Peter?
- I think so.
Then you have my blessing.
I hope you have found
a good place to free on.
Your uncle had planned everything.
He took me to the beach.
He was really great in their swimwear.
I did not look so bad yourself.
We were good at swimming.
It was a beautiful day and he said:
"If we can not swim to the island?"
When we got there...
... We found a perfect location next to
an old tree. We lay us down...
Then he said: "Close your eyes, May."
Then he said: "Open them."
Then he held in this ring.
It glittered in front of me.
I thought it was the sun.
We had been married for 50 years
in August, if not...
So... I hope you make it
very special for Mary Jane.
Do something that she will never forget.
Give her this.
Come on, take it.
- Harry...
- You knew this was waiting, Pete.
I did not kill your father.
He tried to kill me but killed himself.
I'm still here, Peter.
I hate those things.
Harry?
Oh my God...
Harry!
- Exceptions.
- No reaction.
- We will try again. Away.
One more time! Move!
- Police Commissioner Stacy.
- What is it?
Flint Marko who was involved in
the murder of Ben Parker. He has escaped.
He is in the research.
I think we have him.
There he is!
WARNING!
Testing ground for Particle Physics
Where'd he go?
- It is uploaded.
- Silicone mass has changed.
It is probably a bird
flying away when we get started it.
- How is he.
- He can handle himself.
He suffers from memory loss.
Especially short-term memory.
He does not remember accident
or something happened to him recently.
- Is it permanent?
- Maybe. Only time will tell.
- He is awake, if you want to meet him?
- Maybe I should wait?
Was not there a long time only,
he must be rested.
- Hey, buddy.
- Hello.
I have been struck in the head.
I was in an accident, the doctor said.
I will hardly remember anything.
My father is dead, right?
Everything feels so strange.
Hello. I came as fast as I could.
- You know me again.
- How are you?
- The last I remember...
- We love you, Harry.
It feels like... I have
been gone a very long time.
- Now I'm home again.
- It's nice to have you back.
- Excuse me, but you have to go.
- Sure.
- We see you tomorrow?
- Of course.
I think he will be fine
and you seem to be up again.
- You have wonderful friends.
- They are my best friends.
I would sacrifice my life for them.
"Restaurant Constellation."
"Monday 19:30."
- Yes?
- It's me.
- I can not open the door.
- Has it got stuck again?
- Come and help me.
- I will.
Review. They hated me.
- They can not.
- "Young ms Watson" -
- "You can rest your eyes on
but not the ears. "
"Her thin voice reached
not past the first line. "
- Ridiculous, I was there.
- You sat in the front row.
Yes, but... You were great.
It's just a critic.
You have to get used to this.
Believe me, I know.
- Spider-Man hit by it all the time.
- This is not about you.
- It's all about me and my career.
- Yes, I know. You can not just let...
... It beat you down. Believe in yourself,
and you're up on the horse's back soon...
Do not talk on horseback!
Try to understand how I feel.
It's just that...
When I read this...
it seems to be written by my father.
All cars near 54th
and Sixth Avenue.
Uncontrolled crane.
Draw close with caution.
Take them by storm, tiger?
Sorry.
Crane job is bigger than we thought.
We need backup immediately.
Gwen, I have a secret.
It's my copier.
What makes it there in my background?
- They can not stop the crane.
- Call the Edison!
Tell them to break
power to the entire block.
- Are you all right?
- Here it comes again!
- Good God. It's Gwen.
- What?
- What is she doing up there?
- She said something yesterday about a modeling job.
- Who are you?
- Edward Brock Jr..
I work for the Daily Bugle...
and is dating your daughter.
- Are you okay?
- Yes. Just great.
Hey, Spidy! Bugle want a picture.
- Thank God you feel good.
- Hello. I'm the new guy.
- New guy?
- Are you okay?
- From now on, I take the cards for you.
Le. Do you smile? I am just kidding.
- Where is the other guy?
- Are you Parker?
Between me and you,
he is an amateur.
His stuff made you look a little...
puffy out. A little chubby.
You do not
to worry about anymore, buddy!
Dazzle me!
A small thing advertising guys
and I came up with.
Bugle has had a pretty good edition.
Not as good as the New York Times...
... Daily News or The Post or...
- Go on, you idiot!
Blood pressure, Mr. Jameson. Your wife
asked me to keep track of your anger.
Tell my wife...!
Thank you.
So I suggest this campaign,
"Daily Bugle", of course.
"It's hip and relevant."
It occurred to me.
"The 'wow'." It's Eric
after a few cups of coffee...
"And how." It was me again.
Time for your pills.
Not so. Not so.
Drink plenty of water.
Thank you.
Continue.
- He is busy.
- I am here for you, big guy.
- What's that smell?
- Something called "Nice and easy-trapped"
- What are you wearing?
- It's called "Embark"
It was the dumbest idea you've had
and you've had a lot of stupid...
You may not go in there!
- Who are you?
- You hired him last week.
- What's that smell?
- Edward Brock Jr..
Nice shirt. A crane accident.
Check Ijussättningen.
- He likes my shirt.
- Hey, Pete. You better go in there.
The new guy trying to sell
Spideybilder.
Thank you.
Parks! You may come too late.
Bruckner, this was faster.
- I have it here.
- But he has this.
- How could you take it so high?
- Climbed on a flagpole. Almost fell.
- A flag pole?
- What should we use?
I like Bernstein.
Better and cheaper.
- Congratulations! You get $ 50 for the image.
- I'm your guy, JJ.
I know more about photography than most.
It's not about - do not be offended-
- Flagpoles, but Ijus,
composition and drama.
I want an editorial job.
I'm going to marry a girl-
- I have a dream to work for the
best editor of all time.
J. Jonah Jameson.
We have a vacancy.
Johnson finished course.
- You kicked him.
- Wait a minute. I can shoot-
- And have been here long. Is there a
editorial job I deserve it.
He's right, Jonah.
Peter has worked for us for years.
- He has done a good job.
- You want the job both.
- No one cares about what I want?
- I do it.
I want people to see Spiderman
as the villain he is.
He is a scam and full of glue.
Take him in the act.
With your hand in the cookie jar.
Anyone who takes the picture gets the job.
Are you waiting for Chinese New Year?
Get out!
- The image, never.
- We'll see.
Spiderman MAY CITY KEY...
Save the life of police chief DAUGHTER
I believe that a human
can mean a lot.
Enough said.
Welcome home, Harry.
- Thank God you feel good.
- Thanks, Bernard.
I have a welcome home gift.
It's your old ball. Thanks, buddy.
- We were pretty good in the backyard.
- We were miserable.
- We tried to get into mixlaget.
- For cheerleading girls sake.
- Do I have any girlfriends?
- I do not know.
- Do I have any girlfriends, Bernard?
- Not that I know of.
- Pretty cool house, right?
- That's good enough.
- I seem to have plenty of money.
- Yes.
I think I can
change this with a girlfriend.
I appreciate how you helped
me through high school.
I wish I could remember more about him.
He loved you, that's the main thing.
We watch the match in the kitchen
and jaws something.
- Did you see that?
- You can move around still.
Why do you think?
- What is she doing here?
- Gary would have called her agent.
Hello, darling. We have tried to reach you.
I am sorry.
- Because of a critic?
- No, because of all the papers.
- Mary Jane, sit...
- We can say that you got sick.
- It was so badly managed.
- Yes. Now we repeat.
- Sorry MS, I get a beautiful smile.
- Hi, Eddie.
You are so beautiful.
These are the headlines.
- I have to practice. See you later.
- Tonight, perhaps.
- No, not tonight.
- Why not?
Think of the amazing night we had.
We drank coffee, Eddie.
Hey hottie! One more.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, just fine.
- You're not mad at me still?
- No, Peter. I'm proud of you.
I'm going to swing me up from there.
How do you know where to look.
- Give them a good show.
- Do not worry about that review.
Tomorrow night we laugh about it.
- Is not he the one who ran away?
- The description is correct.
You! Stop!
Fire!
Dear New Yorkers, I stand here today
because I fell 62 floors-
- And someone caught me.
Someone who never wants anything in return.
- Hey, MJ.
- Harry!
Where is Pete?
He was shooting, I think. It's so
nice to meet you. You look like you feel good.
I have never felt better. It is a
weird feeling not to know about New York.
- A slap in the head, one is free.
- Do you want to beat me in the head?
- Pete said that you sing in a musical.
- Yes, you were there. You gave me flowers.
- Did I? I am going tonight again.
- It can not. I have stopped.
What happened?
I was not very good.
This is embarrassing, but I
wrote a part for you in High School.
Did you? It was urgulligt.
I wonder, when the parachute does not
trips or when your business robbed-
- Or your house is burning,
who is it that captures your-
- Extinguish the fire and rescue your children?
- Spiderman!
- They love me.
- For your friendly neighbor...
... Spiderman!
- Kiss him!
- Come on, kiss me just.
- Really?
- Yes, they love it.
- Kiss him!
I hope Pete takes a card this.
- Are you okay?
- Yes, okay.
There's something on the roof!
- End of the fun, buddy.
- I do not want to hurt you. Leave me.
You have probably not heard
that I am the sheriff of these parts.
Where will all these guys come from?
Pardon!
Bonsoir.
Le Monsieur Atila un reservation?
- Sorry, but I do not speak...
- Sure, this is a French restaurant?
Oui...?
- Name, please.
- Peter Parker.
We have you.
A table for two. Perk.
- Parker.
- That's what I said.
Perk.
I have a önskemåI. My girlfriend
come here and I have a ring.
Hello. You intend to ask the question tonight?
- Yes, and I want it to be special.
- I love it.
Romance. I am a Frenchman.
When I give the sign,
are you with champagne and the ring...
... In the bottom of her glass.
- Perfect!
I would also like to
musicians play this song.
- Their favorite.
- Take good care of the ring.
I protect it with my life, Monsieur.
- Sil vous plait?
- Oui.
I like you.
- Bonne chance.
- Bon chance.
Would you like some champagne?
How did it there?
Do not cry.
Look at you. You are so beautiful.
Can we afford this?
There is a special occasion.
You play on Broadway...
- I'm not a star tonight.
- You are a star.
- You've earned it.
- Peter...
- You have no idea how I feel.
- I know exactly how you feel.
I've been through this.
It happens all the time.
There are posters of Spiderman in
windows, the kids have me on t-shirts.
I am a big seller on Halloween
and has become something of an icon.
By yesterday, all shouting:
"Spiderman, Spiderman"
I'm just a geek from Queens.
I deserve this?
- Hey, Pete.
- Hello.
I'm here and eat with my parents.
Hello, my name is Gwen Stacy.
This is Mary Jane Watson.
So nice to finally meet you.
Peter talks about you all the time.
Gwen is my labpartner
in Dr. Connors class.
Peter is a genius.
I had not done anything without him.
Speaking of which... Do you have a card on
When I kissed Spiderman?
Do you want to take it to school?
It would be really nice.
For my folder. I mean,
who receive kiss Spiderman?
I can not imagine it.
It was wonderful to meet you.
- Good night.
She goes in my science class.
Not her best subject.
- What is it?
- Why have you never mentioned her?
She is your labpartner.
You saved her life.
She thinks you're a genius
and could not take care of you.
Or did you notice that?
She gave Spiderman punch key.
I will never forget.
- It's just a girl in my class...
- Can I ask one thing:
Who kissed her?
- Spider-Man or Peter?
- What do you mean?
You know exactly what I mean.
It was our kiss.
Why did you do that? You must
have understood how I would feel.
- Do you reject me?
- Repel you?
Why? I love you. You are my
girlfriend and she is a girl in my class.
I do not feel good, so I must go.
- Where are you?
- Do not follow me, please.
Here you are.
Hey, it's MJ.
Sing a song after the beep. "Piiip"
I do not know why you do not respond
or what happens.
I do not know if
You have heard my message.
I... would like to talk to you.
Okay, call me.
- Hello?
- Mr. Parker?
This is an assistant Neil Garett
from the 32nd district.
I'll call the police chief Stacy. He wants
happy to talk to you here at the station.
From the beginning we thought that he is here,
Dennis Carradine, murdered your husband.
- We were wrong.
- What?
Carradine was just an assistant...
killer is still at large.
- What are you talking about?
- This is your husband's killers.
His name is Flint Marko,
a petty thief has been in and out of jail.
- It is not true.
- Two days ago he escaped.
He admitted to a cell mate.
We have witnesses who support his story.
Wait, you do not want to do this.
Jump in! What are you doing?!
- Would you put away these cards.
- I know it's hard, Mrs. Parker
- But be patient with us.
We do our job and catch him.
No, you do not handle your job! I saw my
uncle die and we have been chasing the wrong man-
- And now you say that you had
suspects and witnesses in two years.
Why did we not know?
I'm not going to calm me down!
He murdered my uncle
and is still at large!
All police officers nearby
The L-20 Parkway, answer.
We have an abandoned vehicle and an older
man in the middle of the street. Sorry, Wabash Avenue.
It's MJ, Peter.
I do not want to talk about dinner.
Open only, please.
Aunt May called and told what
has happened. She is worried about you.
- I'm worried about you.
- Do not be.
- You must not do anything stupid.
- Like to find my uncle's murderer?
That you do something you may regret that...
with the other guy.
He took aim at me with a gun.
I moved and he fell.
I accuse you.
Do you want to shut it down there?
I came here because I care about you.
I know you made a mistake
and feel guilty, but...
... I want to be here for you.
- I get it. Thank you.
Never mind.
I do not need your help.
Everyone needs help sometimes...
even Spiderman.
... Is on his way to Madison Avenue, 620...
Tom reports that he is
in place at East 107540th
A man found in apartment B
on the first floor...
- Damage to me! Give me a break!
- You gave my uncle a chance!
Where am I?
What is this?
It feels...
... Good!
This is awesome!
- What do you think?
- I've never seen anything like it.
I'm not a physicist and biologist.
We get some tests tomorrow...
Can we do it now?
It looks like you.
Get any of that stuff on you.
It seems to be a symbiote-
- Who needs a host to survive.
When these kinds of organisms have been implanted-
- They can be difficult to get rid of.
Current bank robbery in
First Eastern Bank in Bismarck.
A sandstorm has been seen nearby.
Draw close gently.
Marko!
I love your new style. Just what I
need for a scoop. Run some pretty rick.
See you, dude.
What the hell!
Flint Marko.
- What would you like me?
- Remember Ben Parker?
The old man you shot down in cold blood.
- What does that have to do with you?
- Everything!
Time to pay back, Marko!
Nice to get rid of.
- The rent...
- Not now.
It's a free country;
but no rent.
- Leave me alone.
- Once I receive the rent.
You get it when you have
cook this damn door!
- It was not fair.
- He's a good guy.
He must have some kind of problem.
The man who killed Uncle Ben,
Flint Marko, was killed yesterday.
- What happened?
- Spider-Man killed him.
Spiderman? Incomprehensible.
Spider-Man do not kill people.
What happened?
I... He was...
I thought you liked...
... He deserved it.
I do not think we can determine if a
person deserves to live or die.
- He killed Uncle Ben.
- Ben meant everything to us...
... But he had not wanted
that we live with a vengeance.
It's like a poison
that can take over.
Before you know it,
transforms it into something horrible.
- Hey, Harry, it's MJ.
- Hello.
I want to have some company. Can I get
past or do anything special?
- No, look over.
- Sure it is OK?
- I have nothing for me. Come here.
- Okay, see you in a while.
- Bernard!
- Yes, Mr. Osborn?
- We get a visit. Can you get food?
- Visit?
- Yes, please.
- Fine visits or usual?
- Can you just get some grub?
- Immediately, sir.
- Mr. Ditkowitch.
- Orange?
No thanks. I apologize
for what happened earlier.
I should not be screaming for the door.
There was nothing to get angry.
It does not matter, but if you have bad
conscience, you can bid on the pizza sometime.
- Today is going well.
- Okay.
- Malfunctioning phone?
- No, I just...
... Wondering what to say.
- If you make a woman-
- You say:
"You are a beautiful woman. I am a good man."
- He should call a woman.
- The Mary Jane? I think it's...
You do not have to do with it! Go now!
- Call her.
- Thanks.
Goodbye.
- Are you hungry?
- Yes.
- Do you like peppers?
- I love it.
Butter!
Check it here.
This part is useful.
"You have been dreaming."
"A little self-deception
helps one through the evening. "
- When did you write this?
- The third year in high school.
- Do you want the part?
- I'm happy in your piece.
You do not even have a scar.
Hardly.
- Sorry.
- Forgive me.
- I did not mean.
- Do not worry... Forgive me.
Forgive me.
You have lost focus.
What have you done?!
Avenge me!
- My father died right?
- Yes.
- I wish I could remember more of him.
- He loved you. That's the main thing.
I swear by my father's grave
that Spiderman will have to pay.
Remember me.
- Yes, father. I remember.
- I was right about her.
If Peter, of all things.
You know what you must do. Get him
to suffer and wish he was dead.
First we attack his heart!
Hello. It's me.
Sing a song after the beep.
Hey, MJ. It is Peter.
I want to talk to you
about last night.
I do not know what I was thinking of.
You came to help me and
- I... want to meet you.
Do you think Peter will live on,
you must do one thing for me.
- It's Ursula.
- Come in.
- Hey, Pete.
- Hello.
You have a telephone.
- The Mary Jane is calling back.
- Really?
- I put the receiver on top of the box.
- Thanks.
- Hello.
- How nice that you called.
- I have tried...
- Can we meet?
- Of course.
- Now?
- On the bridge in the park.
- I'm on the road.
I love you.
You look fantastic.
Peonies.
- Are you okay?
- No.
- It's something I have to say.
- Okay.
It does not work... between us.
- I do not see you anymore.
- What are you talking about?
I do not know...
I am alone...
You are not there for me.
- I can not do it... It's over.
- No... Please.
Do not say that. I've been selfish, but-
- I can pull myself together. Change me.
- It's not that simple.
We love each other. People have problems,
they talk out and resolve them.
Do you see it here. You know what that is?
- Do you know what I want?
- It's someone else!
I'm in love with someone else.
Bravo.
She said she is alone
and that I am not there for her...
... That there is another guy.
- How do you feel?
- Not good.
I was going to marry him.
She has had it rough lately.
The job...
Singing waitress at a jazz club.
It is not what she imagined.
Singing waitress... What are you talking about?
She was fired from the show.
Did she not?
Was she fired?
She told me that she got fired
for you, but not for me?
That's why I asked you to come here.
I'm the other guy.
- What?
- She came to me one night, worried.
She needed someone who cared about her.
You know I always have loved her.
It just...
... Began.
I do not think that's true...
I do not believe in you.
I am very sorry.
I just thought you should know.
- Should I heat up?
- Yes, please.
- How is the pie?
- Almost.
You want something to drink?
Sorry, what was I thinking.
Bad publicity for Mr. "key to the city."
What did you do to her?
What you failed.
I was there when she needed someone.
- Mary Jane and I understand each other.
- She does not know what you are.
She knows me so well. She kissed me
just like she used to kiss me.
Tasted like... strawberries.
What did you think of it, Spidy?
Is that all you have to come up with?
I protected you in High School
and now I'll kick your ass!
- Are you going to kill me as my father?
- I can not convince you.
You took him from me. He loved me.
No. He despised you.
He thought you were embarrassing.
Look at little Goblin Junior.
Will you cry?
"THIEF! Spiderman shows his true colors"
- He made \u200b\u200bme feel safe.
- Now I dare not go home from work.
- My son thought he was the world's guy.
My nine year old daughter loves Spiderman.
Who will she look up to now?
- Gave him the city key?
- I'll make you look worse.
- I just got lucky.
- It must be wonderful for you.
Maybe you should ask JJ to arrange
a little more space on the wall.
- Good morning.
- A wonderful day, right?
What were you saying? I would never
take that card? There you have your hero.
- I did not think he would do it.
- Now, did you do an assessment.
- You must see the truth.
- Funny you said that-
- Because I looked through some
old card and they were very similar.
I have to work.
- You are a sweep, Brock.
- Excuse me?
The card is a forgery.
You are so righteous, Parker.
When should you quit?
You want forgiveness? Be religious.
- What's going on?!
- Is it good to you?
Do not worry, we're kidding only a little.
I beg you, do not do this
because then I lose everything.
- Not one newspaper in town hire me.
- You should have thought of before.
- What are you, Peter?
- View the editor of this.
Tell him to check the source next time.
It is a forgery.
The city's photo department confirms it.
Pack your things and get out.
You've been fired!
- We need to press a denial now.
- I have not done in 20 years!
"Sorry, Spidy. Bugle put the case."
"Counterfeiters kicked."
- It is Dr. Connors, Mr. Parker.
- Dr. Connors.
- What is it?
- It was not a bad test you did.
The chemistry is similar to meteorites
from the 70's.
- Parks?
- Get some milk.
- It enhances the properties of values.
- Give me a cake.
In particular, anger. It may be dangerous.
- You kept nothing?
- Do you have the nuts?
- I have nuts, so I can cook.
- Fix some to me.
Of course not.
- Your photos are so good.
- I plates like you someday.
Parker then...
Parks! Ms. Brent!
That employee I am not for you!
Spiderman in the black suit.
These are amazing, Peter.
We must have them, Jonah.
I pay what I usually do.
Do you want the cards, give me
editorial work. With double pay.
You will really
to like this place.
Am I dressed appropriately?
Not too dressy?
You are gorgeous, girl.
- Thanks.
- I love it there giggling.
This is so cool.
I have never been
at a jazz club before.
I hope we can get a table.
- Find some shade for us.
- This way.
Thank you very much.
- I love this so much.
- Me too.
- Is not that your old girlfriend?
- Yes.
- Do you want to go somewhere else?
- Oh no. That's fine.
See what you can, Mary Jane.
I'll be right back.
Peter?
This is for you.
Check this out.
Was all that for her?
Forgive me.
- Are you all right, Mary Jane?
- Oh, yes.
- What is wrong with you?
- You.
- Can I help you?
- No.
- Are you all right, Paul?
- Yes, it's there, Paul?
- Throw him out.
- Hands off.
Stop it, Peter!
Who are you really?
I do not know.
Brock here, sir...
Edward Brock Junior.
I stand here before you today...
humble... and humiliated.
I just want to ask you one thing...
I want you to kill Peter Parker.
Parks...?
- Hello, Peter.
- Hello.
You do not seem to redecorate often.
Fixed... there's not much
going to change, right?
When we spoke over the phone, I felt
as if something troubled you, so...
... I was going to stop by.
- How is Mary-Jane?
- I do not know.
You never heard of you.
It became something of courtship?
You said... that a husband must
put his wife first of all...
I'm not ready.
What happened?
You seemed so sure of your cause.
Yes... I...
I hurt her, Aunt May.
I do not know what to do with myself.
You must start with the hardest...
To forgive yourself.
I believe in you, Peter.
You are a good person.
I am sure that you get to find
a way to set things right.
In due course.
Sleep well, Spiderman!
I also want to see him dead, Flint.
That is why I looked for you.
I know all about you...
As the Spider-
- Do not let you help your daughter.
It sounds very wrong to my ears.
We both wish to kill the spider...
Against both of us, he has no chance.
- Sound interesting?
- Yes.
Where do you go?
The entire New York holding its breath while
hostage situation continues...
For 30 minutes ago police discovered
This amazing scenario.
A woman held captive in a taxi, which
hanging 80 storeys up in the air-
- In what resembles a large network.
All the police attempt to save woman
were stopped by the Sand Man.
Another danger appeared,
a man dressed in black, as was believed,
- Be the black-clad Spider-Man,
has now proved to be something else entirely.
The hostages have been identified as Mary-Jane
Watson, an actor who appeared on Broadway.
We now broadcast live from the scene
by Jennifer Dugan. - Jennifer?
I'm only a few hundred meters away.
We can see that something happens in the network.
It looks like the giant letters.
They want to confront Spider-Man, but
how can he resist the kind of power...
Harry?
I need your help.
I can not handle both of them alone.
You do not deserve my help.
She needs our help, Harry.
Get out of here!
If I may, sir...
I have witnessed things in this house
I have never spoken about.
- What is it you would have said?
- The night when your father died...
I cleaned his wounds.
The blade that pierced his body...
came from his hovercraft.
I know you're just trying
defend your father's honor-
- But there is no doubt that
His death was caused by himself.
I loved your father...
... Just as I have loved you, Harry.
So that your friends love you.
Look!
He came from nowhere to help
us when all hope seemed lost.
- Peter... They will kill us both.
- I'll help you.
Watch out!
- Hey, Parker.
- Eddie...? Oh my God.
It tingles the spider sense...
... If you know what I mean.
- We can make up any other way.
- Sure... Why not through humiliation.
Kind of like when you humiliated me.
Do you remember?
Do you remember what you did to me?
You made me lose my girlfriend,
so now you lose yours.
How does that sound?
No...!
Hold on, Mary-Jane!
Mary-Jane!
It's hard to imagine
what we now witness.
It's so brutal...
- We can not take much more...
- A tragic day for New Yorkers.
It could mean the end of Spiderman.
You came...
- Just in the nick of time, it seems.
- A little earlier had not damaged.
You may have to make do.
- I need some help here!
- I'm a little busy now!
Give me your hand!
Parks! I need a photographer.
- Need a job?
- Why? I'm just a kid.
- How much do you want for your camera?
- $ 100.
Sure... Here you go.
The film cost extra.
Meet me at the top, Pete!
- Can you increase speed?
- Hold on!
Jump, man!
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- Good.
- Pete!
Am I disturbing you?
Damage never... what you can not kill.
- Your costume... You have to take it off.
- It was you certainly appreciated.
I know the feeling... It feels good.
Forces and everything...
... But you lose yourself.
Drop it.
I like to be mean.
It makes me happy.
Harry!
What are you doing, Peter?
No!
Eddie!
- Mary-Jane.
- I'll get help.
Stay with me.
I did not think this would happen...
... But I had no choice.
There is always a choice. You did
a choice when you killed my uncle.
My daughter was dying.
I needed money.
I was scared.
I told your uncle
I was just looking for car...
He asked me to tuck away
revolver and go home.
Now I realize that he
tried to do me a favor.
Then came my partner
running with the money-
- And I held the revolver in my hand.
What I did to you was horrible...
... And many nights I've changed my mind.
I do not pray for forgiveness...
I just want you to understand.
I have also done terrible things.
I chose not to become like this.
The only thing I have left now...
... Is my daughter.
I forgive you.
- Hey, buddy. How are you?
- I have felt better.
We will take you through this.
No...
I should never have hurt you.
Or put all those things.
It does not matter, Peter.
You are my friend.
The best of friends.
Whatever we do, the struggle over
underway in at, we always have a choice.
It taught me my friend Harry.
He chose to show his best side.
It is our choices that makes us who
we are and we can always make the right choice.
Translated by: Dark_Lord
Visit *--
Tankan. com
--* for more movies and series!