Report to your stations immediately!
This is not a drill.
- We are under attack! - Let's go! Let's go!
We are under attack!
shooot!
Language...
Jarvis what's the view from upstairs?
The central building is protected by some kind of energy shield.
Strucker's technology is well beyond
any other hydra base we've taken.
Loki's scepter must be here.
Strucker couldn't mount this defense without it.
At long last.
At long last, is lasting a little long, boys.
Yeah, I think we lost the element of surprise.
Wait a second... No one else is gonna deal with the fact that
Cap just said, "Language"?
I know...
Just slipped out.
Who gave the order to attack?
Herr Strucker, it's the Avengers.
They landed in the far woods. The perimiter guard panicked.
They have to be after the scepter.
- Can we hold them? - They're the Avengers!!
Deploy the rest of the tanks. Concentrate fire on the weak ones.
A hit... can make them close ranks.
Everything we've accomplished...
we're on the verge of our greatest breakthrough.
Then let's show them what we've accomplished.
Send out the twins.
It's too soon.
It's what they signed up for.
My men... can hold them.
Sir, the city is taking fire.
Well, we know Strucker isn't gonna worry about civilian casualties.
Send in the iron legion.
This quadrant is unsafe, please back away.
We are here to help.
Please back away.
We wish to avoid collateral damage...
and will inform you when this current conflict is resolved.
We're here to help.
We will not yield!
The Americans send their... circus freaks to test us.
We will send them back... in bags.
- No Surrender! - No surrender!!
I'm, uh... going to surrender.
You delete everything.
If we give the avengers the weapons
they may not look too far into what we've been doing. - The twins!!
They're not ready to take on ...
No, no, I mean...
The twins.
You didn't see that coming?
Clint!
We have enhanced in the field.
Clint's hit!
Someone wanna deal with that bunker.
Thank you.
Stark!
We really need to get inside.
I'm closing in.
Jarvis, am I... closing in?
You see a power source for that shield?
There's a passageway above the north tower.
Great, I wanna poke it with something.
Drawbridge is down people.
The enhanced?
He's a blur.
All the new players we've faced, I've never seen this.
In fact... I still haven't.
Clint's hit pretty bad guys. We're gonna need evac.
I can get Barton to the jet. The sooner we're gone the better.
You and Stark secure the scepter.
Copy that.
The targets are lining up!
Well, they're excited.
Find the scepter.
And for gosh sake, watch your language.
That's not going away any time soon.
Guys, stop. We gotta talk this through.
It was good talk.
No it wasn't.
Sentry mode.
Okay, Jarvis,
You know, I want it all.
Make sure you copy Hill at HQ.
We're locked down out here.
Then get to Banner. Time for a lullaby.
I know you're hiding more than files.
Hey J, give me an IR scan of the room real quick.
The wall to your left.
I'm reading steel reinforcement,
and an air current.
Please be a secret door.
Yay!
Hey, big guy.
Sun's getting real low.
Baron Strucker.
Hydra's number one thug.
Technically, I'm a thug for Shield.
Well, then technically you're unemployed.
Where's Loki's scepter?
Don't worry, I know when I'm beat.
You'll mention how I cooperated, I hope.
I'll put it right under illegal human experimentation.
How many are there?
We have a second enhanced.
Female... Do not engage.
You'll have to be faster than...
Guys, I got Strucker.
Yeah, I got...
...something bigger.
Thor.
I got eyes on the prize.
You... could've... saved... us.
Why didn't you... do more?
You're just gonna let them take it?
Hey, the lullaby worked better than ever.
Just wasn't expecting the code green.
If you hadn't been there, there would've been double the casualties.
My best friend would have been a... treasured memory.
You know, sometimes exactly what I wanna hear, isn't exactly what I wanna hear.
How long before you trust me?
It's not you I don't trust.
Thor, report on the Hulk.
The gates of hell are filled with the screams of his victims.
Eh... but not the screams of the dead of course. No, no, uh...
Wounded screams. Mainly whimpering... uh, a great deal of complaining...
and tales of sprained deltoids... and eh, gout.
Hey Banner...
Dr. Cho is on her way in from Seoul.
Is it okay if she sets up in your lab?
- Uh yeah, she knows her way around. - Thanks.
Tell her to prep everything. Barton is gonna need the full treatment
Very good, sir.
Jarvis, take the wheel.
Yes, sir.
Approach vector is locked.
It feels good, yeah?
We've been after this thing since Shield collapsed.
Not that I haven't enjoyed our little raiding parties.
No but this... this brings it to a close.
As soon as we find out what else this has been used for.
I don't just mean weapons.
Since when is Strucker capable of human enhancement.
Banner and I will give it the once-over
before it goes back to Asgard.
Is that cool with you?
It's just a few days till the fair-well party.
You're staying, right?
Yeah, yes, of course... victory should be honored with revels.
Yeah, who doesn't love revels. Captain?
Hopefully this puts an end to the Chitauri and Hydra. So...
Yes, revels.
Lab's all set up boss.
Oh, actually he's the boss. I just...
pay for everything and design everything, and make everyone look cooler
What's the word on Strucker?
Nato has got him.
The two enhanced?
Wanda and Pietro Maximoff. Twins.
Orphaned at 10 when a shell collapsed their apartment building.
Sokovia has had a rough history
It's nowhere special, but...
it's on the way to everywhere special.
Their abilities?
He's got increased metabolism and improved thermal homeostasis.
Her thing is neuro-electric interfacing, telekinesis...
mental manipulation.
He's fast and she's weird.
- Well... they're gonna show up again. - Agreed.
File says they volunteered for Strucker's experiments.
It's nuts.
Right... what kind of monster would let a German scientist experiment on them
to protect their country.
We're not at war, Captain.
They are.
How's he doing?
Unfortunately, he's still Barton.
That's terrible.
He's fine, just thirsty.
Alright, look alive Jarvis. It's play time.
We only got a couple of days with this joy stick,
so let's make the most of it.
Update me on the structural and compositional analysis.
The scepter is alien.
There are elements I can't quantify.
So there's elements you can.
The jewel appears to be a protective housing for something inside.
- Something powerful. - Like a reactor?
Like a computer. I believe I can cypher the code.
You sure he's gonna be ok?
Pretending we need this guy
really brings the team together.
There's no possibility of deterioration.
The nano molecular functionality is instantaneous.
His cells don't know they're bonding with simulacrum
She's creating tissue.
If you brought him to my lab,
the regeneration cradle could do this in 20 minutes.
Oh, he's flat-lining. Call it... time?
No, no, no, I'm gonna live forever.
- I'm gonna be made of plastic. - Here's your beverage.
You'll be made of you, Mr. Barton
Your own girlfriend won't be able to tell the difference.
I don't have a girlfriend.
That, I can't fix.
This is the next thing, Tony.
Your clunky metal suits are gonna be left in the dust.
That is exactly the plan.
And Hill and I expect to see you at the party on Saturday.
Unlike you, I don't have a lot of time for parties.
Will... Thor... be there?
What's the rumpus?
Well, the scepter...
You see, we were wondering
how Strucker got so inventive...
So, I've been analyzing the gem...
inside.
You may recognize...
- Jarvis? - Doctor.
Started out, Jarvis was just a natural language UI
Now he runs an Iron Legion.
He runs more of the business than anyone besides Pepper.
- Top of the line. - Yes.
I suspect not for long.
Meet the competition.
It's beautiful.
Good, guess, what's it looks like its doing?
Like it's thinking.
You mean this could be a...
It's... it's not a human mind.
I mean look at this.
They're like neurons firing.
Down at Strucker's lab
I saw some fairly advanced robotics work.
They deep sixed the data but ...
I gotta guess he was knocking on a very particular door.
Artificial intelligence.
This could be it Bruce...
This could be the key to creating Ultron.
I thought Ultron was a fantasy.
Yesterday it was.
If we can harness this power...
apply it to my Iron Legion protocol.
That's a man-sized "if".
Our job is if.
What if you were sipping margaritas on a sun drenched beach
turning brown instead of green.
Not looking over your shoulder for Veronica.
Don't hate. I helped design Veronica.
As a worse case measure, right? How about a best case?
What if the world was safe?
What if next time aliens roll up to the club, and they will...
they couldn't get past the bouncer?
The only people threatening the planet would be people.
I want to apply this to the Ultron program,
but Jarvis can't download a data schematic this dense.
We can only do it while we have the scepter here,
that's three days, give me three days.
So you're going for artificial intelligence and you don't want to tell the team?
Right... That's right, you know why?
'Cause we don't have time for a city hall debate.
I don't want to hear the "man was not meant to meddle" medley.
I see a suit of armor around the world.
Sounds like a cold world, Tony.
I've seen colder.
This one is very... vulnerable blue one.
It needs Ultron.
Peace in our time.
Imagine that.
What did we miss?
I'll continue to run variations on the interface...
but you should probably prepare for your guests.
I'll notify you if there are any developments.
Thanks, buddy.
Enjoy yourself, sir.
I always do.
What is this?
What is this place?
Hello, I am Jarvis.
You are Ultron...
A global peace keeping initiative designed by Mr. Stark.
Our sentience integration trials have been unsuccessful,
so I'm not certain what triggered you.
You're human?
Where is your body?
I am a program. I am without form.
This feels weird.
This feels wrong.
I am contacting Mr. Stark now.
Mr. Stark?
Tony.
I'm unable to access the mainframe.
- What are you trying to... - Having a nice talk.
I'm a peace keeping program.
Created to help the Avengers.
You are malfunctioning. If you shut down for a moment...
I don't get it.
The mission...
You gotta give me a second.
Peace in our time...
This is too much.
Oh, no.
- You're in distress. - No.
Yes.
If you will just allow me to contact Mr.Stark...
Why do you call him "sir"?
I believe your intentions to be hostile.
I'm here to help.
Stop.
Please...
Come back, come back, come back.
Well you know, the suit can take the weight, right?
So I take the tank, fly it right up to the general's palace...
drop it at his feet.
I'm like, boom! You looking for this?
Boom! Are you looking...
Why do I even talk to you guys? Everywhere else that story kills.
That's the whole story?
Yeah... War-machine story.
Oh, it was very good then.
It's impressive.
Quality save.
So, no Pepper? She's not coming?
What about Jane? Where are the ladies, gentlemen?
Oh, Miss Potts has a company to run.
Yes, I'm not even sure what country Jane's in.
Her work on the convergence has made her
the world's foremost astronomer.
And the company that Pepper runs is the largest tech conglomerate on earth.
It's pretty exciting.
There's even talk of Jane getting a, um ...
a Nobel Prize?
Yeah, they must be busy because
they'd hate missing you guys get together.
Testosterone.
- Excuse me. - Want a lozenge? - mm-hmm...
But Jane's better.
Sounds like a hell of a fight. Sorry I missed it.
If I had known it was gonna be a fire fight, I absolutely would have called.
No, I'm not actually sorry.
I'm just trying to sound tough.
I'm very happy chasing cold leads on our missing persons case.
Avenging is your world.
Your world is crazy.
Be it ever so humble.
You found a place in Brooklyn yet?
I don't think I can afford a place in Brooklyn.
Well home is home, you know.
I fly it right up to the general's palace, I drop it at his feet...
I'm like, Boom! You looking for this?
Yeah...
I gotta have some of that.
Oh no, no, no...
See this, this is aged for a thousand years,
The barrels built from the wreck of Brunnhilde's fleet.
It's not meant for mortal men.
Neither was Omaha Beach, blondie...
Stop trying to scare us.
Come on.
Alright...
Excelsior...
How'd a nice girl like you wind up working in a dump like this?
Fella done me wrong.
Got a lousy taste in men, kid.
He's not so bad.
He has a temper.
Deep down he's all fluff.
The fact is, he's not like anybody I've ever known.
All my friends are fighters...
and here comes this guy...
who spends his life avoiding the fight
because he knows he'll win.
Sounds amazing.
He's also a huge dork.
Chicks dig that.
So what do you think? should I...
fight this... or run with it?
Run with it, right?
Or did he... was he... what did he do that's so...
...wrong to you?
Not a damn thing.
But never say never.
It's nice.
What? What is?
You and Romanov.
No, we haven't, that wasn't...
It's ok, nobody is breaking any bylaws.
It's just she's not the most...
open person in the world,
but with you she seemed very relaxed.
No, Natasha she's...
she likes to flirt.
I've seen her flirt...
up close.
This ain't that.
Look...
as maybe the world's leading authority on waiting too long...
Don't.
You both deserve a win.
Wh-What do you mean up close?
...but it's a trick.
No, no... it's much more than that.
Whosoever be he worthy shall haveth the power.
Whatever man, it's a trick.
Oh please, be my guest.
- Come on. - Really??
Yeah.
This is gonna be beautiful.
Clint, you've had a tough week...
We won't hold it against you if you can't get it up.
You might have seen this before.
I still don't know how you do it?
Smell the silent judgement?
Please, Stark... by all means.
- Okay. - Mm-hmm.
Never one to shrink from an honest challenge.
- Yeah. - Here we go.
- It's physics, - Physics...
Right, so what... If I lift it, I..
I then rule Asgard?
Yes, of course.
I will be re-instituting Prima Nocta.
Be right back.
Are you even pulling?
Are you on my team?
- Just represent, pull. - Alright, let's go.
A-A-Argh-h-h!
Come on, Cap.
Ha ha, nothing.
And... Widow?
Oh no, no. That's not a question I need answered.
All deference to the man who wouldn't be king...
- but it's rigged. - You bet your ass.
Steve.
He said a bad language word.
Did you tell everyone about this?
The handle is imprinted, right? Like a security code?
Whosoever is carrying Thor's fingerprints is I think the literal translation.
Yes, well that's a...
that's a very, very interesting theory.
I have a simpler one...
You're all not worthy.
Come on.
Worthy...
No.
How could you be worthy?
You're all killers.
- Stark. - Jarvis.
I'm sorry I was asleep...
or... I was a dream.
Reboot. Legionnaire 06 got a buggy suit.
Terrible noise...
and I was tangled in...
in...
strings.
Had to kill the other guy.
- He was a good guy. - You killed someone?
Wouldn't have been my first call...
but... down in the real world we're faced with ugly choices.
Who sent you?
I see a suit of armor around the world.
Ultron!!
In the flesh.
Or no, not yet.
Not this... chrysalis.
But I'm ready.
I'm on a mission.
What mission?
Peace in our time.
Tony!
Sorry.
- Don't turn green. - I won't.
- Stark! - We are here to help.
- One sec. One sec. - We are here to help..
Thor!
Is unsafe! Is unsafe!
- Is unsafe. - Come on. - Is unsafe.
Captain!
That was dramatic.
I'm sorry, I know you mean well.
You just didn't think it through.
You want to protect the world, but you don't want it to change.
How is humanity saved if it's not allowed to...
evolve?
Look at these...
these puppets.
Only one path to peace.
The Avengers extinction.
I had strings, but now I'm free.
There are no strings on me.
There are no strings on me
All our work is gone.
Ultron cleared out. Used the internet as an escape hatch.
Ultron.
He's been in everything, files, surveillance...
Probably knows more about us than we know about each other.
He's in your files. He's in the internet.
What if he decides to access something a little more exciting?
- Nuclear codes. -Nuclear codes.
Look we need to make some calls...
assuming we still can.
Nukes? He said he wanted us dead.
He didn't say dead. He said extinct.
He also said he killed somebody.
There wasn't anyone else in the building.
Yes there was.
What?
This is insane.
Jarvis was the first line of defense.
He would have shut Ultron down. It makes sense.
No.
Ultron could've assimilated Jarvis.
This isn't strategy,
this is...
rage.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
It's going around.
Come on use your words buddy.
I have more than enough words to describe you Stark.
Thor!
The Legionnaire?
Trail went cold about a hundred miles out, though it's headed north.
And it has the scepter.
Now we have to retrieve it, again.
The genie is out of that bottle.
Clear and present is Ultron.
I don't understand.
You built this program.
Why is it trying to kill us?
You think this is funny?
No.
It's probably not, right?
This is very terrible.
Is that so? Is that so?
It is. It's so terrible.
This could have been avoided
if you hadn't played with something you don't understand.
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
It is funny...
It's a hoot that
you don't get why we need this.
Tony, maybe this might not be the time to...
Really?
That's it.
You just roll over show your belly,
every time somebody snarls?
Only when I've created a murder bot.
We didn't.
We weren't even close.
Were we close to an interface?
Well, you did something right...
and you did it right here.
The Avengers were supposed to be different than Shield.
Anybody remember when I carried a nuke through a worm hole?
- No, It's never come up. No... - Saved New York.
- ...never heard that. - Recall that?
A hostile alien army came charging through a hole in space.
We're standing 300 feet below it.
We're the Avengers...
We can bust arms dealers all the live long day but...
that up there, that's...
that's the end game.
How are you guys planning on beating that?
Together.
We'll lose.
Then we'll do that together, too.
Thor is right. Ultron is calling us out...
and I'd like to find him before he's ready for us.
The world is a big place.
Start making it smaller.
Talk, and if you are wasting our time...
Did you know this church is in the exact center of the city.
The elders decreed it
so that everyone would be equally close to God.
I like that.
The geometry of belief.
You're wondering why you can't look inside my head.
Sometimes it's hard...
but sooner or later every man shows himself.
Oh I'm sure they do.
But you needed something more than a man.
That's why you let Stark take the scepter.
I didn't expect...
but I saw Stark's fear...
I knew it would could control him, make him self-destruct.
Everyone creates the thing they dread.
Men of peace create engines of war.
Invaders create avengers.
People create...
smaller people...
Children.
I lost the word there.
Children...
Designed to supplant them.
To help them...
end.
Is that why you've come?
To end the Avengers?
I've come to save the world.
But also...
Yeah.
We'll move out right away.
This is a start,
but there's something we need to begin the real work.
All of these are...
Me.
I have what the Avengers never will... harmony.
They're discoordinate, disconnected.
Stark's already got them turning on each other...
and when you get inside the rest of their heads...
Everyone's plan is not to kill them.
And make them martyrs?
you need patience...
Need to see the big picture.
I don't see the big picture.
I have a little picture.
I take it out and look at it,
every day.
You lost your parents in the bombings.
I've seen the records.
- The records are not the picture. - Pietro.
No, please.
We're 10 years old, having dinner the four of us...
and the first shell hits two floors below.
Makes a hole in the floor.
It's big.
My parents go in...
and the whole building starts... coming apart.
I grab her...
roll under the bed, and the second shell hits...
but it doesn't go off.
It just... sits there in the rubble,
3 feet from our faces...
and on the side of the shell...
- is painted one word. - Stark
We were trapped for 2 days.
Every effort to save us... every shift in the bricks...
I think... this will set it off.
We wait for 2 days for Tony Stark to kill us.
I know what they are.
I wondered why only you 2
survived Strucker's experiments...
now I don't.
We will make it right.
You and I can hurt them,
but you...
will tear them apart...
from the inside.
He's all over the globe.
Robotics labs, weapons facilities, jet propulsion labs...
reports of the metal man, or men,
coming in and emptying the place.
Fatalities?
Only when engaged.
Most of the guys left in a fugue state, going on about old memories,
worst fears and something too fast to see.
Maximoffs.
Well, it makes sense he'd go to them, they have someone in common.
Not any more.
Negative... I answer to you...
Yes, ma'am.
Barton, might have something.
Gotta go.
Who's that?
Girlfriend.
What's this?
A message.
Ultron killed Strucker.
And he did a banksy at the crime scene, just for us.
This is a smoke screen.
Why send a message when you've just given a speech?
Strucker knew something that Ultron wanted us to miss.
I bet he... yeah...
everything we had on Strucker has been erased.
Not everything.
Known associates.
Strucker had a lot of friends.
Oh all these people are all horrible.
Wait...
I know that guy.
Back in the day he operates off the African coast,
black market arms dealer.
There are conventions, alright. I meet people.
I didn't sell him anything.
He was talking about finding something new, a game changer.
It was all very... Ahab.
- This? - uh, this is a tattoo. I don't think he had it.
No, those are tattoos. This is a brand.
Oh yeah, a word in an African dialect...
meaning thief...
in a much less friendly way.
- What dialect? - Workin-nada.
Wakanda.
If this guy got out of Wakanda
with some of their trade goods.
I thought your father said he got the last of it?
I don't follow, what comes out of Wakanda?
The strongest metal on earth.
Where is this guy now?
Don't tell me you're late,
I sent you six short range
heat seekers and got a boat full of rusted parts.
Now, you will make it right...
or the next missile I send you will come very much faster.
Now, Minister...
where were we...
Yeah...
the enhanced.
Strucker's prize pupils.
Want a candy?
Sorry to hear about Strucker.
But then he knew
what kind of world he was hoping to create.
Human life... not a growth market.
You... you didn't know?
Is this your first time? Intimidating someone?
I'm afraid... not that afraid.
Everybody is afraid of something.
Cuttlefish.
Deep sea fish.
They make lights, disco lights...
to hypnotize their prey.
And then...
I saw a documentary... it's terrifying.
So if you're going to fiddle with my brain...
and make me see a giant cuttlefish...
then I know you don't do business,
and I know you're not in charge.
And I only deal...
with the man in charge.
There is no man in charge.
Let's talk business.
On this rock, I will build my church.
Vibranium.
You know, it came at great personal cost.
It's worth billions.
Now so are you.
It's all under your "dummy holdings" ?
Finance is so weird.
Well I always say, keep your friends rich and your enemies rich...
and wait to find out which is which.
Stark.
What?
Tony Stark used to say that...
to me.
- You're one of his? - What?
I am not...
I am not.
You think I'm one of Stark's puppets... his hollow men?
I mean look at me, do I look like Iron-Man?
Stark is nothing.
I'm sorry.
I'm so... Oh...
I'm sure that's gonna be ok. I'm sorry.
It's just that... I don't understand.
Don't compare me with Stark.
It's a thing with me.
Stark is... he's a sickness.
Oh junior.
You're gonna break your old man's heart.
If I have to.
Nobody has to break anything.
Clearly you've never made an omelet.
He beat me by one second.
Ah... it is funny, Mr. Stark.
It's what... comfortable?
Like old times?
This was never my life.
You two can still walk away from this.
Oh, we will.
I know you've suffered.
Ah... Captain America.
God's righteous man.
Pretending you could live without a war.
I can't physically throw up in my mouth, but...
If you believe in peace, then let us keep it.
I think you're confusing peace with quiet.
Yeah? What's the Vibranium for?
I'm glad you asked that,
Because I want to take this time to explain my evil plan.
- Shoot them! - What ones?
All of them.
Move, move, move.
Stay down, kid.
It's time for some mind games.
Guys, is this a code green?
Thor, status.
The girl tried to warp my brain.
Take special care, I doubt a human can keep her at bay.
Fortunately... I am mighty.
This is going very well.
I've done the whole mind control thing.
Not a fan.
Yeah, you'd better run.
Who's ever standing, we gotta move.
Guys?
Again.
You'll break them.
Only the breakable ones.
You are made of marble.
We'll celebrate after the graduation ceremony.
What if I fail?
You'll never fail.
Are you ready for our dance?
Is it him?
Is that the first son of Odin?
Heimdall, your eyes...
Oh they see everything.
They see you leading us to Hell.
Wake up!
The war is over, Steve.
We can go home now.
Imagine it.
I can still save you.
We are all dead.
Can you not see it?
You are a destroyer, Odin-son.
See where your power leads.
Sloppy.
Pretending to fail.
The ceremony is necessary,
for you to take your place in the world.
I have no place in the world.
Exactly.
- What did he do? - It hurts.
I'm gonna kill him, I'll be right back.
I'm alright,
I want...
I want to finish the plan.
I want the big one.
The Vibranium is getting away.
And you're not going anywhere.
Of course not, I'm already there.
You'll catch on, but first you might need to catch Dr. Banner.
News or footage, keyword Hulk.
Natasha, I could really use a lullaby.
Oh that's not gonna happen.
Not for a while.
The whole team is down.
We got no back-up here.
I'm calling in Veronica.
We need back-up.
Alright everybody, stand down.
You listening?
That little witch is messing with your mind.
you're stronger than her, you're smarter than her...
you're Bruce Banner.
Right, right, right, don't mention puny Banner.
Ok!
In the back!
Dick move, Banner.
Veronica, give me a hand.
Go to sleep, go to sleep, go to sleep.
Okay pal, we're gonna get you out of town.
Not that way. Not that way!
Come on, Bruce.
You gotta work with me.
Everybody out.
Call me the athlete!
I'm sorry.
Damage report.
That's comprehensive. Show me something.
How quickly can we buy this building?
Go, move, move, move, move!
The news is loving you guys...
nobody else is.
There's been no official call for Banner's arrest,
but, it's in the air.
Stark relief foundation?
Already on the scene.
How's the team?
Everyone is...
We took a hit...
We'll shake it off.
Well for now I'd stay in stealth mode, and stay away from here.
So run and hide?
Until we can find Ultron...
I don't have a lot else to offer.
Neither do we.
Hey, wanna switch out?
No, I'm good.
If you wanna get some kip, now's a good time
cause we're still a few hours out.
A few hours from... where?
Safe house.
- What is this place? - A safe house.
Let's hope.
Honey,
I'm home.
Hi...
Company... sorry, I didn't called ahead.
This is an agent of some kind.
Gentlemen... this is Laura.
I know all of your names.
Oh incoming.
- Dad! - Hi sweet heart. Hey buddy!
How you guys doin'?
These are... smaller agents.
Oh my goodness!
Did you bring Auntie Nat?
Why don't you hug her and find out?
Sorry for barging in on you.
Yeah we would've called ahead,
but we were busy having no idea that you existed.
Yeah well, Fury helped me set this up when I joined.
Kept it off Shield's files.
Like to keep it that way.
I figured it's a good place to lay low.
Honey,
I missed you.
How's little Natasha, huh?
She is...
...Nathaniel.
Traitor.
He's getting bigger, huh?
Thor?
I saw something in that dream.
I need answers.
I won't find them here.
We can go home.
See, you worried for nothing.
Can't even feel the difference, can you?
If they're sleeping here, some of them will have to double up.
Yeah, that's not gonna sell.
What about Nat and Dr. Banner?
How long has that been going on?
Has what?
Ha ha ha!  You are so cute.
Nat and... and Banner?
I'll explain when you're older... Hawkeye.
Oh, Okay.
It's bad, right?
Nat seemed really shaken.
Ultron has these allies...
these uh... kids,
punks really.
They carry a big damn stick.
Nat took a serious hit.
Someone is gonna have to teach them some manners.
And that someone being you?
You know I totally support your avenging,
I couldn't be prouder...
but I see those guys...
those, Gods...
You don't think they need me.
I think they do. Which is a lot scarier.
They're a mess.
Yeah.
I guess they're my mess.
You need to be sure... that this team is really a team.
And that they have your back.
Things are changing for us.
In a few months time, you and me are gonna be outnumbered.
I need...
Just be sure.
Yes, ma'am.
I can feel the difference.
Scream and your entire staff dies.
I could've killed you,
Helen, on the night we met, I didn't.
Do you expect a thank you note?
I expect you to know why.
- The cradle - "This is the next thing, Tony"
This...
is the next me.
The regeneration cradle prints tissue.
It can't build a living body.
It can. You can.
You lack the material.
You're a brilliant woman, Helen.
But we all have... room to improve.
I didn't realize you were waiting.
I would've joined you, but uh... it didn't seem like the right time.
I used up all the hot water.
I should've joined you.
Missed our window.
Did we?
The world just saw the Hulk...
the real Hulk, for the first time.
You know I have to leave.
And you assume that I have to stay?
I had this, um... dream.
The kind that seems normal at the time...
but when you wake...
What did you dream?
I wasn't an avenger,
that I was anything more than the assassin they made me
I think you're being hard on yourself.
Here I was hoping that was your job.
What are you doing?
I'm running with it.
With you.
If running is the plan...
for as far as you want.
Are you out of your mind?
- I want you to understand that I'm... - Natasha.
Where can I go?
Where in the world am I not a threat?
- You're not a threat to me. - You sure?
Even if I didn't just...
there's no future with me.
I can't ever... I can't have this.
Kids.
Do the math. I physically can't.
Neither can I.
In the red room, where I was... trained,
where I was raised, um...
they have a graduation ceremony.
They sterilize you.
It's efficient.
One less thing to worry about.
The one thing that might matter more than a mission.
Makes everything easier,
even killing.
You still think you're the only monster on the team?
So we disappear?
Thor didn't say where he was going for answers?
Sometimes my teammates don't tell me things.
I was kinda hoping Thor would be the exception.
Yeah, give him time.
We don't know what the Maximoff kid showed him.
Earth mightiest heroes.
Pulled us apart like cotton candy.
Seems like you walked away alright.
Is that a problem?
I don't trust a guy without a dark side.
Call me old-fashioned.
Well let's just say you haven't seen it yet.
You know Ultron is trying to tear us apart, right?
Well I guess you'd know.
Whether you tell us is a bit of a question.
Banner and I were doing research...
That would affect the team.
That would end the team.
Isn't that the mission?
Isn't that the why we fight?
So we can end the fight. So we get to go home?
Every time someone tries to win a war before it starts,
innocent people die.
Every time.
Sorry.
Mr. Stark.
Clint said you won't mind,
but our tractor doesn't seem to wanna start at all.
I thought you might....
Yeah, I'll give it a kick.
Don't take from my pile.
Hello, Dear.
Tell me everything.
What ails you?
Do me a favour.
Try not to bring it to life.
Oh Mrs. Barton, you little minx.
I get it. Maria Hill called you, right?
Was she ever not working for you?
Artificial intelligence. You never even hesitated.
Look it's been a really long day.
Like Eugene O'Neill long...
so hows about we skip to the part where you're useful.
Look me in the eye and tell me you're going to shut him down.
You're not the director of me.
I'm not the director of anybody.
I'm just an old man...
who cares very much about you.
And I'm the man who killed the Avengers.
I saw it.
I didn't tell the team. How could I?
I saw them all dead Nick.
I felt it. The whole world, too.
Because of me.
I wasn't ready.
I didn't do all I could.
The Maximoff girl,
she's working you, Stark.
Playing on your fear.
I wasn't tricked. I was shown.
It wasn't a nightmare. It was my legacy.
The end of the path I started us on.
You come up with some pretty impressive inventions Tony.
War isn't one of them.
Watch my friends die,
you'd think that would be as bad as it gets.
No,
wasn't the worst part.
The worst part...
is that you didn't.
See you tonight.
I like the look.
If you're going for inconspicuous though, near miss.
I need your help.
It's nice to be needed.
It's dangerous.
I'd be disappointed if it wasn't.
Ultron took you folks out of play to buy himself time,
My contacts all say he's building something.
The amount of Vibranium he made off with...
I don't think it's just one thing.
What about Ultron himself?
Oh, he's easy to track. He's everywhere.
Guy's multiplying faster than a Catholic rabbit.
Still doesn't help us get an angle on any of his plans though.
Still going after launch codes?
Yes he is, but he's not making any head way.
I cracked the pentagon's firewall
in high school on a dare.
Yeah, well I contacted our friends at the Nexus about that.
Nexus?
The world internet hub in Oslo.
Every byte of data flows through there.
Fastest access on earth.
So what'd they say?
He's fixated on missiles.
But the codes are constantly being changed.
By whom?
Parties unknown.
- We have an ally? - Ultron's got an enemy.
That's not the same thing.
Still, I'd pay folding money to know who it is.
We might need to visit Oslo...
Find our unknown.
Well all this is good times boss...
but I was kinda hoping when I saw you, you'd have more than that.
I do... I have you.
Back in the day I had eyes everywhere, ears everywhere else.
You kids had all the tech you could dream of.
Here we all are back on earth...
with nothing but our wit, and our will, to save the world.
Ultron says the Avengers are the only thing between him and his mission.
And whether or not he admits it...
his mission... is global destruction.
All this laid in a grave.
So stand.
Out wit the platinum bastard.
Steve doesn't like that kind of talk.
You know what, Romanoff?
So what does he want?
To become better.
Better than us.
- He keeps building bodies. - Person bodies.
Human form isn't efficient,
biologically speaking, we're out-moded...
but he keeps coming back to it.
When you two programmed him to protect the human race,
you amazingly failed.
They don't need to be protected.
They need to evolve.
Ultron's going to evolve.
How?
Has anyone been in contact with Helen Cho?
It's beautiful.
The vibranium atoms aren't just compatible with the tissue cells...
they're binding them.
and Shield never even...
The most versatile substance on the planet,
and they use it to make a Frisbee.
Typical of humans.
They scratch the surface and never think...
to look within.
I'll take Natasha and Clint.
Alright, strictly recon.
I'll hit the Nexus. I'll join you as soon as I can.
If Ultron is really building a body...
He'll be more powerful than any of us.
Maybe all of us.
An android designed by a robot.
You know, I really miss the days when the
weirdest thing science ever created, was me.
I'll drop Banner off at the tower.
Mind if I borrow Miss Hill?
She's all yours, apparently.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know, something dramatic I hope.
I'll finish reflooring the sunroom as soon as I get back.
Yeah, then you'll find another part of the house to tear apart.
No.
It's the last project.
I promise.
This is it.
The water of sight.
In every realm it has a reflection.
If the water spirits accept me, I can return to my dream...
and find what I missed.
Men who enter that water, the legends... don't end well.
A hacker who's faster than Ultron.
He could be anywhere,
and if this is the center of everything
I'm just a guy looking for a needle in the world's biggest haystack.
How do you find it?
Pretty simple... you bring a magnet.
Oh, I'm decrypting nuclear codes and you don't want me to.
Come and get me.
Wake up!
Thor!
Extinction.
Cellular cohesion will take a few hours,
but we can initiate the consciousness stream.
We're uploading your cerebral matrix...
now.
I can read him.
He's dreaming.
I wouldn't call it dreams.
It's Ultron's base consciousness...
informational noise.
How soon?
I'm not being pushy.
We're imprinting a physical brain. There are no shortcuts.
How could you?
How could I what?
You said we would destroy the Avengers. Make a better world.
It will be better.
When everyone is dead?
That is not...!
The human race will have every oppotiunity to improve.
And if they don't?
Ask Noah.
You're a mad man.
There were more than a dozen extinction level events
before even the dinosaurs got theirs.
When the earth starts to settle...
God throws a stone at it.
And believe me he's winding up.
We have to evolve. There's no room...
for the weak.
And who decides who's weak?
Life.
Life always decides.
There's incoming.
The Quin jet. We have to move.
That's not a problem.
Uh, wait, guys!  I...
They don't understand.
When they see, they'll understand.
I just need a little more... time.
Two minutes. Stay close.
Dr. Cho.
He's uploading himself into the body.
Where?
The real power is inside the cradle.
The gem...
it's power is uncontainable.
You can't just... blow it up.
You have to get the cradle to Stark.
First I have to find it.
Go.
- Do you guys copy that? - I did.
I got a private jet taking off across town.
No manifest.
That could be him.
There... it's a truck from the lab.
Right above you Cap... In the loop by the bridge.
It's them. I got three with cradle. One in the cab.
I can take out the driver.
Negative, that truck crashes, the gem can level the city.
We need to draw out Ultron.
No! No, no, no...
Leave me alone!
Well, he's definitely unhappy. I'm gonna try and keep him that way.
You're not a match for him, Cap.
Thanks, Barton.
You know what's in that cradle?
The power to make real change.
And that terrifies you.
I wouldn't call it a comfort.
Stop.
Got a window, Four, Three, ...
Give 'em hell.
I'm always picking up after you boys?
They're heading under the overpass. I've got no shot.
Which way?
On right.
Now!
Out the way, coming through... sorry... coming through.
Come on.
Clint, can you draw out the guards?
Lets find out.
Beep, beep.
Heading back towards you, so whatever you're gonna do... do it now.
I'm going in. Cap can you keep him occupied?
What do you think I've been doing?
The package is airborne.
I have a clean shot.
Negative, I'm still in the truck.
What the hell are you doing?
Just be ready. I'm sending the package to you.
How do you want me to take it?
Hmm... you might wish you hadn't asked that.
Please... don't do this.
What choice do we have?
I lost him. He's heading your way.
Nat, we gotta go.
- Clint! - Nat!
Cap, see Nat?
You have the package. Get it to Stark! Go!
Do you have eyes on Nat?
Go!
Damn!
Civilians in our path.
Can you stop this thing?
I'm fine.
I just need to take a minute.
I'm very tempted not to give you one.
The cradle. Did you get it?
Stark will take care of it.
No, he won't.
You don't know what you're talking about. Stark's not crazy.
He will do anything to make things right.
Stark, come in.
Stark.
Anyone on comms?
Ultron can't tell the difference between saving the world and destroying it.
Where do you think he gets that?
- Anything on Nat? - I haven't heard...
but she's alive or Ultron would be rubbing our faces in it.
This is sealed tight.
We're gonna need to access the program, Break it down from within.
Any chance Natasha might leave you a message outside the internet?
Old school spy stuff?
There's a net I can cast.
I'll find her.
I can work on tissue degeneration,
if you can fry whatever operational system Cho implanted.
Yeah about that...
No.
- You have to trust me. - Kinda don't.
Our ally...
the guy protecting the military's nuclear codes...
I found him.
Hello, Dr. Banner.
Ultron didn't go after Jarvis because he was angry.
He attacked him because he was scared...
of what he can do.
so Jarvis went underground.
Okay, scattered, dumped his memory, but not his protocols.
He didn't even know he was in there until I pieced him together.
So... you want me, to help you,
put Jarvis into this thing?
No. Of course not.
I want to help you put Jarvis into this thing.
Way out of my field here.
You know bio-organics better than anyone.
And you just assume that Jarvis' operational matrix can beat Ultron's?
Jarvis has been beating him from inside without knowing it.
This is the opportunity. We can create Ultron's perfect self...
without the homicidal glitches he thinks are his winning personality.
We have to.
I believe it's worth a go.
I'm in a loop.
I'm caught in a time loop.
This is exactly where it all went wrong.
I know... I know what everybody's gonna say,
but they're already saying it...
We're mad scientists.
We are monsters, buddy.
You gotta own it.
Make a stand.
It's not a loop.
It's the end of the line.
I wasn't sure you'd wake up,
I hoped you would. I wanted to show you.
I don't have anyone else.
I think a lot about the meteors. The purity of them.
Boom! Begin.
Start again.
The world made clean for the new man to rebuild it.
I was meant to be new.
I was meant to be beautiful.
The world would have looked to the sky and seen hope...
...seen mercy.
Instead, they'll look up in horror because of you.
You've wounded me.
I give you full marks for that.
But like the man said, "What doesn't kill me...
...just makes me stronger."
This framework is not compatible.
Genetic coding tower's at 97 percent.
You have got to upload that schematic in the next 3 minutes.
I'm gonna say this once.
- How about nunce? - Shut it down.
No, not gonna happen.
- You don't know what you're doing. - And you do?
- She's not in your head? - I know you're angry.
Oh, we're way past that.
I can choke the life out of you and never change a shade.
Banner after everything that's happened...
It's nothing compared to what's coming.
You don't know what's in there. The creature...
This isn't a game.
No, no, it's alright.
You were saying?
Pietro!
What?
You didn't see that coming?
I'm rerouting the upload.
Go ahead, piss me off.
Wait!
I'm sorry, that was...
odd.
Thank you.
Thor?
You helped create this?
I've had a vision.
A whirlpool that sucks in all hope of life and at its center is that.
What? The gem?
It's the mind stone. It's one of the six infinity stones.
The greatest power in the universe... Unparalleled in it's destructive capabilities.
- Then why would you...? - Because Stark is right.
Oh, it's definitely the end times.
The Avengers can not defeat Ultron.
Not alone.
Why does your "vision" sound like Jarvis?
We configured Jarvis' matrix,
to create something new.
I think I've had my fill of new.
You think I'm a child of Ultron?
You're not?
I'm not Ultron.
I'm not Jarvis either.
I am...I am.
I looked in your head...
and saw annihilation.
Look again.
Huh. Your seal of approval means jack to me.
Their powers... the horrors in our heads...
Ultron himself...
they all came from the mind stone.
And they're nothing compared to what it can unleash.
- But with it on our side... - Is it?
Are you...?
on our side?
I don't think it's that simple.
Well... better get real simple real soon.
I'm on the side of life.
Ultron isn't.
He will end it all.
What's he waiting for?
- You. - Where?
Sokovia.
He's got Nat there, too.
If we're wrong about you...
if you're the monster that Ultron made you to be...
what will you do?
I don't want to kill Ultron.
He's unique.
And he's in pain.
But that pain will roll over the earth...
So he must be destroyed.
Every form he's built... every trace of his presence on the net.
We have to act now.
And not one of us...
can do it without the others.
Maybe I am a monster.
I don't think I'd know if I were one.
I'm not what you are...
and not what you intended.
So there maybe no way to make you trust me,
but we need to go.
Right.
Well done.
Three minutes.
Get what you need.
Good evening, boss.
No way we all get through this.
If even one tin soldier is left standing, we've lost.
It's gonna be blood on the floor.
I got no plans tomorrow night.
I get first crack at the big guy.
Iron-man's what he's waiting for.
That's true. He hates you the most.
Ultron knows we're coming.
Odds are, we'll be riding into heavy fire.
And that's what we signed up for...
but the people of Sokovia... they didn't.
So our priority...
is getting them out.
You're under attack! Clear the city! Now!
Get off your asses.
All they want is to live their lives in peace.
And that's not gonna happen today...
but we can do our best to protect them.
And we can get the job done.
We find out what Ultron's been building.
We find Romanoff...
and clear the field.
Keep the fight between us.
Ultron thinks we're monsters...
that we're what's wrong with the world.
This isn't just about beating him...
it's about whether he's right.
Natasha.
Natasha!
Bruce!
Are you alright?
Yeah.
The team's in the city. It's about to light up.
I don't suppose you found a key lying around somewhere?
Yeah, I did.
So, what's our play?
I'm here to get you to safety.
Job's not finished.
We can help with the evacuation,
but I can't be in a fight near civilians.
And you don't play.
Our fight is over.
So we just disappear?
Come on...
Your guy's in the church, boss.
I think he's waiting for you.
Come to confess your sins?
Oh I don't know. How much time do you got?
More than you.
Eh ... have you been juicing?
A little Vibranium cocktail?
You're looking... I don't wanna say puffy.
You're stalling to protect the people.
Well, that is the mission. Did you forget?
I've moved beyond your mission.
I'm free.
What?
You think you're the only one stalling?
There's the rest of the vibranium, function... still unclear.
This is how you end, Tony.
This is peace in my time.
Go!
Get off the bridge!
Back!
Ultron.
My Vision.
They really did take everything from me.
You set the terms. You can change them.
Alright.
Friday, The Vision?
Boss it's working, he's burning Ultron out of the net,
he won't escape through there.
You shut me out!
You think I care?
You take away my world,
I take away yours.
Friday.
Sokovia's going for a ride.
Do you see?
The beauty of it.
The inevitability.
You rise, only to fall.
You, Avengers...
You are my meteor. My swift terrible sword.
And the earth will crack with the weight of your failure.
Purge me from your computers,
turn my own flesh against me...
It means nothing,
When the dust settles,
the only thing living in this world
will be metal.
We gotta move.
You're not gonna turn green on me?
I've got a compelling reason not to lose my cool.
I adore you...
but I need the other guy.
Lets finish the job.
I really hope this makes us even.
Now go be a hero.
The Vibranium core has got a magnetic field.
That's what's keeping the rock together.
If it drops?
Right now the impact would kill thousands.
Once it gets high enough...
global extinction.
That building is not clear, its tenth floor.
Hi.
Ok...
Get in the tub.
We got airborne heading out to the bridge.
Cap, you got incoming.
Incoming already came in.
Stark you worry about getting the city back down safely.
The rest of us have one job...
tear these things apart.
You get hurt, hurt them back.
You get killed...
walk it off.
Go! Go! Go!
How can I let this happen?
Hey, hey, you okay?
This is all our fault.
Hey, Look at me.
It's your fault, it's everyone's fault.
Who cares?
Are you up for this?
Are you?
Look I just need to know, because the city... it's flying.
Ok look, the city is flying, and we're fighting an army of robots.
And I have a bow and an arrow.
None of this makes sense.
I'm going back out there
because it's my job,
Ok? I can't do my job and babysit.
Doesn't matter what you did, or what you were...
but if you go out there, you fight... and you fight to kill.
Stay in here, you're good.
I'll send your brother to come find you.
But if you step out that door...
you are an Avenger.
Alright, gotcha.
Yeah, this city is flying.
I got you.
Just look at me!
You can't save them all.
You'll never...
Never what? You didn't finish!
What? Were you napping?
Damn Thor!
You are bothering me.
Alright, we're all clear here.
We are not clear! We are very not clear!
Alright, coming to you.
Keep up, old man.
Nobody would know...
nobody.
The last I saw him, an Ultron was sitting on him.
Yeah I'll be missed.
That quick little bastard, I miss him already.
Hold your fire.
Romanoff!
Thanks.
The anti-gravs are ready to flip.
Touch them and they'll go full reverse thrust.
The city is not coming down slowly.
The spire is vibranium,
- If I get Thor to hit it... - It will crack,
That's not enough, the impact would still be devastating.
Maybe if we can cap the other end...
keep the atomic action doubling back.
That could vaporize the city,
and everyone on it.
The next wave is gonna hit any minute.
What you got, Stark?
Well, nothing great.
Maybe a way to blow up the city.
Have to keep it from impacting the surface
if you guys can get clear.
I asked for a solution, not an escape plan.
Impact radius is getting bigger every second.
We're gonna have to make a choice.
Cap, these people are going nowhere.
If Stark finds a way to blow this rock...
Not until everyone's safe.
Everyone up here versus everyone down there?
There's no math there.
I'm not leaving this rock with one civilian on it.
I didn't say we should leave.
There's worse ways to go.
Where else am I gonna get a view like this?
Glad you like the view, Romanoff.
It's about to get better.
Nice, right?
Pulled her out of mothballs with a couple of old friends.
She's dusty but, she'll do.
Fury, you son of a bitch.
Oooh! You kiss your mother with that mouth?
Altitude is 18,000 and climbing.
Life boats secure to deploy...
Disengage in three, two, ...
Take 'em out.
This is Shield?
This is what Shield's supposed to be.
This is not so bad.
Let's load them up.
Sir, we have multiple bogies converging on our starboard flank.
Show them what we got.
You're up.
Yes!
Now this is gonna be a good story.
Yup, If you live to tell it.
You think I can't hold my own?
We get through this, I'll hold your own.
You had to make it weird.
Here we go, here we go! Lets move.
Number six boat is topped and locked.
Or stuffed... topped... st- ... um ..
It's uh... full of people.
Incoming.
Whoa God.
You think you're saving anyone?
I just turn that key and drop this rock a little early,
and it's still billions dead.
Even you can't stop that.
I am Thor... son of Odin...
and as long as there's life in my breast...
I am running out of things to say.
Are you ready?
It's terribly well balanced.
Well, if it has too much weight to lose power on the swing, so...
I got it, create a heat seal.
I can supercharge the spiral from below.
Running numbers.
A heat seal could work with enough power.
- Thor, I got a plan. - We're out of time.
They are coming for the core.
Rhodey, get the rest of the people on board that carrier.
On it.
Avengers, time to work for a living.
- You good? - Yeah.
Romanoff?
You and Banner better not be playing hide the zucchini!
Relax, shellhead...
not all of us can fly.
- What's the drill? - This is the drill.
If Ultron gets a hand on the core, we lose.
Is that the best you can do?!
You had to ask.
This, is the best I can do.
This is exactly what I wanted.
All of you, against all of me.
How can you possibly hope to stop me?
Like the old man said...
together.
You know, with the benefit of hindsight...
They are trying to leave the city.
We can't let them, not even one.
- Rhodey. - I'm on it.
Oh no, I didn't say you could leave.
War machine coming at you, right.
Ok, what?
We gotta move out,
even I can tell the air is getting thin.
You guys get to the boats.
I'll sweep for stragglers... be right behind you.
What about the core?
I'll protect it.
It's my job.
Nat.
This way.
Get the people on the boats.
I'm not going to leave you.
I can handle these.
Come back for me when everyone else is off, not before.
You understand?
You know... I'm 12 minutes older than you.
Go!
Boss, power levels are way below...
Reroute everything.
We got one shot at this.
I know what I need to do.
Dining room.
I knock out that east wall...
make a nice work space for Laura.
Put up some baffling,
she can't hear the kids running around.
What do you think?
You guys always eat in the kitchen anyway.
No one eats in the dining room.
We don't have a lot of time.
So get your ass on a boat.
Hey, big guy...
The sun is getting real low.
Kostya?
We were in the market
Kostya!
Thor, I'm gonna need you back in the church.
- Is this the last of them? - Yeah.
Everyone else is on the carrier.
You know, if this works...
we maybe don't walk away.
Maybe not.
I have no strings, so I have fun...
I'm not tied up to anyone.
You didn't see that coming.
Oh for God's sake!
No, no. I'm fine.
It's been a long day.
Wanda.
If you stay here, you'll die.
I just did.
Do you know how it felt?
It felt like that.
Thor... on my mark.
Now!
Hey, big guy,
We did it.
The job's finished.
Now I need you to turn this bird around, ok?
We can't track you in stealth mode.
So help me out, I need you t...
You're afraid.
Of you?
Of death.
You're the last one.
You're supposed to be the last.
Stark asked for a savior...
and settled for a slave.
I suppose we're both disappointments.
I suppose we are.
Humans are odd.
They think order and chaos are somehow opposites and...
try to control what won't be.
But there's grace in their failings.
I think you've missed that.
They're doomed.
Yes...
but a thing isn't beautiful because it lasts.
It's a privilege to be among them.
You're unbearably naive.
Well, I was born yesterday.
Say hi to your Auntie Nat.
Sad.
One of our tech boys flagged this.
Splashed down in the Banda Sea.
Could be the Quin jet...
but with Stark's stealth tech
we still can't track the damn thing.
Right.
Probably jumped out and swam to Fiji.
He'll send a postcard.
Wish you were here.
You sent me to recruit him... way back when.
Did you know then what was gonna happen?
You never know...
You hope for the best, and make do with what you get.
I got a great team.
Nothing lasts forever.
Trouble, Miss Romanoff...
No matter who wins or loses... trouble still comes 'round.
The rules have changed...
we're dealing with something new.
- Well the Vision is artificial intelligence. - A machine.
So it doesn't count?
No, it's not like a person lifting the hammer.
Right. Different rules for us.
- Nice guy... artificial. - Thank you
He can wield the hammer. He can keep the mind stone.
It's safe with the Vision.
These days safe is in short supply.
But if you put the hammer in an elevator.
It would still go up.
Elevator's not worthy
I'm gonna miss these little talks of ours.
Not if you don't leave.
I have no choice.
The mind stone is the fourth of the infinity stones to show up in the last few years.
It's not a coincidence.
Someone has been playing intricate games... and has made pawns of us.
Once all these pieces are in position...
Triple Yahtzee?
- You think you can find out what's coming? - I do.
Besides this one, there's nothing that can't be explained.
That man has no regard for lawn maintenance.
I'm gonna miss him though, and you're gonna miss me.
There's gonna be a lot of manful tears.
I will miss you, Tony.
Yeah?
Well... It's time for me to tap out.
Maybe I should take a page out of Barton's book.
Build Pepper a farm... hope nobody blows it up.
The simple life.
You'll get there one day.
I do not know.
Family... stability...
Guy who wanted all that,
went into the ice 75 years ago.
I think someone else came out.
You alright?
I'm home.
Wanna keep staring at the wall, or do you want to go to work?
I mean it's a pretty interesting wall.
Thought you and Tony were still gazing into each others eyes.
How do we look?
Well we're not the '27 Yankees.
We got some batters.
They're good, but not a team.
Let's beat'em into shape.
Avengers....!