Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
The whole thing began in (Bern), Sweden, 1999
The good old days
I did not think I will return to fabricate problems
And what shall I do?
(Hello (Tony), I (Oldrch Aelian I admire your business
My business? - Is يقصدني I -
Of course Lady (Hansen), my organization is tracking your business "in the" Massachusetts Institute of Technology
, I shouted, I've managed to access
Which floor? That's a good question
Downstairs, I myself have brought him
My organization is made up of a special group of scientists "are called" advanced ideas mechanism
I'll have Monday and one to me, and the other
"Remember," the ideas advanced mechanism ", or short" Im
Of course we will remember, it is written on your shirt
Followed him please, ladies first
Thank you, I'll call you
I am happy to work with you
Met me on the surface in five minutes
Be quick - Well -
See you at the top
Bet on it
Really, I thought it was just a theory
It was also
If you calamity Fbamkanna access to the brain and re-encrypted chemically
This stunning
We can take the system to inherit a living organism
Exactly
Do not touch my intentions, they do not like it
, It's not like others to go to the bedroom
Happy) Let her alone) - I seriously do not touch it -
Stbdoan with plants? - (Yes, I call it (excessive class
Call it (excessive degree)? - Matching human, exactly -
Automatic fix
Disease prevention
You're the smartest woman I met her
Here in Switzerland
This is the best - this week -
You do not hide anything, right?
That's what I'm talking about - Is Tfqdta system (telomerase) computer -
We're fine
Sit
You're over me
What was this?
What was this? - It was a problem and I'm working to resolve it -
This is what happened
Happy New Year - Happy New Year -
See you tomorrow, goodnight - you okay? -
Yes, thank you - I'm abroad -
If you do, why I do this? I did not I create only demons
Did not even know it
You know who I am
Yes, times were good
Then left
(After a period spent in the caves (Afghanistan have to leave this area
I forgot that night in Switzerland "Nowadays, Malibu, CA"
These days I'm a different person "(inventions (Stark) Department of the (t: d"
Become different now
Well, you know who I am
... Sir, would you allow me a few hours to check
! Not yet
Almtakabbat were transplanted
As you wish, sir, as you have set up some means of protection
It is what I'm going to do
I'll do it first
O foolish
How did you get that hat?
What do you do away from the corner? You know what I did
Clean blood there
Sir, do not allow me to remind you that you are awake 72 hours ago?
Please focused ladies, good evening
And welcome to this suite
I am pleased to tell you the arrival of your brother active asshole
Jarvis) filled music)
Come
Well, I think that's wonderful, sent the rest
Not so fast, slowed down a bit
Jarvis), quietly)
Come
What are you scares
I'm the best
I am happy to see you always work, sir
I think that the lack of sleep for 72 hours after taking a nap is a very long time
I did not think that it will get worse
And then ran TV
This is what happened
Some Alqubna the terrorist
I consider myself a teacher
... America
Preparing for a new lesson
(In 1864, (b Colorado
Waiting for the U.S. Army tribesmen (Cheyenne) even went out for hunting (one of the ancient American Indian tribes)
Of the attack on their families and slaughtered
Then occupied their land
(39 hours ago was the base (the peace air attack in Kuwait
I did it
Beside the church the child Almlih army and wives
The soldiers were busy maneuvering
Fighters were eliminated
President (Wallis) continues to deny my strength
Now hear me
You know me, but you do not know where I am
Will not see me and I'm coming
.... And get back to you to provide summary
American plane was hijacked
State raises alert
All attempts to find a (Mandarin) failed
My administration's response to these terrorist incidents will depend on the new element
(I know the name of Colonel (James Rhodes
(American people Saarafh the soon as (the Iron citizen
(The response of President (Wallis
Depending on a man named (war machine) inside plated costume
The same Hilla but painted red and blue, look for this
(And named it (citizen Iron
Color was very clear
The results of the tests are good, is not it?
(Why is it called (Iron citizen - Harken -
The war machine), was very hostile, is not it?) This name sends a better message -
So, what is really happening (Mandarin)?
Seriously, Can we be talking about this guy?
(This is my confidential information (Tony
Well, there were nine explosions - nine? -
Advertised is only three
You have it, no one can hide those bombs
Has no effect - you know that I can help -
, You had to ask only have techniques and a new suit
Alone recovery
Stop the bombings in the air
When grown the last time? - Einstein) had slept three hours per year) -
(We are worried about you, O (Tom I'm concerned about you
Osthajmna now - I'm not trying to be a fool -
Would you mind to sign me? -
If (Richard) does not mind, do you agree? - Yes -
What is your name? - (IRIN) -
By the way, I liked the story of Christmas
(I hear the concerns (the Pentagon
After what happened in New York and living space after New York, foreign and Tri ...
It should look strong
Stop (Mandarin) a top priority - but it is not the responsibility of Superheroes -
Do NOT their responsibility - فهمتك the -
These belong to the American state responsibility - sorry -
Are you okay?
Have Caesarean pen - Are you okay, sir?
Dangle, Tony O
.... How did you
Tony
Sorry
Test the heart and brain
There is no indication of unusual activity in the brain and heart
You been Tzmimi?
Diagnostic you suffer from severe panic attack
I?
Come on, man, this does not leave a good impression - sorry, but I have to go -
Emblem, emblem
Emblem you guys put it up in the toilet
Tony) puts it in his basement)
If, you are suggesting that I am replacing the maintenance team Balrepotat
What I mean is that the human element is very important
But he does not respond immediately
Why? - (Sorry, O (Bambi
Did I say this just - Security -
, Happy), I'm happy you're head of security) - it's the perfect job for you thank you -
With it - I really appreciate it -
Since I took the job - not you have to Ckrini -
Employee complaints increased by 300 percent
This is not Madha
, This praise, of course, this praise they are trying to hide something
We're sorry, you have a meeting
Did you discuss with me in this meeting - Happy) we will discuss this later)
But now we have to go back to this annoying job
How's this?
You out with me this way embarrasses me a little
I know how it looks like this
(Piper) - (Killeen) -
You look great, really Oh my God, you're well
What would you do?
Nothing special, I spent five years with a physiotherapist
(Please, Nadini b (Aldrich
It was supposed to be a security card with you - Happy), not quite)
Really - we're fine -
Are you sure? - Yes -
Rest a little bit - I'll be abroad -
Thank you
(I'm happy to see you, (Killeen
I shouted
Happy Birthday
After years of overcoming the moral embargo imposed by the President on biotechnology research
, My team now has something to offer "an idea I like to call" Xstremst
To turn off the lights
Imagine the human brain
! Wait this universe, the error me
.... But if I did this
This is a brain, a strange match, what do you think of him?
This stunning - it's my brain -
Why? - This inside my head -
It is broadcast neighborhood Otbaana, and will prove to you
Come
Hold my arm, I can afford this
What is this? - Part responsible for the sense of touch -
Pain center in the brain that ... I want to show this
Now The "Xstremst" The effects using our bio-electric
And go to here
Hello - Are you responsible security? -
Listen, I have something for you is happening here
Let me tell you something, when I tell people I guard (Iron Man) were mocking me
I want to retrieve even an iota of dignity
Now I have something important
What's happening? Tell me
Really? - Yes -
Aalmtna meet with the world of the rich and handsome now
Did not recognize him at first
You know I'm good at remembering faces - yes, definitely -
Oldiritg Killeen) had investigated him and discovered that we) قابلناه by the year 1999 at a scientific conference
In Switzerland - already -
I do not remember - of course, because you were with those blonde with big chest -
At the outset of the meeting was normal but now it has become a stranger he Rehn large brain Why? -
Large brain, and I have Jbha
Let me show you see?
I see what? See you and you تشاهدهم the flip screen to begin
I'm not a genius like you trust in, by and come here
Turn the screen order أشاهدهم - I do not know how the heart of this screen -
Do not talk to me like I'm your boss
I do not work, you do not trust this guy he seems Kamraog
Calm down, I ask you to believe in the place and by and brought him a drink
Should be more concerned with what's going on here
This woman is the best thing that happened in your life
And you ignore them - a big brain? -
Yes, the big brain and there is a strange person monitored
I will follow this person and find the license plate and if it has become difficult, so be it as well
(I miss you (Happy - and I also but the old بشخصيتك -
, I do not know what happened to you now the world has become a stranger
I'm sorry to interrupt, ... But I think that there سيسرق
Imagine that you can penetrate any living organism and evaluating the work of nuclear acidophilic change
Would be an incredible thing
Unfortunately, because of my experience I think it will be used in evil
, Such as the use of soldiers (used to improve the armies, and (Tony
Tony, Tony
(You know, I have called (Tony) to enter (IM
13 years ago and has refused to
I feel that there is a new genius and not have to tell Tony and I think that we must take care of it
(Sarvd Oh (Aldrich I wish the assistance
, I can not hide my frustration, but as my father used to say
"Failure is the fog that leads to success"
, It's very deep, but I do not know what they mean
I'm well, the old man was a fool
Sure we Sntkabl again
(Wahhabi) - the car is ready -
, Oh my God, I forgot something must go up again
I apologize for the delay What is this?
Otertdi at home now (such as stated in the Gospel of Mark (Part 15
Yes, something like that you know that everyone has a weakness
And you'll wear it in the living room - only accustomed, is somewhat narrow -
Are رأيتي the gift for Christmas?
Yes, I saw her, I will not miss Christmas gift -
You can not enter through the door? - That's a good question, some workers will come tomorrow to demolish the wall
Are you nervous? Omrrt fine day?
I do not want to push more, Did you like this?
Did you like this rabbit? - Do you like? -
I appreciate this idea, why do not remove this mask and give me a kiss
I can not, I can not do that
... Otstiei that Tmrreha through this this place
I'll go to the garage and get a drink
What a beauty, Beware of radiation
سأخاطر - this is a big risk -
Looking to put your protective suit.
Geiger counter) or something)
Okchwta Emery - This new level baht -
Sorry - you eaten without me? -
What about our appointment tonight?
... It is only - you're talking about yourself -
, Yes, I mean we, we just Ncelik've accomplished something at work
And yes, I've eaten something I did not know Is Staudin for home
(Or ستقومين the drink with (Aldrich Killeen
What?
Aldrich Killian? Are you watching me?
I was worried - no, I was spying on -
I'll go to sleep
Wait, I admit I've made a mistake, I apologize
No longer as you are, it will take some time
(Nothing is left as it is since (New York - really -
I did not notice it, never
Tgrbin something and then end up, because can you explain this?
, Extraterrestrials, other dimensions I'm just a man in the tinplate
The only thing that keeps me, is that you are with me
It's great, I love you
But I can not sleep
You go to bed, I will keep here ... I do not know
The danger is imminent
And I have to protect the only thing that I can not live without it
You mean.
And my armor is...
Machine - It's a part of me -
It's just a distraction - perhaps -
I'll take a bath - Well -
Will join me - Excellent -
! Tony
Stop
, Should I call the dream was not supposed to happen
You must re-adjust the sensor
... Can we just pick ourselves dear, do not go
Below I will sleep, I can not afford this
- You can you adjust?
- Yes
Are you sure? - Yes -
This is for you
The less I did not do anything for you - thank you ... I mean for your understanding -
Sorry, my friend
Where do you go, my friend?
How are you my friend? Do you have an appointment? Do you want to watch a movie with me?
"Yes, the film is called" the end of the concert
Sashahdh with you and your girlfriend addicted, here is the ticket
No, this is not yours
Help me! Help me
A true story about fortune cookies
Looked like a tray
But in fact the invention of U.S.
, But this is bad, full of falsehoods leave a bad taste in the mouth
The disciples destroy another American tradition
, Chinese Theater, Mr. President
I know that it's frustrating
But terrorism season coming to an end
But do not worry, the biggest attack coming
I congratulate
Can you keep it?
"Likes the series" Down Town village best watched on TV as he told me
Men will take care of everything
(Waiting for the arrival (Tony Stark to know, what will be the reaction
... Reaction to this attack
Mr. Stark!
All the evidence suggests that attack (Mandarin
Can you tell us anything about that?
Mr. Stark, you will be eliminated?
Is this what you want?
(This is a message I want to send it to (Mandarin
I did not know formulated by now
My name is Tony Stark and I'm not afraid of you
, And I know that you are a coward so I decided
You're dead
I'll get to take your body
This has nothing to do with politics, it's just revenge
Without the intervention (the Pentagon), this is between you and me
, And if you think you are a man, this is my address
10880, Malibu Port, 90265.
I'll leave the door open, is that what you want?
Waiting
Mandarin database, sir
Assembled by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Central Intelligence Agency
Crime scene is run interactive
Well, what we have
"His name comes from" an ancient Chinese legend
"It means advisor to King"
Has combat experience from South America
Speaks Kaloaaz the
Should he brags this
Close - surpassed heat blast 3000 ° C -
What if I were not a bomb?
Any victims of the military? - Not according to the recordings available -
The temperature data showed once again the beginning of 3000 ° C
Temperatures of more than 3000 degrees - completed analysis the -
Is access to satellite thermal and identify activities that have occurred in the past 12 months
Ruled out places that have nothing to do with an attack Mandarin
No
Are you sure that this is not it?
Are recorded every Mandarin attacks
Has been to use suicide bomb in this incident
The same temperature, 3000 ° C
Two army soldiers
(Do check (Tennessee), O (Jarvis
(Flight Plan Design for (Tennessee
Omazlna allow system knocked on the door?
Disable security systems, really, has threatened terrorist, than this?
I can not do much, Sir, when you give the world press home address
Stand have
You are not Mandarin, is not it? - You do not remember me -
Why I am not surprised? - You know what I ate this morning? -
Three-ply, sir
I want to be with you alone is not here, it salt
, Usually ignore these calls, but now I have a stable relationship
With them - Hey Tony -
- Is there anyone?
- Yes, Maya Hansen.
An old friend, known years ago
Please, do not tell me that there is a child in the second ten waiting in the car
Is at 13, I need your help - why? Why now? -
Because I read newspapers and I do not think you will endure weeks
I'll be just fine
Sorry
The existence of (Happy) in the hospital I did not expect to receive guests
I'm not
Khaliltk old - no, not so -
No, not really, it was for one night
If, so I did
It was a great night - Well, do you know? -
You have found yourself suffering - why? -
We will go out of the city
Will not go into this debate - but we will do -
The man said no - immediately and for an indefinite period -
Great idea. Let's go - this is a bad idea, Please do not Telmusa to her luggage -
Thus, people act natural - I can not protect you abroad -
Is this normal? - Yes, this is normal -
Very natural - It's a big rabbit -
Calm down - I've bought this for you -
You say to me constantly that you do like - I do not like -
Do not do like?
We will be leaving from home
Why? - You should be worried because of this? -
I delivered you - I delivered you first -
As I said, we can not stay here
Come
Take it and I will come and I would find a way out
Do not stand,'ll go, 'Go
Tony!
Miss Potts is out, sir.
Jarvis, where the capacity of Aviation - are processed sir -
Day 1
Equipment not equipped to fight sir
Second
! Tony
Take a deep breath, sir
Been running ability of Aviation
Sir
Sir - Alarm clock stopped -
Emergency alarm is triggered when the force becomes less than 5 percent
Raining snow where we are, in the north?
(We just 5 kilometers (Rose Hills Tennessee
And why?
Jarvis This is not my idea of what we are doing here? (We kilometers away, must be brought (Bieber
I set up the flight plan
This is the place - you are asked? -
How Hilla, take me out? - I think it works well -
This cool
Do not leave me, my friend
Stark, the communication unit will reveal a well-known users
Bieber), that I am)
Must apologize for many things, but first apologize to of and , this will not happen again
Also, sorry for Christmas gift
That's all, sorry
Also forgive me, because I will not be able to return home for the time being
You must find this guy kept safe
I've stolen coat Indian
House home
Are you happy now?
Do not move
Do not move - you get this -
Nice pistol
Alonob longish
Large diameter will reduce the speed of
Now concluded ammunition - What is this thing on your chest? -
Electromagnet
How powerful is it?
Oh my God!
Is this Ironman - Technically, yes -
Technically, you're dead -
This point of view - what happened to him? -
We have the structure in order to take care of me
Sasalehh - Kalmakaneki -
Yes
If you build an iron man and war machine
(Name (Iron citizen - this is the best -
No, not well
... In any case, you add her paintings
Reflective plates? - Yes, to make them invisible
Invisible? - A wonderful thing, is not it?
Great idea,
I will.
No, not great.
What are you doing? You'll break your finger?
Will be suffering. Was injured. leave him alone
Sorry - really -
Nothing wrong, Sasalehh
Mom and Dad working to buy tickets luck
I think he won because he left 6 years ago
This happens, you do not need to worry about so much I need you computer, digital clock, phone
, Activated the antenna of your game, a map of the city and a tuna sandwich
And what will I benefit? - Deliverance, what's his name?
Who? - The boy who beat you in school -
How do you know this?
I'll show you something
(This racket (cricket was joking, it is an effective weapon, and face to face
And will lose his resolve
Only to protect yourself
OK, do you agree? - Agreed -
What is your name? - Harley -
And you - mechanical -
Tony
You know what is going on in the head?
Where Hterta?
System (Stark) security
Must apologize for many things, but first apologize to of and ي, this will not happen again
Why did you come our house? (What is it important to talk it with (Tony
(I think that works for the major (Mandarin
So, if you want to talk in this Flanjd place safer
Your boss works for the Mandarin, but Tony said you plant
, In fact, do I change operations on DNA responsible for 40 people, but you can call me Ballenbatih
This boss has a name? - (Yes, (Aldrich Killian
, The villa was destroyed, sir, but do not mark the presence of the body
No trace of Stark
I must go
.... President has registered with
You will know when I finish
Do it tonight, call me when you are finished
Well guys, I do not want gossip or eye signals, otherwise you will receive a bullet in your face
President on the way to you
What are you waiting for?
Sandwich was accepted with little rust and other materials, but I'll be fine
By the way, when you told me that your sister has the hour you want something more from this potency
, It's six Mnm year-old anyway did not come down them a lot
Oakmenk tell me about New York? - I probably will not do -
This is the best dangle - Can you tell me about the Avengers?
Give me more space
What is the official story here? What happened?
I think it is for a man who lives (nearby, named (Davis
Got a lot of medals in the army
People say that Jane affectionate one day and bomb-making
And died here
Six dead, right? - Yes -
(Including (Davis - yes -
Does not seem logical
Six dead, and there are only five shades
Yes, but people say that shadows signs to indicate the entry of persons Paradise
So the man who made the bomb went to hell because there is a shadow
So they are only five - and you believe this -
This is what is said
You know what this reminds me of? - I do not know I do not care -
The giant gate in New York, Oivkirk this?
You are manipulative, I do not want to talk to this
Osaaudon, aliens - maybe, can you stop? -
I told you that I am suffering from anxiety problem
Is this issue bother you? - Yes, a little bit -
Can I pick up my breath? -, There are bad people in Rose Hills - Need a plastic bag to throw them?
- Taking medicine?
- Do not -
- Suffering from posttraumatic stress?
- I do not think so -
Do you become completely insane? I can not stop, do you want me to stop?
, I told you before, I want you to stop you push me crazy
Well, I've got what I wanted, Osaid now? - What did you say? -
Wait, wait
What was this? - This is because of you, you crazy -
(Let's talk about (Davis
The man who died, his parents relatives? Where do you live and his mother?
Permanent in place - you see, you help me now -
... Sorry, Madam
Thank you - nice hair -
H nice - did not come down them a lot -
I have no doubt this
I wish you good night
Ms. (Davis),
can take place here?
- It's a free country.
- Of course.
Well
Ait want to start racing? - I want to Oazik the bris -
I want to know what you think about what happened
We brought you the dreaded Take it and go
Whatever it was here it was not part of it
Obviously you are expecting the arrival of another person
Yes
Madam son did not kill himself, and I guarantee you he did not kill anyone, there are those who exploited
Why? - Weapon -
I'm not the person who called me, right?
In fact, I did
What happened here?
Called detention
You sheriff, is not it? Yes, and you Who are you?
National Security Are we just fine here - no, not at all -
I need more information about this - I think that this is beyond your level -
Why not call the
Nashville to widen me?
You know, I was hoping to solve this in the right way
But the fun is always good
Dear Assistant, grabbed this mirror
Come on, do you want to have fun, to go
Sounds crazy, does not it? - Yes -
Watch this
I wanted it but I've prepared the most beautiful women you,
Is that what thing? Cheap Trick
My dear, you'll be the title of my CV
Let me, help me
Hello Lefty What do you want for Christmas? - Sayed (Stark) I am very sorry -
No, no, I think that what he is trying to say is Where My dreaded
Not your fault, son.
Do you remember what I told you about and b?t?u?
You liked, Mr. Robot?
This is a job for intelligence guys.
Always protect our butts.
You're Welcome!
Why, you missed something? - I have delivered you -
First, I have delivered you first Secondly, thank you
Third, if done known person does not boast, do free of charge, but will become boastful
Like you?
I admit that you need me, we are connected
I want you to come back to your home and stay with your mother and your mouth closed and protect Suit
And keep the phone next to even respond when Ohatvk
Well, I feel our present? We have finished here
Get out of the way or I cal.
Goodbye Boy.
- Sorry, young man,  You were finished.
- That leave me here, my father?
Yes, do you want to make me feel guilty? - I feel cold -
I know already, do you know how I know?
Because we are connected
It was worth a try
What happened to the picture?
Satellites do not work
We have to manually Nstaidha
Mr. Vice President, I think you should see this
, Oh my God, not again do you follow this President
Mr. President
Keep only lessons
Intend to Onhiama the VPL Christmas morning
Thomas Grichnz) the name of an influential and strength)
Foundation accountant (Rocks) oil
And sure he's a good man
I shoot in the head in front of the TV in 30 seconds
This phone number on your recorder's exciting, is not it?
Imagine this
Dear Americans, if you continue with me your president in a matter of 30 seconds, your president will live
Start counting
How broke my phone? - Can not allow terrorists that Eptdhuk -
You must call him - I strongly advise you not to do this -
This is the right disposition
(The remains only one lesson, President (Alice So run away and hide and let your children
Because it will not protect your or your dogs Aledadon the army
I'll see you soon
Mark (Rhodes) finds this despicable-off - have Takibna broadcast signal, sir
We found the reference in Pakistan - Iron citizen) is ready to attack) Now -
No تتحركوا
Wait a minute
Good evening (Richard) أتتذكر, when you're staring out and everything started to shine a light orange
Yes, who are you? - That I -
I want you to look at it for me because I am what I remember I did the same thing to you
What do you do? Ostzhb to Pakistan? What do you do?
I changed the design something for the company (AIME) is not it? Yes -
Should I contact satellite data need to login
"As is always the" war machine 608 PIN number, please
(I've jealousy more than once so as not to penetrate the O (Tony - are no longer in the eighties, no one says a breakthrough, give me him
"War Machine Rocks" are all uppercase
(This is much better than the (citizen Iron
Not suffice
... Sorry sir, I do not know
I'll call you later, Mom there is something enchanting happens
Tony Stark) inside my truck) - No -
I learned that you are alive - approached -
Is it possible to speak, sir? - Yes -
I am a firm your fans - Is this your truck, or will enter one of them? -
No, no, we're just - what's your name? -
(Gary) - Well -
That's enough, I'm having a lot like this, it's OK - ... Can you say
Yes, what do you want - .... I do not know if you noticed this, but I -
... My appearance like you, but my hair is not the same
Yes
I do not want to bother you, but I want to show you something
Well, this Spanish
Is this me? - Yes -
My girlfriend painted, so you do not completely Chbhec
Jerry), listened to) -
I do not want you here, we both overly excited
I have problems and peruse evil men want to identify important information from files
But I do not have a lot of options
I want you to go up to the top and increase the connection speed
For more than 40%, this is a task you understand -
(Tony) needs (Gary)
(Gary) needs (Tony) - quietly -
Go
What it considers the most important thing that happened in your life?
I think that today, in which it decided I do not let my injury يهزمني
PLEASE MENTION thicker for the camera - (Helene Brent) -
Well, are periodically injection
Will not be tolerant with those who do not conform to the laws of the program
Non-qualified, disabled You are the new generation of human evolution
Hi all, before we start I promise you, he would not Azaajkm something again
Day starts your glory, let's start
Should we leave from here
Bomb is not a bomb it fire inside
These things do not always work, right?
It failed, but you found a buyer, is not it?
(I بعته O (Mandarin
What a funny thing happened
Before you make a rocket to the Nazis
Had dreamed (Werner von Braun) to carry out a trip to space, be a guest of the stars
(You know what I said when I went to a (London
The rocket is designed with distinction
But he landed on the wrong planet
Surprised the world because of this "pure science"
And made us mania
When you see find yourself far
(Should not be harsh on yourself, O (Maya I have given your research of the company
And but (Klilian) used in military contracts - that's exactly what he used to do -
Not Thelomin yourself
(Thank you, (Piper
Appreciate you this
Hello, good evening - Good evening -
(اهربي O (Maya
(Hello (Piper
If, Ostkhbrenne what you are doing in Stark Palace last night?
I was trying to fix things I did not know you and (Mr.) Stfjron the place
If you're trying to save (Stark), even after threatening to us - I told you, O (Killian) we can take advantage of it -
(Piper), (Piper), (Piper) - (If you would like to launch the product next year, I need (Stark -
You are lacking
(This support team (Blue 0 (coordinates are sent suspected of (Mandarin
Roger
No one moves
Support Team (Blue 0) unless (Mandarin) is planning an attack on America these machines, I think you are mistaken target
Yes, you are free, that you want it yes ma'am
Iron citizen) at your service) happy to serve you, you do not need to thank
(SAFN) We've got a shield (Iron citizens)
If you want this you must remove the bodies of them first
(This is the plan (Col.
Harley), tell me what is happening, give me a full report) - eat sweets, Do you want some of them -
How you eat them? - Two or three -
Do you see well? - Somewhat -
Jarvis) What is our status?) I'm fine in some places
You're right Oh Spda, once entered the institution identified sources Mandarin broadcast
, Where? The Far East, Europe, North Africa, Iran, Pakistan, Syria, where is it?
(It is broadcast in reality (Miami - Well -
(Oh boy, driving سأعلمك (Jarvis, but not now, tell me where is the
See the screen and tell me where is
(Written (Miami, Florida - Well, I want armor first -
Where are we? - It's not ship -
In fact, sir, it is shipped but the power source (doubtful may not succeed with (the 42 mark
... What's the problem of electricity? It's two changes will not ... I do not want
Oh my God - Tony -
(Do you have another panic attack? Did not even mention (New York - I've said it, and deny -
Well
What do I do? - Breathe, breathe and by -
You're a mechanic, right? - To -
I've said this - yes, I've done
Why not build something by?
Well, thank you
Miami, Florida
Why so hot here? I told you to put it on a temperature of 60
... This is my fault again, I'll tell you something, I'm not
I did not took 20 minutes
(ايكما is (VINCENT - I -
(NESA)
... You know that the Chinese cakes - there is a man here -
... The U.S. is dependent on the Japanese you -
Damn, damn it - do not move -
I'm here with you, if you want something to take it, but fake weapons because they do not trust me by giving me real
Why? - Want to girls? -
Hey, you're not (Mandarin), where is it?
Where is it? - It is here, it is here -
Is here, but it is not here - what do you mean? -
It's complicated, wait, it's complicated - really? -
I like complexity, removed from the bed
(My name is (Travor Slatorra - What are you? -
You دوبلير, is not it? - No, in fact, do not -
Not تآذني, I am an actor
You have a minute he told me everything - he's just a role, (Mandarin) is not real -
(If, how I came here (Travor
I have a problem in wealth so I did things .... Her two ways
... In the streets do not have to do it the next -
Then they asked me to do the role and I knew something drug
Odjaloc get rid of them? - Gave me more
Gave me a lot, gave me this palace cosmetic surgery, gave me things
Is غفوت to just say? -
No, a beautiful boat of the matter is that I need someone
To make him take responsibility for accidental explosions
Is it?
Killian)?) - Killian)?) -
Is feign turn - already -
Like a terrorist threat - to -
Yes, I cheated a lot and has studied the theory of the killer infiltrator
Western character manipulation
Ready to hear another lesson?
Of course, my performance is bring to life the Mandarin
Your performance? The death of human beings? -
Look around, fashion and landscaping
I think it's charming
We're sorry, but my best friends lying in a coma and may never wake up
, You do not have to defend yourself will pay the price, okay?
Well, Travor what I told him? - I did not tell him anything -
Anything?
No - you had to use the anti-button trance -
I was terrified, but I dealt with it
كالأيام old, right? - Yeah, wonderful Kalguenblh -
Were not my idea - (if you took things (Killian -
I took his money - and now you're here 13 years later -
Inside the cell - not -
Yes - you from بالزنزانة, I'm free to go
(What happened (Tony has approached
Xstremst) practically stable) - I assure you, it is not -
, I saw him blow people Maya) you yourself تخدعين)
If, help me to fix it - "You know who I am"
Oketbt this?
Yes - I remember that night, not what happened the morning -
Is that why Ttardini? - Do not you remember? -
You're an ethical psychologist and you're perfect
تساعدين others, now Look for Halak
I used to waking up every morning with a person still has the spirit
Akhrgeni from here Come
You know what he would say to me and my father? One of his statements favorite
"The second mouse gets on الحبن"
Omazlt angry because of what happened in Switzerland, is not it? How angered you?
I'm here to thank you because you gave me the greatest gift
Despair, do you remember what happened in Switzerland? When told me you Stleghana in the roof?
, In the first 20 minutes you think you will come and then I decided to strode step
Entered the lobby, if you understand what I mean
I want to know what happened to the first mouse
, While you look for that city and no one knows me or knows my stay
راودتني she showed me the idea for years until I go back
(Hidden, O (Tony
بفضلك I as Tauveta, is not it? Adair from behind the curtain
Because when you give them the evil face
(Bin Laden), (Gaddafi), (Mandarin)
People become a target - Try something else -
Citizen you met him - yes, genius actor -
I know that sometimes overused, but this is not entirely my fault
Is a theater actor
Say things do not even know its meaning
In any case meant is that since the fall of the man with the hammer from the sky
No longer of interest to the nuances
What's the next step in your world?
I want to dedicate you the same gift to me
Despair, this live I do not know that you know
At this moment decides to accept the body (Ackstrimsst) or not
I think it will not be accepted and Séajmha
But until it reaches this stage they are in unbearable pain
We did not talk about your gift after
What useful thing that you think about it? - Let him go -
(Wait, (Maya - I was released -
What are you doing? - Half this dose and die -
There are times like this where it is a good test Sabri
Give me this Injector
If you died, O (Killian) What will happen to your soldiers and your product?
I would not do this - what will happen to you if your temperature increased too? -
The good news is, the high position just became empty
You're crazy - No, I am the owner of Vision -
Crazy, but I own a which Asassad the theater tonight
When we get the (citizen Iron) Sitagriq about nine to ten minutes to disassemble
This great last time that I saw there was someone inside
Good evening, gentlemen
Hello Colonel
Retracted
Snkrk from here, do not worry - Stvsdh so -
I'll do, but you can fix it, right?
I'll take this to the base and I want (Potts) me
Still in the second phase
Hearing did not lose, right?
Watch it for a limited edition
Big O
What is the mileage between (Tennessee) and (Miami)? - 832 miles -
Very nice
Can you stop? - Do not do -
Belonged to the sister of a friend for this I'll kill you first
What do you do to me? - We'll see -
You are restricted to bed - yes -
This
You will come out?
Do not open, do not open Well, let's go
You spit fire? Well
Great Day
Tomorrow at a time like this my hand will be the most powerful man at all
And most famous terrorist in the other hand
The war on terrorism will be Bedi
Create a "supply and demand for you and your brothers and sisters"
Believe me, you'll find yourself immersed in a pool of blood during 2,3,4,5 Come
How Nkrsh? - Well, Saattiykma's chance to escape threw your weapons
And left through 5.4
I was supposed to you fled now - before I'm awestruck -
It's time
3.4
Shut up - 54321 -
I told you
Where are the rest?
Frankly I hate working here understand very Grayboa eccentric
That comes better late than not come
Not this time - not the face -
(Happy to be back, Hello (Graphis - Hello, sir -
All units (Stark) trying to escape
Damn
Tony - Rudy, tell me you're from inside Hilla -
No, you inside Haltk? - Somewhat, the main house as hard as you can -
I would like to meet someone
Moved, dragged
Mandarin with us - looking at this -
Why did you come? - Move and Saahtm and face -
I did not know that there are people Sttave have lied to
This is the Mandarin? - I know, this is embarrassing -
(Hello, I'm (Trevor Slattery
I will not dwell this, if Statqlna ... There are some people
(You have it, tell us where (Bieber and I'll stop doing this
Stop what? Well, I understand
I do not know (Piper) but I know the plan
Occur - Do you know what who did Bhlta?
No, but Shaddt the beach when something related to a large compound Bomkanni pick you up there
Swear that I سأفجر and face
I think it's also related to Vice President
Is this important? - Yes -
So, what should we do not have the means of transport?
Ostkhberna for this beautiful boat?
(If what he said is true, we are 20 minutes from (Bieber - must deal with the issue of Vice President also -
Guess who's calling? He was Vice President
Welcome - (Sir, you (Tony Stark -
Welcome back to the land of the living - you become a target for them, we have to Nnqlk to a safe place -
Mr. (Stark) I'm going to eat you have with the elite and the Central Intelligence Agency
And the president in the presidential plane (with Colonel (Rhodes
I feel safe here - (Sir, I am Colonel (Rhodes -
, Using (Iron citizen) Trojan horse want to get rid of President must Nndhirhm the plane
Well, we'll insurance, and if necessary the aircraft to take off (in thousands of 22) in the air in 30 seconds
Is everything okay, sir? - Could not be better -
I love you, little one
Colonel (Rhodes) happy you're here, my son
I feel safe already
We must take a decision either to (save Alris or (Piper
(Sir, have I received anything from (Malibu
Jacks finally arrived and gates are evacuated at this time
And what about the two changes? - Works efficiently shield 92 percent -
This would be sufficient
Behold, I have come, Take me My him the
Is everything all right, Colonel?
I have the honor, Mr. President
If you Stflha, do it - slowly, sir -
Mandarin does not work that way - sir -
Presidential plane facing the threat of
An exchange of fire, a decrease in air pressure - Arne live images now -
(Is this (Rhodes
President, now
Not here
He tried to resist, and on this occasion favors
To see if you will be again, O foolish
How many of the atmosphere? - 13 sir -
How many can I drive? - Four sir -
Relax, what's your name? (Hasr)
Asamaana You must Tmiskin the this person when Tiger proximity
Okay?
Now will connect the power supply so it will not arm (Taatmkny of opening your hands, you can do (Heather
Otren how easy, now the remaining 11
(Do you remember the name of the game (a series of people this is what we're going to do
18,000 feet - grabbed ببعضكم -
Fantastic - 8,000 feet -
6000 feet - Come on you guys -
Come on, come on, come on
Yes - a thousand feet -
800 feet 200 feet - Nmskh -
Hello
Great job guys, you all you wonderful
(Well, (Jarvis
He came out of nowhere
Tell me good news, man - I think I rescued all -
But I left the President
, You can not save the President Hilla, how will save (Piper) without
Jarvis, the time has come - a protocol (Domestic ceremony) sir?
pass
Hello
If you think it will help, it will not do
Not the purpose of you are here to stimulate (Stark) to come by, well this little embarrassing
.... You are here k - Trophy -
Good evening, sir
Welcome on board the ship, Mr. President
, You hear all the tombs of two years ago, plagued by elephants elephant scabies
(This (Roxon Norco,
Of course you remember when 100 million gallons spilled "off the coast of Pensacola" "
And بفضلك converted to trial
What do you want from me?
Nothing sir
I wanted a reason to kill you in front of the TV
, You see I like to find in myself a good politician
At the same time tomorrow, will your store
Handcuffed
Come
Other do not get a heart, okay? - I hope so -
Oh my god
He was hanging over tank, Stlthmh the fire - Viking rituals -
With oil
Took your positions
Well, that's great, kinesthetic camera to site
Omek pistol?
Yes, what do you want me to do? - Cover the upper area -
You see? Managed it - yes, I was the bottle -
I can not correction from this distance
Give me a weapon - not easy, oh Tony -
I know this, give me them
Five of them have
سأراقب place I could not vision
Three men and a woman armed
I miss this shield now - you're right, we need to support -
See
Is this? - Yes -
This - Yes -
Happy Birthday
Jarvis), towards toward (Alokstremst) Almtharon heat) and بتدميرهم it to the fullest
What are you waiting for? He Christmas
Church
Jarvis, Can you prove that the station
This is what you are manufactured by in your spare time? - Everyone needs a hobby -
There helped him
Timing is great - this gorgeous, give me one -
Sorry, but it does not respond only to me
What do you mean? - Sahmik -
Good evening, do you give it? Tarif very -
We identified Ms. place (Bieber), sir - it took a lot -
Stop, revealed, revealed
Otren What happens when Tkablin a old friends?
You're a moron - Let's talk about this at dinner -
Come on, a little nearer
Do you bother?
Do not promote
Is it hot there?
Feel our something?
Sathok inside this Hilla
Tony
Schahidk
Got used you should close your eyes
Close your eyes
Oglgahma, you will not want to watch this
Relax for a minute
Jarvis, give me a suit now
Lord
Mr. President, stuck, I'm coming
Wait, wait
Well
Resist
Looks okay, Mr. President, but I need those Hilla
President safely Ya (Tommy) we will go from here
Omstad sir? - What do you mean? -
Bieber), quietly, Look at me)
I can not extend my hand more must Tflth the
Will not Avltk, I promise
What a shame, I Msktha
Finally we got to the surface
Mark 42), arrived) - This is wonderful -
The return of the prodigal son
What is it?
(Did not deserve my (Tony
You're about to get it would have been perfect
Wait, wait, you're right not deserved
But you are wrong
Is already perfect
(Jarvis, Osdna the known and dawn (Mark 42 - not -
No more of these faces
I have been trying behind the Mandarin you look at it now
I was from the beginning I Mandarin
I do not know what I'm saying
Jarvis, 12, is not an enemy target standing process
Are you angry with me?
Dear
Oh my god
I was very violent
... I was afraid of the very thought you - dead Why? I fell after sixty feet? -
From that caused chaos, now? - This will be discussed -
Why do not you wear so at home?
Delicious bra
I began to understand why you do not give up Hilla
There is no complain of it now
This I am, I'll think of something
Do not touch me, Sahriqk - will not happen -
I'm not hot
Will I be okay?
, No, that you're in a relationship with me will be fine
But I think that I can help in this
I think this happened to me 20 years ago and I was drunk, I think I could make you better
So things are fixed
All Anhravatk?
سأهتم this
(Jarvis) - goes well sir, you want something else? -
You know ماعليك the do
Protocol "clean slate" sir?
flap this, It's Christmas, yeah, yeah
Is that good yet, do you like it?
This is wonderful
So with Christmas morning my trip ended
I started with something pure, something exciting
Then comes the errors
Concessions
We make Xiatinna
It's great seeing you
(As promised dealt with what happened (Piper
Then I thought to myself,
Why do I stand here?
Of course, some people think that progress at risk
But did not live any of these fools with an open mind is full of shrapnel
And now I'm also
I'll tell you, this is the best Kulaiolh years ago
Not Bad - not -
Potato gun, "friend"
If you want to finish this brief
I think I'm going to say Deri was never for the purpose of distraction or hobby
But it was for protection
And now I'm a different man
You can take over the house
Or Khaddaa and My Games
But the only thing that will not take
(I (Ironman