There's simply no way
to shield against
every weaponized agent.
Instead, I can make
super-immune systems
by strengthening
the human cellular response.
Banner, I know
where you're going.
But manipulating
the immune system is
dangerous and stupid.
The President's
science advisors made it
absolutely clear,
no human subjects.
(SIZZLING)
EDITH: David,
I have wonderful news.
I'm gonna have a baby.
(EDITH GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(WAILING)
(COOING)
What's it gonna be?
Look at that, Bruce.
Want a dinosaur?
Let's have a little fight.
(DAVID ROARING)
You don't scare me.
(ROARING)
That's a delicious eyeball.
You're big and green
and scary. I'm gonna run away.
Really, speaking of Cheryl,
guess what...
Bruce, you're hurt!
Jack hit him
with the stick, but Bruce
wouldn't hit him back.
He just stood there, shaking.
(WHISPERS) It's okay.
Yeah, strange
he didn't make a peep.
Any other kid would've
wailed his head off.
That's Bruce. He's like that.
He's just so bottled up.
The samples
we found in your lab,
they were human blood.
You've ignored protocol.
You had no right
snooping around in my lab.
That's my business.
Wrong, Banner.
It's government business,
and you're off the project.
(ALARM BLARING)
Attention, all personnel!
Fail-safe has been initiated.
Gamma decontamination
will occur in 30 minutes.
Evacuate immediately.
I repeat,
evacuate immediately!
(SIREN BLARING)
(GASPS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Edith?
David, what's going on?
I gotta talk to you, Edith.
EDITH: Bruce, stay here.
What are you doing?
(YELLING)
(ROARING)
(CONTINUES ROARING)
EDITH: What are you doing?
DAVID: I'm trying to tell you
what's gotta be done!
David, please stop it! No!
David, no!
(EDITH SCREAMING)
EDITH: No!
DAVID: Yes!
David! No!
(DAVID SCREAMING HYSTERICALLY)
(BRUCE GROANING)
Bruce.
Bruce, wake up, Son.
Bruce. Bruce.
Another nightmare?
I don't know.
I don't remember.
Hi, Mom.
Already off to college.
I'm gonna miss you terribly.
I'll miss you, too.
Please, come here.
Look at you. Soon to be
a great scientist.
I guess. I mean, who knows?
I do.
There's something
inside you so special.
Some kind of greatness.
I'm sure someday you're gonna
share it with the whole world.
But as far as I'm concerned,
security ought to be...
Good morning, Dr. Krenzler.
Good morning.
Security ought to be
beefed up a lot more.
In a place like this
you can't be too careful.
Bruce! Big day.
Did you sleep?
I didn't sleep.
I slept okay. Is Betty here?
She's around.
I really gotta say,
seeing you in that
styling headwear...
You're implying something
about my helmet?
You look like a massive nerd,
even around other scientists.
Can I just ask?
Were you wearing the helmet
while she dumped you?
See, it protects
my very important brain,
Harper.
Go prep the samples.
Hey. I found you.
Betty, hey.
I hate them.
Wait, I just got here.
Who do we hate?
The review board.
We have to make
a presentation on Tuesday.
(GROANING)
And you're gonna
make it with me.
You think I should?
Yeah, you're great
with that stuff.
You start talking about
microbes and nanomeds,
you sound almost passionate.
I'm sorry. That was rude.
Look, nobody expects
this to be easy,
us working together
after being so close.
We were close?
(SNORTS)
Look, if I could be more
whatever, you know.
I'm just...
Don't. It's not
your fault, really.
You're just a byproduct
of my inexplicable obsession
with emotionally distant men.
I'll get over us.
Good for you.
Anyway, I'm just really
stressed about this review.
If we don't get
impressive results today,
we're gonna have a really
hard sell come Tuesday.
Well, then,
let's go be impressive.
Harper?
Ready when you are.
Let's hit it.
Are we passing inspection?
Safeties all going green.
Countdown's started.
Nanomeds released.
Four seconds.
Okay, nanomeds
fully dispersed.
Okay, let's hit Freddie
with the gamma radiation.
Gamma exposure.
Nanomeds now active.
HARPER: Nanomeds
replicating cells on border.
It's working.
HARPER: Cell copy
to disassemble ratio
holding within 1 %.
Imbalanced nanomed activity.
You wanna go to
the review board on Monday
and tell them we've developed
a brand-new method
for exploding frogs?
Yeah, I think maybe
there's a market for it.
I mean, what if
there's a plague?
What have you had, Betty,
like, one beer?
I'm just... I'm just saying,
you know, frogs start falling
from the sky,
who do they come to?
We'd be world-renowned.
Make any parent proud.
I bet they would be.
They actually did want me
to be a scientist.
I mean, your birth parents.
Guess we'll never know.
(SIGHS)
I don't understand
why you don't want to
find out about them.
They're dead.
They died before I could
remember anything.
Why do you always
come back to this?
Don't know.
I guess I figure
there's more to you
than you like to show.
I guess there
couldn't be any less.
Right. So now we come
full circle back to that.
Nice work, Betty.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Betty.
Glenn.
Hey.
Hi.
What happened to your uniform?
Oh, I switched over.
I'm still working
with your father, but...
Well, you know,
the military's
subcontracting out
all the most
interesting work, and...
Can't argue with the paycheck.
I basically run all the labs
on the base now.
Hey, you're...
You're looking good.
You're the genetics expert.
Ah, the good old college days.
So, how's business?
What do you want?
(CLEARS THROAT)
All right,
I'll cut to the chase.
I've been hearing
interesting things about
what you guys are doing here.
Your little molecular
machines have some
incredible implications.
How would you like
to come work for Atheon?
Get paid 1 0 times as much
as you earn now
and own a piece
of the patents.
You just have to say the word.
Two words, the door.
(DOOR CLOSING)
General?
Come in.
Talbot wanted you
to see this, sir.
It's about a lab Atheon
is targeting for acquisition
and removal to Desert Base.
Why isn't it going
through NSC?
It concerns
your daughter, sir.
Hi. Sorry.
Hey, what happened to Benny?
Is he not working
the night shift anymore?
Benny's dead.
I'm the new guy.
Oh.
Good to meet you.
Same.
(CLICKS)
Let's try another.
No, stay here.
I look tired anyway.
Yeah, but you look great.
What's the matter?
(CHUCKLES)
It's these dreams, Doctor.
I keep having them
and they're terrible.
Tell me about your dream.
Well, it starts...
It starts with a memory.
I think it's my first memory.
It's this image I have
from when I was maybe
two years old.
Do you think
it's just a dream?
No, I think it's something
that happened
when I was living
at a desert base
with my father.
BETTY: Anyhow,
the dream goes on
and suddenly l'm alone.
That's terrible.
You know I'd never hurt you.
(DOG WHIMPERING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Hey, there.
What's your name, darling?
What's your name?
(SNARLING)
Okay. It's okay.
(TYPING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
DAVlD: l gotta
talk to you, Edith.
EDITH: Bruce, stay here.
(GASPING)
(PANTING)
(DOG WHIMPERING)
(FROG CROAKING)
C, T, G, A,
G.
Bruce.
My Bruce.
Morning. Glenn dropped by.
What's he doing here?
You know, Dr. Krenzler,
you and I have never had
the chance to get to know
each other properly.
Well, that's because I don't
want to get to know you,
properly or improperly.
(BEEPING)
So leave.
Hey, no worries.
Let me give you
a little heads up.
There is a hair's breadth
between friendly offer
and hostile takeover.
I've done my homework.
The work you're doing
here is dynamite.
Think, GIs embedded
with technology
that makes them instantly
repairable on the battlefield
in our sole possession.
That's a hell of a business.
Well, it's not
what we're doing here.
We're doing the basic science
for everyone.
You know, someday
I'm gonna write a book
and I'm gonna call it,
When Stupid ldeals Happen
to Smart Penniless Scientists.
In the meantime, Bruce,
you will be hearing from me.
About Glenn, I...
There's nothing to talk about.
Okay.
I just wanted to say,
don't worry about him.
I'll handle it.
How?
I'm gonna call my father,
ask him to exert
some pressure.
Last I heard,
you and your father
weren't speaking.
Well,
I guess now I have something
to talk with him about.
HARPER: l think this circuit's
kind of fried. l don't know.
Maybe you wanna
come take a look at it.
Okay, l'll be right there.
(CRACKLING)
(GRUNTS)
(HARPER GROANING)
(GASPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
The gamma's too high!
Bruce, I can't stop it!
Harper, get out!
Get out!
(HEART BEATING)
(DOOR OPENING)
How's Harper?
He's all right.
You saved him.
I don't think
he's coming back to the lab
for a while, though.
I don't understand
how this is possible.
You should be dead.
They worked,
the nanomeds.
I mean, I feel great.
I feel like...
I don't know.
They must have,
like, fixed me.
Bruce, they've killed
everything else that they've
come into contact with.
Are you sure
the doctor checked?
The doctor gave me
the full workup.
He wants to know
where he can get
what I'm taking.
I'm 1 00%.
More.
What do you mean?
Remember my bad knee?
(LAUGHS)
Well, now it's my good knee.
Bruce, this isn't funny.
I was watching you.
You were gonna die,
and I was gonna
have to watch you die.
Betty, I'm sorry.
Really.
Hey, I'm not gonna explode.
Okay?
(CRYING) Yeah.
(SNIFFLING)
You should get some rest.
And I'm fine, really.
I've never felt better.
(PANTING)
(DOGS WHIMPERING)
Your name is not Krenzler.
It's Banner.
What?
Your name, it's Banner.
Bruce Banner.
Bruce.
How did you get in here?
I work here now.
In the labs. The late shift.
It keeps me close to you.
You always work
so late yourself with
your friend Miss Ross.
No, no. Please.
Please. Let me.
You're not well.
You've had
a terrible accident.
You're wondering
why you're still alive.
You're thinking
there's something inside.
Something different,
inexplicable.
I can help you understand,
if you'll let me.
If you'll
forgive me.
Look, mister,
I'm sure I have nothing
to forgive you for.
So perhaps you should
leave now. I'll be fine.
You must know.
You may not want to
believe it, but I can
see it in your eyes.
So much like your mother's.
Of course,
you're my flesh and blood.
But then you're
something else, too,
aren't you?
My physical son,
but the child of my mind, too.
No. You're lying.
My parents died
when I was a small boy.
No, no, that's not true.
That's what they wanted
you to believe.
The experiments, the accident,
all top secret.
They put me away
for 30 years. Thirty years!
Away from you.
Away from our work.
But they couldn't
keep me forever.
After all, I'm sane.
They had to admit it.
You see,
everything
your extraordinary mind
has been seeking
all these years,
it's been inside you.
Now we will understand it.
We will harness it.
(PHONE RINGING)
No, don't answer it.
It's Miss Ross again.
There's something
you need to know
about her, Bruce.
Something troublesome.
Let me protect you from her.
No. Get out.
Bruce...
Get out!
(SNARLING)
Sit!
(DOGS WHIMPERING)
We're gonna have to watch
that temper of yours.
(GAS HISSING)
(DOGS WHIMPERING)
(SNARLING)
BETTY: You sure you're okay?
BRUCE: Yeah,
just glad to be out of bed.
Got a message from my father.
He's coming to see me.
Your father?
When?
Lands in about an hour.
BETTY: The funny thing is,
he called me.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hi, Dad.
Hello, Betty.
WAITRESS: Here, ma'am.
Thanks.
You're welcome. Sir?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Look, I'm gonna
get right to it.
It's about Glenn, isn't it?
He's been snooping
around my lab.
Glenn noticed some things,
asked me to make
some inquiries.
Are you here to question me?
No.
We've turned up
some surprising things.
This Krenzler you work with,
you know who he really is?
How much do you actually
know about him?
I think the question is,
what is it that
you know about him?
Well, right now,
I'm not at liberty...
Not at liberty to
disclose it to me.
Right. Right.
You know, I think I was hoping
that maybe this time
you just honestly wanted
to see me again.
You've got this
all wrong, Betty.
Do I?
Yes. I do want to see you.
I really wish that
I could believe you.
DAVlD: Everything
your extraordinary mind
has been seeking
all these years,
it's been inside you.
(PHONE RINGING)
BRUCE ON ANSWERlNG MACHlNE:
Hi, you've called
Dr. Krenzler.
Please leave a message
and l'll call you right back.
(ANSWERlNG MACHlNE BEEPS)
BETTY: Bruce, hey.
Are you there?
Look, l think l screwed up.
My father...
lt's like he suspects you
of something. l don't know.
l was so impatient,
like always.
l didn't hear him out.
l don't know, l...
l just think
that they're planning
something with the lab.
So,
(GRUNTS)
call me. Okay? Bye.
Betty?
(GROWLING)
(DOG WHIMPERING)
(GROANING)
(BRUCE ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
(GROWLING)
Dispatch! Dispatch!
We have a 41 5 at the lab!
Send the Berkeley P.D. now!
Send them now!
(GROWLING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(ROARING)
Watch out!
DAVlD: Edith?
EDlTH: David,
what's going on?
l gotta talk to you, Edith.
Bruce, stay here.
(GROWLING)
(GASPING)
(ROARING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
My Bruce.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Bruce?
There was some
sort of explosion.
They wouldn't let us
into the building.
I was worried about you.
Well, I'm okay.
What happened to you
last night?
I had the most vivid dream.
It was like being born.
Coming up for air.
Light hitting my face.
Screaming.
My heartbeat,
it was like boom,
boom,
boom.
Were you at the lab?
No.
But something...
And there was that man,
the one with the dogs.
Who?
That new janitor.
He said he was my father.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
I'll get it.
(INAUDIBLE) My father.
My, my.
So this is the young
Bruce Ban...
Krenzler.
I think you left something
in your lab last night.
Mitchell,
escort my daughter outside.
I'll join her shortly.
I'd rather stay here.
Now, Betty.
It's okay. I'll be fine.
Keep him under observation.
I'll be back.
What?
Your friend in there,
there's a good chance
he's caught up in
some very bad business,
unfinished business.
And I promise you,
I'm gonna get
to the bottom of it.
You have my word
I'll make sure he's cared for.
But as of right now,
he is incommunicado.
And for the next
few days at least,
you're gonna stay away
from here.
For your own good.
Okay,
and that's for the new guy
on the night shift, right?
Great. Thank you.
I appreciate it.
(DOGS BARKING)
Dr. Ross.
How unexpected.
Please come in.
I'm sorry to just show up
at your house like this.
I came to ask you something
that I really have
no business asking.
He told you?
He said you talked to him.
Oh.
Please sit down.
Bruce was at the lab
last night.
He said that
you were there, too.
But he can't remember
much about it.
I need to find out
what happened.
So, you want to know
what's wrong with him,
so you can fix him?
Cure him, change him.
My father's with the military.
He seems to think
he's involved in some kind of
threat to national security.
(GROANING)
Your father. Ross.
You brought your father
down upon his head?
How little you understand,
Miss Ross,
and how dangerous
your ignorance has become.
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
My son is unique.
That's why you can't
relate to him.
And because he is unique,
the world will not tolerate
his existence.
Will they?
But you,
you try, don't you?
Yes.
And a very beautiful
woman like you,
your attentions
can't be completely unwanted.
Can they?
No.
Not with eyes like yours,
watching expectantly,
lovingly.
But I'm afraid we're both
too late to help him.
There's nothing I can do
for him or for you.
Besides,
he's made it clear he wants
nothing to do with me.
His choice.
Now if you'll excuse me,
Miss Ross, I got
some work to do.
And don't worry
about the dogs.
You'll be fine.
Just don't look them
in the eyes.
Goodbye.
ROSS: He gets released,
and a month later
your lab is destroyed.
What a coincidence.
So you're just not gonna
tell me where he is, are you?
How many times
do I have to tell you?
I'd like to help you,
but I just don't know.
You know who I am.
Right, Banner?
You're Betty's father.
You're a high-ranking general.
Let's cut the crap.
I'm the guy who had
your father tossed away,
and a lot more like him,
and I'll do the same with you
if I feel so disposed.
You understand?
If you had him tossed away,
then why are you asking me?
I don't remember.
I was always told
my father was dead.
Don't play with me!
You were four years old
when you saw it.
When I saw what?
You were right there.
How could anyone forget
a thing like that?
What?
Oh, some more
repressed memories.
Just tell me.
I'm sorry, son.
You're an even more
screwed-up mess than
I thought you'd be.
Until we get to
the bottom of this,
your lab has been declared
a top-secret military site,
and you're not gonna get
a security clearance
to get back into it
or any other lab that's doing
anything more interesting
than trying to figure out
the next generation
of herbal hair gel.
One more thing.
If you ever come
within 1 ,000 yards
of my daughter again,
I'll put you away for
the rest of your natural life.
(SNIFFS)
Dogs!
(DOGS SNARLING)
Go! Go get her!
And let nothing stand
in your way!
Go!
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
DAVlD: Bruce?
So, they think they can just
throw you away as they did me.
What's wrong with me?
What did you do to me?
l got a visit today.
A very unwelcome visit.
I'm afraid my hand
is being forced.
What did you do to me?
You so much want to know,
don't you?
But I think no explanation
will serve you half as well
as the experience.
In any case, I still don't
quite understand it myself.
If they'd only let me
work in peace...
Of course, my betters
would have none of that.
BRUCE: So you experimented
on yourself, didn't you?
And passed on to me, what?
An alteration. Genetic.
A deformity. I guess
you could call it that.
But an amazing strength, too.
And now, finally unleashed,
I can harvest it.
BRUCE: No.
You'll do no such thing.
I will isolate it
and treat it myself.
I'll remove it,
and I'll kill it before
it does any real harm.
I'll bet you and your Betty
would love to destroy it.
But would you really destroy
part of yourself?
I don't think so.
And as for Betty,
I'm sending her a surprise
visit from some four-legged
friends of mine.
You see, I've managed
to culture some of your
very own DNA, Bruce,
and the results
are tremendous.
They're unstable,
but very powerful.
What about my DNA?
Let's just wait and see
what Betty makes
of the results, huh?
No. You're crazy.
I won't let you.
(CHATTERING)
Get your hands off of me.
Talbot, what's this...
Inside, asshole.
I wanna talk to you.
Listen to me, my father's
going after Betty...
What makes you think
you can go behind my back
and get Ross
to cut me out, huh?
(GROANS)
Listen to me!
Betty's in trouble!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You pathetic freak.
Betty's in danger.
I swear to you,
she'll be killed.
I can state the obvious.
Something tells me
you aren't in
much of a position
to be making
stupid threats to anyone.
(GRUNTING)
Talbot.
Yeah?
You're making me angry.
Oh, am I?
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(ROARING)
MAN: My God, fire! Open fire!
(GROWLING)
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
(THUDDING)
(RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
Bruce?
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
(TWIGS SNAPPING)
(SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
(YELPS)
(SCREAMS)
(BARKING)
(DOG WHINES)
(SNARLING)
(DOGS SNARLING)
(KEYS RATTLING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(DOGS BARKING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELPS)
(SCREAMING)
(SNARLING)
(DOGS GROWLING)
(ROARS)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
(BARKING)
(BETTY SCREAMS)
(DOG SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(HULK PANTING)
He sent these dogs,
didn't he?
But I killed them!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
My God.
It must be the nanomeds.
It must be the gamma exposure.
But we've never seen
any effect like this before.
No. Deeper.
The gamma just unleashed
what was already there.
Unleashed what?
Me.
It.
(GASPING)
It's okay.
What were those animals?
My father sent them.
He is my father.
He wanted me to change.
He wanted me to change
into that mindless hulk.
Why would he want that?
Can you remember anything?
Is there anything
from when you were changed?
It was like a dream.
About what?
Rage.
Power.
And freedom.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello? Sir.
Hello.
Dad?
Betty! Are you all right?
I'm scared.
I need your help.
Where are you?
How are you?
Okay, I guess.
I think that somehow
your anger is triggering
the nanomeds.
How could it? We designed them
to respond to physical damage.
Emotional damage
can manifest physically.
Like what?
Serious trauma.
Repressed memories.
Your father grilled me
about something that happened
to me from early childhood
that I'm supposed to remember.
He did?
It sounded bad, but...
I honestly don't remember.
The thing that worries me
is
a physical wound is finite,
but with emotions,
what's to say it won't
just go on and on
and start a chain reaction?
You know
what scares me the most?
When it happens,
when it comes over me
and I totally lose control,
I like it.
(BEEPING)
(GASPS)
It's okay. I got you.
I'm sorry.
You'll be okay.
It's just to make you sleep.
Target down. Target secure.
I'm going to take you
someplace safe.
Okay? Bruce?
Bruce?
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
MAN: Clear!
(RADlO CHATTERlNG)
Attention on deck.
Carry on.
BETTY: We're buried out here
in the middle of nowhere.
How long are you
gonna keep him sedated?
For the rest of his
natural life, if I have to.
You said I could trust you.
I'm your father.
You can trust me to do
what I think is right,
not what you think you want.
He is a human being.
He is also something else.
Suppose he gets out,
has one of his
little mood swings
in a populated area.
Yes, I'm aware of
the potential danger.
I'm also aware that
he saved my life.
Yeah, from a mutant
French poodle.
I'm indebted to him for that.
He also put three men
in a hospital,
and Talbot's barely walking!
What do you want me to do?
I want you to help him!
Why is he such
a threat to you?
Because I know
what he comes from.
He is his father's son,
every last molecule of him.
He says he doesn't
know his father,
but he's workin' in
the same exact goddamn
field his father did.
So either he's lyin'
or it's somethin' worse,
and he's...
What?
Predestined to follow
in his father's footsteps?
I was gonna say "damned."
Of course you were.
But I'm a scientist.
As a scientist, I believe
we can figure this out
and he can be helped.
I know you do.
Whether you know or care,
I've got a lot of pride
in what you've done.
But this is too big for you.
Look, I know the government
thinks they have a weapon
on their hands.
Otherwise,
he'd be dead by now.
They can probe and prod
all they want,
and in the meanwhile,
just let me try to help him.
Nobody knows him
better than I do.
What did David Banner
do to him?
Cover left.
Clear left.
Cover right!
(SIREN WAILING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(AIR HISSING)
(INHALING)
(GRUNTING)
(HEART BEATING)
(CLINKING)
(CREAKING)
What's happening here?
My hand.
You see, the strength
of my son's DNA
combined with nanomed
reconstruction...
You see, I can partake with
the essences of all things.
Gonna have to ask you to
put your hands up, pal, okay?
Nice and easy.
(WHEEZING LAUGH)
Do you really believe
that I am separate from you?
(LAUGHS)
Whoa!
(GRUNTING)
Where am I?
You're home.
It's hard to believe
we used to live here.
I must have seen you
or known you.
If only I could remember.
This is my old house,
isn't it?
Let's go.
Please try.
(SHUDDERING)
BETTY: What is it?
Nothing.
Really?
Damn it.
Okay, Betty.
What do you want to know?
What was in that room?
What are you afraid
that I'll see?
(GASPS)
See? There's nothing.
It's empty.
BETTY: What do you mean
I don't have access to him?
NSA has decided
to turn over study
of the threat to Atheon.
But you're head of the base.
I thought you were in charge.
But I don't set policy,
and I still take orders.
(YELLS)
I can't believe Talbot
would go around me like this!
Oh, there's a lot of
powerful people that
want in on this.
And money to be made,
lots of it.
You know the worst part
about all this?
When I had
David Banner locked up
and sent that kid away,
I didn't give that boy
a second thought.
He was just collateral damage.
Well, he isn't anymore, is he?
What can I do?
You can go home now.
I'd tell you to go
and say good-bye,
but I've already been informed
that for now
all further contact is
out of the question.
Right.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Hiya, Bruce. How ya feelin'?
Grub okay in here for ya?
What do you want?
That's a good question.
See, I need your cells
to trigger some chemical
distress signals.
You know, so you can turn
a little green for me again,
and I can carve off
a piece of the real you,
analyze it, patent it,
make a fortune.
Do you mind?
I'll never let you.
I'm not sure you've got
much of a choice.
(SCREAMS)
Come on, Bruce.
Aren't you feeling
a little angry?
After all, you've only got
me to play with
now that Betty's dumped you
and gone back to Berkeley.
(SCREAMS)
You're lying.
You know, for me
this is a win-win situation.
You turn green,
and all these guys
come in and kill you,
and I perform the autopsy.
You don't...
(SCREAMS)
And I mop the floor with you
and maybe by accident go
too far and break your neck.
Bad science, maybe,
but personally gratifying.
(SCREAMS)
Come on, Bruce!
Let's see what you got.
(PANTING)
Never.
(GRUNTING)
You know, consciously
you may control it,
but subconsciously,
I bet that's another story.
All right, let's jump-start
those brain waves.
(RADlO CHATTERlNG)
(HUMMING)
(EDlTH CHATTERlNG
lNDlSTlNCTLY)
EDlTH: Bruce.
(GASPS)
My dear Miss Ross.
Welcome back.
There are two guards
right outside.
You don't have to worry.
I'm not angry with you.
Not anymore.
What do you want?
It's over for me now.
I know that.
And soon it'll be
over for Bruce.
That's why I've come to you
to ask you if you could
persuade your father,
as a man, as a father himself,
that if I turn myself in now,
peacefully
and before
he puts me away forever,
that he would let me
see my son
for one last time.
Could you do that for me?
It's out of
my father's hands now.
I understand.
He's a puppet now.
I don't blame him.
You shouldn't.
You should blame yourself
for what you've done
to your son.
And what have I done
to my son, Miss Ross?
Nothing.
I tried to improve
on the limits in myself.
Myself! Not him!
Can you understand?
To improve on nature.
My nature!
Knowledge of oneself!
It's the only path
to the truth
that give men the power
to go beyond God's boundaries!
You know what's beyond
your boundaries? Other people.
All you've given Bruce
is fear.
Fear of life.
Fear?
Perhaps, Miss Ross.
And loneliness, too.
Yes.
I feel them both.
But I have lived
completely once.
DAVlD: l was so much in love,
and she so much wanted a baby.
My baby.
l could tell
from the moment she conceived
that it wasn't a son
l had given her
but something else.
A monster, maybe.
l should have put
a stop to it right then,
but l was curious,
and that was my downfall.
And as l watched
this tiny life unfold,
I began to imagine
the horror of it,
and my curiosity was replaced
with compassion.
DAVlD: But they took away
my chance to cure him.
Your father threw me out.
EDITH: What are you doing?
l remember that day so well,
every moment, every sensation
walking into the house,
the feeling of the handle
of the knife in my hand.
l knew l was doing
a father's work,
fulfilling a father's mercy.
EDlTH (YELLlNG):
David, please stop it! No!
David, no! Talk to me! Listen!
But then she surprised me.
(YELLING)
EDITH: No! No!
David, no!
DAVlD: lt was as if
she and the knife
merged.
No!
You cannot imagine
the unbearable finality of it.
And in that one moment,
l took everything
that was dear to me
and transformed it
into nothing more
than a memory.
Bingo! That must be some
jumbo nightmare he just had.
Okay, do it now.
Start the enzyme extraction.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Sir, negative
on drill penetration.
Damn it, drill him harder!
Give him full RPMs.
Come on, Holeman! Come on!
(GROWLING)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Should I neutralize?
No! I can't do
anything with goop!
Come on!
(ROARING)
All right, put him to sleep.
TECHNICIAN:
It's not stopping him!
(GROWLS)
Ready room, send in
our containment team.
Non-lethals only.
I repeat, non-lethals only.
I must have a sample of him.
WOMAN: Sir!
Jesus!
Hit him with the foam.
TECHNICIAN:
Deploy containment foam.
Talbot, talk to me.
Cease fire!
Under control, General.
I'll let you know
if we need you.
Unacceptable.
Unseat your asses
down there immediately.
I want a full-court
evacuation now.
I'm shutting you down.
Lockdown.
Didn't you hear
what the General said?
I said lockdown!
Clear! I need a sample of him!
(GROWLING)
Take it easy there, buddy.
This might give you
a bit of a sting here, Bruce.
(DRILL WHIRRS)
(GROWLING)
Fall back! Fall back!
Clear your weapon! Clear it!
Give me the M2.
So long, big boy.
Clear!
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
Lockdown the entire
facility immediately.
Target's still moving
towards blue level.
Evacuate the main hall.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
Send in backup, heavy weapons.
Issue general quarters.
Set firing lines
left and right!
Heavy weapons, go, go, go!
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
Contamination, sir.
System readings are redline.
Data's on backup power supply.
(ALARM BLARING)
Incoming!
(ROARING)
(MEN GASPING)
Shut down all power
to the main hall.
Sir?
Show him the way out.
We'll fight him outside.
(MEN CHATTERING)
Driver, stop. Driver, stop.
COMMANDER:
Gunner, traverse left!
Traverse left!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
(MEN GASPING)
Clear back! Clear back!
(GROANING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
Mr. President,
I have some bad news, sir.
Let's have it, General.
I've briefed the President
on Angry Man.
I assume that's what
this is about.
It is, ma'am.
I'm requesting a National
Command Authority override.
Angry Man is unsecure.
I need everything we have
at my disposal in order
to stop his movement.
You're expecting
civilian casualties, General?
Not if I can help it, ma'am.
Consider it done.
Keep us posted.
Contact Goodman Control.
ROSS:
Patch data to the assets.
Contact H.Q.
Have them initiate
an immediate evacuation
in vicinity of
grid coordinates 6-5-1 5.
(GRUNTS)
Confirm that the area
has been cleared.
Confirm area cleared.
MAN ON RADlO:
H.Q. confirms area cleared.
Assets on-line, sir.
ROSS: Gentlemen,
it's time to dig in.
l want this target
stopped in his tracks.
Jesus.
Mayday! Mayday! Ah, shooot!
(HULK GRUNTING)
TANGO ONE: Tango Four is down.
Have CSAR respond
to our 20 ASAP.
TANGO FOUR: We're okay,
but, damn it, get him off us
before he tears us apart!
TANGO ONE: l've got no shot.
Do you have
a clear line of fire?
ROSS: Watch it, Tango Flight.
TANGO ONE:
Break left! Break left!
MAN: Tango Three,
pull back and set up
for a Hellfire shot.
ROSS: Hold your fire
till we draw him off.
TANGO ONE:
Tango One is hot. Gun wazzed.
TANGO TWO: Roger.
Going hot. Guns ready.
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTS)
ROSS: Engage at will.
(GROWLING)
TANGO TWO: Tango One,
pull back! Clear my line!
TANGO THREE: Tango Flight,
clear back. l've got him
painted for Hellfire.
Roger that.
Tango One clear.
Take the shot.
TANGO THREE:
Tango One, Tango Three.
l have contact.
Holy shooot!
He's got my missile!
Mayday! Mayday!
Mayday! Mayday! We're hit!
We're going down!
Give me a head count.
TANGO TWO: Tango Three,
give me a sit rep.
TANGO THREE:
Our kite's busted up,
but we're okay.
ROSS: Tango Flight,
do you have eyes
on the target?
Tango One.
l have him in the rocks.
ROSS: Salvo all.
Turn it into a parking lot.
TANGO ONE: T-bolt,
your parking lot is ready.
We're bingo
for fuel and ammo. R.T.B.
(PANTING)
WOMAN ON RADlO: T-bolt,
this is Goodman Control.
Be advised,
target not destroyed.
He's on the move again.
Damn!
I've got it.
It appears he's heading home.
Launch fast movers.
Have them intercept
and engage.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Betty, Bruce got out.
He's headed your way
and probably right for you.
How far from the base
are you?
I'm already here.
They're taking
his father in now.
That's all good news.
Stay there, Betty.
PlLOT:
Legend One rolling in hot.
Legend Two breaking off left.
l think l can come back around
for a gun attack.
ROSS: Acquire a clear target.
Fire at will.
(GRUNTS)
lncrease altitude.
Civilian aircraft in vicinity.
Pull up! Pull up!
You're headed for the bridge!
(SCREAMING)
l can't pull up!
Okay, you've got him now.
Take him on a ride
to the top of the world.
Let's see what the thin air
will do for him.
PlLOT: lnitiating afterburn.
l'm passing flight level 600.
This is out of my envelope.
ROSS: Hang in there, Legend.
I can't maintain.
He's all over my aerodynamics.
He'll lose consciousness
before you.
Nine-fifty. I can't hold it.
I'm pulling back!
(SCREAMING)
Puny human.
PlLOT: Contact.
He's in the water.
All units, weapons hot.
ROSS:
Let's not take any chances.
You are cleared to fire
on target, Legend.
(RADlO CHATTERlNG)
BETTY: Dad?
Betty?
We don't have a choice.
I have to destroy him.
But you can't.
You will only fuel
his rage, and you will
make him stronger.
It's you he's coming for.
You know that.
Then let me go to him.
Please.
Just give him a chance
to calm down.
(TRAM BELL RINGING)
(PASSENGERS SCREAMING)
ROSS: All aircraft vicinity
of San Francisco,
this is T-bolt on guard.
This area has been declared
restricted airspace.
All aircraft are
ordered to clear
the airspace immediately.
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
(ROARING)
(GROWLING)
MAN ON RADlO: Echo, One-niner.
Weapons are hot.
Target acquired.
Waiting your order to engage.
Repeat,
waiting your orders to engage.
PlLOT: Command code yellow.
Hold for authorization.
All units, hold your fire.
TECHNlClAN ON RADlO:
This is T-bolt to all assets.
You have direct orders
to hold your fire.
l repeat, hold your fire.
PlLOT: Echo, One-niner.
Roger that.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
OFFICER: Hold your fire
until my command!
MAN ON RADlO:
Engine 24 to command.
We are in position now.
You found me.
You weren't that hard to find.
Yes, I was.
(POLlCE RADlO CHATTERlNG)
(SOBBING)
(DOOR OPENING)
Let's take a walk.
That's the deal, gentlemen.
He stays on this base
until we get
the final word from C-3
on how to dispose of him.
In the meantime,
if he does anything
but sit there in that chair,
we're gonna turn on
the juice and he'll be
incinerated immediately.
We've established
a 200-yard perimeter, sir.
If we deploy
the electromagnetic array,
there should be
no collateral damage.
MAN: Here they come!
I'm doin' this for you, Betty.
But one way or another,
we're gonna have to
prepare for the worst.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
I should have killed you.
And I should have killed you.
I wish you had.
I saw her last night.
Saw her face.
Brown hair.
Brown eyes.
She smiled at me.
She reached down
and kissed my cheek.
I can almost remember a smell.
It was like desert flowers.
Her favorite perfume.
It's my mother,
and I don't even
know her name.
(SOBBING)
It's all right, Son.
You go ahead and cry.
Go ahead and cry.
Cry. Crying will do you good.
Don't touch me!
Maybe once you were my father,
but you're not now
and you never will be.
Oh, is that so?
Well, I got news for you.
I didn't come here to see you.
I came here to see my son.
My real son.
The one inside of you.
You're nothing
but a superficial shell,
a husk of flimsy consciousness
ready to be torn off
at a moment's notice.
You can think what you like.
I don't care. Just go!
No, Son. Listen to me.
I found a cure.
For me.
My cells can transform, too,
absorb enormous
amounts of energy.
But, unlike you,
they're unstable.
Son, I need your strength.
I gave you life.
Now you must
give it back to me!
Only a million times
more radiant, more powerful!
Stop it.
Stop? Stop what?
Stop what?
Think about all those men
out there in their uniforms,
barking and swallowing orders,
inflicting their petty rule
over the entire globe!
Think of all the harm
they've done!
To you! To me!
To humanity!
And know this,
that we can make them
and their flags
and their anthems
and their governments
disappear in a flash!
You in me.
I'd rather die.
Oh, that's your answer?
Then indeed you shall die
and be reborn
a hero of the kind
that walked the earth
long before the pale
religions of civilization
infected humanity's soul!
Go!
(MOCKING)
Stop your bawling,
you weak little speck
of human trash.
All right. I'll go!
You just watch me go!
Hit it.
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
Hit it again!
We can't, sir.
There's no power.
Some kind of
counter-electromagnetic field.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Move in and assault
the target. Move in!
MAN: Move, move, move!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Sir, I've located them
on radar. Pear Lake.
Call up the task force.
(GRUNTING)
Yes.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(HULK ROARING)
(HULK GROWLING)
DAVID: That's right. Keep fighting.
The more you fight,
the more of you I take.
TECHNICIAN: Strange.
We're reading a phenomenal
drop in temperatures there.
Simultaneous
radiological activity.
They're absorbing
all the ambient energy.
BETTY: Relax.
DAVlD: Sleep now, Bruce,
and forget forever.
Struggle no more
and give me all of your power.
BRUCE: You think you can
live with it? Take it!
Take it all!
DAVID: Oh, yes! Yes!
(HULK ROARING)
DAVID: Take it back!
It's not stopping!
Take it back!
(DAVID GROANING)
Gentlemen, release.
PlLOT ON RADlO:
Gamma charge away.
Sweet dreams.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
ROSS: Betty, is that you?
Hi, Dad.
l'm glad l caught you.
I'm glad you called.
Thanks.
Look, Betty, you and I...
Well, we both know that
Bruce couldn't have
survived that blast.
But... Well, you know...
What is it?
Well, you know.
The usual loonies,
seein' things.
Only now everything's green.
Right.
Look...
If by some chance
he did survive,
and he should try to
contact you,
try to get in touch,
you'd tell me, wouldn't you?
No, I wouldn't.
But you know as well as I do,
I wouldn't have to.
I mean, my phones are bugged,
my computer's tapped.
I'm under surveillance.
I'll tell you, though,
that if he were alive,
I'm the last person
I would want him to come to
because as much as
I miss him, I...
I loved him. I...
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Betty.
I am so sorry.
I know you are.
(IN SPANISH)
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
(GOAT BLEATING)
(HULK ROARING)