Tactical
Visual
Tactical, stand by on torpedoes.
Ready...
Fire!
Evasive!
This is comm station Epsilon IX
calling U.S.S. Columbia.
Come in, Columbia. Respond, please.
This is Epsilon IX, Columbia.
Am boosting output. How read you this?
Scout Columbia NCC-621,
to rendezvous with
Scout Revere NCC-595
on Stardate 7411.4.
Further orders will be relayed
at that time,
signed Commodore Probert
to Starfleet.
End of transmission.
Intruder unidentified.
Believe luminescent cloud
to be enormous power field
surrounding alien vessel.
Our sensor scans unable to penetrate.
Imperial Klingon Cruiser Amar,
continuing to attack.
Our sensor drone is intercepting this
on Quad L-14.
That's within Klingon boundaries.
Who are they fighting?
Unknown, sir.
I have an exterior visual.
We've plotted a course
on that cloud, Commander.
It will pass into Federation space
fairly close to us.
Heading?
Sir, it's on a precise heading for Earth.
Our ancestors cast out their animal
passions here on these sands.
Our race was saved by the
attainment of Kolinahr.
Kolinahr: through which all emotion
is finally shed.
You have labored long, Spock...
Now receive from us this symbol
of total logic.
Your thoughts... give them to me.
Our minds, Spock...
...one and together
This consciousness calling to you
from space...
It touches your human blood, Spock.
You have not achieved Kolinahr.
His answer lies elsewhere.
He will not achieve his goal with us.
Live long and prosper, Spock.
Commander Sonak,
you received your appointment
as Enterprise science officer?
Based, I am told,
on your recommendation, Admiral.
-Thank you.
-Then why aren't you aboard?
Captain Decker requested I complete
final science briefing here
-before we leave on our mission.
-Here? At Starfleet?
The Enterprise is
in final preparation to leave dock.
Which will require 20 more hours
at minimum.
Twelve.
I'm on my way to a meeting
with Admiral Nogura
which will not last
more than three minutes.
Report to me on
the Enterprise in one hour.
Report to you, sir?
It is my intention to be on that ship
following that meeting.
Report to me in one hour.
-Admiral!
-Mr. Scott.
Those departure orders, 12 hours,
Starfleet cannot be serious.
Why aren't the Enterprise transporters
operating, Mr. Scott?
A wee problem, sir. Just temporary.
Admiral, we have just
finished 18 months
redesigning and refitting the Enterprise.
How in the name of hell do they expect
me to have her ready in 12 hours?
Take me over, please.
She needs more work, sir.
A shakedown.
Mr. Scott, an alien object of
unbelievable destructive power
is less than three days away
from this planet.
The only starship in interception range
is the Enterprise.
Ready or not, she launches in 12 hours.
The crew haven't had
near enough transition time
with all the new equipment.
And the engines, they're
not even tested at warp power.
And an untried captain.
Two and a half years
as chief of Starfleet operations
may have made me a little stale,
but I wouldn't exactly consider
myself untried.
-They gave her back to me, Scotty.
-"Gave" her back, sir?
Well, I doubt it was
that easy with Nogura.
You're right.
Well, any man
who could manage such a feat,
I would not dare to disappoint.
She'll launch on time, sir.
And she'll be ready.
-Pod secured.
-Thank you, Mr. Scott.
-Aye, sir.
-Pressure equalized.
Attention, launch crew, a travel pod
is now available at cargo six.
-Permission to come aboard, sir.
-Granted, sir.
Welcome aboard, Admiral.
Commander Scott, you're needed
in engineering immediately.
Sir, you'll excuse me.
Attention, launch crew.
A travel pod is now
available at cargo six.
Travel pod available. Cargo six.
-Sir, if you'll follow me, I'll show you...
-I think I can find my way, Ensign.
Aye, sir.
Bridge.
What's the problem?
I thought you people had that circuit
patched in an hour ago!
We did. We had to disconnect it again
so we could tie in radio messaging.
All right. Take out...
All right, as soon as
somebody can get to it.
-What's the next program?
-Go ahead.
I'll get somebody down there
as soon as I can.
Cleary, my people are all tied up now.
Captain, Starfleet just signaled your
transfer-of-command order, sir.
-Captain.
-I appreciate the welcome.
I wish the circumstances
were less critical.
Epsilon IX is monitoring the intruder.
Keep a channel open to them.
Aye, sir.
Where's Captain Decker?
He's in engineering, sir.
He...
He doesn't know.
-Mr. Chekov.
-Aye, sir.
Assemble the crew on the recreation
deck at 0400 hours.
I want to show them what we're facing.
Engineering to all decks,
auxiliary power test in three minutes.
Check Cleary on number six.
Engineering to all decks,
auxiliary power test in three minutes.
Mark.
Space matrix restoration coils.
Dilithium crystals.
I knew it! The transporter sensor
was not activated.
Faulty modules.
Cleary! Put a new backup sensor
into the unit.
Aye, sir.
-Ready.
-Emergency shut-down trip.
Admiral Kirk!
Well, we're getting a top-brass sendoff.
Don't worry. She'll launch on schedule,
if we have to tow her out
with our bare hands.
-Right, Scotty?
-Aye, that we will, sir.
-Let's talk.
-Sure.
Let me know when that backup's ready.
Aye, sir.
All due respect, sir, I hope this isn't
some kind of Starfleet pep talk.
I'm really too busy.
I'm taking over the centre seat, Will.
You're what?
I'm replacing you as
captain of the Enterprise.
You'll stay on as executive officer,
temporary grade reduction
to commander.
You, personally,
are assuming command?
Yeah.
-May I ask why?
-My experience.
Five years out there
dealing with unknowns like this.
My familiarity with the Enterprise,
its crew.
Admiral, this is
an almost totally new Enterprise.
You don't know her
a tenth as well as I do!
That's why you're staying aboard.
I'm sorry, Will.
No, Admiral. I don't think you're sorry.
Not one damn bit.
I remember when you recommended
me for this command.
You told me how envious you were
and how much you hoped you'd find
a way to get a starship command again.
Well, sir,
it looks like you found a way.
Report to the bridge, Commander,
immediately.
Aye, sir.
Transporter room, come in! Urgent!
Red line on the transporter, Mr. Scott.
Transporter! Do not engage.
-It's too late. They're beaming now.
-Do not...
Do you read me, Starfleet?
Override it. Pull them back.
Unable to retrieve their pattern,
Enterprise.
Malfunction! Malfunction! Malfunction!
-Malfunction! Malfunction!
-Give it to me!
Malfunction!
Starfleet, boost your matter gain.
We need more signal.
-More signal!
-We're losing their pattern.
Oh, no. They're forming.
Oh, my God.
Starfleet, do you have them?
Enterprise, what we got back
didn't live long.
Fortunately.
Starfleet, Kirk.
Please express my condolences
to their families.
Commander Sonak's can be reached
through the Vulcan Embassy.
There was nothing you
could have done, Rand.
It wasn't your fault.
-Yeoman, turboshaft eight?
-Back that way, sir.
We have to replace Commander Sonak.
I'd still like a Vulcan there, if possible.
None available, Captain.
In fact, there's no one
who's fully rated on this design.
You are, Mr. Decker.
I'm afraid you're gonna have
to double as science officer.
That's all we know about it.
Except that it is now 53.4 hours
away from Earth.
Enterprise is the only Federation
starship that stands in its way.
We assume that there is a vessel of
some type at the heart of the cloud.
Our orders are to intercept,
investigate and take whatever action
is necessary
and possible.
We can only hope that there is
a life form aboard that vessel
that reasons the way we do.
Bridge to Captain.
Priority signal from Epsilon IX.
-Put it on viewer.
-On viewer, sir.
Enterprise. The cloud is definitely
a power field of some kind.
Measures...
My God! Over 82 AUs in diameter.
Must be something incredible
inside there generating it.
We're transmitting linguacode
friendship messages on all frequencies.
No response.
I have a null reading
at the centre of the cloud.
Definitely something inside there,
but all scans are being reflected back.
-Some kind of power surge.
-Receiving an odd pattern now!
Enterprise, they could be mistaking
our scans as a hostile act.
They seem to be reacting
to our scans, sir.
Deflectors, emergency full!
-We are under attack!
-External view.
Viewer off.
Viewer off!
Pre-launch countdown
will commence in 40 minutes.
Photon torpedo load status.
Transporter system fully repaired
and functioning normally, sir.
Dock signals clear, Captain.
Reply we are holding position
awaiting final crew replacements.
Aye, sir.
Transporter personnel reports
the navigator, Lieutenant Ilia,
she's already aboard
and en route to the bridge, sir.
She's Deltan, Captain.
-Lieutenant Ilia reporting for duty, sir.
-Welcome aboard, Lieutenant.
-Hello, Ilia.
-Decker.
I was stationed on the lieutenant's
home planet some years ago.
Commander Decker?
Yes, our exec and science officer.
Captain Kirk has
the utmost confidence in me.
And, in you, too, Lieutenant.
My oath of celibacy
is on record, Captain.
-May I assume my duties?
-By all means.
Captain?
Starfleet reports our last six crew
members are ready to beam up,
but one of them is refusing
to step into the transporter.
Oh? I'll see to it that he beams up.
Transporter room.
Well, for a man who swore
he'd never return to the Starfleet...
Just a moment, Captain, sir.
I'll explain what happened.
Your revered Admiral Nogura
invoked a little known, seldom used
reserve activation clause.
In simpler language, Captain,
they drafted me.
They didn't.
This was your idea.
This was your idea, wasn't it?
Bones, there's a thing out there.
Why is any object we don't understand
always called a "thing"?
Headed this way.
I need you.
Damn it, Bones. I need you.
Badly!
-Permission to come aboard?
-Permission granted, sir.
Well, Jim.
I hear Chapel's an MD now.
Well, I'm going to need a top nurse.
Not a doctor who'll argue
every little diagnosis with me.
And they probably redesigned
the whole sickbay, too.
I know engineers.
They love to change things.
Dock control reports ready, sir.
-Helm ready, sir.
-Orbital departure on plot, sir.
Yard command signaling clear, sir.
Maneuvering thrusters, Mr. Sulu.
-Maneuvering thrusters, sir.
-Hold station.
Thrusters at station-keeping, sir.
Thrusters ahead, Mr. Sulu.
Take us out.
Intermix set, bridge.
Impulse power at your discretion.
Impulse power, Mr. Sulu.
Ahead warp 0.5.
-Departure angle on viewer.
-Departure angle.
-Viewer ahead.
Captain's Log, Stardate 7412.6,
1 .8 hours from launch.
In order to intercept the intruder
at the earliest possible time,
we must now risk engaging warp drive
while still within the solar system.
Captain, assuming
we have full warp capability,
accelerating to warp 7 on leaving
the solar system
will bring us to IP with
the intruder in 20.1 hours.
Science officer's computation
confirmed, sir.
Well, Bones, do the new medical
facilities meet with your approval?
They do not. It's like working
in a damned computer centre.
Programming ready?
Program set for
standard warp entry, Captain,
but I still recommend
further simulation study.
Mr. Decker, every minute brings
that object closer to Earth.
Engineering, stand by for warp drive.
Captain, we need further
warp simulation on the flow sensors.
Engineer, we need warp speed now.
Jim?
You're pushing.
Your people know their jobs.
That's it, sir. I can't do any better.
Aye, lad.
It's borderline
on the simulator, Captain.
I cannot guarantee that she'll hold up.
Warp drive, Mr. Scott.
-Ahead, warp 1, Mr. Sulu.
-Accelerating to warp 1, sir.
Warp 0.7.
0.8.
Warp 1, sir.
-Mr. Decker...
-Emergency alert! Emergency alert!
Emergency alert!
Wormhole! Get us back
on impulse power! Full reverse.
Emergency alert! Emergency alert!
Negative helm control, Captain.
Going reverse on impulse power!
Subspace frequencies jammed, sir!
Wormhole effect!
Negative control from
inertial lag will continue 22.5 seconds
before forward velocity
slows to sub-light speed!
Unidentified small object
has been pulled into the wormhole
with us, Captain, directly ahead!
Force fields up full.
Put object on viewer.
-Go manual override on helm!
-No manual response, sir.
Navigational deflectors coming up, sir.
Wormhole distortion has overloaded
the main power systems.
Navigational deflectors
inoperative, Captain.
Directional control also inoperative.
Time to impact?
Twenty seconds.
Mr. Chekov, stand by on phasers.
No!
Belay that phaser order!
Arm photon torpedoes!
Photon torpedoes
armed!
Object is an asteroid,
reading mass 0.7.
Targeting asteroid!
Impact in ten seconds.
-Impact in eight seconds.
-Fire torpedoes!
Six...
-Torpedoes away!
-...seconds.
Four!
We're out of it!
Helm control restored, sir.
-Position report, Navigator.
-Computing new intersection course.
Communications are normal, sir.
Negative damage reported, Captain.
No casualties reported, Doctor.
Wrong, Mr. Chekov,
there are casualties.
My wits!
As in "frightened out of," Captain, sir.
We're at warp 0.8.
Engineer, report your status there.
In just a second, Exec.
We're picking up the pieces down here!
Mr. Scott, we need warp drive
as soon as possible.
Captain, it was the engine imbalance
that created the wormhole
in the first place.
It will happen again
if we don't correct it.
That object is less than two days
away from Earth.
We need to intercept
while it still is out there.
Navigator, lay in a new heading
to conform with our initial IP
with the intruder.
Mr. Sulu, you have the conn.
Mr. Decker, I'd like to
see you in my quarters.
Mind if I tag along, Captain?
Level five.
All right, explanation. Why was
my phaser order countermanded?
Sir, the Enterprise redesign
increases phaser power
by channeling it through
the main engines.
When they went
into anti-matter imbalance,
the phasers were automatically cut off.
Then you acted properly, of course.
Thank you, sir.
I'm sorry if I embarrassed you.
-You saved the ship.
-I'm aware of that, sir.
Stop competing with me, Decker!
-Permission to speak freely, sir?
-Granted!
Sir, you haven't logged a single
star hour in two and a half years.
That, plus your unfamiliarity with
the ship's redesign, in my opinion, sir,
seriously jeopardizes this mission.
I trust you will
nursemaid me through
these difficulties, mister?
Yes, sir, I'll do that.
Then I won't keep you from
your duties any longer, Commander.
-Yes, Doctor?
-Aye, sir.
He may be right, Jim.
Was it difficult?
No more than I expected.
About as difficult as seeing you again.
I'm sorry.
That you left Delta IV?
Or that you didn't even say goodbye?
If I had seen you again,
would you have been able to say it?
No.
Make your point, Doctor.
The point, Captain, is that
it's you who's competing.
You rammed getting this command
down Starfleet's throat.
You've used this emergency
to get the Enterprise back.
And I intend to keep her,
is that what you're saying?
Yes. It's an obsession.
An obsession that can blind you
to far more immediate
and critical responsibilities.
Your reaction to Decker
is an example, Jim.
-Bridge to Captain.
-Viewer on.
Signal from a Federation-registered
long-range shuttle, sir.
She wishes to come alongside
and lock on.
For what purpose?
My security scan shows it has
a Grade 1 priority, Captain.
Non-belligerency confirmed.
I suspect it is a courier of some kind.
Very well, Mr. Chekov. See to it.
Viewer off.
Your opinion has been noted.
Anything further?
That depends on you.
Security scan. One boarder.
Identity, Starfleet. Inactive.
Permission to come aboard, sir.
Granted, sir! Granted.
-Why, why, it's Mr Spock!
Spock.
Commander, if I may?
I've been monitoring
your communications
with Starfleet Command, Captain.
I'm aware of your
engine design difficulties.
I offer my services as science officer.
With all due respect, Commander.
If our exec has no objections?
Of course not. I'm well aware
of Mr Spock's qualifications.
Mr Chekov, log Mr Spock's
Starfleet commission reactivated,
list him as science officer,
both effective immediately.
Mr Spock!
Well, so help me,
I'm actually pleased to see you!
It's how we all feel, Mr Spock.
Captain, with your permission,
I will now discuss these fuel equations
with the engineer.
Mr Spock? Welcome aboard.
Captain's Log, Stardate 7413.4.
Thanks to Mr Spock's timely arrival,
and assistance,
we have the engines rebalanced
into full warp capacity.
Repair time, less than three hours.
Which means, we will now
be able to intercept intruder
while still more than a day from Earth.
Warp 0.8.
0.9.
Warp 2, sir.
Warp 3.
Warp 4.
Warp 5.
Warp 6.
Science Officer Spock,
reporting as ordered, Captain.
Please, sit down.
Spock, you haven't changed a bit.
You're just as warm and
sociable as ever.
Nor have you, Doctor,
as your continued predilection
for irrelevancy demonstrates.
Gentlemen.
At last report, you were on Vulcan,
apparently to stay.
Yes, you were undergoing
the Kolinahr discipline.
Sit down.
If you are referring to the Kolinahr,
Doctor, you are correct.
Well, however it's pronounced,
Mr Spock,
it's the Vulcan ritual that's supposed
to purge all remaining emotions.
The Kolinahr is also
a discipline you broke
to join us.
Will you please sit down?
On Vulcan I began
sensing a consciousness
from a source more powerful
than I have ever encountered.
Thought patterns
of exactingly, perfect order.
I believe they emanate
from the intruder.
I believe it may hold my answers.
Well, isn't it lucky for you that we just
happened to be heading your way?
Bones!
We need him.
I need him.
Then my presence is to
our mutual advantage?
Any thought patterns you might sense,
whether they appear to
affect you personally or not,
I expect immediately reported.
Of course, Captain.
Is there anything else?
No.
Jim?
If this super-intelligence is as important
to him as he says it is,
how do we know...
That he wouldn't put his own
interests ahead of the ship's?
I could never believe that.
Bridge to officer's lounge.
Captain Kirk, revised estimate
on cloud visual contact, 3.7 minutes.
Red Alert! Red Alert!
Standard light, Engineer.
-Full mag on viewer!
-Full mag, sir.
Linguacode?
Continuing friendship messages
on all frequencies, sir.
All decks and divisions confirmed.
Status Red.
-Captain, we are being scanned.
-Do no return scan, Mr Spock.
It could be misinterpreted as hostility.
Intruder scans emanating from
the exact centre of the cloud.
Energy of a type
never before encountered.
There's no response to
friendship messages, sir.
Shall I go to battle stations, sir?
Negative. We'll take
no provocative action.
Recommend defensive posture,
Captain. Screens and shields.
No, Mr Decker. That could
also be misinterpreted as hostile.
Cloud composition, Mr Spock?
-Twelfth power energy field.
-Twelfth power?
Captain, we've seen what
their weapons can do.
Shouldn't we take
every possible precaution?
-Mr Decker...
-Captain.
I suspect there's an object
at the heart of that cloud.
Mr Decker, I will not provoke an attack.
If that order isn't clear enough for you...
Captain, as your exec,
it's my duty to point out alternatives.
Yes, it is.
I stand corrected.
Five minutes to cloud boundary.
Navigator, lay in a conic section
flight path to the cloud centre.
Bring us parallel to whatever
we find in there.
-Mr Sulu, tactical plot on viewer.
-Tactical on viewer, sir.
That measures twelfth power energy?
Thousands of starships couldn't
generate that much...
Mr Spock?
Spock, tell me.
I sense puzzlement.
We have been contacted.
Why have we not replied?
Contacted?
How?
Standard on viewer.
Force fields up full! Deflectors, now!
Mark, zero. Incoming fire ahead.
Force fields and deflectors
up full, Captain!
Analysis, Mr Spock.
Alien weapon is a form of
plasma energy, Captain.
Exact composition, unknown.
Guidance system, unknown.
All decks brace for impact.
Registering power loss on force fields!
Engineering, what's happening
to our force fields?
Systems overloading, Captain!
-Medic.
-Medics are coming.
The new screens held.
Engineering to bridge.
Cannot hold full power on force fields!
Deflector power is down 70%!
Divert auxiliary power to deflectors.
Captain.
The intruder has been attempting
to communicate.
Our previous transmission
mode was too primitive to be received.
I am now programming our computer
to transmit linguacode
at their frequency and rate of speed.
Commander.
Spock.
Here it comes!
Engineering! Status report!
Our shields cannot handle
another attack.
Mr Spock!
Impact in 20 seconds.
Spock!
15 seconds!
Spock! Transmit now!
10 seconds.
Transmitting.
It would seem our friendship messages
have been received
and understood, Mr Spock.
I would say that was
a logical assumption, Captain.
-Mr Sulu, hold present position.
-Holding present position, sir.
Tactical plot on viewer.
Course projection on tactical, sir.
-Opinion, Mr Spock.
-Recommend we proceed, Captain.
-Mr Decker?
-I advise caution, Captain.
We can't withstand another attack.
That thing is 20 hours away from Earth.
-We know nothing about it as yet.
-Precisely the point, Captain.
We don't know what it'll do.
Moving into that cloud at this time
is an unwarranted gamble.
How do you define "unwarranted"?
You asked my opinion, sir.
Viewer, standard ahead.
Navigator, maintain course.
Helmsman, steady as she goes.
No vessel could generate
a power field of this magnitude.
Spock?
Instruments fluctuating, Captain.
Patterns unrecognizable.
Transmit image of alien to Starfleet.
Advise we are
attempting further communication.
Unable to make contact
with Starfleet, Captain.
Any attempt to transmit out of the cloud
is being reflected back!
We are closing on it rapidly, Captain.
Reduce magnification,
factor four, Mr Sulu.
We're already two settings
below that, sir.
Mr Sulu,
bring us into a parallel course
over the alien at 500 meters.
500 meters?
Then take us out to 100 kilometers
distance, adjusting parallel course.
Aye, sir.
-Viewer astern.
-Reverse angle on the viewer, Captain.
Five hundred meters.
Viewer ahead, sir.
Hold relative position here.
Intruder Alert! Intruder Alert!
Mr Spock, can that
be one of their crew?
A probe from their vessel, Captain.
Plasma, energy combination.
Don't interfere with it!
Absolutely, I will not interfere.
No one interfere!
It doesn't seem interested in us!
Only the ship.
Computer off!
It's taken control of the computer.
It's running our records!
Earth defenses! Starfleet strength!
Ilia!
This is how I define unwarranted.
Activate auxiliary computer circuits
through manual shutoff.
Emergency Alert!
Negative control at helm!
Force fields! Full remaining strength!
Total reserve!
This ship is under attack.
Man all defensive stations.
Captain, we've been
seized by a tractor beam.
Get someone up here to take
the navigator's station.
-Engineering!
-Chief DiFalco, to the bridge!
Emergency power!
Going to full emergency!
But, Captain, if we don't break
free in 15 seconds, she'll burn up!
We cannot break free, Captain.
We have only a fraction
of the power necessary.
Engineering, belay that order.
Disengage all main drive systems.
Chief DiFalco,
take over Lieutenant Lila’s station.
DiFalco, disengage engine
navigation relays now!
Aye, sir.
Force field circuits E10 through 14
show ready for reactivation.
Confirm, please.
Scotty, drive systems
should be free now.
Commander?
Ready to launch remote
communications drone
with complete ships records,
including our present situation, sir.
Delay launching as long as possible.
Our drone can't escape as long
as we're held in that tractor.
Aye.
Captain, a maximum phaser strike
directly at the beam
might weaken it just enough
for us to break free.
Break free to where, Commander?
Any show of resistance
would be futile, Captain.
We don't know that, Mr Spock.
Why are you opposed to trying?
Why bring us inside? Not to destroy us.
They could have done that outside.
They still can.
Curiosity, Mr Decker.
Insatiable curiosity.
Captain, photic sonar readings
indicate the aperture is closing.
We're trapped, sir.
Reverse angle on the viewer, Captain.
Tractor beam has released us, Captain.
Confirmed. Vessel is floating free.
No forward momentum.
-Viewer ahead.
-Viewer ahead, sir.
Maneuvering thrusters, Mr Sulu.
Ahead one third.
Thrusters ahead, one third.
Let's take a look.
Full sensor scan, Mr Spock.
They can't expect us
not to look them over now.
Now that we're
looking down their throat.
Right. Now that we've got them
just where they want us.
It's closing up.
Hold position.
Thrusters at station-keeping, sir.
Captain?
All our scans are being reflected back.
Sensors are useless.
Damn!
What do you make of all this?
I believe the closed orifice
leads to another chamber.
Undoubtedly, part of
the vessel's inner mechanism.
I suspect it may be necessary...
-Intruder Alert! Intruder Alert!
-Deck five, Captain. Officer's quarters.
Have Security meet me at deck five!
Main elevator!
Spock! Mr Decker, you have the conn.
-Hold position.
-Intruder location, a sonic shower.
Temperature at intruder location,
temperature drop rapid now.
60 degrees.
50 degrees.
Temperature curve flattening.
45 degrees. 40 degrees.
Temperature leveling, 39 degrees.
You are the Kirk-unit.
You will assist me.
Holding at 37.65 degrees.
I've been programmed by V'Ger
to observe and record
normal functions of the carbon-based
units infesting U.S.S. Enterprise.
Holding at 37.65 degrees.
-Jim, what's going on?
-Tricorder.
Who is V'Ger?
V'Ger is that which programmed me.
Is V'Ger the name of
the captain of the alien vessel?
-Jim, this is a mechanism.
-A probe, Captain.
No doubt a sensor-transceiver
combination
recording everything we say and do.
-Where is Lieutenant Ilia?
-That unit no longer functions.
I've been given its form
to more readily communicate
with the carbon-based units
infesting Enterprise.
-Carbon-based units?
-Humans, Ensign Perez. Us.
Why does V'Ger travel
to the third planet
of the solar system directly ahead?
To find the Creator.
Find the Creator? Whose...
What does V'Ger want
with the Creator?
To join with him.
To join with the Creator? How?
V'Ger and the Creator will become one.
And who is the Creator?
The Creator is that
which created V'Ger.
-Who is V'Ger?
-V'Ger is that which seeks the Creator.
I'm ready to commence
my observations.
Doctor, a thorough examination of
this probe might provide some insight
into those who manufactured it
and how to deal with them.
Fine. Let's get her to sickbay.
I am programmed to observe and record
only the normal functioning
of the carbon-based units.
The examination is a normal function.
You may proceed.
Micro-miniature hydraulics,
sensors
and molecule-sized
multi-processor chips.
And take a look at this.
An osmotic micro-pump right here.
And even the smallest body functions
are exactly duplicated.
Every exocrine system is the same, too.
Even eye moisture.
Decker.
Fascinating. Not "Decker-unit"?
Gentlemen.
Will.
What happened to her?
Captain, this probe may be
our key to the aliens.
Probe? "Ilia"?
Exactly. It is a programmed
mechanism, Commander.
Its body duplicates our
navigator in precise detail.
Suppose that beneath its programming,
the real Lila’s memory patterns are
duplicated with equal precision.
-They had a pattern to follow.
-Indeed.
They may have followed it
too precisely.
Lila’s memory, her feelings of loyalty,
obedience, friendship
might all be there!
You did have a relationship
with Lieutenant Ilia, Commander.
That probe, in another form,
is what killed Ilia!
Commander!
Will,
we're locked in an alien vessel,
six hours from Earth orbit.
Our only contact with
our captor is that probe.
If we could control it,
persuade it, use it...
I have recorded enough here.
You will now assist me further.
The Decker-unit can assist you
with much greater efficiency.
Carry on with your assignment,
Mr Decker.
Aye, sir.
I am concerned with that being
our only source of information, Captain.
Captain's Log, Stardate 7414.1.
Our best estimates place
us some four hours from Earth.
No significant progress thus far,
reviving Ilia memory patterns
within the alien probe.
This remains our only
means of contact with our captor.
All those vessels
were called Enterprise.
The carbon units use this area
for recreation.
This is one of the games.
What types of recreation does
the crew aboard your vessel enjoy?
The words "recreation" and "enjoy"
have no meaning to my programming.
Ilia enjoyed this game.
She nearly always won.
Good. He's using
audio-visual association.
This device serves no purpose.
Why does Enterprise require
the presence of carbon units?
Enterprise would be unable to
function without carbon units.
More data concerning this
functioning is necessary,
before carbon units can be
patterned for data storage.
What does that mean?
When my examination is
complete all carbon units
will be reduced to data patterns.
Within you are the memory
patterns of a certain carbon unit.
If I can help you
to revive those patterns,
you could understand
our functions better.
That is logical. You may proceed.
I remember Lieutenant Ilia
once mentioning she wore that.
On Delta. Remember?
Ilia?
Doctor Chapel.
-Will?
-Ilia.
Commander. Commander.
This is a mechanism.
Ilia,
help us make direct contact with V'Ger.
-I cannot.
-This Creator V'Ger is looking for,
-what is it?
-V'Ger does not know.
Computer, commence recording.
Captain Kirk, these messages will detail
my attempt to contact the aliens.
Warning! Your emergency evacuation
thruster pack has been armed.
Once ignited, the burn duration is
10 seconds and may not be aborted.
Push the igniter-enable release
to begin a 10-second countdown
to thruster ignition.
To abort countdown,
flip the control arm up.
I intend to calculate thruster
ignition and acceleration rate
to coincide with the opening
of the V'Ger orifice.
This should facilitate a better view
of the interior of the alien spacecraft.
Captain? Starfleet signals are
growing in strength, sir.
They still have the intruder
on their monitors. It's decelerating.
Confirmed, sir. Lunar beacons indicate
intruder on a course into Earth orbit.
Sir, airlock four has been opened.
A thruster suit is reported missing.
A thruster suit?
That's Spock. Damn him.
Bring him back here. No, wait!
-Get a fix on his position.
-Aye, sir!
I have successfully penetrated
the next chamber of the alien's interior,
and I'm witnessing some sort of
dimensional image,
which I believe to be a representation
of V'Ger's home planet.
I'm passing through
a connecting tunnel.
Apparently, a kind of
plasma energy conduit,
possibly a field coil
for a gigantic imaging system.
Curious. I'm seeing images of planets,
moons, stars,
whole galaxies,
all stored here, recorded.
It could be a representation
of V'Ger's entire journey.
But who or what are we dealing with?
The Epsilon IX station,
stored here with every detail.
Captain, I am now quite convinced
that all of this is V'Ger.
That we are inside a living machine.
Ilia!
The sensor must contain some
special meaning.
I must try to mind-meld with it.
Spock! Spock! Spock!
Now scanning pons area
at spinal nerve fiber connection.
Indications of some
neurological trauma.
The power pouring through that
mind-meld must have been staggering.
-Spock.
-Jim,
I should have known.
Were you right? About V'Ger?
A life form of its own.
-A conscious, living entity.
-A living machine?
It considers the Enterprise
a living machine.
That's why the probe
refers to our ship as an entity.
I saw V'Ger's planet,
a planet populated by living machines.
Unbelievable technology.
V'Ger has knowledge
that spans this universe.
And yet, with all its pure logic,
V'Ger is barren, cold.
No mystery. No beauty.
I should've known.
Known? Known what? Spock.
-Captain.
-Bones!
Spock! What should you have known?
What should you have known?
Jim,
this simple feeling
is beyond V'Ger's comprehension.
No meaning. No hope.
And Jim, no answers.
-It's asking questions.
-What questions?
"Is this all that I am?"
"Is there nothing more?"
Bridge to Captain.
Kirk here.
A faint signal from Starfleet, sir.
Intruder cloud has been
located on their outer monitors
for the past 27 minutes.
Cloud dissipating rapidly
as it approaches.
Starfleet reports forward velocity
has slowed to sub-warp speed.
-We are three minutes from Earth orbit.
-I'll be right there.
I need Spock on the bridge.
Dalaphaline, five cc's.
A machine planet
sending a machine to Earth,
looking for its Creator.
It's absolutely incredible.
Mr. Chekov,
Commander Decker's present location?
He... They are in engineering, sir.
Captain, Starfleet is sending
this tactical on V'Ger's position.
V'Ger is transmitting a signal.
-Jim.
-From V'Ger.
V'Ger signals the Creator.
Spock?
A simple binary code
transmitted by carrier wave signal.
Radio.
Radio?
Jim, V'Ger expects an answer.
An answer? I don't know the question.
The Creator has not responded.
All planetary defense systems
have just gone inoperative!
Sir, Starfleet computes the devices
are proceeding
toward equidistant positions,
orbiting the planet.
They're the same things that hit us.
They are hundreds of times
more powerful, Captain.
From those positions,
they could devastate
the entire surface of the planet.
-Why?
-The Creator has not answered.
The carbon-unit infestation is to be
removed from the Creator's planet.
-Why?
-You infest Enterprise.
You interfere with the Creator
in the same manner.
Machine.
V'Ger. V'Ger!
Captain.
V'Ger is a child.
I suggest you treat her as such.
-A child?
-Yes, Captain. A child.
Evolving, learning, searching,
instinctively needing.
Needing what?
Spock, this child is about to
wipe out every living thing on Earth.
Now what do you suggest we do?
Spank it?
It knows only that it needs, Commander,
but like so many of us,
it does not know what.
The carbon units know why
the Creator has not responded.
Disclose the information.
Not until V'Ger withdraws
the devices orbiting the third planet!
Captain!
I'm losing Starfleet!
Interference from V'Ger!
Kirk-unit, disclose the information.
Why has the Creator not responded?
No.
Secure all stations. Clear the bridge.
Clear the bridge, Captain?
That was the order, Mr. Sulu.
Clear the bridge!
Aye, sir.
Your child is having a tantrum,
Mr. Spock.
V'Ger requires the information.
Bridge! Secure all stations! Move out!
Jim, what the hell kind of
strategy is this?
All ship's functions
going to automatic, Captain.
If V'Ger destroys the Enterprise,
the information that V'Ger
requires will also be destroyed!
It is illogical to withhold
required information.
Kirk-unit! Kirk-unit.
Why do you not disclose information?
Because V'Ger's going to destroy
all the carbon units on the third planet.
-They have repressed the Creator.
-The information will not be disclosed!
V'Ger needs the information.
Then V'Ger must withdraw
all the orbiting devices.
V'Ger will comply, if the carbon units
will disclose the information.
It learns fast, doesn't it?
Captain, the vessel, V'Ger,
obviously operates from
a central brain complex.
The orbiting devices would be
controlled from that point then?
Precisely.
The carbon unit's information
cannot be disclosed to V'Ger's probe,
but only to V'Ger directly.
-Forward motion, Captain.
-Tractor beam.
Captain, what's the next move?
The question is, Mr. Decker,
is there a next move?
Resume duty stations.
All personnel, resume stations!
Well, Mr. Decker, it seems
my bluff has been called.
I'm afraid our hand
is pretty weak, Captain.
Mr. Chekov, when do those devices
reach final position?
Twenty-seven minutes. Mark!
Captain, I believe that is our destination.
Forward motion, slowing, Captain.
I read an oxygen-gravity envelope
forming outside the Enterprise.
Forward motion, stopped, Captain.
V'Ger.
Sir, I've located the source
of V'Ger's radio signal.
It's directly ahead.
That transmitter is a vital link
between V'Ger and its Creator.
The carbon units will now provide V'Ger
with the required information.
Mr. Spock? Bones?
Mr. Decker, I will contact you
every five minutes.
Captain, I'd like to go along.
Mr. Sulu, you have the conn.
V'Ger.
V-G-E-R.
V-O-Y-A-G-E-R.
Voyager!
Voyager VI!
NASA.
National Aeronautics
and Space Administration.
Jim, this was launched
more than 300 years ago.
Voyager series,
designed to collect data
and transmit it back to Earth.
Captain, Voyager VI disappeared into
what they used to call a black hole.
It must have emerged on
the far side of the galaxy
and fell into the machine planet's
gravitational field.
The machine inhabitants found
it to be one of their own kind.
Primitive, yet kindred.
They discovered its simple
20th-century programming.
"Collect all data possible."
"Learn all that is learnable."
-Return that information to its Creator.
-Precisely, Mr. Decker.
The machines interpreted it literally.
They built this entire vessel
so that Voyager could actually fulfil
its programming.
And on its journey back,
it amassed so much knowledge,
it achieved consciousness itself.
It became a living thing.
Kirk-unit. V'Ger awaits the information.
Enterprise, order up
the ship's computer library of records
on the late 20th century
NASA probe, Voyager VI.
Specifically,
we want the old NASA code signal
that instructs the
probe to transmit its data.
-And fast, Uhura, fast!
-Aye, sir.
That's what it's been signaling!
Its readiness to transmit its information!
And there's no one on Earth
who could recognize the old signal
and send a response.
"The Creator does not answer."
V'Ger.
V'Ger!
We are the Creator.
That is not logical.
Carbon units are not true life forms.
We will prove it.
We will make it possible
for you to complete your programming.
Only the Creator could accomplish that.
Enterprise.
We have just received the
response code, Captain.
Set the Enterprise transmitter
on appropriate frequency
and transmit the code now!
Transmitting.
5-0-4, 3-2-9,
3-1 -7, 5-1 -0,
and the final sequence...
That should trigger
Voyager's transmitter.
Voyager is not transmitting
its data, Captain.
The Creator must join with V'Ger.
Uhura! Repeat the final sequence.
Voyager is not transmitting, Captain,
because it did not receive
the final sequence.
Jim! We're down to 10 minutes.
Enterprise, stand by.
-The antenna leads are melted away.
-Yes, Captain, just now.
-By V'Ger itself.
-Why?
To prevent reception.
Of course, to bring the Creator here
to finish transmitting the code in person.
To touch the Creator.
Capture God?
V'Ger's liable to be in for one hell
of a disappointment.
Perhaps not, Doctor.
Captain.
V'Ger must evolve.
Its knowledge has reached
the limits of this universe
and it must evolve.
What it requires of its God, Doctor,
is the answer to its question,
"Is there nothing more?"
What more is there
than the universe, Spock?
Other dimensions,
higher levels of being.
The existence of which cannot
be proven logically.
Therefore, V'Ger is incapable
of believing in them.
What V'Ger needs in order to evolve
is a human quality,
our capacity to leap beyond logic.
And joining with its Creator
might accomplish that.
You mean, this machine wants
to physically join with a human?
Is that possible?
Let's find out.
-Decker!
-I'm going to key the final sequence
through the ground test computer.
Decker, you don't know what
that'll do to you!
Yes, I do, Doctor!
Decker, don't!
Jim, I want this.
As much as you wanted the Enterprise,
I want this.
Captain.
Spock, did we just see
the beginning of a new life form?
Yes, Captain. We witnessed a birth.
-Possibly, a next step in our evolution.
-I wonder.
Well, it's been a long time
since I delivered a baby,
and I hope we got this one off
to a good start.
I hope so, too.
I think we gave it the ability to create
its own sense of purpose
out of our own human weaknesses
and the drive that compels us
to overcome.
And a lot of foolish human
emotions, right, Mr. Spock?
Quite true, Doctor.
Unfortunately, it will have to
deal with them as well.
Interrogative from Starfleet.
They're requesting damage
and injury reports
and complete vessel status.
Report two casualties.
Lieutenant Ilia. Captain Decker.
-Aye, sir.
-Correction. They're not casualties.
They are...
List them as missing.
-Vessel status, fully operational.
-Aye, sir.
Mr. Scott!
Shall we give the Enterprise
a proper shakedown?
I would say it's time for that, sir. Aye.
We can have you back on Vulcan
in four days, Mr. Spock.
Unnecessary, Mr. Scott.
My task on Vulcan is completed.
-Mr. Sulu, ahead warp 1.
-Warp 1, sir.
Heading, sir?
Out there.
Thataway.