Locutus.
I am Locutus of Borg.
Resistance is futile.
Authorisation: Picard 47-AT.
- Did I catch you at a bad time?
- No, Admiral, of course not.
I`ve just heard that our colony on
Ivor Prime has been destroyed.
- Long-range sensors...
- Yes, I know. The Borg.
Captain’s log: Stardate 50893.5.
The moment have dreaded for
nearly six years has finally arrived.
The Borg, our lethal enemy, have
begun an invasion of the Federation.
This time
there maybe no stopping them.
- How many ships?
- One, on a direct course for Earth.
They’ll be in Federation space soon.
Admiral Hayes is mobilising a fleet.
- It will take us three hours...
- We’re not going.
- What do you mean?
- We’re to patrol the Neutral Zone.
In case the Romulans decide
to take advantage of the situation.
There has been no unusual activity
along the Romulan border.
Does Starfleet feel
we need more shakedown time?
We`re ready! The Enterprise E is
the most advanced ship in the fleet.
I have gone over all this
with Starfleet. Their orders stand.
Number One,
set a course for the Neutral Zone.
- Bizet?
- Berlioz. What do you have?
We`ve finished
our first sweep of the Neutral Zone.
Fascinating.
20 particles of dust per cubic metre.
52 ultraviolet radiation spikes
and a class-two comet.
This is certainly
worthy of our attention.
Captain, why are we out here?
Starfleet has every confidence
in the Enterprise and her crew.
They`re just not sure
about her captain.
A man once captured
and assimilated by the Borg -
- should not be put in a situation
where he would face them again.
It would introduce an unstable element
to a critical situation.
Your experience makes you
the perfect man to lead this fight.
Bridge to Captain Picard.
We`ve received word from the fleet,
they`ve engaged the Borg.
Mr Data, put Starfleet frequency 1486
on audio.
Flagship Endeavour,
stand by to engage.
Defiant and Bozeman,
fallback to mobile position one.
We have it in visual range.
A Borg cube on course 0215 ...
We are the Borg. Lower your shields
and surrender your ships.
We will add your biological
distinctiveness to our own.
Your culture will adapt to serve us.
Resistance is futile.
All units, open fire.
They`ve broken through
the defence perimeter.
Continue to attack.
We need reinforcements.
96 dead and 22 wounded
on the Lexington.
Lt Hawk, set a course for Earth.
Maximum warp.
I am about to disobey our orders.
Any of you who wish to object
should do so now.
I believe I speak for everyone here
when I say ...
... to hell with our orders.
Red alert. All hands to battle stations.
Engage.
- Report!
- Power off-line, our weapons are gone.
Perhaps today is a good day to die.
Prepare for ramming speed.
Sir, there`s another ship coming in.
It`s the Enterprise.
- The Defiant is losing life support.
- Beam the survivors aboard.
They`ve destroyed the admiral`s ship.
- What is the status of the Borg cube?
- The outer hull has been damaged.
I am reading fluctuations
in their power grid.
Number One,
open a channel to the fleet.
This is Capt Picard.
I`m taking command of the fleet.
Plot in the following coordinates.
Fire on my command.
- Is that a vital system?
- Trust me, Data.
The fleet has responded, sir,
they`re standing by.
Fire.
- Mr Hawk, pursuit course. Engage.
- Aye, sir.
- What?
- I can hear them.
I have a patient here
who insists on coming to the bridge.
- Welcome aboard, Mr Worf.
- Thank you, sir.
- The Defiant?
- Adrift, but salvageable.
- Tough little ship.
- Little?
Mr Worf, we could use some help
at tactical.
You do remember
how to fire phasers?
We`re detecting
chronometric particles.
- They`re creating a temporal vortex.
- Time travel.
- Data, report.
- We`re caught in a temporal wake.
Captain ... Earth.
There are high concentrations
of methane and carbon monoxide.
- Life signs?
- Approximately nine billion.
- All Borg.
- How?.
They did it in the past. They went back
and assimilated Earth, changed history.
Why are we still here?
The temporal wake protected us
from changes in the time line.
- The vortex is collapsing.
- Hold your course.
We must follow them back
and repair the damage they`ve done.
- Come on.
- Good night, Eddie.
Go home.
You`ll regret this tomorrow.
You should have learned by now
that I don`t have regrets.
- One more round, Lily.
- Z, you`ve had enough.
- I`m not flying with a drunken pilot.
- I can`t fly sober.
What is that?
- That is the constellation Leo.
- No, that!
- It`s the ECON.
- After all these years?
We`ve got to get to the Phoenix.
To hell with the Phoenix.
Shields are down.
Main power is holding.
We are in the mid 21st century.
I would estimate we have arrived
ten years after the Third World War.
That makes sense. Most of the
major cities have been destroyed.
- 600 million dead. No resistance.
- Captain.
Mr Worf, quantum torpedoes.
Fire.
They were firing at the surface.
Location?
Western hemisphere.
North American Continent.
- A missile complex in Montana.
- A missile complex?.
Data, I need to know the exact date.
April 4th, 2063.
April 4th.
The day before First Contact.
The missile complex must be
where Cochrane is building his ship.
They came to stop First Contact.
- How much damage, Lieutenant?
- I can`t tell.
We`ll have to go down there
and find out what happened.
Have a security team ready.
Computer, 21st century clothing.
Number One, you have the Bridge.
Over here.
They`re all dead.
See if one of them is Cochrane.
Data, let`s go check the warp ship.
The structural integrity of the missile
appears to be intact.
The fuselage is slightly damaged.
We have the blueprints.
We need a team down here.
- Hold your fire. We`re here to help.
- Bullshit!
Captain, I believe I can handle this.
Greetings.
This woman
requires medical attention.
- Severe radiation poisoning.
- From the damaged ship.
I have to get her to sick bay.
No lectures on the prime directive,
l`ll keep her unconscious.
Tell Riker to beam down with
a search party to find Cochrane.
Crusher to Enterprise.
Two to beam directly to sick bay.
In 48 hours
this ship has to be launched.
Geordi, the ship was damaged in the
attack. Get a repair crew down here.
I`m on my way. Alpha team,
we`re heading down to the surface.
Porter, take command while l`m gone.
Check out the environmental controls.
It`s a little warm in here.
Isn`t it amazing?
This ship
used to be a nuclear missile.
An historical irony. Using an
instrument of mass destruction -
- to inaugurate an era of peace.
A boyhood fantasy. I`ve seen
this ship in the Smithsonian, -
- but I was never able to touch it.
Does tactile contact
alter your perception of the Phoenix?.
For humans, touch can connect you
to an object in a very personal way.
It makes it seem more real.
I`m detecting imperfections
in the titanium casing.
Temperature variations
in the fuel manifold.
It is no more real to me now
than it was a moment ago.
- Would you three like to be alone?
- What have you found out?
- There`s no sign of Cochrane.
- He has to be here.
This ship and this flight
were his dream.
We should consider the possibility
that Dr Cochrane died in the attack.
If that`s true ...
then the future may die with him.
- What do you think?.
- The entire system has gone crazy.
It`s affecting the entire deck.
I`ll check the EPS conduits.
- Hello? Hey!
- Are you talking to me?
Is anyone else working up here?
Not that I know of.
Paul?
Paul, are you okay in there?
Captain, what is it?
Picard to Enterprise. Mr Worf,
is everything all right up there?
We are experiencing some
environmental diffiiculties.
Humidityhas risen 73()%()
and the temperature is up 10 degrees.
Mr Data and I will be right there.
Number One, take charge down here.
The damage to her cell membranes
is repaired. She should be fine.
Find out why it`s so hot in here.
- Now what?
- Crusher to Engineering.
Crusher to Bridge.
- Exactly what`s been happening?
- We`ve lost contact with Deck 16.
I was about to send
a security team to investigate.
No, seal off Deck 16. Post
security teams at every access point.
What environmental conditions
were last reported in Engineering?
92()%() humidity.
39.1 degrees Celsius.
39.1 degrees Celsius ...
Iike a Borg ship.
They knew their ship was doomed.
Our shields were down.
Somehow they transported over here
without being detected.
They`ll assimilate the Enterprise ...
and then Earth.
Picard to Riker.
Enterprise to Away Team.
Respond.
Main control is being re-routed
through Engineering.
Data, lock out the main computer.
I have isolated the main computer
with an encryption code.
The Borg have cut primary power
to all decks except 16.
The Borg won`t stay on Deck 16.
You`re all right. Come on, wake up.
You are all right. Listen to me.
You`re going to be fine.
I need you to do as I say.
- Is the EMH programme on-line?
- It should be.
- Activate the EMH programme.
- What is the nature of the emergency?.
20 Borg are about to break in here.
Create a diversion.
This isn`t part of my programme.
I`m a doctor.
Do a dance, tell a story,
just give us a few seconds.
According to medical research, Borg
implants can cause skin irritations.
Perhaps you`d like
an analgesic cream.
Which way?.
We need to get off this deck.
Follow me.
Engineering will be the central point
from which they control the hive.
If we begin firing in there,
we may hit the warp core.
Our goal should be to puncture
one of the plasma coolant tanks.
Plasma coolant will liquefy
organic material on contact.
The Borg cannot survive
without their organic components.
All weapons will be set
on a rotating modulation.
The Borg will adapt quickly.
We`ll be able to fire 12 shots at most.
You may encounter crew members
who have already been assimilated.
Don`t hesitate to fire. Believe me,
you`ll be doing them a favour. Let`s go.
Deanna!
Will, don`t turn off that ..!
Who is this jerk?. And who told him
he could turn off my music?
Will Riker, Zefram Cochrane.
- Is he a friend of yours?
- Yes.
- Husband?
- No?
Good.
- This, Deena ...
- Deanna.
This ... is the good stuff.
Dr Cochrane ...
To the Phoenix ...
May she rest in peace.
Okay, that wasn`t so good.
- We have to tell him the truth.
- Then the time line ...
This is no time to argue about time.
We don`t have the time.
- What was I saying?
- You`re drunk.
He wouldn`t even talk to me
unless I had a drink with him.
It took three shots of tequila
just to find out his name.
I`ve spent the last 20 minutes
trying to keep his hands off me.
So don`t go criticising
my counselling techniques.
It`s a primitive culture.
I`m just trying to blend in.
He didn`t believe our cover story.
We`re running out of time.
Will he be able to handle the truth?
If you`re looking for my
professional opinion ... He`s nuts.
I`ll be sure to note that in my log.
Captain, I believe l`m feeling ...
anxiety.
It is an intriguing sensation.
Data, perhaps you should deactivate
your emotion chip for now.
Good idea, sir ... Done.
Data, there are times that I envy you.
It`s only me! We have wounded here.
- Get these people back to Deck 14.
- There was a civilian with us.
- We`ll watch for her.
- Please, try to find her.
Lower your weapons. They`ll ignore
us till the consider us a threat.
The manual release.
Mr Worf, hold this position.
Manualrelease on-line.
Perhaps we should just knock.
Data.
Ready phasers.
Data, cover me.
Captain, they have adapted.
Regroup on Deck 15.
Don`t let them touch you.
- Captain!
- Data!
Here!
Help!
Please, help.
- You! How the hell ..?
- Back off!
Who are you?
What faction are you with?
- I`m not with the Eastern Coalition.
- Just get me the hell out of here.
- Now!
- That isn`t going to be easy.
You`d better find a way,
or l`m going to start pushing buttons.
- Follow me.
- Slow!
You won`t be able to break
the encryption codes.
Nor will you
be able to assimilate me.
Brave words.
I`ve heard them before.
From thousands ofspecies
across thousands ofworlds.
Butnow they are alIBorg.
I am unlike any life form
you have encountered before.
You are an imperfectbeing,
created by an imperfectbeing.
Findingyour weakness
is only a matter oftime.
Let me make sure I understand you
correctly, Commander.
A group of cybernetic creatures
from the future -
- have travelled back through time
to enslave the human race.
And you`re here to stop them?
Hot damn! You`re heroic.
- We`re going to prove it to you.
- There she is! Beautiful!
- All right, take a look.
- Well, well, well ...
What have we got here?
I love a good peep show.
That`s a trick.
How did you do that?
- It`s your telescope.
- That`s our ship. The Enterprise.
And Lily is up there?
Can I talk to her?.
We`ve lost contact with the ship.
We don`t know why yet.
- So what is it you want me to do?
- Conduct your flight as planned.
Why tomorrow morning?
At 1 1 o`clock an alien ship
will be passing this solar system.
Alien? You mean extra-terrestrials?
- More bad guys?
- Good guys.
They have no interest in Earth ...
too primitive.
When they discover that humans have
learned how to fly faster than light, -
- they alter their course and make
first contact with Earth right here.
- Here?
- Actually, over there.
It`s a pivotal moment in human history.
You make contact with an alien race.
After you do,
everything begins to change.
Fleets of starships are built
and mankind explores the galaxy.
It unites humanity when they realise
they`re not alone in the universe.
Poverty, disease and war
will all be gone in 50 years.
But unless you make that warp flight
tomorrow, none of it will happen.
You people are all astronauts ...
... on some kind of star trek.
I know this is a lot to take in,
but we`re running out of time.
- We need your help.
- What do you say?.
Why not?
It looks pretty bad, sir.
They control decks 26 up to 1 1 .
When they took Deck 1 1 ,
they stopped.
They`ve assimilated half the ship.
Why stop there?
- What is on Deck 1 1?
- Hydroponics. Deflector control.
They stopped there because
it gave them a tactical advantage.
Return to your checkpoints.
What happened in sick bay?.
Where`s Dr Crusher?.
- Why did you break the cease-fire?
- We didn`t attack you.
There`s a new faction that
wants to prevent tomorrow`s launch.
We`re here to help you.
You are not in Montana anymore.
You are on a spaceship
orbiting the Earth.
- Get me out of here.
- All right.
You want a way out. Here it is.
What is this?
Australia. New Guinea.
The Solomons.
Montana will be up soon,
but it`s a long way down.
I`m not your enemy
and I can get you home.
Put the weapon down and trust me.
Jean-Luc Picard.
That`s my name, what`s yours?
- Lily.
- Welcome aboard, Lily.
Thank you.
Maximum setting. If you`d fired this,
you`d have vaporised me.
It`s my first ray gun.
- There`s no glass.
- Forcefield.
- I`ve never seen such technology.
- It hasn`t been invented yet.
There`s more I have to tell you.
Come on.
Are you ready?
- Who are you?
- I am the Borg.
That is a contradiction. The Borg
have a collective consciousness.
There are no individuals.
I am the beginning, the end,
the one who is many.
I am the Borg.
Greetings.
I am curious,
do you control the Borg collective?
You imply disparity where
none exists. I am the collective.
I`ll rephrase the question.
I wish to understand their hierarchy.
Are you their leader?.
I bring order to chaos.
A cryptic response.
You are in chaos, Data.
You are a machine
who wishes to be human.
I am programmed
to evolve and to better myself.
We, too, are on a quest
to better ourselves.
Evolving toward a state of perfection.
Forgive me, but the Borg
do not evolve, they conquer.
By assimilating other beings we are
bringing them closer to perfection.
Somehow I question your motives.
That is because you haven`t
been properly ... stimulated yet.
You have reactivated
my emotion chip. Why?.
- Don`t be frightened.
- I am not frightened.
- Do you know what this is?
- It would appear to be organic skin.
What a cold description
for such a beautiful gift.
Was that good for you?
- How big is this Federation?
- Over 150 planets.
- They span 8,000 light years.
- You mustn`t get home much.
I tend to think of this ship as home.
I get back to Earth whenever I can.
- They haven`t broken the code yet.
- Who? The zombies?
- The Borg.
- It sounds Swedish.
- How big is this ship?
- 24 decks. 700 metres long.
It took me six months to find enough
titanium just to build a cockpit.
How much did this thing cost?
The economics of the future
are somewhat different.
Money doesn`t exist
in the 24th century.
No money?.
You mean you don`t get paid?
The acquisition of wealth is no
longer the driving force in our lives.
We work to better ourselves ...
... and the rest of humanity.
Actually, we`re rather like
yourself and Dr Cochrane.
All right!
- Come on.
- Is there another way around?
I know what l`m doing.
Definitely not Swedish.
What the hell are you doing?
Perhaps something in satin.
I`m sorry, but we`re closing,
and we have a strict dress code.
If you boys don`t leave ...
- I`m looking for Nicky the Nose.
- He hasn`t been here in months.
This is the wrong chapter.
Computer, begin chapter 13.
Try and look
as if you`re having a good time.
No, look at me.
Try to act naturally.
There he is.
- Ruby, this is not a good time.
- It`s never the time for us, Dix.
- Is that a case you`re working on?
- I`ll see you later.
Okay, but watch your caboose
and dump the broad.
Look what the cat dragged in.
What`s shakin`, Dix?.
The usual, martinis and skirts.
Excuse me.
- I`m going to take that personal.
- No offence.
Hey!
I think you got him.
I don`t get it. I thought
you said this was a hologram.
I disengaged the safety protocols,
so even a holographic bullet can kill.
- What are you doing?
- Looking for the neural processor.
It`s like a memory chip.
It will contain a record of all the
instructions this Borg has received.
- It`s one of your uniforms.
- Yes, this was Ensign Lynch.
Tough luck, huh?
I`ve got to get to the bridge.
- Doctor ...
- Yeah?
- Would you take a look at this?
- Yeah.
I`ve constructed the intermix chamber
from what I remember in school.
- You learned about this in school?
- Yeah.
``Basic Warp Design`` is required
reading. You`re the first chapter.
Well, it looks like you got it right.
This is what we`re using to replace
the damaged plasma conduit.
Yes, but you need to reinforce
the tubing with a nano-polymer.
Dr Cochrane, I know this sounds
silly, but can I shake your hand?
It`s such an honour to work with you.
I never imagined l`d meet
the man who invented warp drive.
I`m sorry ... Thanks.
- Do they have to keep doing that?
- It`s just a little hero worship.
I can`t say I blame them.
We all grew up hearing about you.
Or, what you`re aboutto do.
I shouldn`t say this, -
- but I went
to Zefram Cochrane High School.
Really?.
- I wish I had a picture of this.
- What?
In the future, this whole area
becomes an historical monument.
You`re standing on the exact spot
where your statue is going to be.
Statue?
It`s marble, about 20 metres tall.
You`re looking up at the sky.
Your hand
is reaching toward the future.
I`ve got to take a leak.
Leak?. I`m not detecting any leak.
Don`t you people
from the 24th century ever pee?
Oh, leak! I get it.
- That`s pretty funny.
- Excuse me.
Commander ...
Reports of my assimilation
are greatly exaggerated.
I found something you lost.
- I am a Klingon.
- Mr Worf, report.
The Borg control over half the ship.
There`s no power to the bridge.
I`ve accessed
a Borg neural processor.
They`re transforming the deflector
dish into an interplexing beacon -
- to establish a link with the Borg
living in the 21st century.
But the Borg
are still in the Delta Quadrant.
They`ll send reinforcements.
Humanity will be an easy target.
We must destroy the deflector dish.
We can`t get to deflector control
or a shuttle craft ...
Mr Worf, do you remember
your zero-G combat training?
I remember it made me
sick to my stomach.
- What are you suggesting?
- It`s time we took a little stroll.
There`s a humanoid life-sign
up ahead.
51 1 metres.
Cochrane?
It`s him, all right.
I`ve re-modulated the weapons,
but the Borg will be quick to adapt.
We must make every shot count.
Magnetise.
- Watch your caboose, Dix.
- I intend to.
- How are you doing, Worf?
- Not well, sir.
Try not to look at the stars.
Keep your eyes on the hull.
Let`s go.
Tell me, are you using
a polymer-based neuro-rely -
- to transmit organic nerve impulses
to my positronic net?
If so, how have you solved
the problem of signal degradation?
Do you always talk this much?
Not always, but often.
Why do you insist
on using this primitive language?
Your android brain
is capable of much more.
I am trying to become more human.
We used to be just like them.
Flawed, weak, organic.
We evolved to include the synthetic.
We use both to attain perfection.
Your goal
should be the same as ours.
Believing oneself to be perfect is
often the sign of a delusional mind.
A small being, trying to attack
what he doesn`t understand.
You have no real interest in me.
Your goal is to obtain
the codes for the computer.
That is one of our goals,
one of many.
And to reach it,
l`m willing to help you reach yours.
Is it becoming clear to you yet?
Look at you, standing there cradling
the new flesh l`ve given you.
If it means nothing to you,
why protect it?
I am simply imitating
the behaviour of humans.
You`re becoming more human all the
time. Now you`re learning how to lie.
My programming was not designed
to process these sensations.
Then tear away your skin
as you would a defective circuit.
Go ahead, Data. We won`t stop you.
Do it. Don`t be tempted by flesh.
Are you familiar with
physical forms of pleasure?
If you are referring to ... sexuality, -
- I am fully functional.
Programmed in multiple techniques.
How long has it been
since you`ve used them?
8 years, 7 months,
16 days, 4 minutes ...
Far too long.
- We should bring reinforcements.
- There`s no time.
They`re building it on top of the particle
emitter. It will soon be activated.
- With phasers on full power ...
- The dish is charged with anti-protons.
It`d destroy half the ship.
We have to find another way.
Doctor!
- Still looking for the bathroom?
- I`m not going back.
- We can`t do this without you.
- I don`t want to be a statue.
- Stay away from me.
- We don`t have time for this.
You told him about the statue?
For this to work, all three maglocks
will have to be released.
The magnetic restrictors
are disengaged.
They`ve adapted.
Warning:
Decompression in 45 seconds.
Hawk!
We`ve had a change of plans, Data.
Assimilate this.
- An hour to go. How are you?
- I`ve got a hangover.
Either from the whisky
or your laser beam ... or both.
But l`m ready to make history.
Troi to Riker.
We`re ready to open the launch door.
- Look at that.
- Is there no moon in the future?
Sure, but there are
50 million people living on it.
You can even see Tycho City
and Lake Armstrong on a clear day.
Please ...
don`t tell me it`s all thanks to me.
I`ve heard enough about
the great Zefram Cochrane.
You people have got some
pretty funny ideas about me.
You all look at me
as if l`m a saint or a visionary.
You`re no saint, but you did
have a vision. We`re sitting in it.
You want to know what my vision is?
Dollar signs! Money!
I didn`t build this ship
to usher in a new era for humanity.
You think I want to go to the stars?
I don`t even like to fly. I take trains.
I built this ship so that I could
retire to some tropical island, -
- filled with naked women.
That`s Zefram Cochrane.
That`s his vision.
This historical figure
you keep talking about ...
I never met him.
I can`t imagine I ever will.
Someone once said: ``Don`t try
to be a great man, just be a man.``
- ``Let history be the judge.``
- Rhetorical nonsense.
- Who said that?
- You did, ten years from now.
You`ve got 58 minutes, Doc.
Get on the checklist.
They`re on the move again.
They`ve taken decks 5 and 6.
- They`ve adapted to our weapons.
- We`ll have to further modify them.
In the meantime,
tell your men to stand their ground.
- Fight hand-to-hand if they have to.
- Aye, sir.
Wait.
Captain, our weapons are useless.
We must activate the auto-destruct
and evacuate the ship.
If we destroy the ship,
we destroy the Borg.
- We`re going to stay and fight.
- We have lost the Enterprise.
We have not lost the Enterprise
and we are not going to.
- Not while l`m in command.
- I must object ...
- Your objection is noted.
- With all due respect ...
You`re allowing personal experience
to influence yourjudgement.
You`re afraid.
You want to destroy the ship
and run away. You coward.
If you were any other man,
I would kill you where you stand.
Get off my bridge.
- What now?.
- Carry out his orders.
Dyson, Kaplan,
modify the weapons system.
- We should get off this ship.
- The captain has made up his mind.
- You son of a bitch!
- This isn`t the time.
I know nothing about the future,
but everyone thinks this is suicide.
- They`re just afraid to say it.
- The crew will follow my orders.
- Even if they don`t make sense?
- They don`t know the Borg as I do.
- No one does. No one can.
- What is that supposed to mean?
Six years ago, they assimilated me
into their collective.
I had the cybernetic devices
implanted throughout my body.
I was linked to the hive,
every trace of individuality erased.
I was one of them.
I have a unique perspective on Borg
and I know how to fight them.
If you will excuse me,
I have work to do.
I am such an idiot ...
It`s so simple.
The Borg hurt you, and now
you`re going to hurt them back.
In my century we have
a higher sensibility than revenge.
Bullshit! I saw the look on your
face when we were on the Holodeck.
- You were enjoying it.
- How dare you!
You`re not the first man to get
a thrill from murdering someone.
- Get out!
- Or what? You`ll kill me?
- Like you killed Ensign Lynch?
- There was no way to save him.
- Where was your sensibility then?
- I don`t have time for this.
I didn`t mean to interrupt your quest.
Capt Ahab has to go hunt his whale.
- What?
- You do have books in the future?
This is about saving humanity.
- Blow up the damn ship!
- No!
I will not sacrifice the Enterprise.
We`ve made
too many compromises already.
They invade our space,
and we fall back.
They assimilate entire worlds,
Not again. The line must be drawn here.
This far and no further.
And I will make them pay
for what they`ve done.
You broke your little ships.
See you around, Ahab.
``And he piled upon
the whale`s white hump -
- a sum of all the rage and hate
felt by his whole race.``
``lf his chest had been a cannon, he
would have shot his heart upon it.``
What?
- ``Moby Dick`.
- Actually, I never read it.
Ahab spent years hunting
the white whale that crippled him.
A quest for vengeance.
But in the end it destroyed him -
- and his ship.
I guess he didn`t know when to quit.
Prepare to evacuate the Enterprise.
- ATR setting?
- Active.
Main bus.
Initiate pre-ignition sequence.
Begin auto-destruct sequence.
Authorisation: Picard 47-AT.
Confirm auto-destruct sequence.
Crusher 22-BC.
Authorisation: Worf 37-GE.
Command authorisation accepted.
Awaiting final code.
Destruct sequence A-1 .
15 minutes silent countdown.
- Enable.
- Self-destructin 15 minutes.
There willbe no audio warning.
- So much for the Enterprise E.
- We barely knew her.
Do you think they`ll build a new one?
There are plenty of letters left
in the alphabet.
Mr Worf ...
- I regret some of the things I said.
- Some?
As a matter of fact, I think you`re
the bravest man l`ve ever known.
Thank you, sir.
See you on Gravett lsland.
Captain.
Data.
Control to Phoenix,
final launch checks are complete.
- Good luck.
- Everybody ready to make history?.
I think I forgot something.
It`s probably nothing.
Begin ignition sequence.
God! Now I remember!
Where is it?
We can`t lift off without it.
No, wait. I`ve found it.
Ten, nine, eight ...
Let`s rock `n` roll!
Can you turn that down a little?
We`ve got a red light
on the second intake valve.
Ignore it. We`ll be fine.
Shutdown and separation
on my mark.
Three, two, one ... mark.
Let`s bring the warp core on line.
- Wow!
- You ain`t seen nothing yet.
If you see any of my crew,
give them this.
Orders to live a quite corner of America
and stay out of history`s way.
- Good luck.
- To both of us.
You`re not leaving, are you?
When I was captured, my crew
risked everything to save me.
There is someone still on this ship,
and I owe him the same.
Go and find your friend.
What`s wrong, Locutus?
lsn`t this familiar?.
Organic minds
are such fragile things.
How could you forget me so quickly?.
We were very close, you and l.
You can still hear our song.
Yes ... I remember you.
You were there all the time.
But that ship and all the Borg on it
were destroyed.
You think in such
three-dimensional terms.
How small you`ve become.
Data understands me.
- Don`t you, Data?
- What have you done to him?
Given him what he always wanted,
flesh and blood.
Let him go.
He`s not the one you want.
- Are you offering yourself to us?
- Offering myself?
That`s it! I remember now.
It wasn`t enough
that you assimilated me.
I had to give myself freely
to the Borg ... to you.
I`ve overseen the assimilation
of millions. You were no different.
You`re lying. You wanted more
than just another Borg drone.
You wanted a human being, a bridge
between humanity and the Borg.
You wanted a counterpart,
but I resisted. I fought you.
You can`t begin to imagine
the life you denied yourself.
It`s not too late.
Locutus could still be with you,
just in the way you wanted.
An equal.
Let Data go, and
I will take my place at your side, -
- willingly, without resistance.
Such a noble creature.
A quality we sometimes lack.
We will add your distinctiveness
to our own.
Welcome home, Locutus.
Data, you are free to go.
- Data, go.
- No.
- I do not wish to go.
- I have already found an equal.
Data, deactivate
the self-destruct sequence.
Data, no! Don`t do it!
Data, listen to me ...
Auto-destruct deactivated.
Now enter the encryption codes
and give me computer control.
Data!
Data ...
He will make an excellent drone.
Plasma injectors on-line. Everything
is looking good. I think we`re ready.
We must break the warp barrier in the
next five minutes to get their attention.
- Main cells are charged and ready.
- Let`s do it.
Engage.
Warp field is looking good.
Structural integrity is holding.
Speed:
20,000 kilometres per second.
Sweet Jesus!
Relax, they`re just here
to give us a send off.
I am bringing
the external sensors on-line.
30 seconds to warp threshold.
- Approaching light speed.
- We`re at critical velocity.
- Quantum torpedoes locked.
- Destroy them.
Watch your future`s end.
- Data!
- Resistance is futile.
That should be enough.
Take us out of warp.
- Is that Earth?
- That`s it.
- It`s so small.
- It`s about to get a whole lot bigger.
- Captain.
- Data, are you all right?
I would imagine
I look worse than I ... feel.
Strange ...
Part of me is sorry she is dead.
She was unique.
She brought me closer to humanity
than I ever thought possible.
And for a time,
I was tempted by her offer.
How long a time?
0.68 seconds, sir.
For an android,
that is nearly an eternity.
Captain`s log, April 5th, 2063.
The voyage ofthe Phoenix
was a success ... again.
The warp flight was detected, -
- and the alien ship is on its way
to rendezvous with history.
My God!
They`re really from another world.
And they`re going to want to meet
the man who flew that warp ship.
Live long and prosper.
Thanks.
I think it`s time
we made a discreet exit.
Stand by to beam us up.
You`ve got to go.
I envy you.
The world you`re going to.
I envy you. Taking these first steps
into a new frontier.
I shall miss you, Lily.
Picard to Enterprise, energise.
The moon obscured our presence.
The Vulcans did not detect us.
I`ve reconfigured the chronometric
readings from the Borg sphere.
- All decks report ready.
- Helm standing by.
Lay in a course for the 24th century.
Our future is waiting for us.
- Course laid in, sir.
- Make it so.