Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Yes.
Quite dead.
As a doornail.
Certificate of death, sir.
Stop!
Back away, praddock.
Tuppence is tuppence.
- Beg your pardon!
- I say!
Delinquents.
Newspaper!
We're hungry, sir!
Please, sir, we're very hungry.
Any morsel. We're hungry, sir.
- Any scraps.
- We're starving,
Please, sir. We're very hungry.
Oh! Merry Christmas,
from his lordship, the mayor!
- Please, sir.
- Oh, look. There it is.
Oi! Come back here with that!
That's our meat!
Give it back! That's ours!
Come back here!
- There you are, sir.
- Thanks.
Fresh hot chestnuts.
- How would you like this one?
- That's perfect.
That's a nice fresh eel.
Here is the Father, the Son
and the Holy Ghost. Get lost.
And under which one is the pea?
Boom, boom, boom, boom...
Boom! Get out of here.
There we are. Watch this now.
Merry Christmas, Uncle!
- God save you.
- Bah! Humbug!
Christmas a humbug?
Uncle! You don't mean that.
Merry Christmas.
What reason have you to be merry?
You're poor enough.
What right have you to be so dismal?
You're rich enough.
- Humbug!
- Don't be cross, Uncle.
What else can I be when I live
in such a world of fools as this?
Merry Christmas.
What's Christmastime to you but
a time for paying bills without money.
A time for finding yourself a year older
and not a penny richer.
If I could work my will,
every idiot who goes about
with "Merry Christmas" on his lips
should be boiled in his own pudding
and buried with a stake of holly
through his heart!
- Uncle!
- Nephew!
Keep Christmas in your own way
and let me keep it in mine.
Keep it? But you don't keep it!
Let me leave it alone then.
Much good it has ever done you.
There are many things from which I have
derived good and have not profited.
Christmas being among them.
But I have always thought of Christmas
as a kind, charitable time.
The only time when men
open their shut-up hearts
and think of all people
as fellow travellers to the grave
and not some other race of creatures
bound on other journeys.
And therefore, Uncle,
although it has never put a scrap
of gold or silver in my pocket,
I believe it has done me good,
and I say, God bless it!
Let me hear another
sound out of you, Cratchit,
and you'll keep Christmas
by losing your situation!
You're quite a powerful speaker, sir.
A wonder you don't go into Parliament.
Don't be cross, Uncle.
Come, dine with us tomorrow.
I'll see you in hell first.
But why?
Why so cold-hearted, Uncle? Why?
Why did you get married?
Because I fell in love.
Because...
...you fell...
...in love?
Good afternoon.
I want nothing from you.
I ask nothing of you.
- Why can't we be friends?
- Good afternoon.
I'm sorry, with all my heart,
to find you so resolute.
But I have made the trial
in homage to Christmas, and therefore,
- merry Christmas, Uncle!
- Good afternoon!
- And a happy New Year!
And a very merry Christmas
to you too, Mr Cratchit.
Merry Christmas to you, sir.
There's another one.
A clerk making 15 shillings a week...
...and with a wife and family,
talking about a merry Christmas.
I'll retire to Bedlam.
Ah. Good afternoon.
Scrooge and Marley's, I believe?
Ah...
Have I the pleasure of addressing
Mr Scrooge or Mr Marley?
Mr Marley has been dead
these seven years.
He died seven years ago...
this very night.
Oh...
Well, we have no doubt
that his generosity
is well represented
by his surviving partner.
At this festive season
of the year, Mr Scrooge,
it is more than usually desirable that
we should make some slight provision
for the poor and the destitute.
Many thousands are in want
of common comfort, sir.
Are there no prisons?
Prisons? Yes, yes, plenty of prisons.
And the union workhouses,
are they still in operation?
They are. I wish
I could say they were not.
The treadmill in full vigour?
- Very busy, sir.
- Good!
I was afraid something had occurred
to stop them in their useful course.
Yes. At this festive season, a few
of us are endeavouring to raise a fund
to buy the poor some meat
and drink and means of warmth.
What shall we put you down for?
- Nothing.
- Oh, you wish to remain anonymous?
I wish to be left alone!
I don't make merry myself at Christmas,
and I can't afford
to make idle people merry.
I support the establishments
I have mentioned.
And those who are badly off
must go there.
Many cannot go there.
And, well, frankly,
many would rather die.
Then they had better do it
and decrease the surplus population.
Good afternoon, gentlemen!
Good afternoon.
You'll want all day tomorrow, I suppose?
Well, if quite convenient, sir.
It's not convenient, and it's not fair.
If I were to dock you a half a crown
for it, you'd think yourself ill-used.
And yet you don't think me ill-used
when I pay a day's wages for no work.
Well, it's only once a year, sir.
Poor excuse for picking a man's pocket
every 25th of December.
But I suppose you
must have the whole day.
Be here all the earlier
the next morning.
Sir.
Whoa!
In honour of Christmas Eve!
Bugger it!
Where are you? Here!
Why does everything
seem to happen to me?
Ah!
Get away! Get away!
Ha! Balderdash!
I have given myself the willies.
That's what it is.
It's all still a hum... Ah!
Oh!
How now!
What do you want with me?
Oh, much.
- Who are you?
- Ask me who I was.
Who were you then?
In life, I was your partner,
Jacob Marley.
Can you sit down?
- I can.
- Do it then.
You do not believe in me.
I don't.
Why do you doubt your senses?
Because the littlest thing
can affect them.
A slight disorder of the stomach
can make them cheat.
You may be an undigested bit of beef.
A blot of mustard.
A crumb of cheese.
A fragment of underdone potato.
There's more of gravy than of grave
about you, whatever you are.
Mercy! Dreadful apparition,
why do you trouble me?
Man of worldly mind,
do you believe in me or not?
I do! I must!
Woe! Woe is me!
You are fettered in chains. Why?
I wear the chain I forged in life.
I made it link by link and yard by yard.
Do you recognise its pattern?
Can you imagine the weight and length
of the chain you bear?
It was as heavy and long
as this seven Christmas Eves ago.
Oh, yours is a ponderous chain.
Jacob, tell me no more.
Speak comfort to me, Jacob.
I have none to give.
I cannot stay.
I cannot linger anywhere.
Mark me, in life, my spirit never walked
beyond our countinghouse,
never roved beyond the narrow limits
of our money-changing hole.
Now endless journeys lie before me.
Seven years dead
and travelling all the time?
The whole time. No rest, no peace.
You must've covered
a lot of ground in seven years.
I was blind!
Blind! I could not see my own life!
Squandered and misused.
Oh, woe... Oh, woe is me!
But you were always
a good man of business!
Business!
Mankind... was my business.
The common welfare was my business.
Charity, mercy, forbearance,
and benevolence were all my...
Hear me! My time is nearly gone.
I will. But don't be hard upon me,
Jacob. Pray.
I am here to warn you
that you have yet a chance
at a hope of escaping my fate.
A chance of my procuring, Ebenezer.
You were always a good friend
to me, Jacob. Thank 'ee.
You will be haunted by three spirits.
That's the chance and hope?
- I'd rather not.
- Expect the first
tomorrow when the bell tolls one.
Couldn't I take them all at once,
and have it over with, Jacob?
Expect the second the next night
at the same hour.
And the third upon the next night,
when the last stroke of 12
has ceased to vibrate.
Look to see me no more.
Ah!
I'm sorry.
I wish I could help you.
Ah!
Oh!
Are you the spirit whose coming
was foretold to me?
I am.
Is it possible that
you might put your cap on?
Would you so soon put out,
with your worldly hands,
the light I give?
No, no! No, no! I'm so sorry.
I meant nothing by it.
I meant no offence.
I just thought I...
Who and what are you?
I am the Ghost of Christmas Past.
Long past?
Your past.
Rise.
And walk with me.
But I am mortal and liable to fall.
Bear but a touch of my hand there...
...and you shall be upheld
in more than this.
Whoa!
Good heavens.
I was bred in this place.
I was a boy here.
Your lip... is trembling.
And what's that?
- On your cheek?
- Nothing.
Something in my eye.
Do you remember the way?
Remember it?
I could walk it blindfolded.
Giddyup! Giddyup!
Oh! Whoa!
These are but shadows of things
that have been.
They have no consciousness... of us.
I knew them.
I know every one of them.
They were schoolmates of mine.
Let's go on.
This...
This was my school.
This school is not quite deserted.
A solitary child...
...neglected by his friends...
...is left here still.
I know.
Poor boy.
Poor, poor boy.
Let's... see another Christmas.
Ebenezer!
Dear, dear brother!
I've come to bring you home!
- Home, little Fan?
- Yes, home!
Father is so much kinder
than he used to be.
He spoke so gently to me one night.
I was not afraid to ask him
if you might come home.
And he said yes!
And he sent me in a coach to fetch you.
And we're to be together
all the Christmas long.
And to have the merriest time
in all the world!
You're quite a woman, little Fan.
- She had a large heart.
- She died a woman.
And had, as I think...
...children.
Yes, one child.
True.
- Your nephew.
- Yes.
Do you know this place?
Know it? I was an apprentice here!
Why, it's old Fezziwig.
Bless his heart!
It's Fezziwig alive again!
Yo-ho! Ebenezer, come on!
Come on! Dick! Come on! It's 6:00.
They're going to be here soon.
Dick Wilkins. Bless me, yes.
There he is, Dick Wilkins.
He was very attached to me, was Dick.
Yo-ho, me lads! No more work tonight.
It's Christmas Eve!
Hooray!
Dick, Ebenezer,
let's get cleared away.
We want lots of space.
Lots and lots of space.
Hee-hi!
Whoa!
Maestro!
May I present...?!
Whoo!
Well done! Well done!
And now, kind fiddler, if you please.
It is time for Sir Roger de Coverley!
Hey!
Might I have this dance with you?
Whoo!
Ebenezer, it's your pass.
Another idol has replaced me.
Another idol?
What idol?
A golden one.
There is nothing on this earth
more terrifying to me
than a life doomed to poverty.
May I ask, why do you condemn,
with such severity,
the honest pursuit of substance?
You fear the world too much, Ebenezer.
- You've changed.
- Changed?
Perhaps grown wiser,
but I have not changed toward you.
Our contract is an old one.
It was made when we were
both poor and content to be so.
When it was made...
- You were another man.
- I was a boy!
I release you, Ebenezer.
Have I ever sought release?
- In words, no.
- In what, then?
In an altered spirit.
In another atmosphere of life.
In everything that made my love
of any worth in your sight.
Tell me, Ebenezer, if this contract
had never been between us,
would you seek me out now?
No.
You think not?
I would gladly think otherwise
if I could.
But if you were free today,
would you choose a dowerless girl?
A girl left penniless
by the death of her parents?
You, who weighs everything by gain?
I release you, Ebenezer.
May you be happy in the life
you've chosen.
Spirit, remove me from this place.
I told you, these were shadows
of things that have been.
They are what they are.
Do not blame me.
Remove me. I cannot bear it.
Leave me! Take me back!
Haunt me no longer!
Ah! Oh!
Ah! Ah!
Oh, blast!
Enter, Scrooge!
Come in! Come in
and know me better, man!
I am the Ghost of Christmas Present.
Look upon me!
You have never seen
the likes of me before?
Never.
Have never walked forth
with my elder brothers?
I don't think that I have.
You have many brothers?
More than 1,800.
1,842, to be exact.
Oh.
I see you wear a scabbard, but no sword.
Indeed.
Peace on Earth. Goodwill toward men.
Spirit, conduct me where you will.
Oh...
Touch my robe.
Oh! What's happening?
What are you doing?
Ah!
Oh!
Very strange.
Indeed. Not many mortals are granted
- a heavenly perspective of man's world.
- Yes.
It's quite beautiful.
Spirit, these poor people
have no means to cook their food.
And yet you seek
to close the only places
in which they can warm
their meagre meals every seventh day.
Oh!
Hear me, Scrooge.
There are some upon this earth of yours
who claim to know me and my brothers,
and do their deeds of ill will
and selfishness in our name.
These so-called "men of the cloth"
are as strange to me and my kin
as if they never lived.
Charge their doings to them, not us.
Aye. I will.
Smell that?
Cooking goose!
Come on!
I take it this bleak paupers'
dwelling is of some significance.
It is all your loyal clerk can afford
for his meagre 15 bob a week.
- Mother!
- Papa!
We just came by the baker shop.
And smelled our goose,
cooking delicious.
Shut the door, please. What
happened to your precious father?
And your brother. And Martha,
she wasn't as late last Christmas Day.
Mother, here she is, Mother.
Here's Martha.
Martha! Wait till you see
our goose. 'Tis a wonderful one.
Peter, off with you
to the baker's and collect the bird.
And take the children with you.
And pray, no dallying.
Why, bless your heart alive!
Dear, how late you are!
We had a deal of work to finish up last
night and clear away this morning.
Never mind. Long as you're here. Sit ye
down before the fire and have a warm.
No. No, no, no. There's Father coming.
Hide, Martha.
You must hide. Hide, Martha.
- It's cold out there.
- Hello, Father. Hello, Timmy.
- Why, where's our Martha?
- Uh... Not coming.
Not coming?
Not coming upon Christmas Day?
Here I am, Father!
We got you, Father.
I couldn't bear to see you in a state
of disappointment. If only for a giggle.
It's so lovely to see you, my Martha.
Come on, Timmy. I hear
the pudding singing in the copper.
Shall we have a look, then?
- How did little Timmy behave?
- As good as gold. And better.
Somehow he gets thoughtful
sitting by himself so much,
and he thinks the strangest things
you ever heard.
He told me, coming home, that he hoped
the people sawed him in church,
because he was a cripple...
...and it might make pleasant for them
to remember it upon Christmas Day
who made lame beggars walk
and blind men see.
I believe he grows more hearty
and stronger every day, my dear.
The pudding looks delicious!
The whole wash house smells
like a pastry cook's shop.
Spirit, tell me, will Tiny Tim...?
I see a vacant seat
in the poor chimney corner...
...and a crutch without an owner.
Carefully preserved.
- Hurrah!
- The Christmas goose!
Make space.
Let's get that cover off.
- Oh!
- Lovely! Well done, Peter.
I don't believe I've ever seen
a more magnificent goose cooked.
It is a beautiful bird, that's for sure.
But I'll pray that
one Christmas, perhaps,
the children might taste a turkey.
Perhaps one day, my dear.
Perhaps one day.
A toast.
To Mr Scrooge.
- The founder of our feast.
- Ha!
Founder of the feast, indeed.
I wish I had him here.
I'd give him a piece of
my mind to feast upon,
and I'd hope he'd have
a good appetite for it.
My dear, the children...
It's Christmas Day.
Christmas Day, I'm sure.
How can one drink the health
of such an odious, stingy, hard,
unfeeling man as Mr Scrooge?
As you know he is, Robert.
Nobody knows it better than you.
My dear, Christmas Day.
I'll drink his health for your sake
and the day's, not for his.
A merry Christmas
and a happy New Year.
He'll be very merry and very happy,
I have no doubt.
A merry Christmas to us all,
my dears. God bless us.
God bless us.
God bless us, everyone.
- Merry Christmas and happy New Year.
- God bless.
Kind spirit,
say Tiny Tim will be spared.
If these shadows remain unaltered
by the future... the child will die.
Die! No, spirit. No.
What then?
If he is to die, he had better do it.
And decrease
the surplus population.
- So you're thinking of an animal?
- Yes.
- A live animal?
- A rather disagreeable animal?
- Yes.
- A savage animal?
Wait, wait! Is it an animal
that grunts and growls?
Yes!
- And lives in London?
- Yes.
- A horse?
- No.
- A cow?
- A dog?
- A pig?
- No.
- An ass?
- Yes and no.
- Oh!
I know who it is, Fred!
I know! It's your Uncle Scrooge!
Yes!
Christmas a humbug?
Now, he actually said that?
As I live. And he believes it.
I have no patience
with him, Fred.
I have. I'm sorry for him.
Who suffers from his ill whims?
Only himself.
He decides to dislike us,
won't come and dine with us,
and what's the consequence?
He loses a dinner.
- Indeed, he loses a very good dinner.
- Hear, hear.
- A magnificent dinner.
- Great.
He's certainly given us
plenty of merriment, that's for sure,
and I think it would be ungrateful
not to drink to his health.
He wouldn't take it from me,
but he may have it nevertheless.
A merry Christmas to the old man,
whatever he is. Uncle Scrooge.
To Uncle Scrooge.
Are spirits' lives so short?
My life upon this globe is very brief.
It ends tonight.
- Tonight?
- Tonight at midnight.
Hark.
The time is drawing near.
Forgive me... but I see something
strange protruding from your skirt.
Is it a foot or a claw?
It might be a claw, for the scant amount
of flesh there is upon it.
- Look here.
- Naff off!
Oh, man. Look here.
You daft old geezer.
Look! Look!
Down here!
- Go away!
- Are they yours?
They are man's.
This boy is Ignorance.
This girl is Want.
Beware them both.
Oh!
Ah!
Have they no refuge? No resource?
Are there no prisons?
Are there no workhouses?
Am I in the presence of
the Ghost of Christmas Yet to Come?
You're about to show me shadows
of the things that have not happened
but will happen. Is that so, spirit?
Ghost of the Future, I fear you
more than any spectre I have seen.
But I know your purpose
is to do me good.
I am prepared to bear you company.
Lead on.
The night is waning fast.
It's precious time to me.
Lead on, spirit.
- When did he die?
- Last night, I believe.
- Or sometime Christmas Day.
- I thought he'd never die.
- What's he done with his money?
- Hasn't left it to me.
That's all I know.
It is likely to be a cheap funeral.
For the life of me, I can't think
of anyone who'd want to attend it.
I don't mind going...
if lunch is provided.
There, yes.
What a frightful fellow.
- All right.
- Good day, gentlemen.
Get ahold of yourself, Ebenezer.
You're having a wobbly.
Whoo!
Oh! Oh!
You won't get me in here.
Christmas pudding, no doubt.
I'm... I'm on Lime Street.
Oh, come now.
Oh!
Ah!
Whoa!
Merry Christmas, Joe.
And happy New Year,
to be sure. Come in.
Sit down in me parlour
and let's have a look.
Here.
Whoa!
What do you call these,
Mrs Dilber, huh?
Mrs Dilber?
Bed curtains.
You mean to say you took them down
while he was lying there?
I do.
And why not?
You was born to make your fortune,
and you certainly will do it.
Well,
I shan't hold back my hand
when I can get something by it...
Don't you go getting grease
on them blankets now.
- His blankets?
- Whose else do you think?
He won't be feeling the cold
without them now, I dare say.
I hope he didn't die
of anything catching.
Don't you
be afeard of that.
I ain't so fond of his company
that I'd loiter about.
You can look through that shirt
till your eyes ache,
and you won't find one hole in it.
- It was the best he had.
- Mrs Dilber!
Would have been wasted,
only for me.
- You're fired! Fired!
- How did you mean "wasted"?
Somebody was fool enough
to put it on him to be buried in.
But I took it off him.
This is the end of it, you see.
He frightened everyone away
while he was alive.
Only to profit us now that he's dead.
If he'd had somebody to look after him
when he was struck with death,
instead of lying there, all alone,
gasping out his last breath...
...well, we wouldn't have
these things to sell now, would we?
Hey!
Whoa!
Spirit! I see! I see!
The case of this unhappy
man who dies a solitary, lonesome death
might be my own.
My life
tends that way now.
Merciful heavens! What's this?
Spirit, this is a fearful place.
When I leave it, I shall not leave
its lesson. Trust me. Let's go!
I understand. And I would, if I could,
but I have not the power.
Spirit, if there is any person who feels
emotion caused by this man's death,
show that person to me, I beg you.
- Are we ruined?
- There is hope yet.
Hope? Only if he relents.
He is past relenting.
He is dead.
Dead?
To whom will our debts be transferred?
I don't know, but by then
we'll have the money.
And even if we don't, it's unlikely any
new creditor will ever be so merciless.
We shall sleep tonight
with light hearts, my dear.
Let me see some tenderness
connected to death,
or this chamber will forever haunt me!
It's late.
Past your father's time.
He's walked slow
these last few evenings.
Oh, he has walked...
...with Tiny Tim on his shoulders...
fast, indeed.
But he was very light...
...to carry, and...
...your father loved him so.
- Father.
- You went today, then?
Yes, my dear.
I wish you could have gone.
Would have done you good
to see how green a place it is.
You'll see it often.
And I promised him I would walk there
every...  every Sunday.
My little child!
My little child.
Father, please don't be grieved.
Please, Father.
I'm all right, love.
I'm quite at peace.
I'm sure none of us will
ever forget our poor Tiny Tim.
- Oh, no, Father.
- Never ever.
Thank you.
Thank you, my dears.
Bob.
Spectre... something tells me
our parting moment is at hand.
Tell me...
...who... was that man
we saw lying dead?
Spirit...
...before I draw nearer
to that stone to which you point,
answer me one question!
Are these the shadows
of things that will be
or shadows of things that may be?
Men's courses in life
foreshadow certain ends.
But if these courses are departed from,
these ends will change. Isn't that so?
No. No!
Am I that man who lay upon the bed?
No. Spirit, hear me!
I'm not the man I was!
Why show me this if I'm past all hope?
Spirit!
Spirit, assure me that I may change
these shadows you've shown me!
Change them by an altered life!
No, spirit! No! No, spirit!
Good spirit... help me!
Spirit!
Help me, spirit!
Ah!
Help, spirit!
Spirit, I will honour Christmas in my
heart and try to keep it all the year.
I will not shut out the lessons
of the past, nor present, nor future.
Oh, please, spirit,
tell me I may sponge away
the writing on that stone!
Still here?
They're still here.
I'm still here.
I'm still here!
I don't know what to do.
I'm light as a feather,
merry as a schoolboy.
I've heard that laugh before.
Ah!
- I say, what's today?
- Eh?
- What's today, my fine fellow?
- Today? Why, Christmas Day.
It's Christmas Day?
I haven't missed it.
The spirits have
done it all in one night.
They can do anything they like.
Of course they can. Of course they can.
Hello, my fine fellow. Do you know
the poulterer's on the corner?
- I should hope I did.
- What an intelligent boy.
Do you know whether they've sold
the prize turkey that was hanging there?
Not the little prize turkey,
the big one.
- The one as big as me?
- What a delightful child.
- Yes, my buck.
- It's hanging there now.
Is it? Go and buy it, then!
- Walker!
- No, no, I'm in earnest.
Go and buy it, bring it back here,
and I'll give you a shilling.
Come back in less than five minutes,
and I'll give you a half a crown.
I'll send it to Bob Cratchit's.
He shan't know who sent it.
It's twice the size of Tiny Tim.
Mrs Dilber.
Merry Christmas!
Oh, my God!
He's gone mad!
Yay!
My dear Mrs Dilber,
you're the loveliest creature
I have ever laid eyes upon.
Dance with me, Mrs Dilber.
Dance with me!
- You're barmy, Mr Scrooge!
- Unhand me!
He's completely deranged! Help!
- What a charming woman.
- Help!
I shall love it as long as I live.
What an honest face it has.
Ooh!
Hello. Here's the bird.
Hello! Whoop!
How are you? Merry Christmas.
Why, it's impossible to carry that
to Camden Town. You must have a cab.
Drive on, my good man!
Hilly-ho! Chirrup!
Yahoo!
Hip, hip! Chirry-up!
Bob's your uncle!
Fanny's your aunt!
Here's your aunt's fanny.
Live it up, folks!
You'll be a long time dead!
Don't let the worms have all the fun.
Merry Christmas.
Good morning, sir.
A merry Christmas to you.
- And to you, sir.
- Happy holiday!
And a merry Christmas to you.
- "God bless you, sir."
- Thank you, sir.
Glad tidings.
Sir.
My dear sir, how do you do?
I hope you succeeded yesterday.
A merry Christmas to you, sir.
Mr Scrooge?
Yes. That is my name, and I fear
it may not be pleasant to you.
But allow me to ask your pardon.
And will you have the goodness...
Lord bless me!
- My dear Mr Scrooge, are you serious?
- And not a farthing less.
A great many back payments
are included in it, I assure you.
My dear sir, I don't know
what to say to such...
Do not say anything.
I'm much obliged to you.
Many thanks to you. And bless you.
- Is your master at home?
- Yes, sir.
I'm... his uncle.
Is it an animal
that grunts and growls?
Yes.
- And lives in London?
- Yes.
- A horse?
- No.
- A cow?
A dog.
- A pig.
- No.
An ass.
Yes and no.
- I know what it is, Fred! I know!
- What?
It's your...
Uncle Scrooge?
Well, bless my soul.
I've... come to dinner...
...if you'll have me.
Of course, Uncle! Welcome! Welcome!
Merry Christmas!
Everybody, this is my uncle, Ebenezer.
Be good and pass this.
Here you go. Enjoy.
Next year we must have
this dinner at my house.
I insist.
I'll spare no expense. After all,
you can't take it with you, can you?
No, you can't.
A full 16 minutes late.
What do you mean by
coming here at this time of day?
I'm very sorry, sir.
I am a bit behind in my time.
You are, indeed.
Step in here.
Well, it's only once a year, sir.
It shall not be repeated.
I was making rather merry yesterday.
Now, I'll tell you what, Mr Cratchit.
I'm not going to stand
for this sort of thing any longer.
And therefore...
...I am about to raise your salary!
A merry Christmas to you, Bob.
A merrier Christmas, Bob,
my good fellow,
than I've given you in many a year.
I'll raise your salary, and do whatever
I can to help your struggling family.
And we'll discuss your affairs
this very afternoon
over a bowl of Christmas punch.
But first, let's make up the fires.
I want you to go out...
...and buy another scuttle of coal
before you dot another "I,"
Bob Cratchit.
Off with you, Bob.
We've wassailing to do.
Hilly-ho, Bob!
Yeah. Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
And Scrooge was better than his word.
He did all that he said he would
and more.
And to our Tiny Tim, who got well,
Scrooge was like a second father.
He became as good a friend,
as good a master
and as good a man
as the good old city ever knew.
And it was always said of him
that he knew how to keep Christmas well.
And so, as Tiny Tim observed...
God bless us, everyone.