- What does he want?
- I'll find out.
You don't have to take orders
from this man, you know.
Well, I'm the liaison officer.
So I'm liaising.
You're sure you know what
you're doing, old man?
Yes, and what ever this is,
it's important to him...
that I see it.
- I'll keep an eye on them, sir.
- Very good.
Bastards!
MERRY CHRISTMAS
MR. LAWRENCE
A disgraceful incident has occurred.
I will deal with it myself.
If it's a secret, why show me?
I want you to witness it.
- Know what he did?
- This Dutch soldier?
Not him, he was in a cell
for stealing bananas.
- The Korean guard?
- Of course.
Kanemoto, tell this British
officer what you did.
Kanemoto, come on!
Say it!
Say it! You, Kanemoto!
Why don't you?
Are you too ashamed?
You know now Lawrence?
Last night he stole into the
cell of that Dutch boy.
Kanemoto, show us how you used
this thing of yours.
Show us how you used it on this
white fellow's ass.
Just do it for us now!
Untie him.
Kanemoto! Do it! Hear me? Now!
Has your dainty thing become
too shrunken to be potent?
If you can bugger him again
you may comit Harakiri.
Have you gone mad?
You haven't seen a Japanese
until you've seen Harakiri.
I don't want to watch it!
Do you want me to hate the Japanese?
I'll do it!
Stop it! For God's sake,
stop it!
Lawrence, out of the way!
Haven't you shamed him enough?
Shame? He didn't even resist
being raped!
Can you get up?
You're Dutch, aren't you?
De Jong, sir. Karel De Jong.
Now you'd better
sit down.
Now tell me
what happened.
In the beginning he came in to
dress this wound of mine.
For three days, every night.
He was, he was very kind.
But then last night, he suddenly...
Captain Yonoi! This is
Colonel Lawrence! Come quickly!
Kanemoto, I'll assist you.
Stop it!
Watch this!
Sergeant Hara...
Attention!
What's going on?
Sergeant Hara is going
to execute this man!
- This is not your concern.
- Then why bring me here?
- Who ordered this execution?
- This is not an execution.
Kanemoto is trying to comit
suicide for his crime.
And you ignore it?
Out of compassion.
His family is poor. If we deem
his death an accident...
they will get a pension.
What crime has he committed?
Let me report in private.
I've no time now. I'm due at a
military trial in Batavia.
Make your report later.
This way, sir.
- Captain Yonoi is here, sir.
- Let him in.
I'm Captain Yonoi.
I'm here for the trial.
We are very honoured to have
Captain Yonoi here today.
This is Colonel Fujimura,
President of the court.
- Pleased to serve with you.
- Good to have you here.
My name is Iwata.
The military situation here
is very serious.
Your service is important.
Gentlemen, the defendant is
a very difficult man.
All rise to attention!
Before the court is the
case of Jack Celliers.
Your name is given
as Jack Celliers.
Is that correct?
- Why shouldn't it be?
- What do you mean by that?
Answer the question!
Is your name Jack Celliers?
I've answered that question
about a hundred times.
Read the charges.
The prisoner, Jack Celliers,
a Major in the British army...
parachuted with four men into...
the Banten Valley.
They waged guerilla warfare.
On October 16, they attacked a
Japanese transport unit.
They took ammunition, killed
PFC Takeshi Tazaki, then...
they wounded Corp. Sawafuji
and four others.
His crime is covered by
martial law regulations.
We recommend a death penalty...
as prescribed in section 1
Accordingly, he should receive
the death penalty...
as prescribed in Section 1,
chapter 5 of the regulations.
How do you plead?
Not guilty. I'm not a criminal.
I am a soldier in
His Majesty's army.
One month ago I came out of the
Djaja Sempoer mountains.
I surrendered to Colonel Utsumi
of the Imperial Japanese Army.
I was imprisioned at Sukabumi.
3 days in solitary confinement.
Then I was questioned
by Lieutenant Ito.
He asked me my name and
rank and I told him.
Then Lieutenant Ito asked me:
"Is that true?"
I replied: "of course, it is.
I'm with the British army. "
Do you mean you would never
give a false name?
Let me ask you something.
Why would a man who's about to
die give a false name?
A Japanese soldier who's caught
would give a false name.
But then, a Japanese soldier would
never submit to being caught.
- He would prefer to die.
- But then, I'm not a Japanese.
Why did you refuse to tell
about yourself?
You must tell us your
past history.
My past is my business.
What was the reason for
giving yourself up?
You've just read it,
haven't you?
Your men said they'd kill the villagers
if I didn't give myself up.
- How many men did you have?
- None.
- Liar!
- I'm not a liar.
I had four men but they
were killed in action.
We know you led a group
of native soldiers.
We are bound to find them
sooner or later.
Why don't you confess your crime?
I've never led natives.
Look, why don't I have a defense counsel?
Exactly what kind of trial
are you giving me?
This whole thing's a bloody farce.
Erase all those remarks.
May I question him?
"To be or not to be.
"That is the question,
The prosecutor said that you
landed in Java by parachute.
Under whose orders?
Under the orders of the
Supreme Commander of...
His Majesty's forces in India.
Were you not under the
commander of Java?
You know I came to Java in August.
You know the commander in
Java was captured in March.
- You know Captain...
- Captain Yonoi.
If this man fought in India
as a legitimate soldier.
Then we must treat him as
a prisioner of war.
- We have no proof.
- I believe this man.
What were you asked when captured?
Were you asked how you were
intended to conduct a...
guerilla war with only five men?
Well, I suspect they thought we
were an advance party...
for a new campaign presumably
the invasion of Java!
They wanted to know dates
and places.
What did you say?
I said I thought they
were crackers.
What?
- I thought they were mad.
- And then?
Then they stopped feeding me,
and started beating me.
Can you prove that you
were beaten?
Put on your shirt!
No more questions!
The court retires.
A delay this long usually means
a firing squad.
But nowadays new officers like
to try out their swords...
on white necks.
The verdict in your case
has been postponed.
We shall wait for
further instructions.
Stand up.
Good day for it, sir.
Yes.
You have a family waiting
for you, Corporal?
Wife and two kids, sir.
One with, one without.
How's about yourself, sir?
- Tea?
- Yes, I'd like that.
The prisoner, sir!
Can you guess
what I'm thinking?
Yes, I think so. Can you?
He's rebellious to the end.
You have been found
guilty on all charges.
The sentence will be carried
out without delay.
Make him ready!
- I don't need any help.
- Leave him alone!
I've practiced walking for years.
Firing position!
I don't need that.
The blind fold is for
the firing squad!
So they don't look into
your eyes as you die.
Let him be.
Prepare to fire!
Firing positions!
Fire!
That's a good one!
Sergeant Hara...
Lawrence, can't you let me sleep?
I'm sorry.
I was just now riding on top of
Marlene Dietrich's tummy.
In a hideway in Manchuria!
I must talk to you.
Why's he here?
I want you to protect him.
Why?
My men heard about him.
- I told you not to talk!
- I didn't.
There were Japanese soldiers
and Korean guards there.
You accuse Japanese...?
It was probably the guards.
Don't you realize that everyone
is going to know?
I understood.
Will all your men want to
bugger him now?
Is it true that English men
are all homosexuals?
Don't be stupid.
Listen, I need your help.
A Japanese never asks help
from an enemy.
Hey, are you a homosexual?
He says you are a homosexual.
Are you?
No sir. I am not.
He's not.
You all fear homosexuality!
A samurai doesn't fear it.
Wars create friendships
amongst men.
That hardly means that all
soldiers become homosexual.
You are not soldiers,
you are prisoners!
So you lack discipline,
and you beg favours.
- Shame!
- Sergeant Hara...
I've nothing to be ashamed of.
A new prisioner has arrived.
Another queer's here!
I've brought a prisoner from
the military prison in Batavia.
I'm Sergeant Gengo Hara.
I'll take over.
Your name and rank?
Celliers, Jack. Major,
British Army.
Celliers? Jack Celliers?
Straffer Jack?
Good morning, Colonel.
You bastard!
Stop it!
No! Stop it! Stop it!
You! Officer! Do you
know this man?
We served together in Libya.
We fought the Germans.
Take him to the sick bay.
What kind of a man is he?
Is he a close friend of yours?
No. He's not a close friend, no.
- What kind of a soldier is he?
- He's a fine soldier.
We had a nickname for him
in the 8th Army.
We called him straffer Jack.
Straffer is a kind of um...
it's very difficult to translate.
Straffer is um...
This is astonishingly
difficult sometimes.
In any case,
he was a soldier's soldier.
Why are you so
interested in him?
- What did the doctor say?
- I didn't talk to the doctor.
You fool!
Lawrence, I want him in good
health as quickly as possible.
That's an order!
You don't have to order me
to look after a sick man.
I will send the Japanese
medic to see him.
Why are you so concerned
about Major Celliers?
Send our medic.
- The commanding officer, sir.
- Let him in.
You spend more time with these
Japs than you do with...
your own men.
I called Colonel Lawrence here.
Now from you...
I want the names of all
prisoners who are informed...
on the subject of armaments
and ammunition.
Who are the experts here?
I am not required under
International Law...
to furnish the enemy with
any information.
This is not North Africa.
We are not Germans!
There is no Geneva Convention here.
If you do not follow my orders,
I will have to replace you.
Replace me?
What are you talking about?
Replace me with whom?
Do you know what
he's talking about?
No sir. I don't know.
You promised to improve
our food ration.
You eat the same as we eat.
Give me the names of your experts.
No, Captain Yonoi.
I will not.
Captain Yonoi.
Please try to understand.
Group Captain Hicksley
is an honourable man.
"They are all, all honourable men. "
As commanding officer, I prefer
another honourable man.
Lawrence, this armaments thing.
I think we can string it out
for quite sometime, don't you?
I mean, young Tojo will never
notice the difference.
They're not fools, you know,
sir, the Japanese.
They know how badly the war's
going for them.
A couple months, it could
all be over.
Then why not try and stay alive
for a couple of months?
Sir, I know these people...
I wish you'd be guided
by my knowledge.
I know these people, too.
They're the enemy.
And you're a British soldier.
You know they once
beat the Russians.
Really?
What school did you go to?
Winchester.
Who's looking after Major Celliers?
- I am, sir.
- How's he coming along?
He's a tough man.
Anyone else would have been dead.
When will he be up and
about, do you think?
Christ, I had to give him
a sedative, so he'll sleep...
most of the time. I'd say a
couple of weeks.
- Good. Where's the big chief?
- I'll get him for you.
All right, you malingerers.
Now hear this!
Colonel Lawrence is going to
stay here for a few nights.
- He's one of those, mate!
- Want my boxing gloves?
- Where is he?
- Sleeping.
Take me.
Why was he captured?
He wasn't.
He surrendered.
Why does Capt. Yonoi want to
make him commanding officer?
- I don't know.
- Answer me Lawrence...
Because he's a born leader.
Why are you still alive?
I'd admire you more if
you killed yourself.
A good officer like you!
How can you stand the shame?
We don't call it shame.
Being a prisoner is one of
the fortunes of war.
We surely aren't happy
being prisoners.
We want to escape.
We want to fight you.
That's just quibbling.
No! We want to win.
This camp isn't the end.
We won't kill ourselves.
That's the coward's way out.
You're just scared of dying!
Don't wake the patients.
When I was 12, I visited
the shrine in my village.
I offered my life to the Emperor.
I have already died for my country.
Yes. But you're not dead are you?
It's all right, Jack.
It's Lawrence.
It's all right. You're fine.
It's all right.
Sergeant Hara isn't
going to hurt you.
going to hurt anyone.
What on earth possessed Yonoi
to save me do you think? - I don't know.
What did he say, Lawrence?
What a funny face!
Beautiful eyes, though.
Make him well.
Cure him quickly.
All right?
What's that bloody noise!
What's the matter with them?
They're trying to become
super human gods.
They live in the past,
these fellows.
God help them, Lawrence.
And that's our Captain Yonoi's
voice, isn't it?
He's been screaming
his head off...
ever since you got here.
If he's got something
on his mind...
why doesn't he come out with it?
I rather think he is.
Perhaps we're both
on the same ladder.
Are you okay?
It was a nightmare.
Ueki is worried about these
training sessions...
that they are too violent.
Sir, your shouts make
the prisoners uneasy.
Lawrence has come to me.
- Lawrence is here?
- Outside.
Is it true that our shouts
disturb the prisoners?
Yes, yes, sir. It is.
And you? Do you feel uneasy?
Well, I find the noise irritating,
but it doesn't make me uneasy.
However, some of the sick men...
- That sick officer, too?
- Major Celliers? Yes.
I do not want the prisoners
to become upset.
Thank you, Captain Yonoi.
How wonderful it
would have been...
if we could have
invited all of you...
to a gathering under
our cherry trees.
Yes.
My fondest memory of
Japan is the snow.
The trees covered with snow.
- It was snowing on that day.
- What day?
Don't you know?
February 26, 1936.
Yes... yes.
I was in Tokyo that day.
You too?
No. I had been sent off to
Manchuria 3 months before.
I was not there
for the uprising.
You regret that?
My comrades were executed.
I was left to die after them.
I see. So you were one of the
shining young officers...
And bring that
sick officer Lawrence.
Attention.
Salute.
Eyes right.
Lawrence, where is
that sick officer?
- The doctor stopped him.
- You stopped him, Lawrence.
He is very weak.
Where is the victim?
Let him step forward.
We're here on your orders.
We're under no obligation to
watch this execution.
If you had any humanity left in
you, sir, you would let us leave.
Any of you who can't watch it...
keep your eyes shut or turn round!
But I will no permit you
to leave this site!
Allied officers do not turn
their back on the enemy.
Ready...
Raise your head.
Oh, my God, he's bitten his
tongue off, for Christ's sake.
Roll him over.
Christ. He's swallowed a part
of his tongue.
- Pay your respects.
- Come on, lads.
- Not yet.
- We want to pay our respects!
- You Jap lover!
- Stop them.
You have no respect for anything!
Not even your own men!
You're wrong, Captain Yonoi!
By God, you're wrong.
You are to say nothing
about today's execution...
or this soldier's death
until it is announced.
If you're so bloody right,
you've got nothing to hide!
We must wait for the
official announcement.
This is the right way.
I am right.
Colonel Lawrence,
am I not right?
No. No, Captain Yonoi.
You're wrong.
We're all wrong.
I order all prisoners,
each and everyone of you...
not to go out to the fields
today or tomorrow.
Instead, you shall stay inside
your barracks for 48 hours...
and undergo "gyo".
You'll observe gyo for 48 hours.
There will be no eating
or drinking. Is this clear?
What the hell's gyo?
It's a Japanese cure for laziness.
Laziness, Jesus Christ!
Why don't you listen?
He means spiritual laziness.
And he believes...
that if he takes away the food
and the water, then he also...
takes away the nourishment
for the laziness!
You don't believe that bullshit,
do you?
I don't flaping know!
Sir, I will tell you something
that may surprise you.
If we do it, he'll do it!
- Peasant!
- Here.
- Mills!
- Ibbertson
- I'm hungry.
- Adams.
- Eggs and bacon, mate.
- Baxter!
- Steak and kidney-pie.
Put up with it for another
13 or 14 hours. You can do it!
How about giving us a wee whisky?
What about a double whisky?
De Jong!
Next! Who's next?
He's dead.
He's not dead!
He'll be back in a few days!
De Jong has been killed!
Thank you.
Next.
- Craig!
- Here.
- Smith!
- Yes.
Celliers!
- Where is Major Celliers?
- He said he'd be back soon.
One man is missing.
Major Celliers.
Look, he'll be here in a moment.
Just mark us all here.
I can't do that. I'll have to
report him missing.
No, please.
Just a few minutes!
Celliers?
That's right.
What are those flowers for?
Food.
Food?
I wish they were white, but these
were all that I could find.
In memory of De Jong.
It might be nice if you were to
say something, Lawrence.
Our father who art in Heaven,
Hallowed by thy name
Thy Kingdom come,
Thy will be done
Give us this day our daily bread
And forgive us our trespasses,
As we forgive them that...
- Give me another.
- And lead us not into temp...
What are you doing?
We must observe the gyo.
What the hell are you doing, Major?
I gave Major Celliers
permission, sir.
Ah, changed our tune, have we?
What happened to the gyo?
- What are all these flowers for?
- In memory of De Jong, sir.
He didn't give me permission, sir.
And it was my idea.
Really?
Lawrence, over here.
You knew of Yonoi's plan to
replace me as commander?
Yes, sir, I did.
May I ask why you
didn't tell me?
It's still only a rumor, sir.
You don't like me, do you?
Captain Yonoi doesn't like you.
I don't know what to
make of you, Lawrence.
You've either very clever, or
you're bloody stupid.
But I tell you one thing.
I will never give Yonoi any
information about officers...
or armaments.
You understand that?
And I will never resign as
commander of this camp.
You can tell that to Yonoi.
Never!
Bloody hell!
It's an inspection!
Don't waste the food.
Keep eating it.
I'll take the responsibility.
And keep singing.
Rock of Ages,
cleft for me
Let me hide
Myself in Thee
Let the water
And the Blood
Come on now...
From Thy riven side which
Flow'd Be of sin the
For God's sake get those bloody
flowers off De Jong's bed!
No, leave those on.
I will inspect all of you to see.
You scum!
You aren't eating?
If you've got anything
hidden away in here...
You all have "Manju" cakes!
Talk! Damn it!
Who brought them in here?
Flowers!
Are you crazy?
Well I've tried the "Manju".
And I've tried the flowers.
And I think the flowers
taste better.
Stop resisting!
Stop it.
Shut up.
What was that singing?
They're practicing for christmas.
It's for a funeral!
Who do you think you are?
Are you an evil spirit?
Yes, and one of yours I hope.
To the cell!
He's not an evil spirit.
He's a human being!
Get rid of your superstitions!
We found this radio!
You stayed here, so I'm sure we
can count on you to tell us.
My God!
- Who's there?
- The key!
I can't give it to you.
- It's Captain's orders.
- Isn't he coming?
- Does he come here?
- Every night.
Give me the key.
Take this!
Lawrence, we're going walkies.
Listen, we're getting out
of here! On my shoulder.
Jack, look, we can't...
The tube line doesn't
come this far.
Everything's all right. Yonoi
gave me a Persian rug.
It's all right for you.
I can't get my legs to work.
Do you mind if I take the guard?
He's a lot lighter.
This is quite ridiculous.
I presume you've come
for your carpet.
Why don't you fight me? If you
defeat me, you will be free.
I'll kill him.
I think he's taken a bit of
a shine to you.
To the cells!
Please forgive me, Captain.
I want to apologize for my
behaviour with death.
- Are you able?
- Yes.
Why try to kill him?
That man is a devil! He will
destroy your spirit!
How very straight you sit!
I'm very impressed with you!
I'd sit even straighter if my
legs hadn't been wrecked.
My batman. He committed
harakiri last night.
The government doesn't pay a
death benefit in cases...
of suicide.
Sergeant Hara has advised me
to treat the death...
as a death in action.
This is my batman's
funeral ceremony.
How very thoughtful of
Sergeant Hara.
In your case, Sergeant Hara's
thoughtfulness means that...
your wife will receive a pension
from British Army.
You awful bastard!
Sit up!
This morning I put my seal on
Hara's recommendation.
It has gone to Batavia. We'll
get their answer quite soon.
It's only a formality.
Once the papers arrive, we can
put you to death.
Well that should please
Sergeant Hara.
You brought the radio
into the camp.
You know that is not true.
Not true?
If you didn't do it, who did?
We must punish someone.
But why?
Would you rather punish
the wrong man...
than see the crime itself got
unsolved and unpunished?
Yes.
You mean I'm to die because
you think if there's a crime...
then it must be punished?
And it doesn't matter
who is punished?
You're not by any chance a
Gilbert & Sullivan fan are you?
What?
You're not very funny really.
I see.
So I'm to die to preserve
your sense of order.
Yes. You understand, Lawrence.
You must die for me.
I understand.
But I won't die for you!
Should I have lied about the
radio, Sergeant Hara?
Should I have said I
brought it into the Camp?
Sergeant Hara!
Stop it!
It's your gods.
It's your bloody awful
stinking gods.
They made you what you are.
May they rot in whatever filthy
hell they came from!
Damn them!
Damn your flaping gods!
To the cells!
Wait!
What will happen to
Major Celliers?
That is none of your business.
Oh, you wouldn't execute
Major Celliers...
for a crime like bringing a
wireless into a ward.
Your friend was a
disappointment to me.
Do you want to see him
before you die?
What happened in there?
Wait a minute.
Something's changed.
I read it all wrong.
Do you think you've had it?
What? What?
Bloody radio!
Yonoi said something strange.
He said: "I'm disappointed
in your friend. "
What is wrong with
them, Lawrence?
I don't know.
They were a nation of
anxious people.
And they could do
nothing individually.
So they went mad, en masse.
God I wish they'd
stop hitting me.
I don't want to hate any
individual Japanese.
John.
John Lawrence.
Good night, John Lawrence.
What's up John?
I was dreaming.
I was dreaming about this woman.
Christ, sounds like
she cut it off.
I only met her twice...
I met her only twice.
Just before the fall
of Singapore.
The streets were just
packed with people.
Everybody was trying to get out.
They'd all gone mad.
The hotels were packed.
Everybody was screaming.
And there was this woman,
who was different from...
all the rest, really.
She didn't seem to
be frightened.
I was frightened.
We talked about the war
and she kept saying...
"What's the truth?
I want to know the truth. "
Bloody silly question, really.
We arranged to have breakfast
together the next morning.
And would you believe it?
I was whipped off.
The attack had started.
Japanese landed.
Anyway I got back to the hotel
a few days later...
and would you believe it?
She was still there.
She was standing in exactly
the same place...
that I'd left her.
It was as if she hadn't move
since I walked away.
Like I'd run across the street
for a packet of cigarettes.
I don't think I want to talk
about this anymore really.
Jack, are you there?
Yes, I suppose so.
What's the matter?
The past, again and again.
You've got me at it now, John.
Who is she? Your turn in
the confessional.
I've not had many romantic
interludes of great importance.
My experience lies in the
field of betrayal.
Ride, ride through the day
Ride through the moonlight
Ride, ride through the night
For far in the distance
Burns the fire
For someone who
Was waited long
How do you find the time to
compose these songs?
While you're at school.
Lead us Heavently Father,
Lead us
O'er the world's
Tempestuous sea
Guard us, guide us,
Keep us, feed us
For we have no help
But Thee
Yet possessing every blessing,
If our God our Father be
Listen! They're a two
full notes off!
Savior, breathe forgiveness
O'er us
All our weakness
Thou dost know
- They're after me.
- But why?
- I laughed at them.
- I laughed, too!
They hate me!
They like you.
I won't let them touch you.
Go on home.
Don't look back no matter what!
Understand?
Do what I told you!
Be brave.
Hey, hunchback!
Get out of the way!
Don't run!
All right! You asked for it!
What an earth do you think
you're doing!
Are you all right?
You brought the pastor!
Why did you have to interfere?
Why didn't you go home
like I said?
- I'm sorry.
- No, you're not.
Stop crying.
You hate me, too!
My brother was scared out of
his skin when the time came...
for him to go to school.
I was in the sixth form,
top of my class...
and head of my house.
Even so my brother lived every
day in absolute terror...
of being revealed...
Tomorrow's the initiation.
Any exemptions?
One got a weak heart. But he's
got a doctor's certificate.
I've got one who's blind as a bat.
He can't even pee straight.
You've got a younger brother
in your house haven't you?
- What about him?
- Well, what about him?
- I was merely wondering if he was...
- He's perfectly all right.
If there's any reason why you'd
want your brother excused...
It's awfully decent of you,
but there's no reason.
I knew my brother was
waiting for me.
But I couldn't conscience the
thought of the whole school...
setting eyes on his back.
It would reflect on me...
and anything related to me
was not of the best.
I asked the science master
to let me stay after class...
to make preparations for the
experiments the next day.
Why was he born so beautiful?
Why was he born at all?
He's no bloody use to anyone
He's no bloody use at all
Come on chaps!
- What can you do?
- I hear he can sing.
Oh he's one of those, is he?
Come on sing!
Sing, Sing, Sing.
Sing. Sing. Sing.
Ride, ride through the day
Ride, ride through the night
For far in the distance
Burns the fire
For someone who
Has waited along
Jack, help me!
So how did it go today?
You mean you didn't see?
No. I was in the science
laboratory all afternoon.
I had to finish a job for
the science master.
I see.
My brother never sang
another note... ever.
He took over our father's
farm in due course.
The last time I saw him was
at his wedding.
Over the years, I became,
you might say...
a haunted person.
I really wanted to see him again.
I never did.
I was 32, eligible batchelor...
a reasonably successful lawyer
and absolutely nothing.
When war broke out, God,
I embraced it.
With some inexplicable sense
of relief and the kind...
of enthusiasm I hadn't shown for
anything for... I don't know.
You should have joined the
Foreign Legion, Jack.
It would have been
an easier life.
That's the last thing I want.
- Here comes the milkman now.
- Two pints.
Shouldn't we order an extra one.
It's Christmas remember?
Well, it was lovely chatting
but I really must fly.
It's not you. They've como
for me.
How is it John you're
always wrong?
- The prisoners, sir.
- Come in.
So, Sergeant Hara,
you're human after all.
What?
So Sergeant Hara,
you're human after all.
Lawrence-San!
You know Father Christmas?
What's he saying to us?
Yes, Hara-San.
Father Christmas means Santa Claus.
I'm Father Christmas tonight.
Tonight, I'm Father Christmas.
He thinks he's Santa Claus.
Father. Father Christmas.
Father Christmas!
Go with him.
You're both free.
He's pissed as a newt.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you.
Merry Kurisumasu, Lawrence!
Merry Kurisumasu!
Bonkers.
I brought the squad, sir.
All present, sir.
Lawrence! Why are you here?
- I released him last night.
- Why?
Yesterday I questioned a
Chinese prisoner.
He confessed he smuggled the
radio into the sick bay.
I had him executed.
I was wrong to blame Lawrence.
Why not report it!
- I also released Jack Celliers.
- Without my permission?
Sir, I was a little drunk.
I didn't think Lawrence or
Celliers would do us harm.
I didn't think you wanted
them to be martyrs.
I'll take the consequences.
Whatever happened to your
idea to replace me...
with Major Celliers?
Shut up, sir.
Where is your report on armament's
experts here in the camp?
- There are none here, sir.
- Not one among 600 men?
Do you think you can get away
with such an obvious lie?
I'm told it is the Japanese
way to lie, sir.
Very well! All prisioners
on parade in five minutes!
Dismissed!
All of them, I said.
Everyone!
I'm sending prisoners to
Haruka to build an airstrip.
You'll take charge of them.
You leave in three days.
In the meantime you will be
confined to your room.
Without sake.
What are they up to now?
I don't think it's anything.
Fairly routine stuff this.
- Listen, John.
- What?
I wish I could sing.
It is beautiful.
My orders were explicit!
I said that all prisoners
were to assemble!
You are not all here!
We are all here, sir.
You! Come here!
You lied to me again!
I said all the prisoners!
Where are the men from the hospital?
- They cannot possibly be moved!
- It's out of the question!
All prisoners will
assemble immediately!
Get them! Now!
Get them!
You're faking.
You are not sick!
Your spirits are sick!
Bastard! He's going to die!
Captain Yanoi.
He's dead!
You! Get over here!
You...
you and you...
Come here! Now!
Come here!
As a representative of the
British Air Force how...
many experts in weapons and
guns do you have in your group?
None, sir!
Death!
You! Go back!
Go back!
Go back! Go back!
Stop it!
I am not as sentimental
as Captain Yonoi.
Things will be different now.
Detail...
Attention!
Platoon... attention!
Detail will advance by the left.
Quick march.
Understand them do you,
Lawrence?
If I were you,
I would commit harakiri.
I'm pleased to see you.
Really Jack.
I wanted to come.
Don't apologize.
But I've wronged you, badly.
Help me water these things.
Look, I need to talk to you.
Remember this one?
You know I don't.
It flowers once every
five years. That's all.
I'll be back before
it flowers again.
Cross my heart.
Let's go back to the house.
Ride, ride through the day
Ride through the moonlight
Ride, ride through the night
For far in the distance
Burns the fire
For someone who
Has waited long
I knew you would come,
Mr. Lawrence.
- You've learned English.
- Yes very little. Please?
I very nearly didn't
get your message.
It's tomorrow morning.
Well if it was up to me.
I'd release you today, send
you back to your family.
Thank you.
I'm ready to die.
I don't understand.
My crimes were...
no different from any
other soldier's.
You are the victim of men who
think that they are right...
just as one day, you
and Captain Yonoi...
And the truth is, of course,
that nobody is right.
Do you remember Jack Celliers?
Strange.
I dreamed of him last night.
Did you really?
Captain Yonoi gave me a lock
of Jack Celliers hair...
and he asked me to take it to
his village in Japan.
It's sad.
That he was executed
after the war.
It was as if Celliers,
by his death...
sowed a seed in Yonoi...
that we might all share
by its growth.
Do you remember that Christmas?
Yes.
It was a good Christmas,
wasn't it?
It was a wonderful Christmas.
You were drunk.
May I go on and on being drunk?
Sake is wonderful.
Thank you. Father Christmas.
Thank you.
There are times when victory
is very hard to take.
Good bye. Hara-san.
God bless you.
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas,
Mr. Lawrence!