[Christmas theme music plays]
[door opens and closes]
Clara! Right on time.
I know, Mom. I'm so sorry!
The roads are a mess.
They always are this time of the year.
- That's why I asked you to come early.
- [Clara] I know.
- Wow! Mom!
- [Lydia] Hmm?
- [Clara] This is so beautiful.
- [Lydia] Hmm.
I think this is your best one ever.
It has to be.
I'm being featured
in Seasons Magazine for Christmas.
- You are?
- Mm-hmm.
- Wow!
- [Lydia giggles]
- I love these windows.
- [cell phone rings]
- It's Bonnie.
- [Lydia] But of course.
Hey, Bonnie.
Yeah, Bonnie, slow down.
Well, yeah, it's Christmas.
We always get slammed.
Again?
Yeah, sure. I'll be right in.
- [sighs]
- [cell phone beeps]
- Mom.
- Mm-hmm?
I'm really sorry, but I have to go.
You're really wasting
your talents there, sweetheart.
Can we have a rain check
on baking those cookies?
[Lydia] Oh, no!
Your mother waits for no one,
first born or otherwise.
How do you think your father
became so punctual?
[both laugh]
He was pretty punctual.
- Mm-hmm.
- I love you.
- I love you too. Be careful.
- I will.
- Bye.
[door opens]
[sighs]
[door closes]
Right there. Yes, perfect.
Welcome back
to Can You Stand The Heat!
We started with 50 super celebrity chefs,
and managed to whittle
it down to just three!
So, who's it gonna be?
- Mike Mahoney...
- [audience applauds]
...whose big talent is second only
- to his big mouth?
- Big Mike!
What's that catchphrase?
[all] Let's get cooking!
Mike is in the house, baby!
That's right! Whoo!
[TV hostess] Or Sharl Shaunnessy?
The only baker who has what it takes
to rise to the top.
Tortured artist of cakes
and pastries alike.
[audience clapping and cheering]
[audience gasps]
Or will it be Manhattan's
hottest celebrity chef,
restaurateur and bachelor, Shane Roarke?
- [clapping]
- [women cheering]
[Shane chuckles] Huh? Huh?
Let's see it! Let's see!
Ah, ah, ah!
[chuckles] Yeah, there it is!
[clapping and cheering]
Well, we've waited so long
for the best of the best
to slice and dice, and sift it out.
And now for the winner...
[audience cheering]
Sharl...
Oh, man.
You are...
- not the winner!
- Oh, come on!
[mouthing] I'm sorry.
I'm out of here. This is [bleep].
These two wouldn't know the difference
between a puff pastry and a Danish pastry.
See you later, squids. [bleep]
[laughing] What the [bleep].
[laughs] You can't say that on TV.
And this year's
"Can You Stand the Heat"
celebrity champion is...
Shane Roarke!
- [clapping and cheering]
- [woman] Oh, my God!
[Clara] Guys?
- Guys?
- [woman] Amazing!
- Oh! He's so inspiring--
- Guys!
If you're looking for something to do,
maybe your jobs
could use a little attention?
Yeah, I know,
but we have a really big day,
so, we need to get going.
Like now. Thank you.
[indistinct chatter]
Oh, Clara, you might as well
own this place.
Oh, no, I am happy managing.
Yeah, but your restaurant
in Chicago was great.
I mean, I could just imagine
what you'd do to this place.
Well, enough about that.
Let's just worry about these guests.
Shane won!
- Good for Shane.
- Everyone loves Shane.
I have a table of seven coming in.
- Can you please help me set up?
- OK.
- Thank you.
- He's really cute, though.
[Clara chuckles]
[TV hostess]
Remember that name, folks!
Shane Roarke!
He's the country's most famous chef,
and most eligible bachelor.
Breaking eggs...
And breaking hearts.
Shane Roarke, everybody.
[audience cheering and clapping]
[indistinct chatter]
- Here we are.
- Thank you.
Here we go.
- Great. Thank you.
- [Clara] Enjoy.
- Thanks.
- Hey,
when you get a chance, could you run
some garlic bread to table three.
- Absolutely. You're welcome.
- Thank you.
Yeah, just go with the cab. Perfect.
How is everything?
Good. Your server
will be with you in just a minute.
Thank you.
How is everything over here?
Hey! [clapping]
We don't have all day here!
I'll be right there, sir.
- [Bonnie] I'm not 100 percent sure, but...
- What are you doing?
[Bonnie] I think that guy wants you...
You think?
Hey, can I get two glasses
of red please? Thank you.
[clapping]
- Don't clap at the waitress. She's--
- I'm getting it done.
- Shush. I got this one.
- Don't shush me!
How can I help you?
[scoffs] I ordered a rare steak
and it's not bleeding.
Well, you certainly seemed to have enjoyed
the first half of it.
Yeah, but, I didn't love it.
Shouldn't I love my steak...
Clara?
Well, I'm afraid I can't guarantee you
love on this steak,
but I can get you a new steak.
Rare, extra bloody.
Touchdown!
Oh, wow. Well, the date is over,
and I am so sorry about... that.
Um... [clears throat] Is there a taxi
stand outside? I'll just...
I'll be back in just a minute.
I bet you're glad to be back, huh?
[Clara] Over the moon.
Ah, I can't wait to get home.
I'm exhausted.
I know. Me too. OK, but first
I gotta use the bathroom.
- Again? You just went to the bathroom.
- Yeah, [scoffs] I gotta go again.
- [phone ringing]
- Have you been stealing
cheese from the kitchen again?
So?
- [laughing] So, you're lactose intolerant.
- No, I'm not.
Cheese just makes my stomach
- gurgle a little bit.
- [Clara] Right. My bad.
- Enjoy your cheese. Yeah. Go.
- Can you hold my bag?
Hi, how are you? I'm just checking in.
- [thud]
- [Clara sighs]
[Shane] Can I help you with this?
- Oh, thank you.
- Oh, don't mention it.
- [Clara] This isn't actually my cheese.
- Right.
- Well, this is a nice piece of Gruyère.
- [Clara sighs]
It's still not mine. It's... um...
- [embarrassed laugh] It's not mine.
- [Shane] A friend's.
Yeah.
- [Clara] Uh...
- [clears throat]
[both sigh]
Anyway, uh... enjoy your stay
at Thunder Mountain.
Thank you, um...
- [both] Clara.
- [Shane clears throat]
Right. It's... on my necklace.
[Shane] It is. Yeah.
- Well, have a good night.
- You too. [chuckles]
Bye. [laughs nervously]
- Do you know who that is?
- Mm-hmm, yup, mm-hmm.
- [excited] It's Shane--
- Shh, shh, shh.
- It's Shane Roarke!
- I know. I know.
You know, from that reality show earlier!
- Yeah.
- He's standing-- [giggling] Here's here!
Oh, he's even more handsome in real life.
Did he make a pass at you?
No, Bonnie, he handed me your cheese.
- [laughs]
- Come on.
[inaudible]
Great.
[phone rings]
[sighs]
Shane Roarke is staying at our resort!
Well, you know,
it's not really our resort.
Oh, do you think
he'll come to the restaurant?
Yeah. He might. He might.
If I were Shane Roarke
and I went to our restaurant
- what would I order?
- Pizza!
Yes! Pizza! I mean,
if he's the perfect man,
which we know he is,
he would get pizza.
[indistinct conversation]
Let's do it!
[engine turning over]
[engine starts]
[Clara] Right.
[indistinct conversation]
[both hooting and hollering]
[Hugh Peters] Guys, right here.
Christmas is just around the corner.
And if Thanksgiving was any indication,
I think we can expect it to be
at least twice as busy this year.
Now, I have a very exciting
announcement to make.
To help with the busy season,
and perhaps some
marketing opportunities,
I've hired a new head chef,
starting today.
He's a huge talent. Shane Roarke.
Come out, buddy!
Oh!
It's Shane Roarke! He's not a guest!
- He's with us!
- Uh-huh. Yup. [chuckles]
Now, I know Shane wanted to get started
meeting all of his staff.
And we all have a lot of work to do
getting ready for Christmas.
So, let's welcome Shane,
and make him feel at home.
Thank you.
- Hi. Clara. We met last night.
- [Shane] Hi.
Of course, yeah. The cheese girl.
Actually, no, I'm cheese girl!
Yeah, I know, that was my purse cheese.
[laughs] But who cares?
I'm Bonnie. And you're Shane.
Hi, Bonnie.
[giggling] Yeah,
Clara was holding my purse.
Oh! Well, that's very nice of her.
- [chuckles]
- [Bonnie] She thinks
I'm lactose intolerant,
but I don't think I am.
Bonnie, remember we talked
about first impressions?
[Shane] OK. Uh, I mean,
that's great to know,
if I'm ever preparing something
for you in the kitchen.
- [all three laugh]
- Yeah.
It was nice to meet you.
Uh-huh. Huh.
- [Clara laughs]
- Wow! No,
that guy needs to take it down a notch
with the flirting.
Yeah? Was he flirting with you?
[Bonnie] Oh! You like him, don't you?
What? Don't be ridiculous.
Oh, you do like him. I can tell.
You know what, I'm going to see
if he likes you.
No, please don't.
- You can count on me.
- [Clara scoffs]
I didn't even say I liked him.
Bonnie!
[inaudible conversations]
[Shane] I'm waiting on that pizza...
How are we doing with those scallops?
[inaudible conversation]
Order's up.
[waiter] Enjoy your food.
I think you will all love it.
- That was...
- Jeans!
- Excuse me.
- But also skiing too.
It's-- I don't understand
why he does that everytime.
OK. Sorry, I'll be right back.
- It's not fun.
- Have fun with that.
- [giggling and squealing]
- [glasses clinking]
Hello. I'm the manager here.
I heard you asked to see me.
My name is Clara.
How's everything today?
Can we grab you some more drinks?
[sighs] More drinks!
What a great idea, Claire!
- Oh, It's Clara.
- [Janice] Oh!
- Uh, I'm Janice.
- And I'm the other Janice!
Janice and Janice. Two Janices!
[squeals]
We are just a couple of single girls
on vacation here in the mountains.
And we happened to notice
that your new chef is...
- [both] Shane Roarke!
- Oh, I'm afraid I can't really
be much help. I don't know him
- that well--
- We feel like we know him personally.
So, we were wondering
if you could ask Shane
if he'd like to come out and say hello?
I mean, we would love
to meet him. [chuckles]
Oh, sure. I mean, he's pretty busy...
- Thank you!
- Thanks.
- [glasses clinking]
- [Janice] Shane Roarke. She's gonna get...
- [Clara] Shane! Hi.
- Hi.
Um...
- Hi. Clara. Hi.
- Yeah, now, we've officially said hi.
- Yeah, we have.
Um, I'm--I'm really sorry to bother you,
but I have a table of young ladies.
They asked if you could drop by
to say hello.
I told them you were busy.
So, I can just--
No, no, no. It's fine.
I'll--I'll head over.
Peters says I'm never too busy
to butter up customers,
so, I'll... I'll head over.
OK. Their names
are Janice and Janice.
I'm sorry?
- Janice and Janice. Yeah.
- Two Janices!
Wow! Sounds interesting.
Yeah, well, they kind of freak me out,
but they're very excited to see you.
Oh, OK. Well, tell them
I'm very excited to see them.
- OK. [laughs]
- OK. Thanks.
- I'll head out.
- [Clara] OK.
[inaudible conversation]
[indistinct conversation]
Good afternoon, ladies.
- Hi.
- How are you? Shane.
- Janice.
Janice?
Very nice to meet you, Janice.
And?
- Janice.
- [Shane] You're both Janice?
Wow. He is so smooth.
Isn't he smooth, Clara?
Who?
Oh, sure, pretend you don't know.
I'll play along. Shane!
Hang on a second.
Oh, yeah. I guess he's smooth.
Hi, Mr. Peters.
Hi, Bonnie. Clara? Shall we?
[Clara] Sure. I'll be right there, Hugh.
- Hugh?
- Yeah, that's his name.
Really? I thought it was Peters.
You thought he went by mister,
and then his first name?
OK, don't change the subject.
What's he mean, "Shall we?"
Shall we what?
Shall we mind our own business,
maybe? [chuckles]
Mr. Hugh?
All right, guys. Why don't we
take a little bit of a break?
Right? We've got a busy night.
Cool. Good work.
Thank you.
Chef, very nice on the fryer, by the way.
[man] Thanks, chef!
OK, enough about the schedule.
- Yeah.
- I want to talk to you about this project.
What he have...
- [slurping]
- [Shane humming]
- A little soda on the rocks.
- Thank you.
So, you're pretty smooth
over there with your lady fans.
Hmm. Oh, yeah.
They were, uh, they were interesting,
that's for sure. Fun fact,
they're both named Janice.
- [laughs] Wow.
- Yeah.
- That is interesting.
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Well, I bet you have
a lot of lady fans, huh?
Argh! Yeah. I guess. [laughs]
OK, I see
- where this is headed.
- What?
I should probably tell you
I have a boyfriend.
Just to be clear.
- Oh! OK. Yeah, thank--
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- He is, uh...
a city planner.
- His name is Clive.
- Nice.
You know, Bonnie and Clive.
Like Bonnie and Clyde.
Only instead of Clyde it's...
- Clive.
- Clive. Yeah. [laughs]
I mean, that's lovely.
So, what's up with you and Clara?
You guys been friends
a long time, or what?
Oh, best friends
since we were little kids.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
We both grew up here
in Thunder Valley.
I never left, but Clara went to
Chicago for a few years to open up
her own restaurant.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
It was a really nice place, too.
It just didn't quite work out
like she planned, you know?
Yeah. Yeah, I mean, you know,
Chicago's a tough market.
But anyways, now she's back,
totally alone,
and no boyfriend to speak of.
[Shane chuckles]
So, there's no city planner then?
- No?
- No.
Yeah. Anyone could just ask her out,
and she'd probably say yes.
OK.
Oh, so, what's going on with her
and Peters over there?
[indistinct conversation]
- Really?
- Yeah.
[Clara laughs]
OK. Now...
Oh! No, there's nothing
going on over there.
- [Clara] Yeah...
- I don't... I don't think.
[door closes]
[footsteps approaching]
[Jackie] They're all one of a kind.
They're gorgeous.
They are.
You should pick your favorite one
and place a bid on it.
You know, every year,
our local artists donate these ornaments,
and then we raffle them off for charity.
That's a tradition started
by Jackie's parents
back in year one.
I see you've met my beautiful wife.
Hi, I'm Jackie.
And I'm the lucky husband, Frank Haven.
[laughing] I'm Shane Roarke.
OK. Shane Roarke.
I'd say, black coffee with half a creamer.
- [Jackie snaps fingers]
- [Frank laughs] Impressed?
Well, young man,
you've seen nothing yet.
Oh, the Mountain View
has been our life for...
- what honey, 22 years?
- Twenty-five years.
Twenty-five years, says the boss.
And believe me, she's always right.
[Jackie] Yes, I am. [chuckles]
So, Shane,
you're not from around here, are you?
No, no. Uh, I'm actually
originally from New York.
- Ah!
- [Shane] And, uh...
I've kind of been roving around
for the last 10 years.
[stammers] And I just took a job over
at the Thunder Mountain resort.
Oh, one of our favorite servers
works up there.
[stutters] It's the Surface, right?
- The Summit.
- Yeah, something like that.
- Yeah.
- [laughs] Her name's Clara Garrison.
Clara. I do know Clara.
She's actually...
she's actually the manager now.
A very good one, at that.
Oh, she's terrific!
She worked here part-time
through high school, and then full-time
for a couple of years
before she went to Chicago.
Jackie and I don't have children
of our own,
so Clara's sort of like a daughter to us.
Right.
So, what brings you from the Summit
to the Mountain View?
Uh... [sighs] history, I guess.
Yeah, I'm kind of...
kind of interested in some of the older,
more family-run resorts in the area.
Well, you've missed the height.
I mean, back in the day,
there were a good dozen or more
just along these mountains.
We're one of the few
that are still scrapping out a living.
It's just so hard to compete
with the big resorts
and the chains anymore, you know.
We still get slammed at breakfast!
Yeah, well, thanks to you.
Without her Eggs Florentine
- we'd be dead and buried by now.
- Really?
You should come by some morning!
Well, I would love that.
[inaudible]
All right. We're still waiting
on one more maple-glazed quail,
a seared trout, and we're going
to do the final beef carpaccio.
- I saw that.
- What look? There was no look.
I didn't say look.
You're still here.
Yeah. Um... I'm just
getting a start on tomorrow.
Nice.
[Shane] Oh, hey, I, um...
I just wanted to say thanks
for helping out tonight.
Oh, yeah, no problem. I mean,
it's better together right?
No, no, no. I know. I know.
But, uh, tonight was crazy busy.
[chuckles]
On top of being
a couple of servers short, so...
- thank you.
- Oh, yeah. Tell me about it.
So, I'm also assuming that you probably
didn't have time for dinner tonight?
No, but that's OK. I can just grab
something on the way home.
Oh, please. What do you mean?
I'm gonna be making something for myself.
You know? I mean, they say
I'm not terrible at this.
- [laughs] That's true. I mean...
- [Shane chuckles]
They actually have been saying
that around here, you know.
- Who's been saying that?
- [both laugh]
- That's a great idea, actually.
- OK.
Um, but you cooked all night.
How about I make us something?
- You?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- All right.
- Yes?
I'm not going to say no to that.
[Shane] Uh!
Are you sure
I can't help with anything?
Well, if you grabbed a bottle of wine,
I wouldn't complain.
- I mean, I can do that. Yeah.
- [laughs] Yeah?
That just smells really good. I just-- OK.
- I got this.
- All right.
[Shane] Wow!
That was fantastic.
Well, thank you.
You know, they say
I'm not terrible at this.
Mm. [chuckles] I mean, I heard that.
- [laughs]
- Bonnie told me
that you, uh, [clears throat]
had your own place.
- [Clara] She did, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
[Clara] Well...
that turned out to be
a little girl's dream that got too big.
At least you did it, right?
I mean, most people
just sit around dreaming.
Think. Imagine how proud
that little girl would have been
if she saw what you did?
Pretty proud.
No, I took on more than I could handle.
Maybe it was just bad timing.
And, I doubt it.
Yeah, maybe.
Either way, here I am, back at home,
trying to... figure out what's next.
Huh! I mean,
I think chocolate cake's next.
- [chuckles] Chocolate cake?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, that was my other dream.
So, how did you know?
You wanted to be a chocolate cake?
Yeah, that's exactly what I wanted.
[both laugh]
Thanks for the company tonight.
It was-- It was really great.
Well, it was my pleasure.
And thank you for cooking.
So... [clears throat]
Can I walk you to your car?
My car... Um, well, it's, uh,
it's currently in the shop.
And, uh, the last bus
left about an hour ago.
So, I've been trying to come up
with like a clever way
to ask for a ride.
I will give you a ride. Yeah.
[Clara] Thanks.
[Clara chuckles]
This is it!
Wow. It's a gorgeous building.
How long have you lived here?
I managed to pick it up
with what I had left after Chicago, so...
I am impressed, Ms. Clara Garrison.
With what? The fact
that I'm not homeless? Or...
- [both laugh]
- Hey, I live in a hotel
and all my belongings are in suitcases,
- so...
- [Clara laughs]
So, you are definitely amazing.
[both laugh nervously]
Wow, I can't believe
I'm kissing a celebrity.
What's wrong?
[stammers] Nothing, nothing, nothing.
I--I just don't-- I don't know
if this is the best idea.
I just get a lot of attention
from the show.
I didn't even know you watched it.
I don't. I don't watch your show.
I was just saying I'm surprised.
Like, in a good way.
I feel really stupid--
Hang on, hang on. I don't think
I'm explaining this right,
- but--
- You're definitely not. You--
Good night, Shane.
- [sights]
- [car door closes]
[exhales]
I am such a jerk.
[inaudible]
Two milks, one sugar.
Thank you. You're a lifesaver.
- Are you ready for this morning?
- Hmm...
let me get halfway through
this coffee, and I will be.
Good.
You all right?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
Uh, I'm just ready.
[Hugh] OK.
- It's just up here.
- [Clara] Great.
- There you go. Enjoy.
- [man] Thank you.
Jackie! Sorry to bother you.
Listen, Frank was right.
Those were the best Eggs Florentine
I have ever had.
[chuckles] Really?
Ever. And I happen
to be an expert on eggs.
Are you, now?
Just a little bit. And I'm gonna have
to get that recipe from you.
I taste the smoked cayenne,
but is that mustard powder in there?
You must put a little pinch--
Whoa, whoa, whoa! I'm afraid
that is a trade secret.
- [both laugh]
- OK, I'm not gonna ask.
[Jackie] More coffee?
Actually, I... I should get going to work.
Well, could I grab a coffee to go?
- Of course.
- Actually,
can I get two coffees to go, please?
- Coming right up.
- [Shane] Thank you.
That's Shane's car, isn't it?
[Clara] Uh, I don't know.
[indistinct chatter]
[chairs clattering]
Hi.
- Well, aren't we lucky to find you here!
- [Shane] Janice, Janice. Hi.
You know ladies, I...
I was actually just on my way out.
- Oh, come on.
- Yeah.
Are you too good
for a second breakfast?
- [both laugh and squeal]
- [door bell jingles]
[indistinct conversation]
- So...
- What'd you have for breakfast?
[stammers] Uh, I did the Eggs Florentine.
- [Jackie] Clara! How good to see you!
- Jackie! Aw!
I always save a hug for Frank.
- [Frank] Hi!
- Hi!
Jackie, Frank. This is Hugh Peters.
He owns the restaurant I work at.
Oh, that's right.
[stutters] The something or other.
- [Hugh] The Summit.
- [Frank] Yeah, sounds about right.
- Yeah.
- [laughing] It's a pleasure to meet you.
Clara, you were right.
This place is charming.
Guys, could we get
a couple minutes after breakfast?
We have a proposal
we'd like to run by you.
A proposal! I haven't had one
of those since Frank's.
Turned out pretty good.
- [Clara laughs]
- [Frank] I pay her to say that.
- [all laugh]
- Just sit down,
and--and we'll be with you
right after the rush, OK?
- [Hugh] Can wait. Can wait.
- OK. Would you like coffee?
[both] Yes, please.
- [Hugh] This way.
- [Clara] Thank you.
[women giggling]
Uh, [stammers] it's so nice
to see you guys again.
- [Janice] Really?
- [Shane] Really. Yeah.
You're-- Huh, no, no, I... [chuckles]
- So, you're a Pisces and we're...
- [Shane] I am.
- [Janice continues indistinctly]
- Hmm.
[Shane] What month is Pisces?
[Frank] All right.
This will get you started.
- [Clara] Thank you.
- [Frank] OK.
[Shane] June is Gemini.
So, if you could eat 10 pounds of food
what'd it be?
Ten pounds?
Uh... probably wings.
What is it?
Nothing.
[indistinct conversation]
I figured you might be hungry.
- Aw. Thank you.
- Thank you.
Wow, you were right, Clara.
This smells incredible.
I told you.
Dig in.
You know, ladies. I, um,
I actually really do have to go.
Oh, great idea!
- We're moving the party, Janice.
- OK. One car or two, Shane?
- I, uh...
- One, two. We'll figure it out!
- Yeah. OK.
- Oh! OK.
[indistinct conversation]
Oh, honey.
- So, we'll see you again soon.
- I-- I'll be back before you know it.
I hope so.
If you guys have any questions,
please call me.
I'd be happy to go over anything
to help you decide.
I'll look at it, and then
Jackie will make the decision.
Oh, come on. Not just me!
Lovely meeting you both.
Hope to hear from you soon.
If our Clara's involved,
I'm sure it'll work out.
[Jackie] Oh, that reminds me.
We met somebody else
who works at the resort.
Oh, yeah. Shawn.
- What--What was his last name?
- It's not Shawn.
It's Shane. Shane Roarke.
That sounds about right. Yeah.
Oh, so, he was just here for breakfast?
No, actually he came by yesterday.
Oh!
Anyway, thank you both, so much.
I'll see you soon.
- Have a good time, darling. Bye.
- Bye-bye.
- Shawn? Shane. Shane. Damn!
- No. It was Shane!
Everybody! As you know,
tonight the restaurant will be closed
for our annual charity dinner.
It's all in the spirit
of Christmas, of course,
but if it happens to throw
a little publicity our way,
so, be it.
[whispering] Don't look now,
but someone's throwing you
some major eye attention.
Let's do some good!
...like when you play basketball,
you might play hard. Use some elbow.
Ah, yeah.
You should go on them easier.
[cell phone beeps]
Call Clara.
[cell phone rings]
- Hey, Mom, you're on speaker.
- Hi, Mrs. Garrison.
Hello, Bonnie, darling.
Clara, I've called to remind you
of our family Christmas dinner.
Yes, it is on my radar
and scheduled in.
Will you be bringing someone
other than Bonnie this year?
Actually, Clive and I
are doing Christmas this year.
Good for you!
Mom, you know I'm too busy to date.
So, you're down one Bonnie
and stuck with me.
[Lydia] Mm.
I seem to recall your baby sister
making time for Barry
- while she was at Harvard.
- Mom!
I'm just saying. Just saying.
Mom, I've got to go.
- All right. Just be on time.
- [Clara] I will.
- Bye.
- [Clara] Bye.
Nice.
[Bonnie laughs] Got to love it.
[Clara] Mm-hmm.
Perfect. Thank you.
I managed to sneak you
another chocolate raspberry truffle.
Oh, you devil. Oh, it's so good.
- Thank you.
- [Clara] My pleasure.
The food is better than ever this year.
Well, we have a new chef.
Oh, fantastic! Honestly, though,
the best part isn't the food.
The best part is seeing you guys again.
[both] Aw.
- We look forward to seeing you every year.
- Oh, it's so nice.
Yeah.
So, are you seeing anyone?
- [Hugh] Clara!
- Speaking of seeing...
[Clara] I'll be right back.
I would love for you to meet
my rock star manager Clara.
She is one of a kind.
- [male guest] Clara.
- Nice to meet you.
- Clara, nice to meet you.
- Are you having a great time?
[indistinct conversation]
I'll just gonna check in the kitchen,
and make sure everything is OK.
- Absolutely.
- Great. I'll be back.
And I'm an idiot.
Clara? [clears throat]
Yeah?
Do you mind if I just have a quick word?
I saw you at the Mountain View
this morning...
with those two girls that came in.
[laughs] No, no. OK, I don't know
what you think you saw,
- but it definitely wasn't--
- Hey,
- you don't need to explain yourself to me.
- No, no, I was just eating,
and they forced me to sit with them.
I didn't have a choice.
Yeah, you looked really trapped.
Argh. I don't--I don't want to fight.
I really just came over
to talk to you about the other night.
Please.
Thank you. I...
I wanted to talk to you about, um...
your car. Uh, has...
has the mechanic
gotten back to you at all?
Yeah. It was a problem
with the alternator.
- It'll be ready in a few days.
- OK, great.
Uh, I mean, not--not great.
But I was wondering
if--if you... needed a...
I was gonna offer to take you home
- after work tonight-- OK. Right.
- I'm good.
I guess Mr. Peters can give you
a ride home then?
- You know, Shane...
- Yeah?
However I decide to get to work,
whether I walk or take the bus,
or get a ride with Peters,
- is really none of your business.
- You know, I know, I know. You're right.
You're right-- right, of course.
Look. Please. This isn't... [chuckles]
this isn't how I saw this going.
I just...
Can you just let me explain
why I got freaked out the other night?
That's not necessary
because you were pretty clear.
No, I wasn't. Look...
a celebrity chef isn't something
I ever saw myself becoming.
And I... I misjudged you rudely,
and I just really
would like to be able to...
explain myself properly.
Would you...
would you want--want to
come back to my place
after we're done here tonight?
Because you--you cooked for me. Right?
And it was--it was amazing.
And I would just like to return the favor.
I... I mean, eventually I'll have to,
it might not be tonight, or...
Please?
Yeah.
Sure.
Dinner would be great.
- Great.
- [Bonnie] Great.
I wasn't eavesdropping.
[both chuckle]
So, you, uh, you live in a resort?
- [laughs] Yeah.
- [Clara chuckles]
Uh, I mean, you know,
it's--it's only temporary.
It's not home or anything.
I do hear they have great room service.
Oh, do they?
I'm just kidding.
Everything looks and smells amazing.
Uh, can I help you with anything?
Actually I do have a job for you.
Two jobs.
Number one, is I want you to relax.
And number two is to enjoy yourself.
So, are you relaxed?
- Yes.
- [Hugh] Good.
And are you enjoying yourself?
I am.
- [Clara] Oh! Are you OK? [laughs]
- [Shane] Uh, OK.
And it's really hot. Actually, I'm just...
One second.
Gonna, um...
And...
I...
Anyway, I'm going to... I'll be back.
[chuckles]
What a view.
It is.
I was talking about the mountain.
And the snow.
And the Christmas lights.
I wasn't.
[breathless] Oh, boy.
Is that a good "Oh, boy"
or a bad "Oh, boy"?
It's just the last time we kissed...
[sighs]
I've been on exactly...
five dates.
Three terrible ones, one crazy,
and... [chuckles]
one more that lasted for eight years.
Wow! That is a long date.
You know, the show made me
kind of look a certain way.
But the truth is, I'm not.
I'm not that guy.
I'm not even close to that guy.
Uh, so, when I meet someone now,
they usually expect that person
that I'm not.
You know I'm not that person. Right?
I do.
That's exactly why I wanted you
to come up here.
Because I wanted to apologize.
For misjudging you.
You know, I didn't even like your show.
- Oh, come on.
- I only saw it twice and...
personally, I wanted the other guy to win.
Are you kidding?
That guy microwaved his steak.
Microwaved!
- What!?
- It's blasphemy!
So...
what brought you here, anyway?
I mean, it couldn't have just been
the job offer.
No, you're right, it wasn't.
When I finished the show,
I made myself a promise.
Hmm.
And being here is part of the promise?
Mm-hmm.
It is.
And how long do you plan on staying?
I mean, my contract's for six months.
But I am...
currently working on something
that might keep me here
a little bit longer. Mm-hmm. Maybe.
- Oh?
I still got to do
a little bit more research first.
Mm. Well, aren't you mysterious?
No.
I want to know more about you.
- Me.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I mean, you already know about me.
I'm a recovering failure.
Failing doesn't mean you're a failure.
Unless you give up...
I don't think that's you.
Mm-mmm.
- No?
- Mm-mmm.
So, who am I?
You are strong, determined.
You're definitely smart.
And you are... exceedingly beautiful.
[both chuckle]
Well, I mean,
feel free to go on. You're...
- spot on so far.
- Am I?
Oh, OK, all right. Um...
you want a place of your own.
You want to build it, and watch it grow.
If I had to guess,
I'd say that you are...
planning on opening your own place again.
- Hmm.
- Mm-hmm?
Well, I mean, I've thought about it.
Ah-ha.
Whatever it is...
you will do it.
And it's going to be yours.
And it's going to be great.
[chuckles]
Hey, you don't think it's gonna be
a problem with Mr. Peters
if you keep coming over here, do you?
Mr. Pete--
- Yeah.
- Like me and Peters?
- You and Hugh, yeah.
No, no, we're-- that's-- that's just...
- It's business.
- Oh, is it?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah? Yeah?
Are you working on something big?
Well, I mean, I promised
I wouldn't say anything.
Ah, well, aren't you the mysterious one.
Just a little.
["Sounds Like Christmas"
by Keith Cooper playing]
- Thank you.
- Here you go. Enjoy.
Thank you.
- You really like him, don't you?
- [Clara chuckles]
I think I do. Yeah.
OK. Well, when I first met Clive
I thought he was the most boring person
in the entire world.
You know, I almost didn't go
on a second date with him.
But then I realized, after a while,
he wasn't boring at all.
He was just shy.
Of course, most city planners
are so boring.
[Clara] No.
- You don't say. [chuckles]
- [Bonnie] No, I--I do say.
But the fact is, Clive is the--
He just is the funniest,
most exciting city planner
I have ever met.
And I feel really lucky
I gave him a chance.
I really like Clive.
Me too.
No, I know
Shane isn't a city planner or anything.
- But I guess famous chefs can be fun, too.
- [Clara chuckles]
Yeah, I guess they can.
Well, here's to chefs
and city planners.
You know the craziest thing?
Guess what he [stutters] ordered?
- What?
- Carrots.
Really? I thought he was gonna order
some kind of deer.
- I don't know...
- He would never!
- Clara?
- Yeah.
Can I see you in my office
for a minute, please?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Oh, oh. The principal's office.
Somebody's in trouble.
Oh, you didn't hear?
I am trouble.
Yes, you are!
Hey.
Shut the door if you don't mind
and have a seat.
[door closes]
I see that you've been spending
a lot of time with Shane lately.
Yes, my own personal time.
Is that a problem?
No, no, not per se.
I just-- I wonder if you've had enough
free time to work on our little proposal.
I mean, have you even spoken
to the Havens lately?
Yes, actually! Um, I see them
almost every day at breakfast.
Oh. OK. Um...
You know, I--I, uh...
I got you something.
What? What is this?
It's just a little Christmas present.
Oh, Hugh.
I didn't get you anything.
Don't be silly. Just--just open it.
[Clara chuckles]
Wow. This is beautiful.
I don't know what to say.
Thank you.
You deserve it, Clara.
I couldn't have done
any of this without you.
And if this deal goes through,
you can buy jewelry yourself
that'll make that look like a knock-off.
But... if you could encourage them,
maybe speed things up.
I'd love to get the deal done
before the year end.
Before New Year’s?
Um...
Uh, I think they were kind of hoping
for a bit of time with this.
Ah.
All right. This, um,
this was supposed to be a surprise,
but I was hoping to close the deal
sooner because...
I have a project that I want
to send you to New York for.
New York?
Like you want me to oversee
another acquisition or...
Actually, I want to invest
in a new restaurant.
It would be yours. Ours.
But because I'm here
doing the Haven deal,
if we speed it up,
that would open up
the New York opportunity for you.
Yeah! Wow!
It's great.
You know what? Leave it to me.
They trust me and I think I can help
speed them along.
- I know you can.
- You can count on me.
Good. Uh, so?
Yeah, uh, the schedule.
It's just Bonnie's Thursday,
we need to switch it...
- Oh, hi, there!
- Hi. Here.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
So, I've been meaning to ask.
Um... what are you doing
for Christmas?
I don't know. I haven't, uh,
I haven't really thought about it.
I might--I might go back to the city.
Hmm.
Hmm-hmm.
Well, that makes sense.
I'm sure you probably want
to see your family.
[both chuckle]
Have you told me about your family yet?
You know, I don't think I have.
- Do you have brothers or sisters?
- No. No, just me.
Oh, you're an only child.
[both chuckle]
- Oh, now everything makes complete sense.
- What is that supposed to mean?
You mean I'm weird?
No, I'm just kidding.
But I suppose it's all the more reason
you should go home
and see your parents, right?
Yeah.
- What?
- I want to tell you something.
OK.
I'm not supposed to say
anything, but, um...
I'd really like to share this with you.
[stammers] I'm all ears.
I can keep a secret.
OK. So, you know the project
that Peters and I
- have been working on? Right?
- Hmm.
Well, it has to do with the Mountain View.
- Really?
- Yeah.
He wants to buy them out and renovate it
and turn it into this beautiful
upscale boutique hotel.
And, of course, we would keep
Jackie and Frank on,
but the best part is...
is I would be running it for six months.
OK.
No, this is more than OK.
I mean, this is huge for me.
I'd be overseeing everything.
And then today, he told me
that if I could speed this deal along,
he wants to send me to New York.
Yeah, but Peters got you involved
because of your connection
to the Havens, is that right?
Well, I'd like to think
it's because of my experience,
but, yeah,
the Havens are like family to me.
They trust me.
Of course. Of course they trust you.
But do you trust Peters?
Why are you being so negative about this?
I thought you'd be happy for me.
No, no, no, it's not that
I'm not happy for you.
I'm happy for you. I'm just...
Look, when I first took the job here,
I made a couple of calls.
And Hugh doesn't exactly have
- the best reputation.
- [Clara scoffs]
What?
So, you can sign a big fat deal with him,
and I can't?
No, I just work for the guy.
All right? It's only temporary.
[scoffs] I'm so glad I told you this.
Clara, I'm sorry. It's not...
it's not what I mean. I'm just saying...
that whatever he tells you
about this property
or anything, you--you can't just assume
it to be true, right?
You got to take it with a grain of salt.
[Clara sighs]
But did you ever think
maybe this is all happening
because I'm actually good at my job?
[Shane] No, you are!
You're most certainly good at your job,
but I'm just saying
you might still have blinders on
because of what happened
to you in Chicago.
OK, I'm sorry. That's not...
that's not what I meant.
What I meant to say is he might not be
being honest with you.
And I just want to look out for you.
OK?
I told you this
because I was really excited.
I don't need your approval.
I can take care of myself.
Clara, listen! Clara! Please!
Merry Christmas.
[Lydia] Oh, she is just the cutest!
Does she have her daddy's eyes or what?
- [Darlene] Yes, she does.
- [Lydia and Barry laugh]
I just want to say how thankful I am
to have all of our loved ones
together for Christmas.
Yes, baby.
This was always
your father's favorite time of year,
and not just because of the slopes!
But nothing made him happier
than having us all together.
Maybe next year we'll have a full house.
Right, Clara?
[all laugh]
I'm kidding.
To family.
[all] To family!
[Lydia] Cheers!
Darlene, would you lead us in prayer?
- I'd love to.
- OK.
Dear Lord,
thank you for bringing us together
during this special time.
For blessing us
with all this delicious food
to nourish our bodies.
In the Lord's name,
- Amen.
- [all] Amen!
[Lydia] Thank you, darling.
All right, let's dig in.
Barry, would you do us the honors?
- Yes, I would.
- [Lydia] Thank you.
[Lydia coddles, chuckles]
[Lydia] So, Darlene,
any exciting new cases?
I just started a new case.
It's been very busy. Yes.
So, I can't say too much about it
right now, but, yeah.
[Lydia] And where are my pictures
of the baby?
[Darlene] We--We have one for you.
Don't you worry.
Yeah. We got lots of photos.
So, yeah.
- It's good.
- [Lydia] I'm so proud of you.
[Lydia] Oh,
I really outdid myself this year.
- [Clara] You did!
- [Lydia laughs]
Lydia, I've been meaning to ask.
How did your photo shoot go
- for your gingerbread house?
- Ah, it was for Seasons Magazine.
It went amazing, you know.
Personally,
I think I should be on the cover!
[all laugh]
Or at least like a two-page spread.
- [Barry] Yeah.
- Centerfold.
- [Clara] You know what, I'm just gonna...
I'm just going to clear this
out of the way for everyone.
- [Lydia] Thank you, Clara.
- Thanks.
- Yeah. Excuse me, Barry.
- Mm-hmm.
So, um, how are things at work?
- [Barry] Oh, it's going really well.
- [Lydia] Really well? Good. Yeah.
[chatting continues]
[phone rings]
Well, hello, Clara!
Merry Christmas Eve.
Clive says hi.
- Clive! Say hi!
- Hi.
Hi, Clive.
[Bonnie] OK, s o, how was the meal?
How's the family?
You know.
My favorite couple doing so well.
It's, uh...
amazing, and it's absolutely killing me.
[chuckles]
Do you want to meet for a drink?
Uh, yeah, of course.
Well, let me just check with Clive.
Is it OK if I meet Clara for a drink?
- Yup.
- Clive says yup.
OK, great. I'll meet you--
I'll meet you there.
OK. Bye.
Thanks, babe. See you later.
[sighs]
- Hey, honey. Everything OK?
- Hey.
Yeah. Everything's fine.
Mom, do you think, um...
It'd be OK for you
to go have a drink with Bonnie?
- Yeah.
- [laughs] Sure.
Thank you.
You know, honey, things can change
from one Christmas to the next.
I'm just saying. [chuckles]
Thank you, Mom.
You're welcome.
[Clara sighs]
Now, go have fun.
- OK. I'll see you after.
- [Lydia chuckles]
- [hostess] Hi.
- Hey.
How are you doing?
[Bonnie] Thanks for the drink!
[Clara] No problem.
[laughs]
Thank you for coming.
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
- Hey, Mike!
- [Mike] Yeah?
- How about a couple of drinks?
- [Mike] Sure, no problem.
Christmas... can be a difficult time.
[Mike] Yeah. Here you go.
- Thanks, Mike.
- [Mike] You're welcome.
To best friends and better days.
- Cheers.
- [glasses clinking]
It's just like everyone
was so... happy.
My sister with her perfect husband,
and he's just equally happy with her.
And they're both incredibly happy
with their child.
I mean, it was just...
I'm telling you, Bonnie, it was horrible!
I'm really sorry to hear
about all that happiness.
- That sucks.
- Right?
Well, I'm afraid
I have some happy news?
What?
[Bonnie] I'm engaged!
- [gasps] Oh, Bonnie!
- [Bonnie giggles]
- Congratulations.
- Thank you!
- Oh, you're crying?
- No.
Of course not. I'm not. I'm not.
- You are.
- No, I'm-- They're happy tears.
- They're, uh...
- They don't look happy.
They're happy. I'm happy.
I'm so happy for you!
When are you gonna do it?
I don't know. Maybe in the spring.
Or... [scoffs] a few years from now.
It depends on how long it takes me
to make my own dress.
I don't even know how to sew.
My best friend is getting married.
To a terrific Clive.
And I've fallen for a guy
who may not be that guy.
Or he may be that guy
and I just wrecked everything,
and I may never even see that guy again.
Except at work.
At the restaurant.
And just five days a week.
More with overtime.
Yeah. [sighs]
I'm-- I'm going to quit my job.
[Bonnie] Well, that's a great idea.
[cell phone rings]
Hey, Hugh.
How's... how's your Christmas?
- [children giggling]
- No, the ex-wife dropped off the kids,
unannounced, and I'm just trying
to get some work done.
Oh, that... sounds... fun!
Uh, look. I need you to go to the office
and pick up something for me, please.
Uh, yeah, sure. No problem.
I am totally capable
of doing that right now.
Good. There are documents
in a manila envelope on my desk.
I'd get them myself, but I'm stuck here.
Oh, yeah. Sure. No problem.
I'll... I'll pick them up
and swing by first thing in the morning.
- See you then.
- Yes, you will!
No, no, no. No more cookies.
- No, that’s enough.
- [children continue giggling]
I gotta go. I got to parent here.
- No, seriously. That's five. We're done.
- [children giggling]
What was that about?
It's a secret!
I get told secrets now. No big deal.
Well, you can tell me, too!
Peters just left some paperwork
at the restaurant
that I have to go pick up.
Well, I am in!
Well...
This is my fourth glass,
so, I can't drive.
- [Clara chuckles]
- Ah!
I'll get Clive to drive!
Clive, this is where I work.
- All right. Come on in.
- [Bonnie] Whoa!
Hugh's office.
Really nice. I like it.
OK, what are we looking for again?
A yellow envelope. Like this.
[cabinet drawer clunking]
Honey, I... I think that might be locked.
No, it's just stuck.
B-Bonnie, I...
- See!
- [Clara] Bonnie, I...
I got it.
Me too!
I probably think it's this one
that was on his desk
exactly where he told me
it was gonna be.
Well, this is yellow as well,
so, I think it deserves a look.
This is a...
Oh, this is Shane's contract.
That's a lot of zeros.
This one's just a lot of parking lots.
What?
- Pretty boring!
- [Clara] Oh...
Oh, no, no.
This is, uh... this is just our, uh...
What?
You've got to be kidding me.
What? Is it about me?
Clive, you're a city planner, right?
Correct. Why?
Because we need to go to your office.
- Yay! Oh, my gosh.
- No, no, no.
- Yes!
- We don't do that.
- Oh, we're going!
- Or-- You know what?
- [Jackie] Aw.
- [Frank] Here.
Ah, you know, we forgot
to share the mistletoe.
That's because
we don't need any mistletoe.
- [Frank] Hmm. We don't.
- [knocking at the door]
Shoot. Who's it?
[Frank] Hey! Look who came in
- from the cold. Come here!
- [Jackie] Merry Christmas, Shane!
[Shane] Merry Christmas.
[Jackie] Aw! Oh!
- I'm not intruding at all, am I?
- No, of course not.
Absolutely not! You know
we love guests at Christmas.
OK.
Oh! You look like you could use
something to eat.
How about I make you a nice sandwich,
or Frank can make you a drink?
I'd love a sandwich.
OK, you got it.
- Thanks, honey.
- Thanks, Jackie.
Come on. Take your jacket off.
Make yourself at home.
- Thanks so much.
- You're welcome.
[indistinct conversation]
- [Clara] Bonnie!
- This is great.
This is so exciting!
[Clive] I don't know why I'm doing this.
- This is insane.
- Come on. Please, Clive.
You're doing it because
it's an exciting secret mission.
And because you love me.
Get in. Get in. Quietly.
[inaudible]
- But we love him.
- Yeah.
When I first came here,
I didn't--I didn't tell you guys
what I was looking for.
And I didn't... didn't show you this.
Aw.
[Shane] That's my parents
on their honeymoon.
Yeah, that picture hung up in our kitchen
for as long as I can remember.
They never really said where they took it,
and I didn't really ask
because I was a kid.
But they said it was somewhere
in the American mountainside,
and that one day they'd...
they'd visit again.
But--But they--they never did.
And you think they stayed here?
[Shane] I don't know.
I don't know. I kind of...
You know, I've been ruling out
some of the other places in the area,
but most of them have been
torn down or long closed.
Yeah. I'm so sorry.
I don't recognize them at all.
Of course, this doesn't mean anything
because when this photo was taken
my parents would've been
running the place,
and I would've just been a little kid.
- But, honey, I do recognize that cushion.
- Hmm.
Yeah, yeah.
That's--That's the one right over there.
Yeah, but the trouble is these cushions
are all over the place, you know.
Right.
I--I don't know if it helps,
but on the back
- is a... a date stamped there.
- Hmm.
- Oh, in the 80's.
- Oh! Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You see, we had a fire here in '92,
and it destroyed almost all the records.
Otherwise, we could've looked up
their names in the log book.
[Shane] Right. Yeah, I was...
I was just hoping to find
that ornament, but...
if it were here, you guys probably...
probably auctioned it off anyways.
[Frank] Yeah.
[Jackie] Whoa!
- What?
- Wait, wait, wait a minute.
Wait. Here, check this out.
Here, take this. Take this.
OK.
Oh, there's no way.
I thought you guys would've...
I thought...
I thought you guys would've sold these.
Well... yes, we would've,
but not that one.
That one is special.
That one my mother made the year
they built this place.
And every Christmas Eve we have
our guests put it on the tree.
So, if your parents stayed here
over Christmas...
they would've been asked
to do the honors.
It's our way of making our guests
feel like they're family
at Christmas time.
[sobs]
So, they were here.
They were here.
[Frank] So, Shane...
would you like to do the honors?
You know, I...
I'd actually like to share this
with someone.
If that's OK.
[voice breaking] Thank you for this.
Did you find it yet?
I literally just started looking!
It's, uh... Peters. Hugh Peters.
- [Bonnie scoffs]
- [Bonnie] Hugh.
- Oh. OK, here it is.
It looks like he's made
some exploratory proposals.
What?
[Bonnie] What is it?
It's just a bunch of condos,
or parking lots, and...
Wait, this is not what we talked about.
- I don't understand what this is.
- [Clive] Let me take these
and make a copy.
You can read them in the morning, Clara.
And then you are gonna destroy them.
And then we'll pretend
that this never happened. OK?
OK.
- All right.
- [Clara] Thank you.
I love you guys! Bonnie and Clive!
[all chuckle]
- We're criminals!
- [Clive] Oh, heaven help me.
[all chuckle]
[Lydia humming a Christmas song]
Oh, Merry Christmas, sunshine.
Merry Christmas, Mom. Thank you.
Oh. Someone had
a little bit too much fun last night.
Mm-hmm.
[Lydia chuckles]
[sighs]
Where'd you find these?
They were scattered in the foyer.
I--
[Lydia continues humming]
I can't believe he did this.
How about a bagel and lox?
A Bloody Mary?
[Clara] Mom, I'm so sorry.
I promise I'll be back, OK?
I just have to do something.
No breakfast?
[car approaching]
[knocking on door]
[Hugh] Yeah, I'm coming!
Clara.
- Did you get the folder?
- Oh, you mean Shane's contract? Yes.
Thanks. I have to get these off
this morning.
And there's this!
You don't want to renovate
the Mountain View.
You don't want to "restore it
to its former glory".
You want to tear it down
for condos, and concessions
and parking lots!
[Hugh] These are just
exploratory proposals.
Where did you get these?
You used me
to get to Frank and Jackie.
[Hugh] And you couldn't even
get that done.
They called me this morning
to tell me that the deal is dead.
Yeah, it turns out your boyfriend Shane
convinced them to shut it down.
I never should've trusted that guy.
He's not my boyfriend.
And Shane's in New York.
[Hugh snickers]
Is that--Is that what he said?
Yeah, it looks like Santa's flying past
both of our houses this Christmas.
Yeah, well, you can take
your stupid necklace back, too.
I hope you realize you're fired!
Oh, I quit!
[engine turning over]
Come on!
- [knocking on the car]
- What?
[Shane] Merry Christmas.
Can I give you a ride?
[chuckles] Come on.
[railroad crossing
bells blaring]
[train whistling in the distance]
- [Shane] It's a long train.
- [sighs]
How did you even find me?
I went to your mother's house.
Well, she told me
that you were at Bonnie and Clive's.
And so I went there and, um...
I mean, they told me about
your little crime spree last night.
And then I kind of figured out
where you might be headed.
Look, I know it sounds crazy,
but I went to the office,
there were two envelopes and--
[Shane] I didn't come here for the job.
I came here because
I was looking for something,
that promise that I made to myself.
And that's why I went
to the Mountain View.
And that's why I was there last night.
These are my parents.
Their honeymoon was the one and only
vacation that they ever took.
You know, they lived in New York City,
and they could...
they could barely make ends meet, so...
it was really difficult for them.
My father was a cook at a greasy spoon.
My mother was a server.
And as a kid I saw...
I saw how hard they struggled
in their careers, you know.
[chuckles] But I guess that's...
that's where I developed
my love for cooking.
When I started to get successful
I promised them that I'd slow down
and find myself a beautiful little spot
like the one
that started them off so right.
But I--I didn't.
Three years ago,
my mother died of cancer.
Another year later, my father suffered
a massive heart attack.
So, here I am... [sighs]
three years too late,
trying to make good
on a promise to a family
that I didn't even deserve.
You know any family
would be lucky to have you.
That's really sweet.
Now, come on.
I want to show you something.
[geese honking in the distance]
[Shane] Come on in.
[both] Merry Christmas!
- Merry Christmas.
Dinner will be served
in the main dining room
in a few minutes.
I would actually like to give you
your Christmas present.
It's just like the picture.
Mm-hmm.
Well, would you do the honors?
Please?
[Frank] Gotcha!
That's the most thoughtful gift
anyone could ever give me.
Oh, that's not your gift.
- What?
- No, no. This is your gift.
It took me a long time to figure out
what I wanted to do
for the rest of my life.
But when the picture
brought me to you...
I knew that this... [chuckles]
this was the right choice.
Jackie and Frank
have agreed to sell their hotel.
But only to you.
Shane, I can't afford that.
I want to invest...
solely in your business, Clara...
because you deserve it.
You can fix this place up
any way you want.
Jackie and Frank have agreed
to stick around and work for you.
I mean, I'd like to hand in my resume
for the head chef, of course,
and do all the cooking...
minus the Eggs Florentine.
But you don't have to hire me.
You don't have to do anything
you don't want...
because it's all yours.
Can it be ours?
I love you.
You should know...
I just got you a scarf.
[laughing] That's just what I wanted.
Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas.
[TV reporter] A nine-year-old metro girl
- got a new lease on life...
- [Clive] Hey, Bonnie.
So, my friend Mario
is a liftie over at the gondola.
And he says he could sneak us
up the mountain for a late night ski.
You want to go?
You mean another exciting mission? Yes!
- See! I knew you weren't boring.
- [Clive chuckles]
All right! Let's go do this.
- Now? Oh, OK!
- Right now! Right now!
This is your Grandma's favorite.
She loves it.
- She loves her Auntie Clara.
- [Clara chuckles]
That's a pretty dress!
[Lydia] Shane!
There you are.
I've been meaning to talk to you.
I've been watching your show.
Uh, Ms. Garrison,
I'm gonna have to explain.
Uh, you see on the show,
we have these personas.
- [baby murmuring]
- Yeah, he's not actually that bad.
Yeah. I'm really not.
Uh, Clara, I know that
he's playing a character. [chuckles]
And your brilliant, OK.
- [exhales]
- That's exactly why I want
to pick your brain.
See, I've been thinking
about branding myself
in the gourmet gingerbread
market. Mm-hmm.
- [Shane] Oh! Uh...
- Yeah!
Uh, yeah, listen, I have like three
or four contacts in that market.
Really? I was featured
in Seasons Magazine.
Oh, is that right?
- She tells everyone!
- I should've been on the cover.
But, you know, it was like
a two-page spread. It was great!
I will be right back, I've got a copy.
Matter of fact,
I'm going to autograph it for you.
- [stutters] I'll cheers to that!
- All right. Cheers!
[all] Cheers! Happy New Year!
["Auld Lang Syne" plays]