NARRATOR: One time a year
there's a marvelous night,
when enchantment and wonder
spark and take flight.
Each home fills with joy
on this grand holiday,
with hearts growing warm
in a magical way.
The rooms are all covered
with garlands and wreaths.
The mantel is ready,
with stockings beneath.
Lights twinkle and glow
and bells brightly chime.
The moment's arrived! It's here!
Christmas time.
Three precious gifts lie under this tree.
What secrets they hold?
Let's look, and we'll see.
The first tells a story for us all to hear,
about laughter and family
and those we hold dear.
We love Christmas so much
we want it to stay,
but what if we wished
it was here every day?
(TICKING)
(SNORING)
Anchors aweigh!
Full steam ahead!
Swab the decks, you...
(SNORING IN TUNE)
(IMITATING TRAIN WHISTLE)
(LAUGHING)
All aboard. Next stop, Waterville!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- It's here!
- The one!
The only!
ALL: Best day of the year!
It's Christmas!
Oh, boy! Just what we always wanted!
Hey, look at this!
Cool!
Merry Christmas, boys! What the...
(EXCLAIMS)
(CLATTERING)
You know we have to wait for the family!
Sorry, Uncle Donald.
Aw... It's Christmas,
and I've got a special surprise for you!
ALL: Yeah! (LAUGHING)
But, boys, you didn't... (GRUNTS)
HUEY: Sorry, Uncle Donald.
- ...even read the...
- DEWEY: Sorry, Uncle Donald.
- ...card!
- Bye, Uncle Donald.
- We'll read it later.
- (SIGHS)
Merry Christmas, everybody!
Merry Christmas, indeed!
Where are my boys?
Where are my kisses?
Oh, I could just eat you up!
(CHUCKLES)
- (KISSING)
- (BOYS GRUNTING)
Oh... Ugh! Ew...
DAISY: Oh, Donald?
(GULPS)
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy!
HUEY: Hi, Daisy! Bye, Daisy.
Catch you later!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yow!
(GOBBLING)
LOUIE: Last one down the hill's
a rotten egg!
DEWEY: Not me!
Boys? Dinner!
If there's one thing better...
...than Christmas presents...
...it's Christmas dinner!
Isn't this lovely?
All of us gathered for a wonderful meal?
I think this is
my favorite part of Christmas.
Ooh! Turkey!
Donald? Would you like to carve?
(GOBBLING)
Boys! Where are your manners?
(BURPS)
This turkey is so good!
Your gravy never has lumps!
ALL: We love your cooking, Aunt Daisy!
(YELLING)
Donald! They're just enjoying
my Christmas dinner.
Ah, phooey! (MUTTERS)
All right. Who's for caroling?
Aw, we don't want to sing,
Uncle Scrooge!
We want to play with our toys!
(SINGING) We wish you
a merry Christmas
We wish you a merry Christmas
And a happy New Year
(CHIMING)
DONALD: Bedtime, boys.
Not yet!
Christmas can't be over already.
Good night, boys!
Aw!
- What a great day!
- We should do it more often.
Yeah! Once a week should be enough.
It'll be another 365 days
until we get more Christmas.
"Star light, star bright,
"First star I see tonight,
"I wish I may, I wish I might
"Have the wish I wish tonight."
ALL: We wish
it was Christmas every day.
(IMITATING TRAIN WHISTLE)
(LAUGHING)
All aboard. Next stop, Waterville!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(SNORING)
Boy, those guys sure
like that choo-choo.
They gotta play with
that thing again today?
Hey! Let's play with our new toys.
LOUIE: Whoa!
They're gone.
Hey! What is this?
DEWEY: (GASPS) Whoa!
Didn't we open these yesterday?
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
There's only one way to find out.
We're gonna have to open
these presents.
(RATTLING)
DONALD: Merry Christmas!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
- Whoa!
- Uncle Donald, we did it.
It's Christmas again. Uncle Donald...
It's Christmas again, Uncle Donald.
TWo days in a row!
Aw!
You boys must have been dreaming.
Hey! We almost forgot
about our special surprise!
Whoa!
Where are my kisses?
Oh, I could just eat you up!
(CHUCKLES)
- (KISSING)
- (BOYS GRUNTING)
Oh...
(SPITTING)
We should have seen that one coming.
(BOYS LAUGHING)
Last one down the hill's a rotten egg!
Again!
(GOBBLING)
Boys? Dinner!
Isn't this lovely?
All of us gathered for a wonderful meal?
I think this is
my favorite part of Christmas.
Ooh, turkey!
Boys! Where are your manners?
(BURPING)
(YELLING)
Donald! They're just enjoying
my Christmas dinner.
(GULPS)
(SINGING) We wish you
a merry Christmas
We wish you a merry Christmas
(CHIMING)
Good night, boys!
(LAUGHING)
That was great!
Double great!
Ah! Yeah.
(IMITATING TRAIN WHISTLE)
All aboard. Next stop, Waterville!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- Yeah!
- All right!
Merry Christmas, boys.
Huh? (EXCLAIMS)
- Look out, Uncle Donald.
- (CLATTERING)
Merry Christmas, everybody!
Merry Christmas, indeed!
Where are my boys?
Where are my kisses?
(ALL YELLING)
DONALD: Oh, no, you don't.
I'm gonna make you...
(BOYS PROTESTING)
- AUNT GERTIE: Oh! (KISSING)
- (BOYS GRUNTING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
DAISY: I think this is
my favorite part of Christmas.
(BURPS)
(SINGING) We wish you
a merry Christmas
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
- (CHIPMUNKS LAUGHING)
Merry Christmas, boys!
Huh? (EXCLAIMS)
(CLANGING)
(DOOR OPENS)
DAISY: Merry Christmas, everybody!
Oh, I could just eat you up!
DAISY: This is
my favorite part of Christmas.
(SINGING) We wish you
a merry Christmas
(CHIMING)
(DALE IMITATING TRAIN WHISTLE)
CHIP: (LAUGHING) All aboard.
Next stop, Waterville!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
You can stop Christmas now!
- Please!
(CHIMING)
All aboard. Next stop, Waterville!
Where are my kisses?
(CHIMING)
(LAUGHING)
All aboard. Next stop, Waterville!
- ...favorite part of Christmas.
- (CHIMING)
Who's for caroling?
- (YELLING)
(LAUGHING)
All aboard. Next stop, Waterville!
(DALE IMITATING
TRAIN WHISTLING)
(BOTH YELLING)
(CHUCKLES) Looks like
the end of the line!
(CHIPMUNKS LAUGHING)
Until tomorrow.
When it happens all over again.
You're right. Yesterday's today,
and today is tomorrow,
and it's gonna be the same thing,
day in and day out,
and day in and day out...
Hey! What's wrong? Get a grip!
I'm sorry, fellas.
That's okay. We know how you feel.
If I see the same toys again,
I'll go out of my mind!
Yeah, and if I eat any more turkey,
(CHUCKLES)
I'm gonna need new clothes!
We gotta do something
to liven things up.
LOUIE: (IMITATES STATIC)
Green Leader to Red Leader.
DEWEY: (IMITATES STATIC)
Initiate Pancake Intercept Sequence.
LOUIE: (IMITATES STATIC) Roger.
(DONALD YELLING)
Uh-oh.
(YELLING)
Donald!
Stop playing with the boys' presents.
Where are my boys?
Where are my kisses?
Ooh!
Oh...
Right here, Aunt Gertie.
(BOYS LAUGHING)
Isn't this lovely?
All of us gathered for a wonderful meal?
I think this is
my favorite part of Christmas.
- (GOBBLING)
- Oh!
Turkey!
(BOYS LAUGHING)
(YELLING)
(NOTES PLAYING)
- (STRINGS POPPING)
- (THUDS)
Not the piano! Not my beloved carols!
- (GOBBLING)
- (YELLING)
(STRUGGLING)
(TURKEY YELLING)
Gobble, gobble, gobble.
Well, we still have the tree.
(GASPS)
Let's get out of here
before Uncle Donald gets mad!
Hey, we'll be outside if you need us.
(GASPS)
Donald? Are you all right?
"To Huey, Dewey, and Louie.
"Christmas isn't about
candy canes, holly,
"or lights all aglow.
"It's about the hearts that we touch
and the care that we show.
"Wishing you lots of love,
"Donald and Daisy."
Oh, some Christmas
this turned out to be.
Gee, I don't know about you guys,
but I don't ever want to do that again.
- Me too.
- Me three.
DEWEY: Tomorrow, let's have
the best Christmas ever.
(GRUNTING)
We're sure putting
these sleds to good use!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
DEWEY: Incoming!
Merry Christmas, fellas.
Huh?
Look!
We made you breakfast, Uncle Donald.
Aw! Isn't that nice?
Hey, you want to open presents?
No way, Uncle Donald.
We gotta wait for the family to get here.
Merry Christmas, everybody!
Merry Christmas, indeed!
Don't forget our Christmas kisses,
Aunt Gertie.
Hey, what are they up to?
You boys are so wonderful!
That looks heavy!
ALL: Let us help you!
Why, isn't that sweet? Thank you, boys.
Ooh! Ham!
Uncle Donald, would you like to carve?
Something's up for sure.
Nothing better than
all of us gathering together...
- ...for a wonderful meal.
- It's our most favorite part.
(GOBBLING)
My feelings exactly.
How about some carols,
Uncle Scrooge?
Why, boys, it's like
you could read my mind.
(SINGING) We wish you
a merry Christmas
We wish you a merry Christmas
We wish you a...
What's the big idea?
What are you boys up to?
Why, Donald Duck!
You're spoiling a perfect Christmas.
Nah, Uncle Donald is right.
We are up to something.
ALL: Merry Christmas, Uncle Donald!
HUEY: See?
It's your dream boat, Uncle Donald.
- Oh, thank you, boys.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, how beautiful.
Some Christmas
this has turned out to be.
Oh, I'm just so happy!
(LAUGHING)
(SINGING) We wish you
a merry Christmas
We wish you a merry Christmas
And a happy New Year
(ALL SNORING)
DONALD: Oh, boys!
Come give me a push!
- (CHUCKLES)
- (DOOR OPENS)
(LAUGHING)
- It's over! Christmas is finally over!
- (CHEERING)
The day after Christmas!
Aw, I understand, boys.
You wish it could be Christmas
every day.
ALL: No!
Anchors aweigh!
Full steam ahead?
Whoa! Whoa!
Uh-oh!
Oh, no!
Man overboard!
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS) (SHIVERS)
Whoa!
DONALD: Why does this always
happen to me? I don't understand.
NARRATOR: So, Christmas was meant
to last just one day,
and maybe it's simply better that way.
It's a time to be treasured.
It can't always be here,
but the feeling it gives us
can last the whole year.
Now, this gift holds a story
both wondrous and rare,
about a father and a son
and the love that they share.
This Christmas, they'll learn
before the night's through,
if we care for each other,
our dreams can come true.
GOOFY: (SINGING)
Hark, the hairy angels sing
Come on, Maxie!
At least hum a few bars.
MAX: Dad, hurry up!
Deck the walls with cows and collies
Fa la-la la la la-la la la
The mailman comes at noon, Dad!
Hmm, let's see now.
Uh... Oh! How about one of them
snazzy electrical recliners?
Yeah, Dad. Whatever.
Naw, don't want to turn
into some highfalutin fancy-pants.
Yeah, yeah. Great, Dad. But Santa
won't get our letter if we don't leave
now!
- (GASPS)
- Whoa!
(YELLING)
(CAR HONKING)
Hold on, Dad! We're taking a shortcut.
Maybe we ought to slow her down
before we break the sound barrier!
- What?
- We're headed straight for the mall!
Great idea!
Whoa!
(ALL CLAMORING)
- Low bridge!
- Really? Where? Ow!
Go on ahead
and stop the mailman, son!
I'll be right behind you! Don't worry!
I won't let you down!
(WHOOPING)
- (THUDS)
- (WOMEN SCREAMING)
'Scuse me!
- (WOMAN SCREAMS)
- Oops!
Pardon me, ma'am!
Didn't mean to get fresh!
(CHUCKLES)
Wait! Wait!
Hey! There's a madman
on the ornament!
WOMAN: There he goes!
MAN: What is he doing?
Oh!
(GASPING)
(CHEERING)
(SCREAMING)
Oops. Sorry.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Wait! Stop!
You have to mail our letter to Santa!
Hey, get out of the road, kid!
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPS) Ow!
Whoa! Wow!
(YELLING)
Whoa!
Do you have anything bigger?
I have an empty space right here.
(GASPS)
Ooo! I'll take it!
Phew.
(YELLS)
(SCREAMING)
But my dad's gonna be here
any minute! Honest!
Sorry, kid.
- (GOOFY YELLING)
- Gotta go.
(PANTING)
(SLOBBERING)
Special delivery for the North Pole.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, man.
You really think Santa
will get the letter in time?
Sure as I'm standing here.
Whoa! Ow.
Slippery.
I gotta get it. I just gotta.
My very own, one-of-a-kind,
carbon-fiber, torque-rod, snappy-flex,
tip-to-tail, rail-to-rail, wooden core,
twin-directional snowboard!
Phew, that's a mouthful.
With adjustable forward-lean,
high-backed, skid plate,
scooper-toe, step-in bindings!
Look at this. All nice
and neat and ready for ol' Santy.
(MACHINE HUMMING)
(GRUNTING)
Merry Christmas Eve, Pete!
Why, if it ain't the Goofmaster himself.
Say, we got us
some more work to do, Max,
or Santy's never gonna
find our chimney...
(YELLING)
(THUDS)
(LAUGHING) Ain't that quaint.
The Goofbrain
thinks there's a Santy Claus.
There isn't?
(LAUGHING)
Like father, like Goof.
Kid's got the Goof gene
coursing through his bloodstream.
There is too a Santa! Whoa!
(GRUNTS)
Aw, now, son. Come here.
See, it's an urbane myth,
like that, "Locked Mess Monstrosity."
And the fella that brings
the sweepstakes checks, see?
Well, think of it. An old guy in a red suit,
cruising the whole,
entire world in one night.
Using reindeer what fly?
Why, it's practically impossible!
Look, kid. I've been around, see?
Been to all the foreign lands,
Brooklyn included.
And I never seen,
nor met a soul who's seen,
this Santy Claus fella.
Look, Maxie! I found the front door!
So long, neighbors.
Have a very merry Christmas.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, and a happy New Year.
(SINGING) Doh, doh, doh, doh,
cows and collies
Di, di, di, di, di, doo, doo
Hey!
How about giving your old man a hand?
What is it, Maxie?
Why, you look like Santy Claus
put a lump of coal in your stocking.
I heard there isn't any Santa Claus.
Oh, who went and told you
a silly thing like that?
- Mr. Pete.
- Oh, that figures.
Son, of course there's a Santy!
Otherwise we'd have a lot of
out-of-work elves running around.
You think?
Think? Heck, I'm sure.
You take it from me, son.
Have I ever been wrong?
- Well...
- Why, even a broken clock
is right two or three times a day.
And this time, I'm right!
Believe me. Santa won't let you down.
Do you really think he'll come?
Why, as sure as pigs fly!
Hey, Dad.
What'd you ask for from Santa?
Oh, you know, just the usual.
What's that?
(WHISPERING) It's a surprise.
Now, plug her in
and let the joy of Christmas shine!
(BULBS SHATTERING)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- Wow!
Phew. Now that'll put
the spirit of Christmas in you.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
'Course there's a Santa.
GOOFY: Believe me,
Santa won't let you down.
An old guy, in a red suit,
cruising the whole,
entire world in one night?
Using reindeer what fly?
Why, it's practically impossible!
Impossible! Impossible!
Hiya, Maxie! Wanna help?
Did you know that there were over
two billion children in the world?
Hmm, no wonder
I keep tripping over roller skates.
That means Santa would have to
make like 800 visits a second,
not including bathroom breaks.
Well, I guess ol' Santy's
been at it so long,
he figured out all the shortcuts.
(STRUGGLING)
Oh!
(CHUCKLES) Looks like it's gonna be
a white Christmas after all!
Dad! This is serious!
Oh, I know, son, but...
(SNIFFING)
Gosh, something sure smells
mighty tasty!
(YELLING)
Ah...
But how can a reindeer fly?
Oh, that's easy. It's those antlers. They...
Well, you know, with the wind and all...
That there creates lift, and...
Hot, hot, hot, hot! Hot, hot!
Still, it's a lot of work for one guy.
And that's why
we leave him these cookies
for a quick pick-me-up, up... Whoa!
But it just doesn't
quite make sense, Dad.
Mmm, chestnuts.
(GOOFY HUMMING)
Where are we going, Dad?
Going to share
the joy of Christmas with those
a little less fortunate.
Well, shouldn't Santa be doing this?
Oh, Santy's on a very tight schedule
this time of year,
so we're giving him a helping hand.
Whoa!
(CHUCKLES)
Looks like I might need one, too.
(LAUGHING)
(IMITATING CAR ENGINES)
Hey.
Wanna play toy "carses"?
I only gots two, but you can have one.
Santa gave me this one last year.
This year I hope
he's gonna give me another one.
You know, kid,
I ain't so sure there is such a thing as...
Christmas Eve dinner is served!
Whoa!
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHING)
Oh!
- MAN: (CHUCKLES) Oh, my!
- CHILDREN: Wow!
- Mr. Goofy, that's incredible!
- That was like magic!
Gosh! (CHUCKLES)
Christmas magic.
- Thank you so much.
- With things being so tight this year,
well, without you, we wouldn't have...
Aw, don't mention it. (CHUCKLES)
You'd do the same for me.
But have you ever really
actually seen Santa?
He's got a big white beard.
But have you ever
actually seen him in person?
- Where?
- (RUSTLING)
Ho, ho, ho!
- Merry Christmas!
- Santa!
(GASPS) Santa?
- You made it!
MAX: Did you get my letter?
It's Santa!
Who wants to be the first
to sit on Santy's lap?
- Me, me, me! Here!
- Santa, me!
Santa, me! Pick me!
I'm so glad you came! Wow!
I almost didn't believe anymore.
But now...
Phew.
Everything's okay.
So, I want my very own
one-of-a-kind, carbon-fiber,
torque-rod, snappy-flex, tip-to-tail,
rail-to-rail, twin-directional snowboard.
Uh, please.
(LAUGHING)
Dad?
Oh...
You tricked me! How could you?
Uh... Ho, ho...
Santy's got a little problem
with one of his elves,
but he'll be right back...
Gosh, Maxie, I'm real sorry.
I was just trying
to make those kids happy.
Remember the old Goof tradition
of eating one of Santy's cookies
before bedtime?
What's the point?
And remember
how we always open just one present
on Christmas Eve?
(HIGH-PITCHED) Hiya, Maxie!
(NORMAL VOICE) Why, looky here.
It's your ol' stuffed bear.
- Remember what you named him?
- Old Stuffed Bear.
Remember who gave him to you?
Yeah. Santa.
But that's when I was little.
(SINGING) Oh, you better watch out
You better not cry
You better not pout
I'm a-telling you why
Santy Claus is coming to town
- No, he's not!
- (HIGH-PITCHED) Trust me, Max.
You just gotta believe. Santy's real.
- No, he's not!
- (NORMAL VOICE) Yes, he is!
No, he's not!
(CLATTERING)
I promise.
Then prove it!
When Santy shows up,
we'll be right here to greet him.
And then I'll snap a picture of him
so you'll always have
the photographic evidence.
(SCOFFS) Yeah.
If you don't fall off the roof first.
Oh, I won't fall off the roof, Maxie.
You just watch.
(SLEIGH BELLS RINGING)
Santy Claus is coming to town!
Oh!
Bright!
(DOG BARKING)
Whoa!
Ooh!
Told you you'd fall off the roof.
I didn't fall off the roof. Whoa!
Where's Santy? I didn't miss him, did I?
- Nope.
- Then where is he?
I don't know about you,
but I'm cold and tired.
And Santa Claus is not coming.
(SNIFFLING)
(SNEEZES)
(CREAKING)
Why doesn't he just grow up
and face the facts?
"Don't forget
"Max."
Aw, Dad.
GOOFY: Max! Wake up! Look, son!
Look! It's him! It really is!
Do you see him, Maxie?
Do you? Huh? Huh? Do you?
Yoo-hoo! Santy! Over here!
Oh, I almost forgot.
Smile, Santy!
- Dad, the lens cap!
- Oops!
I'll get it right this time for sure.
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
Come down from the roof
with your hands up.
We have you surrounded.
What in the name of Pete
is going on here, for Pete's sake?
Maybe he's running a little late?
Whoa!
Dad! Dad!
Are you okay?
You were right about everything.
I even fell off the roof.
Hey, Dad, it's okay.
So Santa didn't show. No biggie.
Well, since he's not coming,
at least we can eat all his cookies.
I'm not hungry.
Hey, Dad.
Here's something from me!
Open her up.
Maybe later.
(SINGING) Oh, you better watch out
You better not cry
You better not pout I'm telling you why
'Cause Santa Claus is coming to town
(SIGHS)
(CLATTERING)
Max?
(GASPS) Burglars!
Whoa!
(GASPS)
(STUTTERING) Santy!
Ho, ho, (CLEARS THROAT) ho.
Merry Christmas!
Santy! I'm so happy you came!
Gosh. I thought you'd be taller.
And you look trimmer
than you do in your pictures.
Oh, well, you know,
a camera adds 50 pounds.
You have to meet my boy Maxie!
Oh, yeah. I'd love to,
but I gotta get going.
TWo billion kids, 823 a second.
Very tight schedule.
Wait, Santy!
He's around here somewheres.
Wait! Santy!
Santy!
(GASPS)
- Maxie?
- Hi, Dad.
What are you doing
dressed up like Santy Claus?
I just wanted to make you happy,
like you did for our neighbors.
Oh, Maxie, I might have let you down,
but you sure didn't let me down.
(SLEIGH BELLS RINGING)
Could it be? Do you think?
Gosh, it sure looks like
- Santa Claus!
- Santa Claus?
I believe it is.
Wow. My very own, one-of-a-kind,
carbon-fiber, torque-rod, snappy-flex,
tip-to-tail, rail-to-rail,
wood core, torsionally stiff,
twin-directional snowboard!
(SNIFFS)
Thanks, Santa.
What's all the commotion out here?
If it's another robber,
I'm gonna get him...
Ooh! Santa?
Well, hey! Hey, Santa!
I believed in you all along!
For real and for true!
So where are my presents?
SANTA CLAUS: Ho, ho, ho!
Merry Christmas!
But what about my squirty gun
and my yo-yo?
I know you can hear me!
Santa didn't forget your gift, did he?
Every year I ask or the same gift,
and every year, I get it.
- What's that?
- Your happiness.
Uh-oh.
What is it, son?
(CHUCKLES) Got you the same thing.
Merry Christmas, Dad.
Merry Christmas, Max.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go share my new present
with little Jimmy next door.
That's my boy.
(LAUGHING)
NARRATOR: So, Christmas is found
in the way that we live.
Not what we receive,
but what we can give.
Now the last present here
may seem rather small,
not fancy or flashy, or special at all.
But this gift can be given
by the rich or the poor.
It's a gift of the heart,
and it means so much more.
Thanks, Joe! Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas, George.
You working tonight?
Not tonight! It's Christmas Eve!
(PLAYING)
(BARKING)
There it is, Pluto,
the perfect gift
to go with Minnie's watch.
(SIGHS) My Minnie.
They close at 5:00?
Well, I'm a little short right now,
but you and I are gonna make
lots of tips today.
- Aren't we, fella?
- Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! (PANTING)
We'll stop by right after work
and pick it up.
Come on. Let's get this tree
over to Minnie's.
(BARKING)
MINNIE: Oh, Figaro,
there's nothing but bills!
(MEOWS)
How am I ever going to afford
to get Mickey a present?
(DOOR OPENS)
(PURRING)
Aw, Mickey! (GIGGLES)
When you play your harmonica,
my heart sings!
You know, an instrument like that
deserves a special case.
Oh, yeah. Someday.
(SINGING) La la-la-la la la
Come on into the kitchen.
Breakfast is almost ready.
(SHRIEKS)
You sure I'm not eating you
out of house and home?
'Course not, silly. I have plenty.
Ta-da!
Aw, for me?
Uh-huh! (GIGGLES)
You wouldn't happen
to have the time, would you, Minnie?
- Well, let's see. It's...
- Gosh.
Sure is a beautiful watch!
MINNIE: (SIGHS) My one heirloom.
I'll bet it'd look real nice
with a gold chain
around your pretty neck.
- MINNIE: Aw, Mickey.
- (MICKEY CHUCKLES)
Oh, my goodness! I've gotta go to work!
Madam, your sleigh awaits!
Oh, how wonderful.
(IMITATES HORSE)
Giddyap, Pluto!
(GIGGLES)
See you tonight!
- Come on, fella. We got work to do!
- (BARKING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
PETE: (RECORDED)
Welcome to Crazy Pete's Tree Lot!
Hurry, folks.
Only one more day till Christmas!
Easy credit, no money down!
(LAUGHS)
Hey! This stuff works pretty good!
(CHUCKLING)
Merry Christmas, Mr. Crazy Pete.
Aw, merry-shmerry. I'll be merry
when I've sold all those 10-footers!
Why are you standing there
with your face hanging out?
Get to work!
Okay, fella. You know what to do.
Shake a leg!
PETE: Quit slacking over there!
There's a customer waiting!
Oh, do be careful of the paint.
- Yes, ma'am!
- Such a nice young man.
Here's a little something for you.
Gosh, I don't expect anything.
I'm just glad to help.
Oh, boy! Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you!
Hot dog! Looks like I'll finally be able
to get Minnie that chain for her watch.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Uh, we'd like to buy a tree...
Did I hear you folks
are looking for a tree?
Boy, oh, boy! Is this your lucky day!
(CHUCKLES)
This here's what you folks need.
Ten feet of towering Nova Scotia pine.
Wow. It's bigger than our house.
Well, it's a little more than we need.
Well, missus,
I gotta be honest with you.
This is all I got left on the lot!
The others have been
"reservated" in advance.
You don't want these kids
going without a tree, now, do you?
(COUGHING)
We are gonna get a tree,
aren't we, Daddy?
Um, this is all we have.
Well, that'll be just fine
(CHUCKLES) for a down payment.
I'll set you up
with a nice installment plan.
All's you gotta do is sign here!
(SINGSONG) We're gonna get a tree
We're gonna get a tree
Get your foot off the brake, Pops.
The kids are waiting.
MICKEY: Hey! How about this tree?
I found it out back.
It hasn't been "reservated." (GULPS)
Wow!
It's beautiful.
It's perfect!
We'll take it.
(GROWLS)
MAN: Merry Christmas!
And thank you again.
- Thanks a lot!
- Merry Christmas!
- (GROWLING)
- So long! Merry...
Christmas.
I had them on the hook
for a 10-foot tree!
(CHUCKLES MEEKLY)
I'm taking what I would have made
off of that tree out of your pay!
(GROWLING)
But I...
(BARKING)
- Whoa!
- Now get off of my lot!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCOFFS) Chumps.
(SNIFFING)
Hmm, somebody's burning their ham.
(YELLING)
A little warm! It's hot!
(GRUNTING)
(SHRIEKING)
Incoming!
(GRUNTS)
- Not my 10-footers! (SOBBING)
- (SIRENS WAILING)
ANNOUNCER: Attention,
holiday shoppers!
Don't forget to bring
all your last-minute purchases
to our gift-wrapping department.
Oh, I've never seen it so busy.
Wow, Minnie, who made you
Santa's number-one helper?
Oh, I really want to get Mickey
something special this year.
Without that Christmas bonus,
I'm sunk!
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello? Okey-dokey. Bye.
Mr. Mortimer wants to see you
in his office, right away.
(GASPS) Oh, my Christmas bonus!
- Ginnie!
- Uh, that's Minnie.
Right. I've been making a list
and checking it twice,
and I found that you have been
Santa's best little helper this season!
Your hard work is about to be rewarded.
Close your eyes
and hold out your hands.
Oh, Mr. Mortimer,
I can't thank you enough.
Yes, I know. Now don't interrupt.
- Penny...
- That's Minnie.
Whatever. On behalf of
Mortimer's Department Store,
it gives me great pleasure
to present you with your
Christmas bonus!
- (MINNIE GRUNTS)
- (THUDS)
A fruitcake?
No need to thank me.
The expression on your face
is thanks enough. (CHUCKLES)
And now, scoot along.
Back to the gift-wrapping department,
where you belong.
Oh, and, Winnie. Merry Christmas!
Oh, Mickey.
How am I ever going to get
your present now?
There's just gotta be a way
to get Minnie's present by 5:00.
(PLAYING)
You got any ideas, fella?
(WHIMPERING)
Don't worry, boy.
We'll come up with something.
We just gotta.
(PLAYING)
Do you think the band
will ever show up?
I don't know.
They're putting out a fire
at the Crazy Pete Tree Lot.
Just went up like a Roman candle.
FIREFIGHTER: Uh, Chief?
Looks like the toy drive's a big fat bust.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Listen! That music!
(GASPS) Come on!
(GRUNTS)
Hmm?
MICKEY: Where we going, fellas?
FIRE CHIEF: A concert in the park.
Oh, look, bub. We're desperate.
We need music for the toy drive,
and you're our only hope!
I don't have time, Chief.
I gotta get a gift for my girl.
Look, pally, don't do it for us.
- Do it for the kids.
- But I...
Look, son. To these kids,
the only difference between
a broken heart and a smile is you!
You're on! Break a leg, pal.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
Look, I'm really sorry, but I can't stay.
I got some Christmas shopping
to do, you know, and...
Gosh.
(PLAYING)
(TROMBONE PLAYING)
The band is back!
FIREFIGHTER: Must have been
a hot one at Crazy Pete's.
(ALL CHEERING)
Well, guess I'll be
showing up at Minnie's empty-handed.
That was terrific!
(CHUCKLES) Thanks to you,
this was our best toy drive ever!
You and that harmonica
sure make a great team.
Yup. She's worth her weight
in gold, all right! (CHUCKLES)
Holy cow! That's it!
We've still got two minutes
to get to the shop!
- Come on, Pluto!
- (BARKING)
- Thanks, fellas!
- Goodbye!
- FIREFIGHTER: Thanks again!
- WOMAN: Merry Christmas!
(HORN HONKING)
(YAWNING)
Sorry!
MICKEY: Hey! What's going on?
(HORN HONKING)
Whoa!
(WHIMPERS)
This is our stop!
(BOTH GRUNT)
Oh, look! There's the shop.
(BELL TINKLING)
Oh, excuse me, sir.
I was just hoping to trade this
for a gift for my girl.
Well, sorry, son.
That harmonica isn't worth much.
Well, merry Christmas.
You're worth a lot to me, old friend.
(PLAYING)
(HOWLING)
(GROANS)
Say, maybe that harmonica
is worth something after all.
Come on in. Come on in.
(PLUTO BARKING)
- (PANTING)
- (MEOWS)
MICKEY: Can't wait
to open your present, can you, boy?
(CHUCKLES) I know just how you feel.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Oh! I love Christmas so much!
Say, Mickey,
why don't you play some music?
(LAUGHS)
Isn't it time we were
opening our presents?
And, speaking of time, what time is it?
Well, I think it's time
for you to open your gift.
Oh! A case for my harmonica.
Oh, my! A chain for my watch.
Oh, Mickey, it's beautiful.
But I traded my watch
to get you that case.
And I traded my harmonica
to get a chain for your watch.
Oh, Mickey! I can't believe you gave up
what means the most to you for me.
Oh, Minnie.
You're all the music I'll ever need.
(CHUCKLES)
(YAWNS)
(SIGHS)
Merry Christmas, Mickey.
Merry Christmas, Minnie.
MINNIE: Want some fruitcake?
(GIGGLES)
NARRATOR: A gift from the heart
is cherished and true.
A present is best
when love's given, too.
So, in the end,
it's love that's the reason
that Christmas is more
than a gift-giving season.
It's a time with our loved ones
to show that we care,
when families and neighbors
come together to share.
So, this Christmas season,
let us all do our parts,
to keep Christmas spirit
alive in our hearts.
(SINGING) What fun it is
to ride and sing
A sleighing song tonight
Jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the way
(HOWLS)
Oh, what fun it is to ride
In a one-horse open sleigh
Hey Jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the way
Oh, what fun it is to ride
In a one-horse open sleigh
- CHORUS: One-horse open sleigh
- One-horse open sleigh
One-horse open
(GIGGLING)
Deck the halls with boughs of holly
Fa-la-la la-la, la-la la la
Tis the season to be jolly
Don we now our gay apparel
Fa-la-la, la-la-la, la la la
Troll the ancient Yuletide carol
Fa-la-la la la, la-la la la
Fa-la-la la la la-la la la
(GOOFY CHUCKLES)
We wish you a merry Christmas
And a happy New Year
Good tidings we bring
to you and your kin
We wish you a merry Christmas
And a happy New Year
Deck the halls with boughs of holly
Fa-la-la la la
Those jingle, jingle bells
Deck the halls
With boughs of holly
Fa-la-la la la
Tis the season
We wish you a merry Christmas
Deck the halls with boughs of holly
Fa la-la la la la
Tis the season to be jolly
Don we now our gay apparel
Fa-la-la, fa la la la
Troll the ancient Yuletide carol
Fa-la-la la la, la-la la la
Everybody sing the Yuletide carol
Fa la-la la la la
Fa la-la la la, la-la la la, yeah
Merry, merry Christmas
A very merry Christmas
See the blazing Yule before us
Fa-la la la-la la-la la
Strike the harp and join the chorus
Fa-la-la la la, la-la la la
Follow us in merry measure
While I tell of Yuletide treasure
Fa-la-la la-la-la la
Deck the halls with boughs of holly
We wish you a merry Christmas
Tis the season to be jolly
Merry, merry Christmas
Yeah, yeah
Fa-la la la la la
Merry, merry Christmas
Yeah, merry, merry Christmas
Jingle, jangle
Santa's got a brand new bag