[childish laughing]
[children singing spookily]
[Georgie]
You'll float, too!
[Young Beverly]
I saw all of us.
All of us were there.
Back in the cistern.
But we were older.
We were our parents' ages.
Am I still handsome
as an adult?
[boys chuckling]
You grow into your looks.
- [Young Eddie laughs]
- What the flap does that mean?
What about me?
Like now,
but taller.
Swear it.
Swear if It isn't dead,
if It ever comes back,
we'll come back, too.
[Mike] Memory,
it's a funny thing.
People want to
believe they are
what they choose
to remember.
The good stuff.
The moments.
The places.
The people
we all hold on to.
[wind blowing]
But sometimes...
sometimes
we are what we wish
we could forget.
[children screaming]
[screaming]
- [carnival music playing]
- [lively chattering]
[carny] Okay, kids.
Get ready.
- Go!
- [bell dings]
Who's it gonna be?
First one to pop
their balloon's a winner!
It could be anyone!
We got a real
- barn burner here, folks.
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
[carny] It's getting close.
Who's gonna catch the
leader, huh?
Who's gonna be
the big winner tonight?
- Oh, yeah!
- Whoo!
[bell dinging]
Winner, winner,
chicken dinner.
- Thank you.
- Wow.
You really showed 'em, huh?
I did. I...
Yeah.
Hey, girl, do you want this?
[clicking tongue]
[whispering] Thanks
for letting me win.
Yeah.
[Victoria's mom]
What'd you get, Vicky?
[Don] Aww.
Such a gentleman.
[Victoria's mom]
Look at that!
Well, here is
your consolation prize.
Look at that.
Never been a fan
of the beaver,
but look at this hat.
I mean...
Thank you.
So, we need
to talk logistics.
Ooh. How romantic.
Romantic?
What's so
flaping romantic, huh?
- [spits]
- [Webby] Hey.
Your mommas ever teach you
boys to respond to someone
when they ask you
a flaping question?
Come on, Adrian.
You got a problem, faggot?
I don't,
but Meg Ryan called.
She wants her wig back.
[Don] All right. All right.
Come on.
Come on, Adrian.
Stuff like that is
why I have to leave
this shithole town.
Small minds.
They have small dicks.
I'm being serious.
We belong elsewhere.
Hey, look,
if you end up hating New York,
we can always
move back here.
[Adrian] I just want
to be with you.
I don't care.
New York, Derry, whatever. It's...
You have to say that.
I don't have
to say anything.
Take off that flaping hat.
- Oh, God.
- Come on, let's go.
[Webby] Wouldn't want to
give people the impression
we allow a bunch of flaping
fairies like you in this town.
Yeah, he was
born here, asshole.
- All right, let's go.
- No. You know what?
I'll take off the hat
for you.
But why leave it there?
Anything else
you would like me
to take off
for you tonight?
Any special requests, ladies?
[all grunting]
[Webby] Fucker!
- [Don] Let him go!
- [Don and Adrian groan]
- [coughing]
- [wheezing]
- What's that?
- Stop.
I don't think
you'll be needing that.
- [Don] Leave him alone!
- [Chris] Hit him.
He's got asthma, fucker!
[groans]
- [groaning]
- [Chris laughing]
- [wheezing]
- Come on!
- [groans]
- flap him up!
[Webby] Come on,
kick him!
Come on,
kick the shooot out of him.
Adrian! [grunting]
- [coughing]
- [Chris laughing]
I still hate
your flaping hair.
Adrian!
- Get the flap off him!
- [continues coughing]
Look what you did
to his flaping face!
Hey! Hey!
Help me get him up.
[Don] Adrian. [groans]
Help me get this flaping
punk up right now.
[groaning]
Give me the hat, Chris.
It's flaping mine!
I said give me
the flaping hat!
[Don] Adrian!
[Adrian wheezing]
You like that?
Welcome to Derry,
motherfucker.
[Don] No! Adrian!
No!
[train horn blowing]
Let's get the flap
out of here.
- Let's go!
- [Don] No!
Adrian!
Help!
Help me!
Somebody!
[continues wheezing]
Somebody flaping help me!
[panting]
- Oh...
- [Adrian gasping]
Adrian.
[Adrian wheezing]
- [Adrian screaming]
- No!
[Adrian groaning]
[faint distorted
carnival music playing]
Adrian!
[whimpering]
[children] We all
float down here!
[Mike] Thing is,
sometimes what we wish
was forgotten,
what we tried to
leave in the past,
won't stay there.
- [radio beeping]
- [gasps]
[dispatcher]
Units, please respond.
I'm getting reports of a
body found dismembered.
[officer] Come back.
Was that "dismembered"?
[dispatcher]
That's affirmative.
Scene is near
the south entrance
of the festival grounds.
[officer]
Copy that. En route.
Any directive for TC?
[dispatcher]
That's affirmative.
Chief said to tape off
the Derry Street Bridge.
[Mike] Sometimes,
it comes back for you.
[chattering on radio
continues indistinctly]
[indistinct chatter]
[knocking on door]
- [door opens]
- Ah.
[keys clicking]
Mr. Denbrough?
They need you on set.
We're just going to
go this way.
- I'm doing it. I'm doing it.
- No, don't!
[man] Hey!
Clear the door!
Oh, come on.
You've never seen Indiana Jones?
Watch your back.
Hey, hey.
You a crewmember?
I'm the writer.
[construction noises]
[assistant whispers]
Your husband's here.
Hey!
Do you have the pages?
[woman] Everyone,
keep clear of the crane.
My friend,
a film needs an ending.
- You do know that, right?
- Oh, yeah.
You said that
you needed another day
to finish the pages,
and we're shooting this thing.
It's tonight.
That's, like, 17 hours...
Everybody, calm down, okay?
I'm calm.
I want you to be
happy with the movie.
You understand?
I'm on your side.
That's great.
'Cause in my book, the ending...
Is terrible.
All due respect,
people loved your book. Loved.
They hated the ending.
You said
you liked the ending.
That was a lie.
- We gotta do better, okay?
- Yeah.
Audra, you have my notes.
Would you...
Okay, thank you very much.
Take me back to one, please.
Bye.
You have his notes?
He's not wrong.
You hate my endings, too?
Not all your endings.
But this...
- Okay.
- Just...
What? Do you want me
to keep lying to you
- just because I'm your wife?
- You're my wife?
No. No.
But you know what?
You've been blowing smoke
up my ass for eight years?
I guess I thought
you were someone else.
I have not been
blowing smoke up your ass.
Everybody wants
a happy ending.
Everybody wants closure.
But that's not
the way life works out.
I think what Peter wants
and what the studio wants...
The studio?
When'd you become a company man?
Jesus, you're an artist.
Come on.
What's wrong with just doing it
the way it's written?
The way I wanted.
What's wrong with being
the woman I want you to be?
flap you, Bill.
[stammering] On the page.
The part, I mean. Not you.
- [cell phone ringing]
- [sighs]
Hello?
Bill Denbrough?
It's Mike.
Mike who?
Mike Hanlon.
- From Derry.
- [groaning]
You need to come home.
[breathing heavily]
[car horns honking]
[Myra on phone] Eddie,
I keep telling you
not to scare me
like this.
And you never
listen to me.
All right. Myra, please.
Not now.
You shouldn't be out there.
Eddie, it's not safe
to drive
when the roads
are slick like this.
Sweetheart,
it stopped raining, like,
three hours ago.
All right?
- Everything is gonna be fine.
- [horn honking]
Hey, dickhead!
Flow of traffic mean anything to you?
What if you hydroplane?
I'm not gonna hydroplane.
It is my job
to assess risk.
So, please trust me
when I tell you
that, statistically speaking,
I am much more likely to
get into an accident
because I am talking
to you on the phone!
All right?
I have to go.
I will talk to you soon.
Goodbye.
[phone ringing]
Edward Kaspbrak speaking.
You didn't say,
"Okay, bye, I love you,"
like you usually do.
Listen to me. I can't!
I'm going to be
late to this...
meeting.
Say "I love you," Eddie.
Okay, I love you, Mommy.
What?
- Myra. Bye.
- [beeps]
Hello? Who's this?
It's me. Mike.
Mike who?
[taxi horn blaring]
[Mike] Eddie! You okay?
[Eddie] Yeah,
I'm pretty good.
Dude! Dude,
what the flap?
You were fine, like,
five seconds ago.
- Who was it? Who called? Huh?
- [breathing heavily]
Rich? Rich?
Talk to me.
You're on in two minutes.
You good?
'Cause you look not good.
- I'm fine.
- You're fine? Okay.
And we're walking.
We're walking.
Sixty seconds.
Even faster. All right.
Can we get him
a bottle of water, maybe?
- Bourbon.
- Bourbon. Sure, sure.
And a mint.
It is showtime.
- I don't think I can do this.
- It's what you do.
- You kill. You're a killer.
- That was fast.
Okay. We are
good to go, and...
Hey! Where we going?
Where we going?
- No. This way. Attaboy.
- [bell ringing]
Okay.
All right.
How do I look?
Your hands are shaking, Rich.
shooot.
[announcer]
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Richie Tozier!
- [audience cheering]
- [music playing]
All right.
How are we doing tonight?
So, my girlfriend
caught me masturbating
to her friend's Facebook page.
[audience laughing]
And so now
I'm in Masturbators Anonymous.
And I stand up
at the first meeting
and I say, "My name
is Richie Trashmouth."
- [boy 1] Trashmouth.
- [boy 2] Shut up, Richie.
- [boy 3] flaping perv.
- [boy 4] Shut up, Richie.
[boy 5 echoing] Pussy!
Trashmouth. Uh...
Forgot the joke.
[scattered applause]
[woman] You suck!
[chuckles awkwardly]
[man] Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen,
for letting us
present to you today.
Now, this will include
over a million square feet
of commercial
and residential space.
State-of-the-art
office towers.
What I'm really looking for
is to understand
how we create even more
retail opportunities.
If we put in walls here
and all along here...
[Ben on speaker]
Lose them.
With all due respect,
Mr. Hanscom...
Ben, please.
And with all due respect to you,
I'm getting claustrophobic
just looking at this model.
Aren't you?
Look. Throw up more walls,
it's gonna feel like a prison.
You know what people
want to do in prison?
Get out. Right?
This should be a place
that brings people together.
A meeting ground.
A clubhouse.
And if,
- while people are there...
- [cell phone ringing]
Excuse me
for one second.
- Hello?
- [Mike] Ben?
It's Mike Hanlon.
From Derry.
[operatic music playing]
[Patty] Should I just book it?
You're sure you can
get away from work?
It's summer, why not?
Okay, we are
Buenos Aires-bound.
[Patty chuckles happily]
[cell phone ringing]
Stanley Uris speaking.
It's Mike.
I'm sorry?
Mike Hanlon.
From Derry.
Mike.
God, sorry. Yes, hi.
[chuckles nervously]
[stammering] I don't
know why I didn't...
How long's it been?
[chuckles]
A long time.
27 years.
It's come back,
hasn't it?
That's why
you're calling me?
It's starting again, Stan.
Bad things are happening.
[stammering]
Did you call the others?
I mean,
what if they don't come?
We made a promise,
remember?
How soon
can you get here?
Um...
Well, I... [stammers]
Yeah, I would need to
do a few things...
Tomorrow.
We don't have much time.
I'll text you
everything you need.
I'll see you soon,
Stan the Man.
[water running]
[breathing heavily]
[mouthing]
Do you swear?
I swear, Bill.
[Stanley gasps]
[gasps]
- [cell phone ringing]
- [gasps]
[Mike] You made
a promise, Beverly.
[Beverly] I'm so sorry, Mike.
I don't even really remember.
Haven't you ever wondered
why you can't seem
to remember the things
most people should
about where they're from,
about who they are,
why you have that scar
on your hand?
No one else remembered,
either.
Eddie, Ben, Stan, Richie...
Bill.
You have to come back.
You all do.
When?
- [gasps]
- Whoa.
Are you okay?
What's going on?
It's the middle of the night.
You're packing?
I didn't want to wake
you, honey.
I know this week's
been really exhausting.
I just got a phone call from
an old friend from Derry.
I have to go back there.
It's really hard
to explain why.
It's okay.
You don't have to explain
yourself to me. Relax.
I trust you.
Thank you.
I just don't understand
why you'd lie to me.
I heard you.
You said the name Mike.
Yes, my friend.
See, there was
a group of us back then,
and we all made a promise to
each other when we were kids.
You know trust is everything
in a relationship.
You know
it's everything to me, right?
- I know. This isn't...
- Right?
What?
Like the last time?
I never cheated on you.
[whimpers]
You're a bad flaping liar,
- Bev.
- [groaning]
You're not going anywhere,
okay?
I want you to stay right here,
and you're gonna show me
what it is you're gonna
do with Mike. Okay?
You're hurting me, honey.
No one else is
gonna love you like me.
- You know that, right?
- [grunts]
[Tom groans]
[stammering] I'm sorry.
- [whimpering]
- [grunting]
Don't make this
flaping harder!
Don't.
[Beverly groaning]
- [grunts]
- [groans]
[groaning]
[Tom yelling]
[groans]
[panting]
You're nothing without me!
You know that, right?
Tell me I'm wrong!
[horn honks]
[children's voices echoing]
[gasps]
[screaming]
[police radio chatter]
[Borton] Jesus Christ.
Boys.
Little prick's got balls,
I'll give him that.
Far enough, Bowers!
I'm not done yet.
I'm not done.
I'm not flaping done.
- On your knees.
- I can't. No!
I gotta kill them all!
flap, flap!
flaping kill them all!
Stop it!
- Cuff this sorry sack of shooot!
- flap you! [yells]
flap you!
Henry Bowers,
I am placing you under arrest
for the murder
of Oscar Bowers.
Do you understand, dipshit?
You have the right
to an attorney.
to remain silent.
[laughing]
[nurse] Bowers!
Bowers, calm the flap down!
[indistinct announcement
on PA]
[Henry laughing]
Someone needs a little extra
clozapine today, don't they?
Stay in your flaping room.
- [bed creaks]
- [gasps]
[gasps]
[creature chuckling]
[screams]
[creature groaning]
Hockstetter.
My knife.
[music playing]
- Whoa.
- Careful.
This way.
Thanks a lot.
- [Mike] Hey.
- Oh...
- Mike, you look good.
- Bill.
Yup. Whoa.
Hey. How you doing?
Bill.
I didn't know
if any of you would...
I mean,
after all this time...
- Yeah.
- But of course you came.
You know,
an oath is an oath.
Losers
gotta stick together, right?
The Losers.
You remember that.
That's good.
What else do you remember?
I am allergic to soy,
anything that has egg in
it, uh, gluten,
and if I eat a cashew,
I could realistically die.
Holy shooot.
Is there a password
or something?
I'm sorry.
The new kid.
Ben?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
[Ben] Oh, my God.
- It's been so long.
- [Beverly chuckles]
[Young Beverly] Stay cool,
Ben from soc class.
[Young Ben]
You too, Beverly.
[Young Beverly] Hang tough,
new kid on the block.
[Richie] Wow.
You two look amazing.
What the flap
happened to me?
- What's going on, man?
- [Ben] Hey, man.
- It's Richie. Hi.
- Yeah. It's Ben.
[both laughing]
- Hi.
- Hey.
[gong rings]
This meeting
of the Losers' Club
has officially begun.
Look at these guys.
[mouths] Ben.
[all cheering]
So, wait, Eddie,
you got married?
Yeah, why's that so flaping
funny, dickwad?
What?
To, like, a woman?
- flap you, bro.
- [Richie laughing]
flap you!
All right. What about you, Trashmouth?
You married?
There's no way
Richie's married.
No, I got married.
- Richie, I don't believe it.
- When?
- Did you not hear this?
- [Eddie] No.
You didn't know
I got married?
- No.
- Yeah, no. Me and your mom
are very, very happy
right now.
- [all laughing]
- [Beverly] Yeah, very happy.
- [Bill] He totally fell for it!
- Thanks.
[laughing continues]
flap you.
She's very sweet.
Sometimes, she'll put her arm around me,
and she'll whisper to me,
she'll go...
[imitates Jabba the Hutt
speaking alien language]
We all get it.
My mom was a great, big, fat person.
Shh.
Hilarious. Hysterical.
[laughing continues]
[Richie] Yeah,
it's a nice watch.
Wait, let's talk about the
elephant not in the room...
Ben.
What the flap, man?
Okay, okay.
Obviously, I lost a few pounds.
- [Richie] Lost a few pounds?
- [Eddie] Yeah, no shooot you lost
- a few pounds.
- You're, like... You're hot!
[Eddie] That's true.
[Richie] No, you're like
every Brazilian soccer player
wrapped up into one person.
Gorgeous.
Leave him alone.
You're embarrassing him.
Okay, okay, all right.
Please, come on.
Is Stanley coming
or what?
Someone save me.
Stan.
Stan...
Stan Uris.
Stan Urine.
Stanley Urine.
No, no, he's a flaping pussy.
He's not gonna show.
Why would
Stanley save you, anyway?
Was I not the one
who basically
performed surgery on you
- after Bowers cut you up?
- Yes!
Holy shooot!
That's right.
Please tell me you ended
up becoming a doctor, Eds.
No, I ended up becoming
a risk analyst.
[Richie] Oh, that sounds
really interesting.
What does that entail?
Yeah, so I work for
a big insurance firm and...
[Richie imitates snoring]
[all laughing]
flap you, dude.
flap you.
Was this job
invented before fun?
- That's so not funny.
- [Richie] It is funny.
What the flap
are you laughing at?
I propose a toast
to the Losers.
[all protest]
[lively chattering]
Let's take our
shirts off and kiss!
[all] Oh!
- Oh, here we go.
- [Eddie] Thank you.
Thank you.
Like, Rogan-Marsh,
half my wife's closet Rogan-Marsh?
That's... [laughs]
That's huge.
That's our line.
Me and my husband, Tom.
How long have
you been married?
Hey, we saw your movie,
- by the way.
- [Bill] You did?
[Beverly] Oh, my God!
It was so good.
- [Bill] Oh, my God.
- It was so scary.
And the ending sucked?
[chuckles]
Yeah, it did.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
What?
Nothing.
This is just weird.
[Beverly] Yeah.
Just all this,
all these memories,
people that I don't even
remember forgetting.
I mean, it's weird, right?
Now that we're all here,
everything just comes back
faster and faster.
I mean, all of it.
Yeah.
Yeah, you know,
when Mike called me, I threw up.
Isn't that weird?
Like, I got nervous.
I got, like,
sick and I threw up.
[Richie chuckles]
I feel fine now.
I feel very relieved to be
here with you guys.
Why is everybody
looking at me like this?
When Mike called me,
I crashed my car.
- Seriously?
- [Eddie] Yeah.
[Ben] shooot, man,
I hear you.
I mean, my heart
was literally
pounding right
out of my chest.
- I thought it was only me.
- [Bill] It was like pure...
[Bill stuttering]
Fear.
It's fear.
What you felt.
Why did we all
feel like that, Mike?
You remember something
we don't, don't you, Mike?
Something happens to you
when you leave this town.
The farther away,
the hazier it all gets.
But me, I never left.
So, yeah.
I remember.
I remember all of it.
Pennywise.
Oh, the flaping clown.
[breathes heavily]
- Oh, shooot.
- [Richie] Pennywise.
Mike, you said you wanted
our help with something.
What was that?
There's an echo
here in Derry
that bounces back
every 27 years.
What are you talking about?
Hold on.
Listen, listen.
We thought
we stopped It back then.
We thought It
was done, but...
[Richie] Mike.
- [whimpers]
- A week ago, a man,
Adrian Mellon, slaughtered.
A girl, Lisa Albrecht,
the other night, went missing.
[Bill] All right.
There've already been others,
and there will be more.
[Richie] I don't want to
hear about this shooot.
- More death. More pain.
- Calm down.
Let's get another drink.
Let him explain.
Explain it to us, Mike.
That echo,
we might have changed It,
just like It changed us.
But we didn't stop It.
Because It just bounced back.
We made an oath.
That's why I brought you back.
That's why you're here.
To finish It.
For good.
Well, that shooot got dark fast.
Thanks, Mike.
My fortune cookie
just says "Could."
They don't know how to do
fortune cookies here.
Mine just says "Guess."
You wanna throw
that over here?
[Bill exhales deeply]
What you got, Mikey?
[inhales shakily]
[Eddie] Wait, what?
[Mike] This is
what I'm talking about.
[Richie] "Guess. Cut.
Not. Could. It."
It's a message.
[Richie] No,
"Guess it could not cut."
[Eddie] Why would it guess
it could not cut?
[Ben] Cut what?
[Richie] "Guess
it could not cut."
"It" goes in front.
There.
"It could not guess."
- It couldn't guess.
- [Richie] "Could it..."
No. "Could it not cut."
When it says "It,"
is it talking about It?
- Yeah. All right.
- [Eddie] Is that what it means?
- Is "It" It?
- Where does this go?
That's what
I'm talking about.
It... It could...
[Richie] I don't know
what it flaping means!
You flap with
the fortune cookies, Mike?
- No.
- Whoa. Let him speak, man.
This is not me.
This is what It does.
[Eddie]
I need my flaping inhaler!
[Richie] What is wrong with you, man?
Why'd you call us?
- This is not flaping funny!
- [Eddie] This is so not funny!
- [Bill] Beverly?
- This is so not funny.
[breathing shakily]
[men gasp]
[Eddie]
Why does it say Stanley?
Someone else
flaping answer me!
[fortune cookies rattling]
Holy shooot.
What the flap
is that, man?
Oh, my God.
Whoa, whoa!
[crying]
- Whoa!
- [whimpering]
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
shooot.
Hey! Hey!
That fortune cookie's
looking at me! shooot!
[yelping]
I don't want to be here.
I can't flaping do this.
I wanna go home!
I don't wanna be here!
Holy shooot!
Hey! God damn it.
[panicked chattering]
[both screaming]
Hey, Eddie!
[bleating]
[screaming]
[yelps]
Whoa! flap!
It's not real!
[screeches]
This isn't real!
It's not real!
[waitress]
Is everything all right?
Yeah, yeah.
Could we get the check?
That's what
Pennywise does, right?
He fucks with us.
So, Stanley's probably fine.
Hey, Mike.
Do you have Stan's number?
Yeah.
[boy] Hey, Richie.
[Richie] How'd you...
How'd you know my name?
The fun's just beginning.
Right?
What he said, is it...
Listen.
You think this is funny?
All right?
Think this is
some sort of game, huh?
Well, flap you,
all right?
[Bill] Rich,
be careful, dude.
flap you!
I'm not afraid of you!
"The fun's just beginning."
The line from your act, dude.
I'm a fan.
- Are those your parents?
- Yeah.
You want a picture?
- You okay, Dean? Come on.
- I think I'm good.
[Richie] Okay, cool.
He's a good kid.
Jesus, Richie.
You don't remember a line
from your own show?
I don't write
my own material.
I flaping knew it!
Hello, Mrs. Uris.
My name's Beverly Marsh.
I apologize for calling,
but I'm an old friend
of your husband's.
You lied to us.
That's not okay.
Yeah, first words out of your
mouth should have been like,
"Hey, man. You want to come
to Derry and get murdered?"
'Cause then
I would have said no.
Guys.
[Richie]
flaping entrapment, man.
[Patty on phone] Oh...
[Patty sighs tearfully]
He passed.
[Beverly] When did it happen?
Yesterday.
It was horrible,
the way he died.
His wrists.
- In the bathtub.
I'm sorry.
I have to go.
[Beverly] We're all very
sorry, Patty.
Thank you.
Stanley.
Pennywise knew.
He knew before we did.
We have to stop him.
I have a plan.
[Richie] I got a plan.
Getting the flap out of Dodge
before this ends worse
than one of Bill's books.
Who's with me?
We made a promise
to each other.
Let's un-make the promise.
Richie, other people
are gonna die.
Other people
die every day, man!
We don't owe
this town shooot!
Plus, I just remembered I grew up
here, like, two hours ago.
So, I'm flaping leaving.
flap this.
[Eddie] I'm sorry, man,
I'm with Richie.
- Eds, please.
- Listen.
What? We stay,
we die, that's it?
I'm gonna go back to the inn,
I'm gonna pack up my shooot,
and I'm gonna
drive to my home.
- I'm sorry, man. Good luck.
- [car engine starting]
No, Eddie. Please.
Please, Eddie!
Eddie, wait!
You okay?
I'm gonna head back
to the Town House, too.
- Are you coming?
- Yeah.
You should have told us,
Mikey.
Bill. Please, man.
I'm begging you.
Please.
Just listen to me, man.
What are you gonna say?
What could you possibly say
that would make
any kind of a difference?
They're all gone.
Come on.
Let me show you something.
One thing. And if you want to
leave, you can leave.
Just let me show you
this first. Please.
[spectators cheering]
[boy] Lapskew!
What kind of name is that, huh?
My mom swings
better than you!
How many times
do I have to...
She doesn't even play
baseball! You suck!
Mommy, how much longer?
Victoria,
we came to watch the game.
We're gonna
watch the game.
[spectators chanting]
[gasps]
Hello, Vicky.
Isn't that what
your friends call you?
Vicky?
How did I know that?
I guess I must be
your friend, too. [laughs]
If you're my friend,
why are you hiding in the dark?
You're not my friend.
You're scary.
[Pennywise crying]
Why are you crying?
People always make fun
'cause of the way I look.
I thought if you
couldn't see my face,
then maybe you'd
want to be my friend.
Never mind. [sobs]
Oh, silly old Pennywise,
you'll never have no friends.
People make fun
of me, too.
They do?
'Cause of this.
Well, isn't that silly?
That little thing?
Why, I can blow
that thing right away.
You could?
Oh, yes!
One poof and it'd be gone!
[giggles]
You would have to get close
enough to see my face.
I don't know, Vicky.
No, it's okay.
I won't make fun. I promise.
Promise promise?
Well, okie-dokie!
Just come on in
a little closer,
and we'll blow it away on
the count of three! [giggles]
[giggles]
One,
two...
You're supposed to say three.
[spectators cheering]
[music playing on video]
[John laughing]
[John sighs]
[man shuddering]
[door buzzes]
Holy flap.
Boo!
- [yelps]
- [laughing]
flap yeah!
Hey, Hockstetter.
- Let's go! [whooping]
- [tires screeching]
Let's get our shooot and
get the flap out of here.
Did you leave
your stuff here?
No, my stuff's
still in the car.
[door closes]
- Tell me.
- Tell you what?
Whatever it is you're
afraid to tell me right now.
Bev. Bev.
Back at the Jade when you were
on the phone with Stanley's...
Stop.
She told you that she
found him in the bathtub,
but, Bev, I saw you.
I heard it.
You said it first.
Whatever you guys
are talking about,
let's make it happen faster,
all right? We gotta go.
Eduardo, andale!
Let's go!
There's something
you're not telling us.
You knew how Stanley died.
You knew.
Wait, what?
I can't do this.
She knew how Stanley
was going to die,
is that what
she just said?
You can't just
walk away from this.
- [bell dinging]
- How did you know
where he killed himself?
Bev.
Talk to me.
Just talk to me.
Like we used to.
Come on,
how did you know?
Because I saw it.
I've seen all of us die.
[bags thumping]
Okay, I just got to
grab my toiletry bag,
and then we can go.
[bags thud]
What'd I miss?
[Bill] The library?
- [Mike] Mmm-hmm.
- [Bill gasps]
Wow.
Didn't this place
used to be bigger?
Yo! [stutters]
Mike, where are you going?
Mike, you live here?
Yeah.
Make yourself at home.
[fridge door opens]
- You want some water?
- [Bill] Yeah, sure.
[water pouring]
You see, memory's the thing.
It's the key.
It's the key
to everything.
If It really does want
us [stutters] back here,
don't you think the
smartest thing we can do
is just get the hell
out of Derry?
No, no, no.
It does want us back.
Of course It does!
But It doesn't know
I know what I know.
What do you know?
How to kill the shooot
out of It!
I've read every book.
I've talked to every person
in this godforsaken town,
everybody that would talk to
me, anyway,
and that's not a long list.
But it wasn't enough.
I had to know
how this all started.
How It started.
And It started
- here.
- Whoa.
- What am I looking at, Mike?
- It's an artifact.
Early 18th century Shokopiwah.
Shoko...
How'd you get it?
I found it, in the...
No, no,
they gave it to me.
I stole it.
You stole it?
- From Native Americans?
- Uh...
- It's complicated.
- Yeah, it is.
They helped me
on my journey.
So beautiful.
They showed me things.
A vision.
Ow.
Holy flap.
I feel kind of funky.
Hot.
Am I sweating?
I need you to see
what they showed me, Bill.
[echoing] Bill.
They live outside of Derry.
Beyond It's reach.
They moved there
many years ago.
Their holy man,
their holy of holies,
he took me in.
[speaking native language]
[Mike in English]
Fed me their sacred Maturin.
I started to...
To react.
All living things
must abide by the laws
of the shape they inhabit.
[screaming]
[Mike] While I sat there,
looking out over the valley,
I saw It arrive.
I knew that one day,
I would have to make you all see.
Mike,
did you put something
in my drink?
It's, uh...
It's a root.
You... [stutters]
You drugged me?
No, it's a root
with properties.
It's just a micro-dose of
what the Shokopiwah gave me...
Why would you do that?
...to open my eyes.
I don't feel real good.
I need you to look,
and you'll see.
[Bill] I don't feel good.
[Mike] Open your eyes.
Open your eyes.
They showed me the past.
[yelps]
Showed me the way
It appeared to them.
[whimpering]
[screams]
They showed me
their pain.
[both screaming]
They showed me
how to stop It!
[Native Americans chanting
in native language]
[Bill breathing heavily]
It's over.
You're okay.
Did you see it?
The ritual?
- The Ritual of Chud?
- Yeah, I knew you...
I knew you would see it.
I saw the whole flaping
thing, Mike.
That's how we kill It.
How are we going
to do it?
Everybody already
[stuttering] said no.
But with you,
they'll listen.
This won't work
without all of us.
Okay. So, what do you mean
that you've seen us all die?
Yeah,
'cause I gotta be honest.
That's a fucked-up thing
to just drop on somebody.
Every night since Derry,
I've been having
these nightmares.
People in pain.
People dying.
People...
[Eddie]
So, you have nightmares.
I have nightmares.
People, they have nightmares.
But that doesn't mean
that your visions are true.
I've watched
every single one of us...
[Bill] You've seen
every single one of us what?
At the place that
Stanley wound up.
That's how we end.
Okay, how come the rest of
us aren't seeing that shooot?
I mean,
what makes her so different?
The Deadlights.
She was the only
one of us
that got caught in
the Deadlights that day.
We were all
touched by It.
Changed.
Deep down. Like an infection.
Or a virus.
A virus.
You understand.
Slowly growing.
That virus,
it's been growing for 27 years.
This whole time,
metastasizing.
It just got to Stan
first, because...
He was the weakest.
Jesus Christ, Rich.
Just saying what everyone
else is thinking, man.
I mean,
Rich, come on.
What Beverly sees,
it will come to pass.
It's what'll happen to
all of us, eventually,
unless we stop It.
How the hell are we
supposed to do that?
The Ritual of Chud.
The Shokopiwah.
The first ones who fought
It, they have a saying.
"All living things
must abide by
"the laws of the
shape they inhabit."
A tribal ritual?
Are you flaping kidding me, man?
All right,
there's gotta be another way.
Okay? This thing comes
back, what, every 27 years?
Let's just kick the can down
the road and do it then.
Wait, we'll be 70 years
old, asshole.
[Beverly] It doesn't
work that way.
None of us make it
another 20 years,
and the way it happens...
So, if we don't beat It
this cycle, then...
We die.
Horribly.
Yeah, I don't need
the "horribly" part.
I didn't say it.
She said it. Not me.
[Bill] All right, guys.
Look.
I've seen [stuttering]
what he's talking about,
and it's all true.
It's the only way.
If we want
this ritual to work...
We have to remember.
Remember what?
[wind blowing]
[Mike] It's better
if I show you.
We don't have
much time.
His cycle
will end soon.
And once it does...
[Eddie] We're fucked.
[Beverly] The Barrens.
This is where we came.
After the rock fight.
The clubhouse.
You built that for us.
Yeah, the hatch has got to
be around here someplace.
[Eddie] You did.
I do remember that!
- Oh!
- Whoa! Whoa!
You okay?
[Beverly laughs]
- What?
- Nothing, it's just...
You haven't changed.
It's a good thing.
[both chuckle]
You know what?
I actually think the door was more like
around...
[crashing]
Found it.
I'm okay!
Come down!
What the dick is this?
How'd you build it?
When did you build it?
Here and there,
I guess.
It was already dug
out from something,
so I just had to
reinforce the walls
and get some wood
for the roof door,
and that's pretty much it.
Pretty good for
my first time, huh?
[Young Stanley yelps]
[Young Richie] Now,
that's a cool feature.
What happens when
you put your hand
on the other pillar,
professor?
Okay, you see, this is exactly
why there are safety codes,
why we have permits.
This place is a death trap.
You understand that?
Well, it's a work in progress.
Okay, Eddie?
Just so you know, I get
hurt, you are liable.
And, also, what is this?
The switch of an iron maiden?
That's a flashlight.
What is that,
a horse hitch?
When do you have
horses down...
Oh, this is cool.
That was like,
three dollars,
so be careful with that, please.
I have one of these.
Hey, Stan, you see this?
Yeah, okay,
can you maybe not?
Maybe not what? Yeah, yeah, hold on.
Maybe not what?
Be awesome and have fun
and celebrate the magic
of the paddle-ball?
Wow.
Oh, good going, fucknut.
You broke his thing.
- I broke it?
- Yeah,
you broke it
with your face.
What?
[Young Eddie] I'm not putting
my flaping hand down there.
[blows]
[Eddie] Oh, man.
That's so cool.
[Bill] Oh, my God.
[Eddie] How do we all not
remember that this was here?
[Richie as Pennywise]
Hey, Losers.
Time to float.
[laughing]
- Ahh!
- flap, Richie.
- Dude!
- Remember when he used to say
that shooot?
And he'd do that little dance.
[vocalizing]
Am I the only one
who remembers this shooot?
Are you gonna be like this
the entire time we're home?
All right. Just trying to
add some levity to this shooot.
I'll go flap myself.
[whistling]
It smells so flaping
terrible in here.
Hey, you guys?
[stuttering] This says "Stan."
"For the use
of Losers only."
Bill.
- ['80s music playing]
- The flap is this?
So you don't get
spiders stuck
in your hair
when you're down here.
Stanley, we're not afraid
of flaping spiders.
I stand corrected.
[laughs] That's a first.
Touche.
Hey, Rich,
your ten minutes are up.
What are you talking about?
The hammock.
Ten minutes each was the rule.
- I don't see any sign.
- [Young Eddie] Are you
being this way right now?
Really? No, no, no.
Why would there be a sign if
it was a verbal agreement?
And I remember you agreeing
on the flaping rule!
[both grunting]
[Young Richie]
I can see your vagina!
[Young Eddie]
Ten minutes each.
[Young Richie] Go back in
your dumb little corner!
I fucked your mom!
[Young Eddie] No, you didn't.
Take that back!
You're awfully good at
this, new kid.
You really think so?
There's actually a summer
program in Bar Harbor.
Teaches you, like,
everything about architecture.
I was thinking about applying.
[Young Richie] I'll do that.
I'll do anything to get
the hell out of Derry.
Man, when I graduate,
I'm going to Florida.
What's in Florida, Mike?
I don't know.
You know, I guess it's just a
place I always wanted to go.
Stan, you should go
with Mike to Florida.
You already act 80.
You'd clean up with all the grandmas.
[imitates kissing]
[all laughing]
Do you guys think
we'll still be friends?
When we're older?
[Young Richie] What?
Why wouldn't we be?
Do any of your parents
still hang out
with their friends
from middle school?
I mean, things might
be different then.
We all might be different.
We'll always still be friends.
I don't think that just,
you know,
[stuttering] goes away
because we get older.
[Young Beverly]
Yeah, Stan. Come on.
You don't have
to be so...
Sad.
He was old
before his time.
[Eddie] Yeah.
I wonder what he was
like all grown up.
Probably what he
was like as a kid.
The best.
Here.
All right, Mike.
What are we doing here?
The ritual.
To perform it
requires a sacrifice.
- Sacrifice? I nominate Eddie.
- Wait, what?
Because you're little.
You'll fit on a barbeque.
I'm 5'9". It's, like,
average height in most of the world.
It's not that kind of
a sacrifice, guys.
Mike?
The past is buried.
But you're gonna have
to dig it up.
Piece by piece.
And these pieces,
these artifacts,
that's why we're here.
They are
what you'll sacrifice.
And since Stan
isn't here to find his...
I figured we should
all be here together
to find his artifact.
I think Bill just did that.
Okay, Mike, so where
do we find our tokens?
Yeah, I gotta be honest, man.
All due respect.
This is flaping stupid,
all right?
Why do we need tokens?
All right?
We already remember
everything.
Saving Bev,
defeating It...
I mean,
we're caught up!
It's not everything.
We fought.
But what happened after that?
Before the house
on Neibolt.
Think.
[stuttering] We can't
remember, can we?
See, there's more to our story.
What happened that summer.
And those blank spaces,
like pages torn out of a book.
That's what
you need to find.
We need to split up.
You each need to
find your artifact.
Alone.
That's important.
When you do,
meet me
at the library tonight.
[Eddie] Yeah,
I gotta say,
statistically speaking,
you look at survival scenarios,
we're gonna do much
better as a group.
Yeah, splitting up
would be dumb, man.
Okay, we gotta go together.
All right?
We were together that
summer, right?
[Bill] No.
Not that [stutters]
whole summer.
[Young Bill]
Take it back.
- [groans]
- [Young Beverly] Bill!
You're just
a bunch of losers.
flap off!
- flaping...
- Stop!
We were all together
when we hurt It.
That's why
we're still alive.
Yeah? Well,
I plan to keep it that way.
[Young Beverly]
I bet by tomorrow,
we'll all be
back together.
[stutters] I don't think so.
Well, if we're gonna stop
It, we better be.
Maybe Richie was right.
Maybe we shouldn't do anything about
It, or maybe we can't.
Okay, don't let them
get to you.
It's a little late
for that.
You should go.
Before your dad sees.
[doorbell rings]
Yes?
Sorry. I...
May I help you?
I thought I rang Marsh.
Marsh?
Alvin Marsh?
My father.
I grew up here.
Dear,
it's not for me to
tell you this,
but your father
passed away.
I'm so sorry.
You didn't know?
We hadn't spoken
in a while.
Well, won't you
come in?
Let me offer you
something to drink.
No, it's fine.
I have to go.
It's the least
I can do.
Sure. Okay.
[door closes]
Is it like you remember?
Cleaner.
Well, you feel free
to look around
while I get
the water boiling.
Oh, really, it's fine.
You don't need to do that.
Don't be so polite.
[Mr. Marsh]
Today is her birthday.
I can still smell
her perfume.
And she'd still be alive
if it wasn't for you.
Mama was sick.
You know that's why
she did what she did.
She did what she did
because she was embarrassed
to be your mother.
You look like her.
But you are nothing
like her.
Come here.
I said come here!
Close your eyes.
[sniffing]
You know that I
would never hurt you.
You know that,
don't you?
[sobbing] I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You'll always be my little
girl, won't you?
Always.
[laughs]
"Your hair is winter fire,
"January embers...
"My heart burns
there, too."
- [music playing]
- There. I do apologize.
It gets so very hot
here this time of year.
It's fine.
Well, you feel like you
could just about die.
But you know what
they say about Derry.
"No one who dies here
ever really dies."
[clock ticking]
But tell me,
how is it being back in Derry?
It's good.
Strange.
Strange?
Oh, my.
Strange, how?
- [oven timer dings]
- [Mrs. Kersh] Oh.
I had some cookies in
the oven before you came.
You stay right there.
I really... I shouldn't impose...
I'm gonna...
No, no, no. I insist.
[record skipping]
Mrs. Kersh,
are these your family?
Yes, dear.
My father came to this country
with $14 in his pocket.
And he didn't ask
for a handout
the way that people
come in here these days.
You know what he did?
What did he do,
Mrs. Kersh?
My father joined the circus.
[music becomes distorted]
I was always
Daddy's little girl.
What about you?
[Pennywise] Are you still
his little girl, Beverly?
[Beverly breathing heavily]
Are you?
[stomping footsteps
approaching]
[growling]
[Beverly yelping]
Mustn't lie
to our father!
[Mrs. Kersh cackling]
Help!
[Pennywise]
Run, run, run.
Run, run.
You haven't
changed anything yet.
changed their futures.
You... You haven't
saved any of them.
Close your eyes, Bev.
flap you!
If you don't believe,
close them
and see!
[laughing evilly]
[screaming]
Come on, you.
Come on.
[Connor] Ken,
you little bitch...
Yes!
You're flaping good.
[electronic voice]
Game over.
- Ah, well, I gotta go.
- Hey!
Um...
How about we
go again?
Play some more,
you know?
[Belch] flap you, man.
Only if you want to.
Dude, why are you
being weird?
I'm not
your flaping boyfriend.
Whoa, I...
I didn't...
What the flap's
going on here?
You assholes
didn't tell me
your town is
full of little fairies.
[Young Henry]
Richie flaping Tozier?
What? You're trying to
bone my little cousin?
Get the flap out of
here, faggot!
flaping move!
[panting]
[crying]
[Pennywise]
Want a kiss, Richie?
[breathing heavily]
[rustling]
- [gasps]
- [roaring]
[screaming]
[Young Richie grunts]
[laughing evilly]
It's not real. It's not real.
I think I just shooot
my pants.
[exhales]
[cheerleaders chanting]
- [Adrian] Canal Days Festival.
- shooot.
Closing performance
is tonight.
Hope to see you there, handsome.
[Pennywise] Did you miss
me, Richie?
Oh, flap!
'Cause I've missed you.
No one wants to play
with the clown anymore.
Play a game with me,
would ya?
How about Street Fighter?
Oh, yes.
You like that one, don't you?
[Pennywise grunts]
Or maybe
Truth or Dare?
Jesus.
Oh, you wouldn't want
anyone to pick "truth,"
though, would ya, Richie?
You wouldn't want anyone
to know what you're hiding.
[Pennywise laughing]
I know your secret
Your dirty, little secret
Oh, I know your secret
[whimpering]
Should I
tell them, Richie?
This isn't happening.
This isn't real.
It isn't real. It isn't happening.
It isn't real.
- [taunting playfully]
- [screams]
[Pennywise grumbling]
Come back and play!
[distorted] Come back
and play with the clown!
- [horn honking]
- Whoa!
- I'm so sorry. Sorry.
- [driver] Watch it, you jerk!
Sorry.
[laughing shakily]
[laughing]
Oh, man!
- [shopkeeper] Can I help you?
- Hi.
Yeah, I want to see about the...
[stuttering]
Baseball card?
The bowling ball?
No, the... [stuttering]
- Banjo?
- [chord plays]
- Beaver?
- [chitters]
flaping bike.
You wanna use
that kind of language,
take it out
in the street.
I'm sorry.
Can we just start over and
pretend that I just walked in?
How can I help you?
Thank you. Yes.
I want to buy the bike.
Aren't you William
Denbrough, the writer?
Yeah, that's...
That's me.
That bike
used to be mine.
Well, it's mine now.
But you're
the big author.
You want it,
you can afford it.
[chuckles]
All right.
How much?
$300.
You can afford it.
I'll get it.
[Bill] I guess
that's kind of a deal.
You... You want me to
sign it for you?
Nah.
I didn't like the ending.
[Bill] Uh...
Three big ones.
- All yours.
- Uh-huh.
I don't know
how fast she'll go.
Been there
a lot of years.
[Bill] You know what,
mister?
She was fast enough
to beat the devil.
- [metal clanging]
- [groaning]
[panting]
Come on.
[yelps]
[laughing] Yeah,
I missed you, too.
Yeah!
Whoo!
Hi-ho, Silver!
Away!
[children's laughter echoing]
Bye, Billy!
I know you're
down there.
I know you [stuttering]
can hear me.
There's something
I have to know.
All of the kids in this
town you could have taken,
why [stuttering] Georgie?
Say something!
Why him?
[shouting] Why him?
Why him? Why him?
[sobbing]
[Pennywise] Why?
Because you weren't
there, Billy.
[Pennywise laughing evilly]
[Georgie] Billy,
don't leave.
Hello?
Billy.
I'm still here.
Help me.
Georgie.
Georgie?
Help me, Billy.
Take my hand.
I've got you, buddy.
Come on.
[Georgie] He's coming.
Take my hand!
- I got you. Come on.
- Billy, please. He's coming.
- Take my hand.
- Billy!
Come on,
take my hand!
[yelping]
[laughing]
[screaming]
[panting]
[childish laughing]
I hate you!
I hate you.
[Dean] Who are
you talking to?
Move, move, move!
Move! Move!
You hear voices from that
sewer, you stay away from it.
You hear voices
from the sewer?
No.
No. Just stay away
from that sewer.
I only hear voices
in the tub.
You know.
From the drain.
What kind of voices?
Kids.
And other times,
like a...
Like a clown?
You listen to me.
You listen good.
You need to
get out of this town.
All right? Tell your parents.
Make up a reason.
You make up a flaping lie.
I don't care what you do.
Just get out of this town.
Make them
never bring you back.
Do you understand?
You leave Derry and
you stay out of Derry!
Do you understand me?
I'm supposed to be
at the festival.
Tell me you understand!
[breathing heavily]
I'm supposed to be
at the festival.
I gotta go.
Just be careful!
[exhales]
- [school bell ringing]
- [students chattering]
[boy] Come on,
let's get the flap outta here.
Wake up, fat-ass.
[Young Ben groans]
flaping loser.
- [sighs]
- [door closes]
[Cover Girl playing
on headphones]
[gasps]
Whoa.
Easy. It's just me.
What are you and your little
buddies up to in here?
Oh. Those guys are
definitely not my buddies.
No, I meant
your real friends.
Joey. Jonathan.
Donnie. Danny.
- Oh.
- [turns walkman off]
Are you smoking
in school?
Secret hideout.
Don't tell anyone.
You okay, new kid?
Yeah, no, I'm fine.
I guess I'm just worried
that we're not all gonna be
the same after the fight.
As long as we can still hang
out, who cares?
You really mean that?
Well, yeah,
of course, dummy.
You and me.
Oh, my God!
I meant as a friend.
You actually thought
I could like someone
as fat and gross and
disgusting like you?
[lighter clicking]
No matter
how many stupid poems
[demonic voice] you write.
[gasps]
"Your hair is winter fire.
"January embers.
"My heart
burns there, too."
[panting]
That's not the real Beverly.
Beverly would never
say anything like that.
She'd never say that.
- [screams]
- Kiss me, fat boy.
- [yells]
- [screams]
[panting]
[grunting]
Oh, nobody wants to
kiss the fat boy.
Just leave me alone.
Alone?
Oh, you've always
been alone.
That's not true.
I have real friends.
Bill. Eddie. Mike. Stanley.
Richie. Beverly.
They're my real friends.
Kiss me as if it
were the last time.
[grunting]
[roars]
[janitor] What the hell
are you doing, kid?
[exhales]
[sniffling]
[door opens]
Guys?
[Beverly] Hey.
[Ben] Hey.
So, what did you see
out there?
Something I wish
I hadn't.
So, what, we just...
We kill It, and then we just
forget everything again?
I hope so.
Don't you?
I don't know.
I guess I want to hold on
to the good stuff, you know?
Mmm.
Come on.
There must be something from
the past that you don't
want to forget again.
I remember
being scared shitless.
Cold.
I remember you guys
in your tighty-whities.
Okay. Please forget
that moment.
I remember this.
I remember the boy
who wrote it for me.
Not him, so much,
but how he made me feel.
And a kiss.
It's still blurry,
but I think the longer we're here,
the more I can see it.
The more I can see that moment.
The more
I can see...
Bill.
I think.
I don't know.
Do you remember...
- [door opens]
- Bev, um...
- Move. Move.
- [Beverly] What's wrong?
I'm leaving.
[Ben] What?
You can't leave, man.
We split,
we all die.
Yeah, I'll take my chances.
We're gonna die, anyway.
Rich. Um...
Rich.
Hey, kids!
It's Burrow the Beaver!
Come on down.
It's the last day
of the festival here
at Canal Days.
[upbeat music playing]
Ahh!
Asshole!
[Muzak playing]
- [ripping]
- Hello?
[sniffing]
Can I help you?
Yeah, I called in...
I had prescription
called in for Kaspbrak.
Kaspbrak?
It's an inhaler.
Uh... Eddie Kaspbrak?
Mmm-hmm.
That's me.
I remember you.
Yeah.
- Mmm-hmm.
- How's your mom?
Oh, uh...
Well, she died a few years ago.
It's very sad.
It was from liver cancer.
What's that?
- What's what?
- That.
- All right.
- Uh-huh.
- Okay.
- [grunts]
No, it's not gonna pop.
It's a mole.
It might not be cancer.
Cancer?
But it might be.
You just stay here.
I'll get you something.
[squeaking]
Okay.
You came here for your
stinky breath pills?
[stammers] My breath
is fine.
Thank you.
That's not
what my dad said.
He said you have a tumor.
On your dick.
[laughs]
But you don't
take pills for...
Wait, what did
your dad say?
There you go.
I hope your dick
feels better.
Thank you.
For the inhaler,
not for the penis thing.
[Mrs. Kaspbrak] Eddie!
Eddie bear!
[Young Eddie] Mommy?
[Mrs. Kaspbrak] Eddie bear!
[yelps]
Mommy?
Eddie, come help me!
Quick!
[gagging]
[inhales deeply]
[Mrs. Kaspbrak] Eddie!
Mommy?
Eddie?
Eddie, help me!
Quick, help me!
Mommy?
Eddie bear,
come help me, quick!
[glass shatters]
[Young Eddie gasps]
[yelping]
[screaming]
[Mrs. Kaspbrak] Eddie?
[Young Eddie] The flap
is she doing here?
What is taking you
so long?
I don't know.
Why are you here?
Mommy!
He's coming!
You gotta get me outta here!
- Who's coming?
- Eddie.
[rustling]
[Young Eddie]
What the flap is that?
[Young Eddie
breathing heavily]
- [growls]
- [Young Eddie whimpering]
- Mommy.
- You gotta get me outta here.
- [growling]
- [Mrs. Kaspbrak] He's coming!
He's gonna kill me!
Eddie!
Help! Please, help me!
He's going to infect me!
Eddie! He's gonna infect me!
Eddie!
- [Young Eddie grunts]
- Help me!
- [Mrs. Kaspbrak whimpering]
- [growling]
Help me, Eddie!
He's coming, Eddie!
- [grunting]
- Eddie, hurry!
- He's gonna infect me, Eddie!
- [snarling]
[screaming]
Oh, my God!
Eddie!
Hurry up, Eddie!
- [snarling]
- [screaming]
Eddie!
[both screaming]
- [Young Eddie] I can't do it!
- [Mrs. Kaspbrak] Eddie! Eddie!
I'm sorry, I can't do it.
[screams]
I knew you would leave me, Eddie!
[sobbing]
- [both screaming]
- [creature snarling]
[Mrs. Kaspbrak]
Eddie, help me!
[Mrs. Kaspbrak screaming]
[screaming]
[Mrs. Kaspbrak] Eddie!
[Young Eddie sobbing]
What's all this shooot
doing here?
Why is that curtain
still here?
Okay, all right.
Are you gonna
do this, Eds?
It's just a memory.
You're fine.
Deep breath.
Okay.
You gonna do it?
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
shooot! Oh, shooot!
Oh, flap!
[Eddie yelping]
Stop! Stop!
[choking]
[yelling]
[Eddie grunting]
That's right!
flap you!
[Eddie choking]
[Angel of the Morning playing]
[screaming]
What the flap?
[whimpers]
[shouting indistinctly]
[gasps] What?
Push, don't pull,
you moron.
- Oh. [laughs] Thanks.
- [bells jingle]
Oh, my God.
What happened to you?
Nothing. I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Everything's fine.
Hey, how you doing?
Where's everybody else?
Richie wants to leave.
Ben's upstairs
trying to get him to stay.
Eddie's just scared.
So am I, Bill.
Aren't you?
We're all scared.
That's what worries me.
Because that's
what It wants.
We can do this,
but we have
to stick together.
[object clattering]
Should we be running?
This is Derry.
I'm kinda getting used to it.
What does that mean?
shooot. It's the kid.
What?
It's the kid
from the place.
The Chinese place.
I saw him
on the way here.
He lives
at my old house.
He was going to the fair, and...
He's going to the fair.
I gotta help him.
Okay, okay. Listen to me.
We'll go together.
I'm gonna get Richie
and Ben and we'll go.
There's no time.
I can't let it happen again.
What happened before
wasn't your fault.
None of it was.
I wish
that were true, Bev.
Bill! Bev!
- What is this? What happened?
- Uh...
Did Bill just leave?
I couldn't stop him.
Everybody's leaving.
It's all right. It's Bill.
He'll be back.
He'll come back.
Well, at least
I got Richie to stay.
flap. Oh.
[car unlocks]
[engine starts]
Oh. And then the leper,
he threw up all over me.
"Hey, it's Mike Hanlon.
"Why don't you
come back to Maine?"
It's your time, Eddie.
- [yells]
- [groans]
[muffled] What?
[Henry laughing]
Why?
Why did you do that?
Because he says
it's your time.
Who says it's my time?
[laughing]
You know, Eddie.
- [whimpering]
- You know.
Time to float.
[both laughing]
Where did he go?
Now give me back
my flaping knife!
[groans]
You should cut
that flaping mullet.
It's been, like,
30 years, man.
- [groaning]
- [Eddie] Guys!
Oh, shooot.
Eds?
[Beverly screaming]
[Ben] Jesus, Eds.
What the hell?
- Bowers is in my room.
- Oh, my...
[glass shattering]
- [Eddie] Is it bad?
- [Beverly] No.
[groans]
[Young Henry] I'm gonna
carve my whole name
onto this cottage cheese!
- [grunting]
- [groaning]
[blows kiss]
[laughing]
[Henry] One down!
flap yeah!
[panting]
[children chattering]
Hey!
Hey, kid! Kid!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I'm so sorry. I'm sorry.
Hey!
Excuse me. Excuse me. Hey! Hey!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
flap.
[carnival music playing]
[spooky laughing]
[groans] flap!
[groaning]
Kid! Hey, kid!
[groans]
flap.
Kid?
[grunts]
Hey!
[grunting]
Kid. [groans]
Kid? Hey! Hey!
Kid! [groans]
- [gasps]
- flap. [groaning]
shooot.
Hey.
What are you
doing here?
[laughing] Hey.
No, I'm here to
[stutters] help.
Stop following me!
I'm gonna get you
out of here.
[squeaking]
No.
Please.
[Dean whimpering]
Ah.
I'm here this time.
Just take me.
[Pennywise groans]
[laughing]
- [groans]
- [Bill yelps]
- Son of a bitch!
- [Pennywise laughing]
- [groans]
- [whimpering]
[Pennywise laughing]
- [Bill grunting]
- [Dean whimpering]
[screaming]
Help!
[Bill and Pennywise grunting]
- [panting]
- [whimpering]
[yelling]
- [Dean screaming]
- [Bill yelps]
[Bill panting]
I should go back there.
I just flaping
left them in the lurch, man.
I should go back there.
What the flap are you talking about?
flap that.
flap them.
I got dates
in flaping Reno, man.
[Young Stanley
singing in Hebrew]
[congregants responding]
[Young Stanley] Reflecting
on the meaning of
what I just read,
the word "Leshanot"
comes up a lot,
which means "to
change, to transform."
Which makes sense,
I guess,
because today I'm
supposed to become a man.
It's funny, though.
Everyone, I think,
has some memories
they're prouder of
than others, right?
[timer beeping]
And maybe that's why
change is so scary.
'Cause the things we wish
we could leave behind...
- Good morning, Mike.
- How you doing?
...the whispers we wish
we could silence...
His pa is the one.
The one that set that fire.
...the nightmares we most
want to wake up from,
the memories we wish
we could change...
...the secrets we feel
like we have to keep
are the hardest to
walk away from.
The good stuff?
The pictures in our mind
that fade away the fastest?
Those pieces of you it
feels the easiest to lose.
- Maybe I don't want to forget.
- [camera clicking]
Maybe if that's what
today is all about,
forget it, right?
- Thank you, Stanley.
- [stammering]
Today, I'm supposed
to become a man,
but I don't feel
any different.
I know I'm a loser.
And no matter what,
- I always flaping will be.
- [congregants gasp]
Thanks for showing up,
Stanley.
[Mrs. Hanlon] Mike! Help!
[Mrs. Hanlon screaming]
Help us!
- Please, Mikey, get help!
- [Mr. Hanlon] Help us!
Please, Mikey,
get help!
- [Mrs. Hanlon] Mikey!
- [both scream]
[Henry yelling]
[groans]
[laughing]
You should
have burned, Mike.
[yelling]
Just like
your druggie parents.
- [grunting]
- Can you see them yet?
[laughing] Crisping?
[both grunting]
Like fried flaping...
[groans]
[thuds]
I guess you could say
that was long overdue.
Get it?
'Cause we're in a library.
[retches] No.
Oh...
[Beverly] Mike?
- [Ben] Hey.
- [Beverly] Hey. Oh, my God.
[Beverly screams]
[Beverly panting]
Are you all right?
No, I'm not all right.
I just flaping killed a guy.
I was talking to Mike.
Where's Bill?
- [cell phone ringing]
- [clears throat]
Bill, we're all
at the library.
Where are you at?
[stuttering] He took a little
kid, Mike.
He took a little kid right
in flaping front of me.
No, no, no, no, no.
Just, just...
Look, just come here
to the library.
We can talk about
the plan.
- I'm gonna go kill It.
- No, no, no.
I don't want any of you
to get killed with me.
Bill! Bill!
He's going
to fight It alone.
- What?
- [Mike] Alone.
It's about the group.
The ritual doesn't work
without the group.
Doing it together
is why it'd work.
Mike, did he tell you
where he was going?
If he really wanted
to kill Pennywise,
there's only one place
he'll go.
The same place the ritual
needs to be performed.
Oh, we're not gonna like
this, are we?
[sighs] flap.
[breathing heavily]
[Beverly] Bill!
No, no,
you guys, no!
[stuttering]
I started all this.
It's my fault that
you're all here.
This curse, this flaping
thing that's inside you all.
It started growing
the day
that I made you go
down to the Barrens
because all I cared about
was finding Georgie.
Now, I'm gonna
go in there,
and I don't know
what's gonna happen,
but I can't ask you
to do this.
[Beverly] Well,
we're not asking you,
either.
- Bev...
- We didn't
do it alone
then, Bill,
so we're not gonna
do this alone now.
Losers stick together.
So, does somebody
want to say something?
Richie said it best
when we were here last.
I did?
- "I don't want to die"?
- Not that.
"You're lucky we're
not measuring dicks"?
[Bill] No.
"Let's kill
this flaping clown"?
Let's kill this
flaping clown.
[Richie] Hmm.
Well, I love what he's
done with the place.
Beep-beep, Richie.
All right.
Hey, hey.
That's the basement, right?
[groaning]
[Beverly] Ben?
[Eddie] No, no!
Hey, hey! Ben!
[both] Ben!
Ben? What's wrong?
[continues groaning]
- Ben!
- Okay. All right.
- [Bill] Ben!
- [rattling]
Okay, that can't
be good, right?
- [Ben continues groaning]
- [Beverly gasping]
Help! Hey!
[whimpers]
[pounding on fridge door]
[both] Ugh!
It's Stan.
- [Ben screaming]
- [whimpering]
[Beverly] It can't
be real.
- [yelling]
- Oh!
- [all yelping]
- Oh, God.
shooot.
[hyperventilating]
I'd still be alive if
it wasn't for you, Bill.
No.
- Beverly!
- [screaming]
[Pennywise laughing]
[Ben whimpering]
[knife unsheathing]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[cracking]
Richie, what's happening to me?
[groaning]
You gotta be
flaping kidding.
[laughing]
[yelps] flap!
Oh, God damn it, get it away from me.
Oh, God!
[snarling]
Whoa, whoa!
[yelping]
[panting]
- [footsteps retreating]
- [Pennywise laughing]
Eddie.
Hey. Are you okay?
I'm...
Oh, there he is.
[screaming]
Get it off of me!
- [Bill grunting]
- [continues screaming]
Get it off of me!
[Ben] Richie!
- [Mike] Richie!
- Richie! Hey!
- [Bill grunting]
- [Richie screaming]
- [Richie] Get it off of me!
- I wanna go home.
Get the knife!
God damn it, Eddie,
get the knife!
Bill! Get it off of me, Bill!
Quick! [screaming]
- Eddie, get the knife!
- [grunts]
Ahh! flap!
- [grunting]
- [Young Stanley groaning]
[grunting]
[Bill grunts]
[panting]
[Beverly] What?
[grunts]
[grunting]
[laughing]
Is everybody okay?
- [coughing]
- [Bill] You all right?
[stuttering] He could have
flaping died, man.
You know that, right?
I can't see.
Georgie's dead. The kid's dead.
Stanley's dead.
You want Richie, too?
I don't want Richie, too.
I don't. I don't.
Please don't
be mad, Bill.
I was just scared.
[crying]
That's what
he wants, right?
Don't give it to him.
A lot of memories, huh?
All bad.
[rats squeaking]
[Eddie] Oh, man.
Blech. Gray water.
shooot. This is it.
This is where
it happened.
No, no, no.
No. Ugh!
[Pennywise] Bevvie.
Bev, what is it?
I thought
I heard something.
- [screaming]
- [laughing]
Bev!
Time to sink!
- [laughs]
- [screams]
[Mike] Bev!
[echoing] Guys.
Okay, guys.
Come on.
Hey, guys.
Guys, come on.
[crying] Please, come on.
I don't want to walk
out of here alone.
[all gasping]
- You okay?
- [Beverly crying]
I feel like crying.
Mike. Where do we go from here?
[Mike] In the depths
is where It crept.
In the beneath,
to find belief.
In the depths
is where It crept.
In the beneath,
to find belief.
Is he okay?
I think at this point,
that's a relative question.
What's on
the other side?
I don't know.
No one does.
[Bill] Whoa,
whoa, whoa!
Mike.
- Mike, don't.
- All right.
- See you down there.
- [all] Mike!
Wait! [stammers]
- Stay together.
- Okay.
You guys,
I can't do it.
I can't.
You saw what happened up there.
I was gonna
let you die.
I just flaping
froze up.
If you let me go
down there with you,
I'm gonna get us all killed.
[inhales deeply]
Hey, hey, hey.
Give me that.
- Give me that.
- Richie.
Let go,
you little turd.
- Just let me get...
- [inhaler spraying]
[inhales deeply]
- I got it.
- Stop.
Listen to me.
You had a moment.
Fine.
But who killed a psychotic
clown before he was 14?
Me.
Who stabbed Bowers
with a knife
he pulled out
of his own face?
Also me.
Who married a woman 10
times his own body mass?
- Me.
- Yeah.
You're braver
than you think.
All right.
Thanks, Rich.
- Ow.
- Sorry.
[Beverly] Hey.
Here.
Take it.
It kills monsters.
- Does it?
- Yeah.
If you believe
it does.
Thanks, Bev.
[Mike echoing] You guys good?
[Bill] Yeah.
Can you get through that?
[Mike] It's the only way.
This way.
It's in here!
Through here.
It's tight,
but we can get through.
This is where It hid.
So, all this has been under
Derry, like, forever?
Not forever.
Just a few million years.
It can only be
attacked in its true form.
The ritual
will show us that.
And what is
It's true form?
I hope it's a puppy.
Like a Pomeranian or...
I'll shut up.
It's light.
A light that must be
snuffed out by darkness.
Your artifacts.
Place them in the fire.
The past must
burn with the present.
This is the boat
that I built
with Georgie.
[Eddie] It's my inhaler.
[inhales deeply]
Come on, dude.
Something that
I wish I had held on to.
This is a page
from my yearbook.
That only
one person signed.
I probably should
have forgotten it,
but I couldn't,
because I kept it in my wallet
for 27 years.
This is a token
from the Capitol Theater.
- You brought an actual token?
- [Richie] Yeah, man.
That's what we were supposed to
do, asshole.
Do you have any idea how long
that's gonna take to burn?
Yeah, but so is your
inhaler, dude.
Guys, come on.
All the toxic fumes and
the plastic and shooot, so...
Look closely, Bev.
You see it?
That's where
you hit Bowers.
The rock fight.
The day these bonds were forged.
That's not
gonna burn, either.
Oh, wait.
Couldn't forget
about Stan,
again.
[Mike] Okay.
Grab hands.
Come on.
The Ritual of Chud.
It's a battle of wills.
The first step
was our reunion.
The second was
the gathering of tokens.
This is the final step.
What the...
flap is that?
- [Mike] Don't look at them!
- [Eddie] Are those
- the Deadlights?
- Don't look at it!
Okay.
Turn light into dark.
Turn light into dark. Say it!
- [Eddie] Say what?
- Say it!
[all] Turn light
into dark.
[Mike chanting
in native language]
[others in English]
Turn light into dark.
Turn light
into dark.
[continues chanting
in native language]
[others chanting in English]
Turn light into dark.
Mike, what's happening, man?
Keep chanting!
Turn light
into dark.
[Mike chanting
in native language]
[others chanting in English]
Turn light
into dark!
Turn light into dark!
- [Mike] Keep chanting!
- Turn light into dark!
[Mike chanting
in native language]
[Eddie] Turn light into dark!
Turn light into dark!
Is it working?
Did we do it?
[box creaking]
[Mike grunting]
What is this?
Is this part of it?
Mike, is this supposed
to be happening?
- [Eddie] What? No, no, no.
- Keep chanting!
- What?
Turn light
into dark!
- Turn light into dark.
- Come on!
[all] Turn light into dark.
Turn light into dark.
- [whimpering]
- Whoa!
[gasps]
Hey! Hey!
[all yelping]
shooot!
Move, move!
Whoa!
[groans]
- [high-pitched ringing]
- [muffled shouting]
Bev. Bev.
- [Beverly] Richie.
- [Richie] Are you okay?
- I can't hear shooot.
- He's okay.
- [Bill] Are you all right?
- [Ben] Yeah. No, no, no.
- [Eddie] Wait, where's Mike?
- [Ben] Mike!
[men] Mike!
- I'm here!
- [Richie] Hey, guys.
Did we do it? Did we do it?
Yeah? Did we do it?
[Richie] We put the
tokens in the thing.
That's good, right?
[Eddie] We did it, right?
[all exclaim in fear]
shooot! shooot!
Oh, did it work, Mikey?
Did it work?
[Pennywise laughing]
Tell them why your silly
little ritual didn't work.
Tell them
it's all just a...
What's the word, Eds?
Gazebo?
Mike, what's
he talking about?
[stuttering] Mikey?
Oh, Mikey, you never showed
them the fourth side, did you?
[Pennywise laughing]
Didn't want them to know
what actually happened to
the poor Shokopiwah?
- Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
- [rumbling]
[Shokopiwah screaming]
flap, Mikey.
You lied to us, again?
[stammering] No,
but they didn't believe!
They didn't believe
they could kill It!
That's why it didn't
work back then!
Are you flaping kidding
me, Mike?
- We hurt him.
- flap!
[Bill] flap you, Mikey.
I needed something,
anything, for us to remember.
Anything for us
to believe!
- God damn it!
- flap!
[Pennywise laughing]
[all screaming]
[Beverly] The Deadlights!
Don't look at them!
[groans]
For 27 years,
I dreamt of you.
[laughing]
I craved you.
Oh, I've
missed you! [laughs]
Mike! Move back!
Waiting for
this very moment.
Mikey!
You gotta move, Mikey!
- Sorry. I'm sorry, guys.
- [Eddie] Mike, come on, man!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Time to float!
[all gasp]
- Oh, shooot!
- Sorry.
[Eddie] Mike, come on, get up!
Get him up!
- [Bill] Go, go!
- [Eddie] Run!
- Oh, shooot!
- [Bill] Run! Go, go, go!
[snarling]
Go, go, go!
Go!
[Ben] Go, go, go!
Where'd he go?
Don't worry.
We'll find a way out.
[gasps]
[coughing]
- Oh, shooot!
- [yelps] Can he see us?
- [both screaming]
- Oh, my God!
[Eddie] shooot.
Oh, shooot.
[Richie] Holy shooot!
Holy shooot! Run!
[Eddie] Oh, shooot!
[both gasp]
[Richie] shooot.
You gotta be flaping kidding me.
We're trapped.
- Where do we go?
- [rumbling]
[both screaming]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[screaming]
[groaning]
[yelping]
- [Eddie] God damn it!
- [Richie] Uh...
All right.
"Not Scary At All." All right?
No, no, no.
- [stammering]
- Wait. Why?
They're flipped.
He's flaping with us.
- Are you sure? Positive?
- Trust me.
- Yes!
- Okay.
[woman] Where's my shoe?
[woman tap dancing]
[woman laughing]
[Eddie and Richie screaming]
What the flap?
You told me to trust you!
[screaming continues]
He's not
flaping with us.
Let's go to
"Not Scary At All."
Okay. [breathing heavily]
It's all right.
Let's go.
[panting]
Oh, shooot.
No way am I falling
for this shooot again.
Oh, yeah.
That thing's a flaping monster.
Richie, make it sit.
I know your moves,
you little bitch.
Rich?
It's gone, man.
- Yeah. Wait.
- Oh. Okay.
Okay.
Sit.
[Eddie] He did it.
Oh, that's cute.
- That's a good boy.
- That's actually super cute.
That's a good boy.
- Are you a good boy?
- [Richie] Good boy.
- [snarling]
- [both screaming]
shooot!
Yo, next time,
we just go with regular "Scary."
Next time?
[Georgie] I lost it,
Billy.
It just floated off.
[stuttering]
I'm not mad at you.
It's your fault what
happened, isn't it?
You weren't really that
sick that morning, were you?
No.
I just pretended
because I didn't want to
play with you.
I just didn't want to.
You lied and I died.
You lied and I died!
It happened because of
me, Georgie. Me.
No, no, no.
It was...
Lied and died!
- [yelps]
- Lied and died!
Lied and died!
[muffled]
You lied and I died!
[breathing heavily]
[suffocating]
[exhales shakily]
[pounding on door]
[yelps]
You in there, you little shooot?
I can smell you.
[sniffs] You smell
just like Lois Lane.
Here's Johnny!
[voices chattering loudly]
[voice laughing sinisterly]
[liquid rushing]
[gasps]
[screaming]
[yelping]
[continues screaming]
All that success,
all those sit-ups,
but deep down,
still just
a little fat, fat,
fatty loser...
[Pennywise laughing]
...who always knew
he would die alone.
[screaming]
[hissing]
- Slut!
- Bev!
[screaming]
Beverly!
Bevvie.
Just open up the door for
me, okay?
Beverly,
can you hear me?
[grunting]
Come to Daddy, now.
Bev, don't listen!
[yelps]
Bev!
Are you still
my little girl, Bevvie?
[gasping]
Beverly, I love you!
Ben!
Are you still
my little girl, Bevvie?
my little girl?
Not anymore!
- [grunts]
- [screaming]
[Mr. Marsh] You little...
"Your hair
is winter fire.
[whimpering]
"January embers.
"My heart...
"My heart..."
[shouting]
No!
[Ben screaming]
Ben!
- [continues screaming]
- Ben!
[both grunting]
[Ben gasping]
"January embers."
"My heart
burns there, too."
It was you.
[Pennywise whooping]
We deserve to die.
No.
You were the best big brother
there ever [stuttering] was.
No! We killed
our little brother!
[Bill shushing]
He loved you.
And just because
you didn't want to play
on a rainy day,
just one time,
that does not
make it our fault.
[gun clicks]
[chuckling]
[gun clicking]
And it never,
ever...
[breathing heavily]
...did.
- [gasps]
- [yells]
[coughing]
Bill.
- Miss me?
- [gasps]
I know what you are.
That's why
I'm not afraid.
[groaning]
[laughing]
Well, I know
what you are.
A madman.
[Mike yelping]
[grunts]
Hey, fuckface!
[groans]
You wanna play
Truth or Dare?
Here's a truth.
You're a sloppy bitch!
Yeah, that's right!
Let's dance!
Yippee-ki-yay...
[gasps]
This kills monsters.
If you believe it does.
Beep-beep,
motherfucker!
[howls]
[grunts]
[choking]
Holy shooot!
[wheezing]
Rich!
Oh, Rich!
Hey, Rich,
wake up!
Hey.
Yeah, yeah! There he is, buddy!
Hey, Richie, listen!
I think
I got him, man!
I think I killed It!
I did! I think
I killed It for real!
- [groans]
- [yelps]
[screaming]
[gasping]
Eddie.
Richie.
[screaming]
[gasps]
[Pennywise laughing]
No!
Eddie.
Uh-oh!
[screaming]
No!
[yelping]
[gasps]
[groaning]
[all] Eddie!
[Ben] Eds!
- Eds! Eds!
- [Richie] Eddie!
[Bill] Eds,
come on, man.
[Eddie groaning]
[Ben] Be careful!
Be careful!
[labored breathing]
Come out
and play, Losers!
He's hurt.
He's hurt really bad.
We gotta
get him out of here.
How are we supposed
to do that, Richie?
I almost killed It.
The leper.
My hands
around his throat.
And I could feel
him choking.
I made him small.
He seemed so weak.
The Shokopiwah.
All living things
must abide by
the laws of the shape
they inhabit.
[Ben] Guys!
There's a passageway.
Through here.
The tunnel.
Pennywise has to
make himself small
to get through the entrance
of the cavern, right?
Okay, so, if we can get back
there, we can
- force him down to size.
- Yeah.
We make him small.
Small enough so we can kill him.
I can smell
the stink of your fear!
[Pennywise laughing]
- Let's go! Go!
- [Ben] Come on! Come on!
It's tight. It's tight.
Be careful!
I need a little rest.
Oh, thanks. [groaning]
Hey.
Hey, Richie?
I gotta
tell you something.
What?
What's up, buddy?
I fucked your mother.
[laughing]
[Pennywise] Losers out!
[Bill] Go. Go!
[yelping]
[all screaming]
[Pennywise whoops]
Gotcha!
Whoa!
You filthy little children.
[laughs]
You got a plan B, man?
What the hell do we do now?
You die.
That's what you do.
[Ben] Mike?
There's more than one way
to make someone small.
Oh!
Make him
believe that he is.
- [stutters] What?
- Make him believe that he is.
Oh? Me?
Small? [laughs]
I am
the Eater of Worlds.
Not to us,
you're not.
You're just a clown.
[growling]
You're a weak old woman.
The Eater of Worlds.
A headless boy!
Impostor!
[snarling]
You're a mimic!
A mimic!
You're a flaping bully!
You're just
a flaping clown!
Eater of Worlds!
A clown!
A dumb flaping clown!
[Bill] Clown!
A leper!
[Beverly] You're a clown!
You're a clown!
A painting!
[Ben] You're a clown!
[Bill] I'm not afraid
of you anymore!
A motherfucking
stupid mummy!
[Mike] You're a clown!
Clown! Clown!
- [all shouting]
- [Pennywise groaning]
- [Mike] Clown!
- Clown!
You're a flaping clown!
[Beverly] You're a clown!
- [Ben] A stupid mummy!
- Clown!
[Ben] Clown, motherfucker!
I am the Eater of Worlds!
[Ben] Clown!
- Clown!
- You're just a clown! Clown!
- I am the Eater of Worlds!
- [Ben and Bill] A clown!
- [Pennywise snarls]
- [Bill] Whoa!
[losers chanting]
A clown! A clown!
[screaming]
[Mike] No one's
afraid of you.
No one's scared of you.
[losers] Clown! Clown!
Clown. Clown. Clown.
[moaning]
- Clown.
A clown.
With a scared,
beating heart.
[whimpering]
[heart beating]
- [snarls]
- [yelps]
- [whining]
- [heart continues beating]
[screaming]
Look at you.
You're all grown up.
[laughing]
[wheezing]
[dying breath]
Eddie. Eddie.
Eddie.
We got Pennywise, man.
Eddie?
- [crying]
- [rumbling]
[Beverly] Richie.
He's gone.
He's all right.
No, he's just hurt.
We gotta get him outta here.
He's hurt. Ben.
Bill, he's okay.
We gotta get him outta here.
Bev.
Richie. [sniffles]
What?
Honey, he's dead.
We have to go. Come on.
Come on, Richie.
We gotta go.
- Come on, buddy. Come on.
- [rumbling intensifies]
[Ben] Let him go, man.
Let him go.
- [Bill] Got it.
- [all urging]
We can still help him, guys!
We can still help him!
[Ben] Go! Go! Get up!
Guys, we can
still help him!
[Richie] No! Eddie!
Eddie!
[Mike] Come on!
Let's go!
Come on! Let's go!
Move, move!
- Move, move!
- [Beverly] Run!
[Mike] Run!
[all yelping]
- Eddie!
- No, no, no!
Eddie!
We gotta get in there
and get him!
He's still in there!
Eddie!
[Ben] You know what?
Eddie would have
hated this, guys.
What? Cleaning ourselves
in dirty water?
Yeah.
He'd be telling us we'd get
streptococcal something.
- [chuckles]
- Yeah.
But he would have
made us laugh, though.
Oh, yeah.
He'd be
looking out for us.
The way he always was.
Ain't that right, Richie?
[sobbing]
Hey.
Oh.
Thank you.
I don't have
my glasses on,
so I don't know who you people
are, but thank you.
[all laughing]
I legit
can't find my glasses.
You're serious?
- Glasses?
- Go that way.
Around here somewhere?
- I can't see them.
- Oh, I see them. Right there.
- Where?
- Look. Right...
If you just go, like...
Anybody have any luck?
Hey, guys.
Look.
Nothing lasts forever.
I can't go home
like this, guys.
My mom will kill me.
Dude, you've been gone
for 24 straight hours.
Your face is definitely
on a milk carton by now.
Also, that puke smells worse
than your mom's slippers.
[Young Beverly]
Oh, shut up, Richie.
Okay, first of all,
my mom's slippers
smell like potpourri, asshole.
No, they don't.
Yes, they do.
And, also, how would you know
what they smell like
in the first place?
[Young Mike] Can we
just keep it quiet,
please,
until we get home?
[Young Ben] "Potpourri" is
literally a French word
meaning "rotten pot."
[Young Richie] I knew there
was something rotten about it.
- [cell phone ringing]
- [Bill sighs]
- Mike?
- Hey. [chuckles]
I just thought
I'd check up on you.
You know,
just to see if you learned
how to finish
a book for once.
[chuckling]
I just finished
the first chapter.
And I think I actually know
where I'm going this time.
Good.
Say, can I ask
you a question?
Sure.
Why do you think
we're not forgetting?
You know, like last time?
Maybe 'cause It's dead.
Or maybe 'cause
we have more
we want to remember
than we want to forget.
I like that one.
You decide
what you want to do?
About leaving Derry?
Man, I've been in this cell
for 27 years.
Just seeing
what It wanted me to.
I think it's time I saw
the sky for a change.
Go get it, Mikey.
Oh, did you get the letter?
[stammers]
What letter?
You'll know
when you see it.
Well, hold on.
I just got the mail.
We all got one.
[Bill] Patricia Uris?
Just...
Just read it.
Okay.
And call me.
Anytime.
I will.
And, Bill,
I love you, man.
I love you, too.
All right.
See you around.
[Stanley] Dear Losers,
I know what this must seem like,
but this isn't
a suicide note.
You're probably wondering
why I did what I did.
It's because I knew I was
too scared to go back.
And if
we weren't together,
if all of us alive
weren't united,
I knew we'd all die.
So, I made
the only logical move.
I took myself
off the board.
Did it work?
[Stanley sighs]
Well, if you're reading
this, you know the answer.
I lived
my whole life afraid.
Afraid of
what would come next.
Afraid of what
I might leave behind.
Don't.
Be who you want to be.
Be proud.
You sleep okay?
Yeah.
I had a beautiful dream.
[Stanley] And if you find
someone worth holding on to,
never ever let them go.
Follow your own path.
Wherever that takes you.
Think of this letter
as a promise.
[Eddie] A promise
I'm asking you to make.
[Mike] To me.
[Ben] To each other.
[Beverly] An oath.
[Stanley] See,
the thing about being a Loser
is you don't have
anything to lose.
So...
[Young Richie]
Be true.
[Young Eddie]
Be brave.
[Young Mike] Stand.
[Young Beverly] Believe.
[Young Bill]
And don't ever forget...
[Young Stanley]
We're Losers,
and we always will be.