Captain's Log:
Stardate 81 30.3.
Starship Enterprise
on training mission...
to Gamma Hydra, section 1 4...
coordinates 22-87-4.
Approaching Neutral Zone.
All systems normal
and functioning.
Leaving section 1 4
for section 1 5.
Stand by. Project parabolic course
to avoid entering Neutral Zone.
Aye, Captain.
Course change projected.
Captain, I'm getting something
on the distress channel.
- On speakers.
- Imperative.
This is the Kobayashi Maru
out of Altair VI.
We have struck a gravitic mine
and have lost all power.
Our hull is penetrated and we have
sustained many casualties.
This is the Starship Enterprise.
Your message is breaking up.
Can you give us your coordinates?.
Repeat, this is the--
Enterprise, our position
is Gamma Hydra, section 10.
- In the Neutral Zone.
- Hull penetrated.
Life support systems failing.
Can you assist us, Enterprise?.
Data on Kobayashi Maru.
Subject vessel is third-class
neutronic fuel carrier...
crew of 81,
300 passengers.
Damn.
Mr. Sulu,
plot an intercept course.
May I remind the captain that
if a starship enters the Zone--
I'm aware of my responsibilities,
mister.
Estimating two minutes
to intercept.
Now entering the Neutral Zone.
Warning.
We have entered NeutralZone.
We are now in violation
of treaty, Captain.
Stand by, transporter room.
Ready to beam survivors aboard.
Captain,
I've lost their signal.
Alert. Sensors indicate
three Klingon cruisers.
-Bearing 3 16 markk 4, closing fast.
-Visual.
Battle stations.
Activate shields.
Shields activated.
Inform the Klingons
we are on a rescue mission.
They're jamming
all the frequencies.
Klingons on attack course
and closing.
We're over our heads.
Mr. Sulu, get us out of here.
I'll try, Captain.
Alert. Klingon torpedoes
activated. Alert.
Evasive action.
- Engineering, damage report.
- Main energizer hit, Captain.
Engage auxiliary power.
Prepare to return fire.
Shields collapsing, Captain.
- Fire all phasers.
- No power to the weapons, Captain.
Captain, it's no use.
We're dead in space.
Activate escape pods.
Send out the log buoy.
All hands abandon ship.
Repeat, all hands abandon ship.
All right, open her up.
Any suggestions, Admiral?.
Prayer, Mr. Saavik.
The Klingons don't take prisoners.
Lights.
Blowers on.
Captain.
Trainees,
to the briefing room.
Maintenance crew,
report to bridge simulator.
Physician, heal thyself.
Is that all you gotta say?.
What about my performance?.
I'm not a drama critic.
Mr. Saavik, you gonna
stay with a sinking ship?.
- Permission to speak candidly, sir.
- Granted.
I don't believe this was a fair
test of my command abilities.
- And why not?.
- Because there was no way to win.
A no-win situation's a possibility
every commander may face.
- Has that never occurred to you?.
- No, sir. It has not.
How we deal with death...
is as least as important
as how we deal with life.
Wouldn't you say?.
As I indicated, Admiral,
that thought had not occurred to me.
Well, now you have something
new to think about. Carry on.
Engineering cadets,
assemble on C level.
Admiral.
Wouldn't it be easier to put an
experienced crew back on the ship?.
Galloping around the cosmos
is a game for the young, Doctor.
Now, what is that
supposed to mean?.
Aren't you dead?.
I assume you're
loitering around here...
to learn what efficiency rating
I plan to give your cadets.
I am understandably curious.
They destroyed the simulator room,
and you with it.
The Kobayashi Maru scenario
frequently wreaks havoc...
with students and equipment.
As I recall, you took the test
three times yourself.
Your final solution was,
shall we say, unique.
It had the virtue of
never having been tried.
Oh, by the way,
thank you for this.
I know of your fondness
for antiques.
""It was the best of times...
it was the worst of times."
Message, Spock?.
None that I'm conscious of.
Except, of course, happy birthday.
Surely the best of times.
Captain Spock, Captain Spock.
Space shuttle leaving
in 15 minutes.
- Where are you off to now?.
- The Enterprise.
I must check in before
your inspection. And you?.
Home.
Why, bless me, Doctor. What beams
you into this neck of the woods?.
Beware Romulans bearing gifts.
- Happy birthday,Jim.
- Thanks.
Romulan ale. Why, Bones,
you know this is illegal.
I only use it for
medicinal purposes.
I got a border ship brings me
in a case now and then...
across the Neutral Zone.
- Now, don't be a prig.
- 2283.
Well, it takes this stuff
a while to ferment.
Here, give me.
Now, you open this one.
I'm almost afraid to.
What is it?.
Klingon aphrodisiacs?.
More antiques
for your collection.
Bones, this is charming.
They're 400 years old. You don't
find many with the lenses intact.
- What is it?.
- They're for your eyes.
For most patients your age,
I'd administer Retnax V.
- I'm allergic to Retnax.
- Exactly. Cheers.
Cheers.
Happy birthday.
- I don't know what to say.
- You could say "thank you."
Thank you.
Damn it,Jim, what the hell's
the matter with you?.
Other people have birthdays. Why are
we treating yours like a funeral?.
- I don't want to be lectured.
- What the hell do you want?.
This is not about age,
and you know it.
It's about you flying
a goddamn computer console...
when you want to be
out there hopping galaxies.
Spare me your notions of poetry.
We all have our assigned duty.
Bull!
You're hiding-- hiding behind
rules and regulations.
- Who am I hiding from?.
- From yourself, Admiral.
Don't mince words, Bones.
What do you really think?.
Jim, I'm your doctor...
and I'm your friend.
Get back your command.
Get it back before you turn
into part of this collection.
Before you really do grow old.
Starship Log:
Stardate 8130.4.
Log entry by
First Officer Pavel Chekov.
Starship Reliant on orbital
approach to Ceti Alpha VI...
in connection
with Project Genesis.
We are continuing our search
for a lifeless planet...
to satisfy the requirement
of a test site...
for the Genesis Experiment.
- So far, no success.
- Standard orbit, please.
Mr. Beach,
any change in the surface scan?.
Negative. Limited atmosphere
dominated by Craylon gas...
sand, high-velocity winds.
Incapable of supporting
life-forms.
Does it have to be
completely lifeless?.
Don't tell me
you found something.
We picked up a minor energy flux
reading on one dynoscanner.
Damn. Are you sure?.
Maybe the scanner's
out of adjustment.
I suppose it could be a particle
of preanimate matter...
caught in the matrix.
All right.
Get on the comm-pic to Dr. Marcus.
Aye, sir.
Maybe it's something
we can transplant, hmm?.
You know what she'll say.
Let me get this straight.
Something you can transplant?
Yes, Doctor.
Something you can transplant?.
- I don't know.
- It may only be preanimate matter.
Then again, it may not.
You boys have to be
clear on this.
There can't be so much as a microbe,
or the show's off.
Why don't you have a look?.
But if it can be moved--
You bet, Doctor.
We're on our way.
Well, don't have kittens.
Genesis is going to work.
They'll remember you in one breath
with Newton, Einstein, Surak.
Thanks a lot.
No respect from my offspring.
Par for the course.
You teaming up with me
for bridge after dinner?.
Maybe.
What is it?.
Every time we have dealings
with Starfleet, I get nervous.
We are dealing with
something that...
could be perverted
into a dreadful weapon.
Remember that overgrown Boy Scout
you used to hang around with?.
- That's the kind of man--
- Listen, kiddo.
Jim Kirk was many things,
but he was never a Boy Scout.
Captain Terrell,
stand by to beam down.
Chekov, are you sure
these are the correct coordinates?
Captain,
this is the garden spot...
of Ceti Alpha VI.
I can barely see it.
There's nothing here.
The tricorder must be brokken.
Chekov, over here.
Those look like cargo carriers.
Hey, give me a hand.
What the hell happened?.
If they crashed,
then where's the rest of the ship?.
What the hell is that?.
Botany Bay?
Botany Bay!! Oh, no!
We've got to get out of here now!
Damn! Hurry!
- What about the tricorder?.
- Never mind that. Hurry! Hurry!
Chekov, what's the matter
with you?.
Come on! Hurry!
Starship Reliant
to Captain Terrell.
This is Commander Kyle.
Will you please respond, Captain?.
Captain Terrell,
respond, please.
Let's give them
a little more time.
Khan.
I don't know you.
But you--
I never forget a face.
Mr....
Chekov.
Isn't it?.
I never thought
to see your face again.
- Chekov, who is this man?.
- A criminal, Captain.
A product of late 20th-century
genetic engineering.
What do you want with us?.
Sir, I demand to be--
You are in a position
to demand nothing, sir.
I, on the other hand,
am in a position...
to grant nothing.
What you see
is all that remains...
of the ship's company and crew
of the Botany Bay...
marooned here 15 years ago
by Captain James T. Kirk.
- Listen, you men and women--
- Captain, Captain.
Save your strength, Captain.
These people had sworn
to live and die at my command...
200 years before you were born.
Do you mean he never
told you the tale?.
To amuse your captain?. No?.
Never told you how the Enterprise
picked up the Botany Bay...
Iost in space
from the year 1996...
myself and the ship's company
in cryogenic freeze?.
- I've never even met Admiral Kirk.
- Admiral?.
Admiral.
Never told you
how Admiral Kirk...
sent 70 of us into exile...
on this barren sand heap...
with only the contents of
these cargo bays to sustain us?.
You lie!
On Ceti Alpha V, there was life.
- A fair chance--
- This is Ceti Alpha V!
Ceti Alpha VI exploded...
six months after
we were left here.
The shock shifted the orbit
of this planet...
and everything was laid waste.
Admiral Kirk never bothered
to check on our progress.
It was only the fact of my
genetically engineered intellect...
that allowed us to survive.
On Earth...
200 years ago...
I was a prince...
with power over millions.
Captain Kirk was your host.
You repaid his hospitality by
trying to steal his ship...
and murder him.
You didn't expect to find me.
You thought
this was Ceti Alpha VI.
Why are you here?.
Why?.
Allow me to introduce you
to Ceti Alpha V's...
only remaining
indigenous life-form.
What do you think?.
It killed 20 of my people...
including my beloved wife.
Oh, no, not all at once.
And not instantly,
to be sure.
You see, their young
enter through the ears...
and wrap themselves
around the cerebral cortex.
This has the effect
of rendering the victim...
extremely susceptible
to suggestion.
Later, as they grow...
follows madness...
and death.
Khan, listen to me.
These are pets, of course.
Not quite domesticated.
Captain Kirk
was only doing his duty.
That's better.
Now tell me,
why are you here?.
And tell me where I may find...
James Kirk.
Enterprise to Admiral Kirk's
shuttle. You're cleared for docking.
Approach port side torpedo bay.
Enterprise, this is Admiral Kirk's
party on final approach.
Enterprise welcomes you.
Prepare for docking.
I hate inspections.
I'm delighted. Any chance
to go aboard the Enterprise.
I, for one, am glad to have you
at the helm for three weeks.
I don't think
these kids can steer.
Open the airlock.
- Permission to come aboard.
- Welcome, Admiral.
I think you know
my trainee crew.
Certainly, they have
come to know you.
Yes, we've been through
death and life together.
Mr. Scott, you old space dog.
You're well.
I had a wee bout, sir,
but Dr. McCoy pulled me through.
Wee bout of what?.
- Shore leave, Admiral.
- Oh, I see.
And who do we have here?.
Midshipman First Class Peter
Preston, engineer's mate, sir.
-First training voyage, Mr. Preston?.
-Yes, sir.
I see.
Well, shall we start
with the engine room?.
We'll see you there, sir.
Everything is in order.
That'll be a pleasant surprise,
Mr. Scott.
I'll see you on the bridge,
Admiral.
Company, dismissed.
I believe you'll find
everything shipshape, Admiral.
Oh, do you?.
Do you have any idea,
Midshipman Preston...
how many times I've had to listen
to Mr. Scott on the comm...
telling me his trouble?.
Do you have any idea the ribbing
I've had to endure...
in the officer's mess
to the effect that...
the Enterprise is
a flying deathtrap?.
Oh, no, sir!
This is the finest engine room
in the whole Starfleet!
If the admiral can't see the facts,
then with all due respect...
he's as blind
as a Tiberian bat.
Sir.
Midshipman, you're a tiger.
My sister's youngest, Admiral.
Crazy to get to space.
Every young man's fantasy.
I seem to remember it myself.
Mr. Scott, are your engines capable
of handling a training cruise?.
Give the word, Admiral.
- The word is given.
- Aye, sir.
But, Admiral, how about
the rest of the inspection?.
This is Starfleet Operations.
Enterprise is clear for departure.
Admiral on the bridge.
- Prestage flux chamber, port.
- On.
- Prestage flux chamber, starboard.
- Main stage flux chamber, port.
- Enabled.
- Running lights on.
- Main stage flux chamber starboard.
- Enabled.
- Intercooler status.
- Standby.
- Very well, Mr. Saavik.
- You may clear all moorings.
- Aye, sir.
- All moorings are cleared, Captain.
- Thankyou.
Lieutenant...
have you ever piloted
a starship out of space dock?.
Never, sir.
Take her out, Mr. Saavik.
Aye, sir.
For everything there is
a first time, Lieutenant.
Don't you agree, Admiral?.
- Aft thrusters, Mr. Sulu.
- Aft thrusters.
- Would you like a tranquilizer?.
- Ahead one-quarter impulse power.
Ahead one-quarter impulse power.
- We are free to navigate.
- Course heading, Captain?.
Captain's discretion.
Mr. Sulu...
you may indulge yourself.
Aye, sir.
Does that about do it?.
I don't think there's
another piece of information...
we could squeeze
into the memory banks.
- We'll design a bigger one.
- Who would want to build it?.
Dr. Marcus.
Comm-pic coming in
on hyperchannel.
It's the starship Reliant.
On the screen, please,Jedda.
Come in, please. This is
the Reliant calling Regula I.
Repeat, this is USS Reliant.
Commander, we are receiving.
This is Regula I. Go ahead.
Ah, Dr. Marcus. Good.
We're en route to you
and should be there in three days.
En route?. Why?. We weren't
expecting you for three months.
- Has something happened?.
- Nothing has happened.
Ceti Alpha VI has checked out.
Then I don't understand
why you're coming.
We have received new orders.
Upon arrival at Regula I...
all materials
of Project Genesis...
will be transferred
to this ship...
for immediate testing
on Ceti Alpha VI.
- Who do they think they are?.
- Please, be quiet.
Commander Chekov,
this is completely irregular.
Who gave the order?.
The order comes from
Starfleet Command, Dr. Marcus...
direct from the general staff.
It's a civilian--
Genesis is a civilian project
under my control.
I have my orders.
Pin him down, Mother.
Who gave the order?.
The order comes from...
Admiral James T. Kirk.
I knew it! I knew it!
The military's wanted
to get their hands on this.
This is completely improper.
I have no intention
of allowing Reliant...
or any unauthorized personnel
access to ourwork or materials.
I am sorry that you
feel that way, Doctor.
Admiral Kirk's orders
are confirmed.
Please prepare to deliver Genesis
to us upon our arrival.
Reliant out.
Well done, Commander.
You realize, sir, they will attempt
to contact Admiral Kirk...
and confirm the order.
Hold, please.
Thank you, sir.
Lieutenant, are you wearing
your hair differently?.
It's still regulation,
Admiral.
May I speak, sir?.
Self-expression doesn't seem
to be one of your problems.
You're bothered by your performance
on the Kobayashi Maru.
- I failed to resolve the situation.
- There's no correct resolution.
It's a test of character.
May I ask how you
dealt with the test?.
You may ask.
That's a little joke.
Humor.
It is a difficult concept.
- It is not logical.
- We learn by doing.
Who's been holding up
the damn elevator?.
Thank you, sir.
- She change her hairstyle?.
- I hadn't noticed.
Wonderful stuff,
that Romulan ale.
-Admiral Kirk.
- Kirk here.
I have an urgent comm-pic
from Space Lab Regula I, sir.
Dr. Carol Marcus.
- I'll take it in my quarters.
-Aye, sir.
It never rains, but it pours.
As a physician,
you should appreciate...
the dangers of reopening
old wounds.
- Sorry.
-Jim, canyou read me?
I can hearyou, Carol.
What's wrong?. What's the matter?.
Why are you taking
Genesis away from us?
Taking Genesis?. Who's taking
Genesis?. Who is taking Genesis?.
- I can see you, but I can't hear.
- Carol--
Jim, did you give the order?
- What order?. Who's taking Genesis?.
- Please help us.
I will not let them have Genesis
without proper authorization.
Have Genesis?.
On whose authority
can they do this?
No one's authority.
- Uhura, what's happening?.
- Transmission jammed at the source.
Alert Starfleet headquarters.
Aye, sir.
I want to talk
to Starfleet Command.
We must have order in here.
This has to be a mistake.
Mistake.
We're all alone here.
They waited until everyone
was on leave to do this.
Reliant is supposed to be at
our disposal, not vice versa.
- Starfleet never intended--
- I can't believe Starfleet--
I tried warning you. Scientists
are always pawns of the military.
Starfleet has kept the peace
for 100 years.
I cannot subscribe to your
interpretation of this event.
You may be right, Doctor...
but what about Reliant?
She's on her way.
- Well, get your gear together.
- Where are we going?.
That's for us to know
and Reliant to find out.
We have a problem.
Something may be wrong on Regula I.
We've been ordered
to investigate.
If memory serves, Regula I is
a scientific research laboratory.
I told Starfleet Command all we had
was a boatload of children.
But we're the only ship
in the quadrant.
Spock, these cadets of yours,
how good are they?.
How will they respond
under real pressure?.
As with all living things...
each according to his gifts.
Of course, the ship is yours.
No, that won't be necessary.
Just get me to Regula I.
As a teacher on
a training mission...
I am content to command
the Enterprise.
If we are to go
on actual duty...
it is clear that the senior officer
on board must assume command.
It may be nothing.
Garbled communications.
- You take the ship.
-Jim...
you proceed from
a false assumption.
I am a Vulcan.
I have no ego to bruise.
You're about to remind me that
logic alone dictates your actions?.
I would not remind you of that
which you know so well.
If I may be so bold...
It was a mistake foryou
to accept promotion.
Commanding a starship
is your first, best destiny.
Anything else is
a waste of material.
- I would not presume to debate you.
- That is wise.
In any case,
were I to invoke logic...
Iogic clearly dictates
that the needs of the many...
outweigh the needs
of the few.
Or the one.
You're my superior officer.
You are also my friend.
I have been and always
shall be yours.
- Stop the energizers.
- Stop energizers.
Put me on speakers.
An emergency situation
has arisen.
By order of Starfleet Command,
as of now, 1 800 hours...
I'm assuming command
of this vessel.
Duty officer,
so note in ship's log.
Plot a new course for Space
Laboratory Regula I. Engine room.
- Mr. Scott.
-Aye, sir?
- We'll be going to warp speed.
-Aye, sir.
Course plotted for Regula I,
Admiral.
Engage warp engines.
- Prepare forwarp speed.
- Ready, sir.
I know none ofyou
were expecting this.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to have to ask you to
grow up sooner than you expected.
Warp five, Sulu.
So much for
the little training cruise.
Course to intercept
Enterprise ready, sir.
Excellent.
- Helmsman?.
- Sir, may I speak?.
We're all with you, sir.
But consider this--
We are free.
We have a ship and the means
to go where we will.
We have escaped permanent exile
on Ceti Alpha V.
You have proved
your superior intellect...
and defeated the plans
of Admiral Kirk.
You do not need
to defeat him again.
He tasks me.
He tasks me,
and I shall have him.
I'll chase him
'round the moons of Nibia...
and 'round
the Antares maelstrom...
perdition's flames...
before I give him up.
Prepare to alter course.
Space Station Regula I,
please come in.
Dr. Marcus, please respond.
This is Enterprise call--
It's no use.
There's no response from Regula I.
- But no longer jammed.
- No, sir. No nothing.
There are two possibilities--
They are unable to respond;
they are unwilling to respond.
How far?.
Twelve hours, forty-three minutes,
present speed.
"Give up Genesis," she said.
What in God's name does it mean?.
Give it up to whom?.
It might help my analysis
if I knew what Genesis was...
beyond the biblical reference.
Uhura, have Dr. McCoy
join us in my quarters.
- Aye, sir.
- Mr. Saavik.
You have the con.
Well, I've got sick bay ready.
Please tell me what's going on.
Computer, request
security procedure...
and access to
Project Genesis summary.
Identify for retina scan.
Kirk, Admiral James T.
Security scan approved.
Summary, please.
Project Genesis--
a proposal to the Federation.
Carol Marcus.
What exactly is Genesis?
Well, put simply,
Genesis is life...
from lifelessness.
It is a process
whereby molecular structure...
is reorganized
at the subatomic level...
into life-generating matter
of equal mass.
Stage one of our experiments
was conducted in the laboratory.
Stage two ofthe series will be
attempted in a lifeless underground.
Stage three will involve
the process on a planetary scale.
It is our intention to introduce
the Genesis Device...
into a preselected area
of a lifeless space body--
a moon or other dead form.
The device is delivered,
instantaneously causing...
what we call
the Genesis effect.
Matter is reorganized
with life-generating results.
Instead of a dead moon,
a living, breathing planet...
capable of sustaining
whatever life-forms...
we see fit to deposit on it.
-Fascinating.
-The reformed moon simulated here...
represents the merest fraction
ofthe Genesis potential...
should the Federation wish
to fund these experiments...
to their logical conclusion.
When we consider the problems
of population and food supply...
the usefulness of this process
becomes clear.
This concludes our proposal.
Thank you for your attention.
It literally is Genesis.
Power of creation.
Have they proceeded
with their experiments?.
The tape was made about a year ago.
I assume they've reached stage two.
Dear Lord, do you think
we're intelligent enough to--
Suppose--
What if this thing was used
where life already exists?.
It would destroy such life
in favor of its new matrix.
Its new matrix.
Do have any idea
what you're saying?.
I was not attempting to evaluate
its moral implications, Doctor.
As a matter of cosmic history,
it has always been...
easier to destroy
than to create.
Not anymore.
Now we can do both at the same time.
According to myth,
the earth was created in six days.
Now watch out! Genesis will
do it for you in six minutes.
I do not dispute that
in the wrong hands--
In the wrong hands?.
Would you mind telling me
whose are the right hands...
my logical friend?.
Are you, by any chance,
in favor of these experiments?.
- Gentlemen, this isn't--
- Really, Dr. McCoy.
You must govern your passions.
They will be your undoing.
- Logic suggests--
- Logic?.
My God, the man's
talking about logic.
We're talking about
universal armageddon.
- You green-blooded, inhuman--
- Bridge to Admiral Kirkk.
Admiral, sensors indicate
a vessel in our area, closing fast.
- What do you make of her?.
- It's one ofours. It's Reliant.
Reliant?.
Try the emergency channels.
Picture, Mr. Saavik.
Slow to one-half impulse power.
Let's be friends.
Slowing to one-half
impulse power.
Reliant in our section--
this quadrant, sir, and slowing.
Sir, may I quote general order 1 2?.
"On the approach of any vessel...
when communications
have not been established--"
Lieutenant, the admiral is
well aware of the regulations.
Aye, sir.
Is it possible their
comm system has failed?.
It would explain
a great many things.
They're requesting
communication, sir.
Let them eat static.
They're still running
with shields down.
Of course.
We are one big happy fleet.
Ah, Kirk, my old friend.
Do you know the Klingon proverb
that tells us...
revenge is a dish
that is best served cold?.
It is very cold in space.
This is damn peculiar.
- Yellow alert.
- Energize defense fields.
I'm getting a voice message.
They say their chambers coil
is overloading their comm system.
- Spock?.
- Scanning.
Their coil emissions
are normal.
They still haven't raised
their shields.
Raise ours.
- Their shields are going up.
- Lock phasers on target.
Locking phasers on target.
- Locking phasers.
- Raise shields.
Fire!
- Get those shields up!
- Trying, sir!
I can't get power.
- Turn off those damn channels!
- Mr. Scott on the screen.
We're just hanging on, sir.
The main energizer's out.
- Try auxiliary power.
- Aye, aye, sir,
Damage report.
- They knew exactly where to hit us.
- Who?.
Who knew where to hit us?.
And why?.
One thing is certain.
We cannot escape on auxiliary power.
Visual.
Sulu, divert power to phasers.
- Too late.
- Hang on!
- Scotty, what's left?.
-Just the battery, sir.
I can have auxiliary power
in a few minutes.
We don't have a few minutes!
- Can you give me phaser power?.
- A few shots, sir.
- Not enough against their shields.
- Who the hell are they?.
Admiral, the commander of
the Reliant is signaling.
He wishes to discuss
terms of our surrender.
Put it on screen.
- Admiral--
- Do it!
While we still have time.
On screen, sir.
You still remember, Admiral.
I cannot help but be touched.
I, of course, remember you.
What is the meaning of this attack?.
Where's the crew of the Reliant?
Surely, I have made
my meaning plain.
I mean to avenge myself upon you,
Admiral.
I deprived your ship of power,
and when I swing around...
I mean to deprive you
of your life.
But I wanted you to know first
who it was who had beaten you.
If it's me you want...
I'll have myself beamed aboard.
- Spare my crew.
- I make you a counterproposal.
I'll agree to your terms if--
if--
in addition to yourself...
you hand over to me
all data and material...
regarding the project
called Genesis.
Genesis?. What's that?.
Don't insult my intelligence,
Kirk.
Give me time to recall
the data on our computers.
I give you 60 seconds,
Admiral.
Clear the bridge.
At least we know he
doesn't have Genesis.
Keep nodding as though
I'm still giving orders.
Mr. Saavik, punch up the data charts
of Reliant's command console.
Reliant's command?.
- Hurry.
- Forty-five seconds.
- The prefix code?.
- It's all we've got.
- Chart's up, sir.
-Admiral?
We're finding it.
Please.
Please, you've got to give us time.
The bridge is smashed.
The computer's inoperative.
Time is a luxury
you don't have, Admiral.
Damn!
It's coming through now, Khan.
- Reliant's prefix number is 16309.
- I don't understand.
You have to learn why
things work on a starship.
Each ship has its own
combination code--
To prevent an enemy from
doing what we're attempting.
We're using our console...
to order Reliant
to lower her shields.
Assuming he hasn't changed the
combination. He's quite intelligent.
Fifteen seconds, Admiral.
How do we know
you'll keep your word?.
I've given you no word to keep,
Admiral.
In my judgment,
you simply have no alternative.
I see your point.
Stand by to receive
our transmission.
Mr. Sulu, lock phasers on target
and await my command.
Phasers locked.
Time's up, Admiral.
Here it comes. Now, Mr. Spock.
Sir, our shields are dropping.
- Raise them!
- I can't!
Where's the override?.
The override?.
Fire!
Fire! Fire!
- We can't fire, sir!
- Why can't you?.
They've damaged the photon control
and the warp drive.
We must withdraw! Sir, we must!
Enterprise will wait.
She's not going anywhere.
- Sir, you did it.
- I did nothing!
Except get caught
with my britches down.
I must be getting senile.
Mr. Saavik, you go right
on quoting regulations.
Meantime, let's find out
how badly we've been hurt.
- Is the word given, Admiral?.
- The word is given.
Warp speed.
Aye.
Why?.
He wants to kill me for passing
sentence on him 15 years ago.
He doesn't care who stands
between him and his vengeance.
I'm sorry, Scotty.
He stayed at his post
when the trainees ran.
Admiral, this is Spock.
Engine room reports
auxiliary power restored.
We can proceed
at impulse power.
Best speed to Regula I.
Kirk out.
Scotty, I have to ask.
Is there any chance of getting
the mains back on the line?.
I do not think so, sir,
but you'll have my best.
Thanks.
I know you tried, Doctor.
You all right?.
I don't know.
Doctors lose patients sometimes.
Damn it. I'm still in the dark.
How did he know about Genesis?.
I don't know.
But what's important is to prevent
him from getting his hands on it.
You said it yourself, it's a bang
that could rearrange the universe.
There still may be time.
You gave as good as you got.
We're alive only because I knew
something about these ships...
that he didn't.
Approaching Regula
and Space Lab Regula I.
Space Station Regula I,
this is the Starship Enterprise.
Please come in.
Space Station Regula I,
do you read?
Space Station Regula I, this is
Enterprise. Please ackknowledge.
This is Enterprise.
Do you read me?
Space Station Regula I,
do you read?
Please come in.
There's no response, sir.
Sensors, Captain?.
Scanners and sensors
are still inoperative.
There's no way to ascertain
what's inside the station.
No way of telling if Reliant
is still in the area.
Precisely.
What do you make of that planetoid
beyond?.
Regula is class D.
It consists of various
unremarkable ores.
Essentially a great rock in space.
Reliant could be hiding
behind that rock.
A distinct possibility.
-Engineering.
-Aye, sir.
Mr. Scott, do you have enough power
for transporters?.
Barely, sir.
- I'm going down there.
- Khan could be down there.
He's been there. Hasn't found what
he wants. Can you spare someone?.
- There may be people hurt.
- Yeah. I can spare me.
Begging the admiral's pardon,
general order 15--
"No flag officer shall
beam into a hazardous area...
without armed escort."
There's no such regulation.
All right. Join the party.
Mr. Spock, the ship is yours.
Jim. Be careful.
We will.
Indeterminate life signs.
Phasers on stun.
Move out.
Well, rigor
hasn't set in.
This couldn't have happened
too long ago,Jim.
Carol.
This is Enterprise calling
Space Lab Regula I. Respond please.
Admiral. Over here.
Dr. Marcus, come in, please.
Oh, my God.
Please acknowledge signal.
Please--
Commander Uhura,
this is Lieutenant Saavik.
We're all right.
Please stand by. Out.
Oh, sir, it was Khan.
We found him
on Ceti Alpha V.
- Easy. Easy.
- He--
He put creatures
in our bodies...
to control our minds.
It's all right.
You're safe now.
Made us say lies...
do things...
but we beat him.
He thought he controlled us,
but he did not.
The captain was strong.
Captain.
Where's Dr. Marcus?.
Where are the Genesis materials?.
He couldn't find them.
Even the data banks were empty.
Erased?.
He tortured those people.
But none of them would tell him
anything. He went wild.
He slit their throats.
He wanted to tear the place apart,
but he was late.
He had to get back to the Reliant
in time to blow you to bits.
Where's Reliant's crew?. Dead?.
Marooned on Ceti Alpha V.
He's completely mad, Admiral.
He blames you
for the death of his wife.
I know what
he blames me for.
The escape pods
are all in place.
Where's the transporter room?.
- Did he make it down here?.
- It was not my impression.
He spent most of his time trying to
wring the information out of people.
Anything?.
The unit's been left on...
which means nobody remained
to turn it off.
Those people back there bought
escape time for Genesis...
with their lives.
This is not logical.
These coordinates
are deep inside Regula...
a planetoid we know
to be lifeless.
If stage two is completed,
it was going to be underground.
It was going to be
underground, she said.
Stage two ofwhat?.
- Kirk to Enterprise.
- Spock here.
Captain Spock, damage report.
Admiral, if we go by the book,
like Lieutenant Saavik...
hours could seem like days.
I read you, Captain.
Let's have it.
The situation
is grave, Admiral.
We won't have main power
for six days.
Auxiliary power
has temporarily failed.
Restoration may be possible
in two days. By the book, Admiral.
Meaning you can't
even beam us back?
Not at present.
Captain Spock...
if you don't hear from us
within one hour...
your orders are to restore
what power you can...
take the Enterprise
to the nearest starbase...
and alert Starfleet Command as soon
as you're out of jamming range.
Sir, we won't leave you behind.
If you don't hear from us, there
won't be anybody behind. Kirk out.
Well, gentlemen,
you can stay here, or--
If it's all the same, Admiral,
we'd like to share the risk.
Right. Let's go.
Saavik?.
- Go?. Where are we going?.
- Where they went.
Suppose they went nowhere?.
Then this will be your big chance
to get away from it all.
Admiral.
Genesis, I presume.
Phasers down!
You!
- Where's Dr. Marcus?.
- I'm Dr. Marcus.
Jim!
Is that David?.
Mother, he killed everybody
we left behind.
Oh, of course he didn't.
David, you're just
making this harder.
I'm afraid it's even harder
than you think, Doctor.
Please don't move.
Chekov?.
I'm...
sorry, Admiral.
Your Excellency,
have you been listening?.
I have indeed, Captain.
You have done well.
I knew it.
You son of a bitch!
- Don't move, anybody!
- Captain? We are waiting.
What's the delay?.
All is well, sir.
You have the coordinates
to beam up Genesis.
First things first, Captain.
Kill Admiral Kirk.
Sir, it is difficult. I--
I try to obey, but--
Kill him.
I--
Kill him, Terrell, now!
God sakes!
What is it?.
Khan, you bloodsucker!
You're gonna have to do
your own dirty work now.
Do you hear me? Do you?
Kirk.
Kirk, you're still alive,
my old friend.
Still, "old friend."
You've managed to kill
just about everyone else.
But like a poor marksman,
you keep missing the target.
Perhaps I no longer
need to try, Admiral.
They can't take it!
Khan, you've got Genesis.
But you don't have me.
You were going to kill me.
You're going to
have to come down here!
I've done far worse
than kill you.
I've hurt you...
and I wish to go on
hurting you.
I shall leave you
as you left me--
as you left her--
marooned for all eternity...
in the center
of a dead planet.
Buried alive.
This is Lieutenant Saavik
calling Enterprise.
Can you read us?.
He's coming around.
It's no use, Admiral.
They're still jamming
all channels.
If Enterprise followed orders,
she's long since gone.
If she couldn't obey,
she's finished.
So are we, it looks like.
I don't understand.
Who's responsible for all this?.
Who is Khan?.
Well, it's a long story.
We appear to have
plenty oftime.
Is there anything to eat?.
I don't know about anybody else,
but I'm starved.
How can you think of food
at a time like this?.
First order of business--
survival.
There is food
in the Genesis cave...
enough to last a lifetime...
if necessary.
We thought this was Genesis.
This?.
It took the Starfleet
Corps of Engineers...
ten months in space suits
to tunnel out all this.
What we did in there,
we did in a day.
David, why don't you show Dr. McCoy
and the lieutenant our idea of food?.
We can't just sit here.
Oh, yes, we can.
This is just to give us
something to do, isn't it?.
Come on.
Admiral?.
As your teacher Mr. Spock
is fond of saying...
I like to think that there
always are possibilities.
I did what you wanted.
I stayed away.
Why didn't you tell him?.
How can you ask me that?.
Were we together?.
Were we going to be?.
You had your world,
and I had mine.
And I wanted him in mine...
not chasing through the universe
with his father.
Actually...
he's a lot like you...
in many ways.
Please tell me
what you're feeling.
There's a man out there
I haven't seen in 15 years...
who's trying to kill me.
You show me your son
that would be happy to help him.
My son.
My life that
could have been...
and wasn't.
What am I feeling?.
Old.
Worn out.
Let me show you something...
that'll make you feel young...
as when the world was new.
Impulse power restored.
Excellent.
More than a match
for poor Enterprise.
You did all this in a day?.
The matrix formed in a day.
The life-forms grew later
at a substantially accelerated rate.
Jim! This is incredible!
Have you ever seen the like?.
Can I cook or can't I?.
Where is she?.
Sir, may I ask you
a question?.
What's on your mind?.
The Kobayashi Maru, sir.
Are you asking me if we're
playing out that scenario now?.
On the test, sir.
Will you tell me what you did?.
I would really like to know.
Lieutenant, you are looking
at the only Starfleet cadet...
who ever beat the no-win scenario.
How?.
I reprogrammed the simulation so it
was possible to rescue the ship.
What?.
He cheated.
Changed the conditions
of the test.
Got a commendation for original
thinking. I don't like to lose.
Then you never faced
that situation-- faced death.
I don't believe
in the no-win scenario.
Kirk to Spock.
It's two hours. Are you ready?.
On schedule. Give us coordinates,
and we'll beam you aboard.
All right.
I don't like to lose.
We were immobilized. Captain Spock
said it would be two days.
You go by the book.
Spock, you know Dr. Marcus.
- Why, of course.
- Hello, Mr. Spock.
- I'm taking this bunch to sickbay.
- By the book?.
By the book.
Regulation 46-A.
"If transmissions are being
monitored during battle--"
"No uncoded messages
on an open channel."
You lied.
- I exaggerated.
- Hours instead of days.
Now we have minutes
instead ofhours.
- They're inoperative below C deck.
- What is working?.
Not much, Admiral.
We have partial main power.
- That's it?.
- Best we could do in two hours.
That young man, he's my son.
Fascinating.
- Admiral on the bridge.
- Battle stations.
Tactical.
Uh-oh.
She can still outrun us
and outgun us...
but there is the Mutara Nebula
at 153 mark 4.
Scotty, can we make it inside?.
The energizer's bypassed
like a Christmas tree...
so don't give me
too many bumps.
No promises. On yourway.
Trouble with the nebula, sir, is
all that static discharging gas...
clouds our tactical display.
Visual won't function,
and shields will be useless.
Sauce for the goose,
Mr. Saavik.
The odds will be even.
Ready to fire away one.
There she is!
Not so wounded
as we were led to believe.
So much the better.
Estimating nebula penetration
in 2.2 minutes.
Reliant is closing.
If they go in there,
we'll lose them.
Explain it to them.
That was close.
They don't want us
going in there.
Admiral, what happens if Reliant
fails to follow us into the nebula?.
I think we can guarantee that
she'll follow us, Lieutenant.
Remind me to explain to you
the concept of the human ego.
Best speed, Scotty.
One minute
to nebula perimeter.
Why are we slowing?.
We daren't follow them
into the nebula, sir.
Our shields would be useless.
They are reducing speed.
- Uhura, patch me in.
- Aye, sir.
You're on, Admiral.
This is Admiral Kirkk.
We tried it once your way, Khan.
Are you game for a rematch?
I'm laughing at
the superior intellect.
Full impulse power.
No, sir! You have Genesis.
You can have whatever you--
Full power!
Damn you!
I'll say this for him--
he's consistent.
We are now entering
the Mutara Nebula.
Emergency lights.
Tactical.
Inoperative.
Raise the shields.
As I feared, sir--
not functional.
I'm reducing speed.
Target, sir.
- Phaser lock inoperative, sir.
- Best guess. Fire when ready.
Aft torpedoes, fire!
Hold your course.
Phasers starboard!
Fire!
Damage, Mr. Scott.
Admiral, I've got to take
the mains off the line.
It's radiation.
Joachim.
Yours...
is superior.
I shall avenge you.
Could you use
another hand, Admiral?.
Man the weapons console,
Mr. Chekov.
Sporadic energy readings,
port side aft.
Could be an impulse turn.
He won't break off now.
He followed me this far.
He'll be back.
But from where?.
He's intelligent,
but not experienced.
His pattern indicates
two-dimensional thinking.
- Full stop.
- Full stop, sir.
Z minus 10,000 meters.
Stand by photon torpedoes.
Torpedoes ready, sir.
Look sharp.
Fire.
Uhura, send to commander,
Reliant.
- Prepare to be boarded.
- Aye, sir.
Commander, Reliant.
this is Enterprise.
Surrender and prepare
to be boarded.
Enterprise to Reliant.
You are ordered
to surrender your vessel. Respond.
Reliant.
Come in, Reliant.
You are ordered
to surrender your vessel.
Enterprise to Reliant.
You are ordered to surrender
your vessel. Respond.
No, Kirk.
The game's not over.
To the last
I will grapple with thee.
Admiral.
Scanning an energy
source on Reliant.
A pattern I've
never seen before.
It's the Genesis wave.
- What?.
- They're building up to detonation.
- How soon?.
- We encoded four minutes.
We'll beam aboard
and stop it.
You can't.
Scotty, I need warp speed in
three minutes, or we're all dead.
- No response, Admiral.
- Scotty!
Mr. Sulu, get us out of here.
Best possible speed.
Aye, sir.
Are you out
of your Vulcan mind?.
No human can tolerate
the radiation that's in there!
As you are so fond of observing,
Doctor, I am not human.
You're not going in there.
Perhaps you're right.
- What is Mr. Scott's condition?.
- Well, I don't think that he--
I'm sorry, Doctor. I have no time
to discuss this logically.
Remember.
Spock! Get out of there!
Spock, get out of there!
- Time, from my mark.
- Two minutes, ten seconds.
Engine room! What's happening?.
Good God, man!
Get out of there!
No! Don't!
Time.
Three minutes, thirty seconds.
Distance from Reliant.
Four thousand kilometers.
We're not gonna make it, are we?.
No, you can't get away.
From hell's heart,
I stab at thee.
For hate's sake...
I spit my last breath...
at thee.
Sir, the mains
are back on line.
Bless you, Scotty.
Go, Sulu!
My God, Carol, look at it.
Engine room.
Well done, Scotty.
Jim...
I think you'd better
get down here.
- Bones?.
- Better hurry.
Saavik, take the con.
No! You'll flood
the whole compartment.
- He'll die.
- Sir, he's dead already.
It's too late.
Ship...
out of danger?.
Yes.
Don't grieve, Admiral.
It is logical.
The needs of the many
outweigh--
The needs of the few.
Or the one.
I never took
the Kobayashi Maru test...
until now.
What do you think
of my solution?.
I have been...
and always shall be...
your friend.
Live long...
and prosper.
No.
We are assembled here today...
to pay final respects
to our honored dead.
And yet it should be noted that
in the midst of our sorrow...
this death takes place
in the shadow of new life...
the sunrise of a new world...
a world that our beloved comrade
gave his life to protect.
He did not feel this sacrifice
a vain or empty one...
and we will not debate his profound
wisdom at these proceedings.
Of my friend,
I can only say this.
Of all the souls I have
encountered in my travels...
his was the most...
human.
Honors...
hup.
Come.
I don't mean to intrude.
No, not at all.
I should be on the bridge.
Can I talk to you
for a minute?.
I poured myself a drink.
Would you like it?.
Lieutenant Saavik was right.
You never have faced death.
No, not like this.
I haven't faced death.
I've cheated death.
I've tricked my way
out of death...
and patted myself on the back
for my ingenuity.
I know nothing.
You knew enough to tell Saavik
that how we face death...
is at least as important
as how we face life.
Just words.
But good words.
That's where ideas begin.
Maybe you should listen to them.
I was wrong about you...
and I'm sorry.
Is that what
you came here to say?.
Mainly.
And also that I'm...
proud.
Very proud...
to be your son.
Captain's Log:
Stardate 8141.6.
Starship Enterprise
departing for Ceti Alpha V...
to pick up the crew
of USS Reliant.
All is well.
And yet I can't help wondering
about the friend I leave behind.
"There are always
possibilities, '"Spock said.
And if Genesis is indeed...
Iife from death...
I must return
to this place again.
He's really not dead...
as long as we remember him.
"It's a far, far
better thing I do...
than I have
ever done before."
A far better
resting place I go to...
than I have ever known.
- Is that a poem?.
- No.
Something Spock was trying
to tell me on my birthday.
You okay,Jim?.
How do you feel?.
Young.
I feel young.
Space, the final frontier.
These are
the continuing voyages...
of the Starship Enterprise.
Her ongoing mission...
to explore strange, new worlds...
to seek out new life-forms
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no man has gone...
before.