Senators, consider the opportunities
for the Empire.
At last the destinies of the planets
Romulus and Remus will be united.
Shinzon of Remus offers us a chance to
make ourselves
stronger than ever.
It would be madness to reject it.
I beg you not to let prejudice or politics
interfere with this alliance.
By joining Shinzon's forces with ours,
not even the Federation
- will be able to stand in our way...
- Enough!
The decision is made. The military
does not dictate policy on Romulus.
The Senate has considered
Shinzon's proposal and rejected it.
He and his followers will be met with
force and sent back to their black rock!
- Do I make myself clear?
- Yes, sir.
Praetor, I have an appointment
with the Tholian ambassador.
Of course.
Senators, are there any others
who wish to speak?
Then I call for a vote on the motion to
open trade negotiations with Celes II.
The Reman mines have not
been filling their quotas.
Consider the trade committee's findings.
As much as we don't want...
Someone alert security!
Bring back Senator Tal'Aura!
Duty. A starship captain's life
is filled with solemn duty.
I have commanded in battle, negotiated
peace between implacable enemies.
I have represented the Federation
in first contact with 27 alien species.
But none of this compares
with my solemn duty today...
...as best man.
Now, on an occasion such as this,
it is expected that I be gracious
and fulsome in my praise
on the wonders of this blessed union.
But have the two of you
considered what you are doing to me?
You're happy, but what about my needs?
This is all a damned inconvenience.
While you're settling in on the Titan,
I will be training my new first officer.
You know him.
He's a tyrannical martinet who will never,
ever allow me to go on away missions!
That is the regulation, sir.
Starfleet Code, section 12...
- Data.
- Sir?
- Shut up.
- Yes, sir.
15 years I've been waiting to say that.
No, seriously, Will, Deanna,
there's still time to reconsider. Yes?
- No.
- No? Very well, then.
Will Riker, you have been
my trusted right arm for 15 years.
You have kept my course
true and steady.
Deanna Troi, you have been
my guide and my conscience.
You have helped me recognise
the better parts of myself.
You are my family.
In maritime tradition...
...I wish you both clear horizons.
My good friends, make it so.
The bride and groom!
You ever think about marrying again?
No, 23 was my limit.
Worf?
- Are you all right?
- Romulan ale should be illegal.
It is.
- A lovely toast.
- It was from the heart.
Don't worry. I'll brief your new counsellor
on everything she has to know.
Like hell you are!
You already know too much about me.
I take it there'll be no speeches
during the ceremony on Betazed?
No, no speeches and no clothes.
Ladies and gentlemen and invited
transgendered species,
in Terran and Betazoid conjugal rites,
I've discovered it is traditional
to present the happy couple with a gift.
Given Commander Riker's affection
for archaic musical forms,
I have elected to present the following
as my gift, in honour of their conjugation.
Never saw the sun shining so bright
Never saw things going so right
Noticing the days hurrying by
When you're in love, my, how they fly!
- Blue skies, smiling at me
- Irving Berlin!
Nothing but blue skies do I see...
It's tradition, Worf.
- You should appreciate that.
- I will not do it!
- Won't do what, Mr Worf?
- Captain, I think it inappropriate
for a Starfleet officer to appear... naked.
Come, a strapping fellow like you?
What can you be afraid of?
I'm picking up an odd electromagnetic
signature from the Kolarin system.
- What sort of signature?
- Positronic.
It's very faint but I've isolated it to
the third planet in the Kolarin system.
- What do we know?
- Uncharted.
- We'll have to get closer for more detail.
- Theories?
Positronic signatures are only known
to emanate from androids.
It is logical to theorise
there is an android on Kolarus III.
Just what I feared. Captain?
Diverting there takes us close
to the Romulan Neutral Zone.
It's still well on our side. I think...
...it's worth a look.
Don't worry, Number One.
- We'll have you to Betazed in time.
- Thank you, sir.
Where we will all honour
the Betazoid tradition.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'll be in the gym.
Mr Branson, lay in a course
for the Kolarin system, warp five.
What do you think, Data?
A long-Iost relative?
I read six distinct positronic signatures,
spread out over a few kilometres.
- What about the population?
- Isolated pockets of humanoids.
It appears to be a pre-warp civilisation
in early industrial development.
I wouldn't recommend the transporter.
That ion storm doesn't look neighbourly.
- It could head our way without warning.
- Understood.
- Data, Mr Worf, you're with me.
- I needn't remind you...
I appreciate your concern, Number One,
but I've been itching to try the Argo.
I'll bet.
Captain's prerogative.
There's no foreseeable danger.
And your wife wouldn't forgive me
if anything happened to you.
You have the bridge... Mr Troi.
I am puzzled by the human predilection
for piloting vehicles at unsafe velocities.
Over that rise, sir, half a kilometre.
The electromagnetic field
is disrupting my tricorder.
- We're within metres of the signal.
- Fan out. Let's search around.
- It appears to be a robotic arm.
- Very astute.
Bring it to the vehicle.
This doesn't feel right.
The final signature is 100 metres north.
- It's you.
- The resemblance is striking.
Fascinating.
To the vehicle!
I think it's time
to try some unsafe velocities.
Why do you have a shiny head?
- Conversation isn't appropriate.
- Why?
- The captain has to concentrate.
- Because...
- Data!
Sorry, sir.
Have I said something wrong?
You know, all things considered, Data,
I think you have nicer eyes.
Our eyes are identical, Doctor.
- So what have we got, Geordi?
- Well...
...his mechanics are like Data's,
with less positronic development.
The neural pathways aren't as
sophisticated. I'd say he's a prototype.
Something Dr Soong created
prior to Data.
- Do you have a name, sir?
- I am... B-4.
B-4? Dr Soong's penchant
for whimsical names has no end.
How did you come to be
where we found you?
- I do not know.
- Do you remember anything of your life?
No. Why does the tall man
have a furry face?
Number One, keep me informed,
and Geordi, reassemble him.
- B-4, do you know who I am?
- You are me.
No. My name is Data.
I am your brother.
Tea, Earl Grey, hot.
An Alpha Priority communication from
Starfleet Command for you, Captain.
Acknowledged.
Admiral Janeway, good to see you.
Jean-Luc. How would you like
a trip to Romulus?
- With or without the fleet?
- A diplomatic mission.
We're invited, believe it or not. There's
been an internal political shake up.
The new Praetor, Shinzon,
has requested a Federation envoy.
- New Praetor?
- Here's more. He's Reman.
Believe me, we don't understand
it either. You're the closest ship.
Go and hear what he has to say.
Get the lay of the land.
An unstable Empire could
mean trouble for the quadrant.
- Understood.
- We're sending you all our intelligence.
But it's not much. I don't need to tell you
to watch your back.
- Hardly.
- The Son'a, the Borg,
the Romulans...
you get all the easy assignments.
- Just lucky, Admiral.
- Let's hope it holds. Janeway out.
Helmsman, lay in a new course.
Take us to Romulus. Warp eight.
Course laid in.
- Romulus?
- The Opal Sea will have to wait. Engage.
As you can see, one side
of Remus always faces the sun.
Due to the extreme temperatures on that
half, the Remans live on the dark side.
Little is known of the Reman homeworld,
although scans have revealed dilithium
mining and heavy weapons construction.
The Remans themselves are considered
an undesirable caste in the Empire.
They're said to be formidable warriors.
In the Dominion War, Reman troops
were used as assault forces.
- Cannon fodder.
- How did a Reman get to be Praetor?
- I don't get it.
- Romulan collaborators?
- Coup d'état?
- The Praetor's power is their fleet.
They must have been behind Shinzon.
What have we learned about Shinzon?
Only a part of his military record.
He is young and a capable commander.
He won 12 major engagements
in the war.
- Beyond that, we know nothing.
- Well, we're sailing into the unknown.
Keep at it. Give me anything
you can. Dismissed.
I still can't believe the captain
went along with a memory download.
He agrees that the B-4 probably has
the same self-actualisation
parameters as myself.
If my memory engrams are successfully
integrated into his positronic matrix,
- he should have all my abilities.
- He'd have all your memories as well.
- You feel comfortable with that?
- I feel nothing, Geordi.
With my memory engrams, he will be
able to be a more complete individual.
- An individual more like you, you mean?
- Yes.
Maybe he's not supposed to be like you.
Maybe he's supposed to be as he is.
That might be so, but he should have
the opportunity to explore his potential.
OK, we're done.
- B-4, do you know where you are?
- I am in a room with lights.
Remember our father?
- Our father?
- Yes, Dr Soong.
- No.
- Do you know the name of the captain?
No.
Data, he's assimilating
a lot of programming.
He's a lot less sophisticated than you.
We don't know if his matrix will be able
to adapt. We need to give him time.
Geordi, what purpose does this serve?
- What?
- This.
A redundant memory port.
Maybe the provisional storage
is in case
his neural pathways overload.
Mind if I keep him here?
Run a few diagnostics?
I do not mind.
- Data!
- No.
Remain with Commander La Forge.
He will try to help you.
Captain's log: Stardate 56844.9.
The Enterprise has arrived at Romulus
and waits at the designated coordinates.
All our hails have gone unanswered.
We've been waiting for 17 hours.
- Counsellor?
- They're out there, sir.
- Captain! Recommend we raise shields.
- Not yet, Mr Worf.
With due respect to diplomatic protocol,
the Federation Council isn't here.
- We are.
- Patience. Diplomacy is very exacting.
- We will wait.
- Captain...
- Shields!
- No!
- Captain...
- Tactical!
52 disruptor banks,
27 photon torpedo bays,
primary and secondary shields.
She's a predator.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Enterprise, we are the
Reman warbird, Scimitar.
- Praetor Shinzon, I'm pleased to...
- I am not Shinzon.
I am his viceroy.
We are sending transport coordinates.
- Not very chatty.
- Away Team, transporter room four.
I hope you'll forgive the darkness.
We are not comfortable in the light.
- Praetor Shinzon?
- Captain Picard.
Jean-Luc Picard.
I'd always imagined you taller.
Isn't that odd?
You may scan me without subterfuge,
Commander Data.
- You are not as we imagined you.
- No?
You're human.
Why have you asked us to come here?
Praetor?
- I've never met a human woman before.
- I'm only half human.
Deanna Troi, of Betazed.
Empathic and telepathic abilities,
ship's counsellor.
All this I knew. But I never knew
you were so beautiful.
You're quite familiar with our personnel.
I am, Commander Riker.
May I touch your hair?
We came to Romulus on a matter we
were assured was of great importance.
If you have anything to say to us as
Federation representatives, do it now.
Yes, I'm sorry, Captain.
There is so much we need to talk about.
- I would be interested to know what.
- Unity, Captain!
Tearing down the walls between us
to recognise that we are one.
I'm talking of the thing
that makes us the same.
Peace. We want peace.
You're thinking this all sounds
too good to be true,
but that the chance
for peace is too promising to ignore.
I'm right?
- Yes.
- Perhaps it's time to add illumination.
Computer, raise the lighting four levels.
When I was young I had an odd disease.
I developed
a hyper-sensitivity to sound.
Even a whisper caused me agony.
No one could do anything.
Finally I was taken to a doctor
with experience of Terran illnesses.
And he diagnosed Shalaft's Syndrome...
Do you know of it, Captain?
Yes.
Then you know
it's a very rare syndrome.
Genetic. Apparently, all the male
members of a family have it.
Eventually I was treated and now
I can hear as well as you can, Captain.
I can see as well as you can.
I can feel everything you feel.
In fact, I feel exactly what you feel.
Don't I, Jean-Luc?
Come to dinner tomorrow on Romulus.
Just the two of us.
Or should I say, just the one of us?
I think you'll be wanting this.
Until tomorrow then, Captain.
We have much to discuss.
Computer, return lighting
to previous level.
There's no doubt. Right down to
your strain of Shalaft's Syndrome.
He's a clone. They probably used
a hair follicle or skin cell.
- Why?
- I intend to find out, Number One.
Inform Starfleet of the situation. I need
to know where the hell he came from.
Counsellor.
We supported you, Shinzon,
when you assassinated the Senate.
You told us the timing was perfect
to attack the Federation. Why the delay?
You don't have to understand.
Why bring the Enterprise here?
- I have a purpose.
- Then enlighten us.
Silence, Romulan!
You must learn patience, Commander.
Spend 18 hours every day
under the lash of a Romulan guard
and you'll soon understand patience.
Now go.
Commander Donatra.
Remain.
There's a word I want you to consider.
Allegiance. It's something I demand
from those who serve me.
- Do I serve you?
- Yes... And I think faithfully.
Commander Suran, on the other hand,
gives me pause.
Here's another word, Praetor.
Trust.
Do you trust me?
How far does that trust extend?
How deep does it go?
What must a commander do
to prove herself faithful?
What must a woman do?
You are not a woman.
You are a Romulan.
Serve me faithfully
and you will be rewarded.
Keep those lovely eyes
on Commander Suran.
And at the first sign of treachery...
Dispose of him.
Then you will have proven yourself.
Now go.
Commander!
If you ever touch me again...
...I'll kill you.
The Romulans had gained possession
of your DNA and created me.
And when I was ready,
they were going to replace you with me.
Put a Romulan agent at the heart
of Starfleet. It was a bold plan.
- What happened?
- As happens frequently on Romulus,
a new government came to power
and abandoned the plan.
They were afraid I'd be discovered
and that it would lead to war.
- Not quite the face you remember.
- Not quite.
A lifetime of violence will do that.
They broke my nose, my jaw.
But so much is the same. The eyes.
- Surely you recognise the eyes?
- Yes.
Our eyes reflect our lives, don't they?
And yours are so confident.
- So I'm not as tall as you expected?
- I'd always hoped I might hit two metres.
As had I.
How did you end up on Remus?
They sent me there to die.
How could a mere human survive
the dilithium mines?
Not that it mattered, as I was no longer
part of their plans against the Federation.
In those terrible depths lived only the
damned. Along with the Reman slaves,
I was condemned
to unceasing labour and starvation
under the brutal heel
of the Romulan guards.
Only the strongest
had any hope of survival.
I was only a child when they took me.
I didn't see the sun or the stars
for ten years.
The only thing the Romulan guards
hated more than the Remans...
...was me.
But one man took pity on me,
the man that became my viceroy and
protected me from the guards' cruelty.
He taught me how to survive.
And in that dark place,
where there was nothing of myself,
I found my Reman brothers.
They showed me the only kindness
I've ever known.
- This is all to liberate the Remans?
- The single thought behind all I've done.
From secretly building the Scimitar
to assembling my army.
Finally coming to Romulus, in force.
I knew they'd never give us freedom.
- I would have to take it!
- But how many Romulans died for it?
Too many. But finally the Empire
is realising that there is a better way.
And that way is peace.
- You don't trust me.
- I have no reason to.
You have every reason.
If you had lived my life,
and experienced the suffering of my
people, you'd be standing where I am.
If you'd lived mine, you'd understand
my responsibility to the Federation.
I cannot allow my personal feelings
to unduly influence my decisions.
All I have are my personal feelings!
I want to know what being human
means. The Remans gave me a future.
- You can tell me about my past.
- I can tell you about mine.
- Were we Picards always warriors?
- I think of myself as an explorer.
Well, were we always explorers?
I was the first Picard
to leave our system.
It caused quite a stir in the family,
but I'd spent my youth...
Looking at the stars, dreaming
about what was up there, about...
New worlds.
I'm trying to believe you.
If there is one ideal
the Federation holds most dear,
it is that all men,
all races, can be united.
What better example?
A Starfleet captain
standing in the Romulan Senate.
Nothing would make me more proud
than to take your hand in friendship.
In time. When trust has been earned.
- Sir, the main computer was accessed.
- Source?
It'll take time to figure out. The data
stream was re-routed all over the ship.
- What was accessed?
- That's what I can't figure out.
It's mostly basic stellar cartography:
Star charts, protocols, colony uplinks.
- It's not even restricted material.
- We must still learn the source.
Captain, there's something else.
I was reviewing the sensor logs. Look!
When the Scimitar de-cloaked, there
was a spike in the tertiary EM band.
You're not going to believe this.
It's Thalaron.
- I thought Thalaron radiation was theory.
- That's why initial scans missed it.
He's got it.
Research was banned in the Federation
because Thalaron is biogenic.
It can consume organic material
at the subatomic level.
I can't overestimate the danger
of Thalaron radiation.
A microscopic amount could kill
all of us in seconds.
Understood. I want to know what he has
and how we can neutralise any threat.
I need options.
This was a mistake. We're wasting time.
My time. And I'll spend it how I choose.
Do not forget our mission, Shinzon.
We must act. Now!
We'll return to the Scimitar.
I was merely curious about him.
Come.
Come in.
Remember him?
- He was a bit cocky as I recall.
- He was a damned fool.
Selfish. Ambitious.
Very much in need of seasoning.
He turned out all right.
I really wanted to believe Shinzon.
But this Thalaron radiation
just can't be explained away.
Whatever he's after, it isn't peace.
Is he very much the way you were?
Oh, yes.
- Data to Captain Picard.
- Go ahead.
We have identified the source
of the unauthorised computer access.
We have found a tactical advantage.
On my way.
Will?
As ship's counsellor,
I recommend you get some sleep.
Some honeymoon!
Come to bed.
Imzadi.
He can never know you as I can.
He can never touch you as I can.
- This isn't real!
- Feel my lips.
I'm with you, Imzadi.
I'll always be with you now.
- This isn't real!
- What is it?
- No!
- Deanna?
- Deanna!
- No!
The bond has been broken.
Find her again.
We've received the transponder signal.
It's accelerating.
You have no more time for games.
Have the doctors prepare.
Transport.
Begin the download.
Tea, hot.
Aside from elevated levels of adrenalin
and serotonin, you're perfectly normal.
Deanna, can you describe it?
It was... It was a violation.
Shinzon's viceroy seems able
to reach into my thoughts.
I'm a liability. I request to be relieved.
Permission denied. If you can endure
more of these assaults, I need you.
Now more than ever. The Enterprise
is far from Federation space...
Shields up!
Hello.
Why am I here? Why do this?
I was Ionely.
- What are you going to do?
- I need a blood sample.
What is it your Borg friends say?
Resistance is futile.
Oh, yes, the android.
- The bait you couldn't refuse.
- All of this to capture me?
Don't be so vain.
After we found it, we had to make
a few modifications.
An extra memory port,
a hidden transponder.
I've now gained access to Starfleet's
communications protocol.
I now know the exact location
of your entire fleet.
- You may go.
- Where?
Out of my sight.
- What is all this about?
- It's about destiny!
- About a Reman outcast...
- You're not Reman!
And I'm not quite human! So what am I?
My life is meaningless
as long as you're still alive.
What am I while you exist?
A shadow? An echo?
If your issues are with me,
then deal with me.
This has nothing to do with my ship
or the Federation!
But it does. We will no longer
bow before anyone as slaves.
Not the Romulans
and not your mighty Federation.
We are a race bred for war.
And conquest.
You're ready to plunge the quadrant into
war to satisfy your personal demons?
It's amazing how little you know yourself.
- I'm incapable of such an act!
- You are me!
The same noble Picard blood
runs through our veins.
Had you lived my life,
you'd be doing exactly as I am!
So look in the mirror. See yourself.
Consider that, Captain.
I can think of no greater torment for you.
Shinzon... I'm a mirror for you as well.
Not for long, Captain.
I'm afraid you won't survive to witness
the victory of the echo over the voice.
His cloak is perfect. No tachyon
emissions, no residual antiprotons.
Keep at it, Geordi. Find a way in.
Praetor Shinzon needs the prisoner.
- About time, Data.
- My mission succeeded.
I have located the radiation source.
This entire ship is a Thalaron generator.
The activation matrix is on the bridge.
It's a weapon, then... And the download?
Shinzon believes he has
our communication protocols.
They'll give him inaccurate locations
for all Starfleet vessels.
- Good work.
- Sir...
Geordi fitted the prototype
for the Emergency Transport Unit.
Use this, sir, to return to the Enterprise.
- It'll only work for one of us.
- Yes, sir.
We'll find a way off together.
It is time for the procedure.
Move, puny human animal!
A bit less florid, Data.
Kill him!
This way, sir. There is a shuttlebay
94 metres from our current position.
- There it is, sir!
- Go!
It has encrypted security.
Alacrity would be appreciated!
Reman is a complex language
with pictographs as verb roots...
That's fascinating, Data,
but we really need that door open!
According to the ship's manifest,
they are Scorpion-class attack fliers.
- Data, what do you imagine this is?
- Port thruster.
Would you like me to drive, sir?
- Can you open the shuttlebay doors?
- Negative. A forcefield is now in place.
Well, then... only one way to go.
- Is this wise, sir?
- We're about to find out.
- Power up the disruptors.
- Ready, Captain.
Fire!
Tractor beam!
Lock on transporter!
I have them.
- This has gone far enough!
- I thought we'd discussed patience.
Mine is waning. We supported you as
you promised action. Yet you delay.
The Enterprise is immaterial. They
won't make it out of the Neutral Zone.
In two days, the Federation will be
crippled beyond repair.
Satisfied?
- For the moment.
- And when I return
you and I shall have a little talk
about showing proper respect!
What's happening to his face?
Commander, a moment.
Are you prepared
to have your hands drenched in blood?
He's not planning to defeat Earth.
He's planning its annihilation.
His sins will mark us all, for generations.
The more I studied his DNA, the more
confusing it got. I drew one conclusion.
Shinzon was created
with temporal RNA sequencing
so that his aging
process could be accelerated
to reach your age more quickly
and skip 30 years of his life.
But the sequencing wasn't activated,
so his cellular structure is decaying.
- He's dying.
- Dying?
- Can anything be done for him?
- Only a complete transfusion
from the only donor
with compatible DNA... You.
- How long does he have?
- I can't say for sure.
But the rate of decay is accelerating.
Then he'll come for me.
I know.
- Brother, I cannot move.
- No.
I have only activated your cognitive
and communications subroutines.
- Why?
- Because you are dangerous.
Why?
You were programmed to gather
information to use against this ship.
I do not understand.
It's called a cascading biogenic pulse.
Thalaron's properties allow the energy
beam to expand almost without limit.
Depending on its radiant intensity,
it could encompass a ship.
Or a planet.
He'd only have built such a weapon
for one reason. He's going after Earth.
- How can you be certain?
- I know how he thinks.
Destroy humanity,
you cripple the Federation.
- The Romulans invade.
- No way of penetrating his cloak?
No.
He could be close to every Starfleet ship
and they'd never know.
We do have one advantage.
He needs your blood to live.
- He might come after you first.
- I'm counting on it.
We've been ordered to sector 10-45
to meet our fleet.
- Strength in numbers.
- So we hope.
He must not be allowed
to use that weapon.
All other concerns are secondary.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
All hands, battle stations.
Initiate the forcefield!
Captain's personal log. We're heading
for Federation space at maximum warp.
The crew has responded with
the dedication I've come to expect.
Like a thousand other commanders
on other battlefields, I wait for the dawn.
How long?
A matter of hours...
We must begin the procedure now.
How long until we reach the Rift?
Seven minutes.
Data, what's our current position?
How soon until we reach the fleet?
At our current velocity, we will
arrive at sector 10-45 in 40 minutes.
"For now we see
but through a glass darkly."
- Sir?
- He said he's a mirror.
- Of you, sir?
- Yes.
I do not agree. Although you share
the same genetic structure,
your life has created an individual.
If I had lived his life, is it possible that
I would have rejected my humanity?
B-4 is identical to me, although his
neural pathways are not as advanced.
Even if they were, he would not be me.
- How can you be sure?
- I aspire, sir. To be better than I am.
B-4 does not. Nor does Shinzon.
We are passing through the Bassen Rift.
The projection will return.
It's interfering with our uplink?
The Rift affects all long-range...
Evasive manoeuvres!
Target weapons systems and shields.
I don't want the Enterprise destroyed.
Can you learn to see in the dark?
- Report.
- He's cloaked. We can't get a lock.
He hit our warp drive. We're on impulse.
Full phaser spread, zero elevation!
All banks on my mark!
Scan for shield impacts!
Stand by torpedoes!
Fire!
You're too slow, old man.
Attack pattern Shinzon Theta.
- We are losing dorsal shields!
- Full to port! Fire all ventral phasers!
Minimal damage to the Scimitar.
Defensive pattern Kirk Epsilon.
Shields online.
Already on it.
- Counsellor Troi, report to the bridge.
- Captain, we are being hailed.
On screen.
Captain Picard, will you join me
in your ready room?
You can't trace
my holographic emitters, Captain.
And you can't contact Starfleet.
It's just the two of us now, Jean-Luc.
- As it should be.
- Why are you here?
To accept your surrender.
I can clearly destroy you at any time.
Lower your shields and allow me
to transport you to my ship.
And the Enterprise?
I have little interest
in your quaint vessel, Captain.
Look at me.
Your heart, your hands, your eyes
are the same as mine.
The blood within you,
the raw material is the same.
- We have the same potential.
- That's the past...
It can be the future.
Buried deep within you,
beneath the years of pain and anger,
there is something never nurtured: The
potential to make yourself a better man.
That is what it is to be human:
To make yourself more than you are.
Oh, yes, I know you.
Once, you looked at the stars
and dreamed of what might be.
Childish dreams, Captain.
Lost in the dilithium mines of Remus.
I am what you see now.
I see more. I see what you could be.
The man who is Shinzon and Picard
could never annihilate an entire planet!
- He's better than that!
- He's what his life has made him.
And what will you do with that life?
Waste it in a blaze of hatred?
- There is a better way.
- It's too late!
Never! Make the right choice now!
- I can't fight what I am!
- Yes, you can!
I'll show you my true nature.
Our nature.
And as Earth dies, remember
I will always be Shinzon of Remus!
My voice shall echo through time long
after yours has faded to a dim memory!
Two ships de-cloaking, sir! Romulan!
Captain!
It gets worse.
- We are being hailed.
- On screen.
Captain Picard, Commander Donatra
of the warbird Valdore.
Might we be of assistance?
Assistance?
This is a matter of internal security.
We regret you've become involved.
When this is over, I owe you a drink.
Romulan ale, Captain. Let's get to work.
You heard the lady. Let's go to work!
Coordinate our attack with the Valdore.
- Triangulate fire on shield impacts.
- Aye.
- Aft shields at 40%.
- Keep our bow on the Scimitar.
- Power to forward shields.
- Aye.
Target the warbird.
All forward disruptor banks.
- Forward shields at 10%!
- Bring us about!
Drop cloak on aft port quadrant.
Prepare for emergency stop.
- What?
- You heard me!
He's losing his cloak!
Stand by all forward disruptor banks!
- She's almost on us!
- Not yet.
- Praetor!
- Full stop! Fire!
Restore aft cloak. Full about.
That drink will have to wait.
- You have life support?
- For the moment.
- But we're crippled.
- Understood.
Losing structural integrity on decks
12 to 17, sections 4 to 10.
Forcefields holding.
Evacuate those decks.
Re-route power to shields.
Captain, I may have a way to find them.
Prepare for a lateral run.
All starboard disruptors.
What is it?
She's here!
He's resisting me.
- No!
- Remember me?
Now!
Fire!
Bring me Picard!
You!
Get the cloak back! Target shield
coordinates Beta-3. All disruptors. Fire!
Ventral shielding lost on deck 29!
Compensate!
- Intruder alert!
- Number One.
- Let's go!
- Security detail to deck 29!
- The Romulans fought with honour.
- Yes, they did, Mr Worf.
Cover me!
Medics!
Report!
We have no photon torpedoes.
Phaser banks down to 4%.
If we targeted all phasers in a pattern?
Scimitar shields are still at 70%.
It would make no difference, Captain.
What's he doing?
He wants to look me in the eye.
We've got him!
He thinks he knows what I'm going to do.
Divert all power to the engines.
Even from life support. Give me it all.
- Ready, Captain.
- We are being hailed.
Deanna, stand by. Open a channel.
- I hope you're still alive, Jean-Luc.
- Oh, yes, I am.
Don't you think it's time to surrender?
Why should the rest of your crew die?
Shinzon, I don't think I ever told you
about my first Academy evaluation.
In particular, I was thought
to be extremely... over-confident.
As much as I enjoy listening to you talk,
I really think...
On my mark, Deanna!
All hands, brace for impact!
Engage!
Hard to port!
Divert all power to the engines.
Full reverse!
Computer, stand by
auto-destruct sequence Omega.
Voice pattern Jean-Luc Picard.
Authorisation Alpha-Alpha-3-0-5.
Auto-destruct is offline.
Disruptors are not functional, sir.
Deploy the weapon.
Kill everything on that ship.
Then set a course for Earth.
We must complete our mission.
Matrix initiated.
Sequencing procedure for Thalaron
radiation transfer activated.
Some ideals are worth dying for,
aren't they, Jean-Luc?
Thalaron intermix procedure initiated.
Deployment
of targeting arms commencing.
How long until he can fire?
Targeting should take seven minutes.
When the arms are fully deployed...
...the matrix on the bridge will relay the
Thalaron radiation to the firing points.
No one on the Enterprise will survive.
- How can he? He'll kill you.
- It's not about me any more.
- Prepare a site-to-site transport.
- I don't think...
- That's an order!
- Let me go.
I have to do this... You have the bridge.
Put some distance between you
and the Scimitar. Now, Mr La Forge.
Aye, sir.
That's it! Transporters down.
Counsellor Troi, assume command.
Geordi, come with me.
Thalaron intermix levels 30%.
Four minutes to firing sequence.
Thalaron intermix level 50%.
Three minutes to firing.
Thalaron intermix level 60%.
Two minutes to firing sequence.
Thalaron intermix level 80%.
I'm glad we're together now.
Our destiny is complete.
One minute to firing.
Thalaron intermix level completed.
30 seconds to firing sequence.
- Goodbye.
- Ten...
...nine... eight... seven...
...six... five...
...four... three...
Data?
Captain!
It's Data.
- We're being hailed.
- On screen.
Open a channel.
This is Commander Donatra.
We're dispatching medics and supplies.
Thank you.
You've earned a friend
in the Romulan Empire today.
I hope the first of many. Valdore out.
Geordi... prepare the shuttlebay
for arrivals.
They don't know our procedures.
- Just open the doors.
- I'll take care of it.
You have the bridge, Number One.
Thank you.
To absent friends.
To family.
First time I saw Data, he was leaning
against a tree in the holodeck...
...trying to whistle.
Funniest thing I ever saw.
No matter what he did,
he couldn't get the tune right.
What was that song?
Can't remember the song.
Come.
- Will.
- Permission to disembark, sir.
Granted.
So, where's the Titan off to?
The Neutral Zone.
We're heading up the new task force.
The Romulans are interested in talking.
I can't think of a better man for the job.
If I may, some advice
about your first command?
Anything.
When your first officer insists
you can't go on away missions...
Ignore him.
I intend to.
Serving with you has been an honour.
The honour was mine, Captain.
I don't know if this has made sense.
I wanted you to know the man he was.
In his quest to be more like us...
...he helped us to see
what it means to be human.
My... brother was not human.
No, he wasn't.
But his wonder, his curiosity about
every facet of human nature...
...allowed us to see
the best of ourselves.
He evolved.
He embraced change because he always
wanted to be better than he was.
I... do not understand.
Well, I hope some day you will.
Captain, the warp engines are ready.
Coming. Inform Commander La Forge.
We'll talk later.
Never saw the sun...
- Shining so bright
Never saw things...
Going so right.
Going so right