Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
TACTICAL...
VISUAL...
TACTICAL,
STAND BY ON TORPEDOES.
READY...
FIRE!
EVASIVE!
OUR ANCESTORS CAST OUT THEIR ANIMAL
PASSIONS ON THESE VERY SANDS...
...SAVING OUR RACE THROUGH
THE ATTAINMENT OF KOLINAHR.
KOLINAHR: THROUGH WHICH ALL
EMOTION IS RENOUNCED AND SHED.
YOU HAVE LABOURED
FOR MANY SEASONS, SPOCK...
AND YOU HAVE PROVED YOURSELF
WORTHY TO RECEIVE FROM US...
THIS SYMBOL OF PURE LOGIC.
YOUR THOUGHTS...
GIVE THEM TO ME.
OUR MINDS ARE JOINED, SPOCK...
TOGETHER, AND AS ONE.
I SENSE THE CONSCIOUSNESS
CALLING TO YOU FROM SPACE...
YOUR HUMAN BLOOD
IS TOUCHED BY IT, SPOCK.
YOU HAVE NOT YET ATTAINED
KOLINAHR.
HE MUST SEARCH ELSEWHERE
FOR HIS ANSWER.
HE SHALL NOT FIND IT HERE.
LIVE LONG AND PROSPER, SPOCK.
STARFLEET HEADQUARTERS
STARDATE: 7410.2
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.podnapisi.net