There he is! Let's get him.
Come on!
I'm over here!
Verify materialization sequence.
Bring up the resolution
on radar unit 12.
- Area 7 to Command.
- Go ahead.
We could use another
survey team out here, sir.
Base to Ensign McCauley
and Ensign Gilles,
please report to Area 7
and assist the edaphology team.
Acknowledged.
Transferring anthropometric-data files
to secondary processor.
Still working on correlating
that unidentified blood groupings.
Comparative linguistic analysis
is complete, sir.
Admiral Dougherty is waiting
for this. Transmit it to the ship.
Alert. Area 12.
- The android, he's out of control.
- Report.
He's headed toward the village.
We're trying to stop him.
Over there!
Magnify.
Hold your fire.
What is it? What's happening?
Base to Commander Data.
Rerouting microhydraulic
power distribution.
- Regulating thermal overload.
- Data, report to base immediately.
Transferring positronic-matrix
functions.
Engaging secondary protocol.
He's trying to remove the headpiece.
All field units,
intercept the android.
Artim, it's all right.
Get inside, now.
Find shelter. Everyone, get inside.
Now! Back to your homes. Move it!
Now! Move!
Secondary protocol's active.
- They can see him.
- Stop him. Now.
Commander Data, stand down.
That's an order.
I repeat, stand down!
Who are they?
It's an M-class planet.
Population 300 million.
- Say the greeting again.
- Yew-cheen chef-faw.
Emphasis on the "cheen"
and the "faw."
You either need a new uniform
or a new neck.
"Yew-cheen chef-faw."
My collar size is exactly
as it was at the academy.
Of course it is.
Our guests have arrived.
They're eating the floral arrangements
on the banquet tables.
I guess they don't believe
in cocktails before dinner.
Oh, my God. Are they vegetarian?
That's not in there.
Perhaps we should have the chef
whip up a light balsamic vinaigrette,
something that goes well
with chrysanthemums.
- Yew-cheen.
- Chef-faw.
Yew-cheen chef-faw.
- Bridge to Captain Picard.
- Go ahead, ensign.
Command wants to know
our ETA at the Goren system.
The Goren system?
They need us
to mediate some territorial dispute.
No, no. We can't delay the
archeological expedition to Hanoran II.
That'll put us right in the middle
of the monsoon season.
- Captain.
- Thank you.
The diplomatic corps is busy
with Dominion negotiations.
Oh, yes. So they need us
to put out one more brushfire.
Can anyone remember
when we used to be explorers?
Deck 10.
Remember, they have a significantly
less advanced technology than ours.
They only achieved warp drive
last year.
And the Federation Council decided to
make them a protectorate so quickly.
In view of our losses to the Borg
and the Dominion,
the council feels we need
all the allies we can get these days.
Captain on deck.
You'll be expected to dance
with Regent Cuzar.
Can she mambo?
- Very funny.
- The captain used to cut quite a rug.
La Forge to Picard. Captain, I need
to talk to you before the reception.
- Captain.
- Mr. Worf.
- Worf.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- I was at the Manzar colony...
- He's late. Can it wait?
- I don't think so, commander.
- Excuse me.
Tell him I'm already here. I'll talk
to him when he arrives. Mr. Worf...
Geordi, the captain
would like you to come up.
Tell him we received a communiqué
from Admiral Dougherty.
It's about Data.
Yew-cheen chef-faw, Regent Cuzar.
Welcome aboard the Enterprise.
Captain Picard, may I welcome you
in the time-honored tradition
of my people.
We are so honored to be accepted
within the great Federation family.
- We have a dance later, I believe.
- I look forward to it.
Counselor.
- Nice beadwork.
- Captain. Excuse me. Captain.
Captain, Admiral Dougherty is
onboard a Son'a ship in Sector 441.
He's requesting Data's schematics.
- Is something wrong?
- The message doesn't say.
Well, Data should have
been back by now.
They were only scheduled to observe
the Ba'ku village for one week.
Geordi, would you set up
a secure com-link
- to the admiral in the anteroom.
- Aye, sir.
Captain, Hars Adislo. We met at
the Nel Bato conference last year.
Did you ever have a chance
to read my paper
on thermionic transconductance?
Would you excuse me?
He's not acknowledging
any Starfleet protocol.
He's not responding
to any of our hails.
Have you any idea what precipitated
this behavior?
None. Now he's holding
our people hostage down there.
The Enterprise could be
at your position in two days, admiral.
That's probably not a good idea.
Your ship hasn't been fitted
for this region.
- There are environmental concerns.
- What kind of concerns?
We haven't fully identified
the anomalies yet.
They're calling this whole area
the Briar Patch.
It took us a day to reach a location
where we could even get
a signal to you.
Just get me Data's schematics.
I'll keep you informed. Dougherty out.
- His emotion chip?
- He didn't take it with him.
- Send the admiral Data's schematics.
- Aye, sir.
- Yes, sir.
- Ensign, would you report to the galley
and tell the chef to skip
the fish course.
- Aye, sir.
- I would like our guests to depart
as soon as etiquette allows.
I'm going to ask Worf to delay his
return to DS9 so that he can join us.
We're gonna stop by Sector 441
on our way to the Goren system.
- They are in opposite directions, sir.
- Are they?
I never should have let you talk me
into that duck blind in the first place.
Your Federation procedures
have made this mission
ten times as difficult
as it needed to be.
Our procedures were in place
to protect the planet's population
from unnecessary risk.
Planet's population?
Six hundred people.
If you want to avoid
unnecessary risks,
next time, leave your android home.
Bridge to Ahdar Ru'afo,
we are approaching the planet.
Take us into a high orbit.
Lie down, admiral, the girls
will take 20 years off your face.
Another time, perhaps.
Your self-restraint
puzzles me, admiral.
You continue to deny yourself
every benefit this mission has to offer.
I prefer to wait until we can share
the benefits
with all the people of the Federation.
- Report.
- Phaser blast. Unknown origin.
Raise shields.
- Take us out of orbit.
- Photon torpedoes. Brace for impact.
- The vessel has broken off pursuit, sir.
- Visual contact.
That's our ship.
Captain, we're about to lose all
communications with Starfleet.
Do you have everything you need?
I've downloaded all the files on the
duck-blind mission and the Son'a.
You have two days
to become experts.
Mr. Worf, our job is to come up
with a plan to safely capture Data.
I've already had Commander La Forge
modify this tricorder
with one of Data's actuation servos.
Its operational range is only 4 meters,
but it will shut him down.
Good to have you back, Mr. Worf.
Slow to one-third. Take us in.
Half century ago,
they conquered two primitive races,
the Tarlac and the Ellora,
and then integrated them into
their culture as a labor class.
Look at this. "The Son'a
are known to have produced
mass quantities of the narcotic
ketracel-white."
"Their ships are rumored
to be equipped
with isolytic subspace weapons
outlawed by the second
Khitomer Accord."
Why would we be involved
with these people?
Good question.
- You haven't done that in a long time.
- What?
- What you're doing to my neck.
- Was I doing something to your neck?
Bridge to Commander Worf.
- Worf?
- Captain.
I don't know how they do it
on Deep Space Nine,
but on the Enterprise,
we still report for duty on time.
Sorry, sir. I'm on my way.
We'll skip the court martial this time.
Picard out.
When was the last time we aligned
the torque sensors?
Two months ago, sir.
They don't sound right.
The torque sensors
are out of alignment.
By 12 microns.
- You could hear that?
- When I was an ensign,
I could detect
a 3-micron misalignment.
Excuse me, sir, the Son'a ship
with Admiral Dougherty aboard
has entered tracking range.
Straighten your baldric, commander.
On screen.
Captain, I wasn't expecting you.
This is too important for the Enterprise
to be on the sidelines, admiral.
I wish I had better news.
Commander Data attacked us
in a mission scout ship yesterday.
Ru'afo and I have decided
to send in an assault team.
Commander Worf and I are working
on several tactical plans to save...
Your android has turned
dangerously violent, captain.
Considerable damage
was done to my ship.
He must be destroyed.
I know what Data means to Starfleet,
Jean-Luc,
but our crew is at the mercy
of those people on the planet.
If our first attempt
to capture Data fails...
...I will terminate him.
I should be the one to do it.
I'm his captain...
...and his friend.
All right.
You have 12 hours, captain,
then I want you out
of the Briar Patch.
In the meantime, we'll head out
to the perimeter to call
for Son'a reinforcements,
in case you fail.
Understood.
Good luck, captain.
Dougherty out.
Sensors are not picking up any ships
coming from the surface.
Transmit a wide-band covariant signal.
That ought to get his attention.
He must be using the planet's rings
to mask his approach.
The metaphasic radiation of
the rings is in a state of extreme flux.
We'll steer clear of those.
Come out, come out
Wherever you are
- Sir?
- It's something that my mother...
Hold on.
Open all hailing frequencies.
Data, this is Captain Picard.
Data, please respond.
If we fire tachyon bursts, it might force
him to reset his shield harmonics.
When he does,
we can beam him out.
Make it so.
Direct hit.
He is resetting his shield harmonics.
Beam him out.
He has activated
a transport inhibitor.
Prepare to enter the atmosphere.
We'll use the ionospheric boundary
to shake him.
Scanners are off-line.
Evasive maneuvers.
Heading 1-4-0, mark 3-1.
He can fly a ship.
He can anticipate tactical strategies.
Clearly, his brain is functioning.
We've seen how he responds
to threats.
I wonder how he would respond...
Mr. Worf, do you know
Gilbert and Sullivan?
No sir, I have not had a chance
to meet all the new crew members
since I have been back.
They're composers, Worf.
From the 19th century.
Data was rehearsing a production
of H.M.S. Pinafore just before he left.
A British tar
Is a soaring soul
As free as a mountain bird
His energetic fist
should be ready to resist
A dictatorial word
Sing, Worf, sing.
- His nose should pant
- And his lip should curl
- His cheeks should flame
- And his brow should furl
- His bosom should heave
- And his heart should glow
And his fist be ever ready for a...
Knockdown blow
- His nose should pant
- And his lips should curl
His cheeks should flame
And his brow should furl
His bosom should heave
And his heart should glow
And his fist be ever ready
For a knockdown blow
Prepare the docking clamps.
His eyes should flash
With an inborn fire
His brow with scorn be wrung
He never should bow down
To a domineering frown
Or the tang of a tyrant tongue
- His heart should stamp
- And his throat should growl
- His hair should curl
- And his face should scowl
- His eyes should flash
- And his breast protrude
And this should be
His customary attitude
- His foot should stamp
- And his throat should...
His hair should curl
And his face...
Inertial coupling
is exceeding tolerance.
If we do not release him,
he may destroy both vessels.
I'm not letting go of him.
We must stabilize
the damping field.
Reroute emergency power
to inertial dampers.
The auto-sequencer was
damaged by phaser fire.
Transferring controls to manual.
Power sequence realigned,
engaging stabilizers.
Damping field established.
Maximum power.
Now, Mr. Worf.
Captain, Commander Data
is safely in custody.
Got it!
Captain, Subahdar Gallatin,
Son'a command.
Lieutenant Curtis,
attaché to Admiral Dougherty.
- Are you all right?
- We've been treated extremely well.
They have incredible
mental discipline.
Clarity of perception.
My name is Sojef.
Jean-Luc Picard.
These are my officers,
Dr. Crusher, Counselor Troi.
- Would you like something to eat?
- No, we are here to...
...rescue them.
As you wish.
But I would ask you
to disarm yourselves.
This village is a sanctuary of life.
Prepare the hostages
for transport to the ship.
They should be quarantined
before joining the ship's population.
We were under the impression they
were being held against their will.
It's not our custom
to have guests here at all,
let alone hold anyone
against their will.
The artificial life form
would not allow them to leave.
In fact, he told us they were our
enemies and that more would follow.
- Are you our enemy?
- Anij.
My people have a strict policy
of noninterference in other cultures.
It's our Prime Directive.
Your directive apparently doesn't
include spying on other cultures.
The artificial life form is
a member of my crew.
Apparently, he was taken ill.
There was a phase variance
in his positronic matrix,
which we were unable to repair.
I think the captain finds
it hard to believe
that we'd have any skills
repairing a positronic device.
Our technological abilities
are not apparent
because we have chosen not
to employ them in our daily lives.
We believe that when you create
a machine to do the work of a man,
you take something away
from the man.
But at one time we explored
the galaxy just as you do.
- You have warp capability?
- Capability, yes.
But where can warp drive take us
except away from here?
I apologize for our intrusion.
And because they have
warp capability,
the consequences
to their society will be minimal.
You've done a terrific job, Jean-Luc.
Now, pack your bags
and get the hell out of there.
- How's Data?
- In stasis.
La Forge is completing
the diagnostic.
I'll need all your paperwork tomorrow.
We're heading back your way.
Set a course to rendezvous with us
so you can transfer the crew
and equipment on your way out.
You're not finished here?
Just a few loose ends to tie up.
Dougherty out.
Come in.
- Hi.
- You got a minute?
Sure.
I need a little counseling.
Well, there's a first time
for everything.
So do I lie down or what?
Well, whatever
makes you comfortable.
But this isn't one
of the usual therapeutic postures.
But it is comfortable.
Why don't you try sitting up.
Why don't you try lying down.
Well, you're in quite a mood today.
Do you really need counseling,
or did you come down here to play?
I think I'm having a midlife crisis.
- I believe you.
- I'm not sleeping well.
Dr. Crusher has something
that can take care of that.
What I need, I can't get
from Dr. Crusher.
Counselor, do you think it's possible
for two people to go back in time,
fix a mistake they've made?
On this ship, anything's possible.
- Yuck.
- "Yuck"?
I never kissed you
with a beard before.
I kiss you, and you say, "Yuck"?
I had to reconstruct Data's neural net
and replace these.
They contain memory engrams.
- How were they damaged?
- By a Son'a weapon.
There's no doubt about it, captain.
That's what caused Data
to malfunction.
But the Son'a report claims that they
didn't fire until after he malfunctioned.
Well, I don't believe
it happened that way.
Why would they fire on him
without provocation?
All I know is that he was functioning
normally until he was shot.
Then his fail-safe system
was activated.
- Fail-safe?
- His ethical and moral subroutines
took over all of his basic functions.
But you're saying he still knew the
difference between right and wrong.
In a sense, that's all he knew.
The system was designed
to protect Data against anyone
who might try and take advantage
of his memory loss.
And yet he attacked us, and he told
the Ba'ku that we were a threat.
- The implants bothering you?
- I'm all right.
I think I'm just tired.
Geordi?
- Captain?
- You're on the Enterprise, Data.
I seem to be missing
several memory engrams.
There they are.
Data, what's the last thing
that you remember?
His nose should pant
And his lip should curl
From the mission.
I was in an isolation suit gathering
physiometric data on the Ba'ku.
My last memory is going into the hills,
following some children.
Artim? Do you remember where
you were on the day of lightning
when the artificial life form
appeared to us?
In the hills by the dam.
Can you show us?
There is no reason to fear me.
I am now operating
within normal parameters.
- What?
- They fixed me.
Captain, the boy is afraid of me.
It's nothing personal, Data.
You have to remember, these people
have rejected technology.
I am the personification
of everything they have rejected.
Until this week, that young man
probably never saw a machine,
let alone one that walks and talks.
Bridge to Riker.
Can I get back to you, Mr. Worf?
Admiral Dougherty
is on the com-link, sir.
Patch him through.
- Yes, admiral?
- Why haven't you left orbit?
Captain Picard
is still on the surface, sir.
- Doing what?
- He didn't want to leave
until we could adequately explain
why Data malfunctioned.
His future in Starfleet
could depend on it.
Remind the captain
his 12 hours are up.
- Yes, sir.
- Dougherty out.
Your body is producing
far too many toxins.
We've reached the limit
of genetic manipulation.
I won't need any more
genetic manipulation
if our Federation friends will allow us
to complete this mission.
Tricorder functions are limited
due to heavy deposits of kelbonite
in these hills.
How about a passive radiation scan?
Curious.
There appear to be strong neutrino
emissions coming from the lake.
Can he breathe underwater?
Data doesn't breathe.
Won't he rust?
No.
Captain! Captain!
I believe I know what is causing
the neutrino emissions.
The vessel is clearly Federation
in origin, captain.
"Just a few loose ends to tie up."
We're not interested in such things.
I am.
- I think it would be wiser...
- I'm going with you.
It is a holographic projection.
Incomplete, I might add.
What you're seeing is
a computer-driven image
created by photons and force fields.
I know what a hologram is, captain.
The question is, why would anyone
want to create one of our village?
Data, if you were following the children
and discovered this ship...
It is conceivable I was shot to protect
the secret of its existence.
Why would they duplicate this village,
except to deceive the Ba'ku?
- Deceive us?
- To move you off this planet.
You go to sleep one night
in the village,
wake up the next morning
on this flying holodeck,
transported en masse.
Within a few days,
they're relocated on a similar planet
without ever realizing it.
Why would the Federation or the Son'a
wish to move the Ba'ku?
I don't know.
Computer, end program.
Decloak the vessel.
Help!
I can't swim!
Don't panic.
I've been shot at, thrown into the lake
out of a ship that's come to abduct us,
what's there to panic about?
In the event of a water landing,
I have been designed to serve
as a flotation device.
Mr. Worf, did the hostages mention
anything about a cloaked ship
during their debriefing?
- No, sir.
- Debrief them again.
Have you been in a fight, Mr. Worf?
No, sir. It is a gorch.
Gorch?
Pimple, sir.
Oh, well, it's... It's hardly noticeable.
Smooth as an android's bottom,
eh, Data?
I beg your pardon, sir?
Admiral Dougherty wants to know
why we haven't left yet.
We're not going anywhere.
Deck 5.
Klingons never do anything small,
do you?
Dr. Crusher asked to speak
to you when you returned.
- Picard to Crusher.
- Captain,
the Son'a hostages declined
to be examined.
I had them confined to quarters.
- And our people?
- They're fine.
In fact, they're better than fine.
Increased metabolism,
improved muscle tone, high energy.
We should all be so lucky.
Very well, doctor. Picard out.
Worf, don't release the Son'a officers
until I've talked to Ahdar Ru'afo.
Aye, sir.
Commander, may I?
Computer, music.
No, no, not that. Something Latin.
- Specify.
- The mambo.
That's more like it.
How old are you?
We came here from a solar system
on the verge of self-annihilation,
where technology had created weapons
that threatened to destroy all life.
A small group of us set off
to find a new home,
a home that would be isolated
from the threats of other worlds.
That was 309 years ago.
And you haven't aged
a day since then.
Actually, I was a good deal older
when we arrived,
in terms of my physical condition.
There's an unusual
metaphasic radiation
coming from the planet's rings.
It continuously regenerates
our genetic structure.
You must have noticed
the effects by now.
We've just begun to.
And I suppose you're 75.
No, I'm 12.
The metaphasic radiation won't begin
to affect him until he reaches maturity.
To most offlanders,
what you have here
is more valuable than...
...gold-pressed latinum.
I'm afraid that's the reason
that someone
may be trying to take
your world away from you.
The artificial life form was right.
If it were not for Data, it's probable
that you would be relocated by now.
How can we possibly
defend ourselves?
The moment we pick up a weapon,
we become one of them.
We lose everything we are.
It may not come to that.
Clearly, the architects of this
conspiracy want to keep it a secret.
Not only from you
but from my people as well.
I don't intend to let them.
We've always known that to survive,
we had to remain apart.
Hasn't been easy.
Many of the young people want
to know more about the offland.
They're attracted to stories
of a faster pace of life.
Most of my people
who live that fast a life,
would sell their souls
to slow it down.
But not you?
There are days.
You don't live up to your reputation
as an offlander, Picard.
Well, in defense of offlanders,
there are many more people like me.
Who wouldn't be tempted
by the promise of perpetual youth?
I don't think so.
You give me more credit
than I deserve.
Well, of course I'm tempted.
Who wouldn't be?
But some of the darkest chapters
in the history of my world
involve the forced relocation
of a small group of people
to satisfy the demands
of a large one.
I'd hoped that we'd learn
from our mistakes, but...
...it seems that some of us haven't.
This is extraordinary craftsmanship.
It's the work of students.
They're almost ready
to become apprentices.
In 30 or 40 years,
some of them will take their place
among the artisans.
Apprenticing for 30 years.
Did your people's
mental discipline develop here?
More questions.
Always the explorer.
If you stay long enough,
that will change.
Will it?
You stop reviewing
what happened yesterday.
Stop planning for tomorrow.
Let me ask you a question.
Have you ever experienced
a perfect moment in time?
A perfect moment?
When time seemed to stop, and you
could almost live in that moment.
Seeing my home planet
from space for the first time.
Yes, exactly.
Nothing more complicated
than perception.
You explore the universe.
We've discovered that a single moment
in time can be a universe in itself.
Full of powerful forces.
Most people aren't aware enough
of the now to even notice.
I wish I could spare
a few centuries to learn.
It took us centuries to learn that it
doesn't have to take centuries to learn.
There's one thing I don't understand.
In 300 years,
you never learned to swim?
I just haven't got around to it yet.
I wonder if you're aware of the trust
you engender, Jean-Luc Picard.
- In my experience, it's unusual for...
- For an offlander?
For someone so young.
Geordi.
Captain.
As it turns out, there wasn't anything
wrong with my implants at all.
There was something right
with my eyes.
When Dr. Crusher removed
the ocular connections,
she found that the cells
around my optic nerve had...
Started to regenerate.
It may not last.
And if it doesn't, I just...
I just wanted, before we go...
You know, I've never seen a sunrise.
At least not the way you see them.
Come.
Am I to understand that you are
not releasing my men, captain?
We found the holoship.
Ru'afo, why don't you let
the captain and me...
No!
This entire mission has been
one Federation blunder after another.
You will return my men,
or this alliance will end
with the destruction of your ship.
You're looking well,
Jean-Luc. Rested.
I won't let you move them, admiral.
I will take this
to the Federation Council.
I'm acting on orders
from the Federation Council.
How can there be an order
to abandon the Prime Directive?
The Prime Directive doesn't apply.
These people are not indigenous
to this planet.
They were never meant
to be immortal.
We'll simply be restoring them
to their natural evolution.
Who the hell are we to determine
the next course of evolution
for these people?
Jean-Luc, there are 600 people
down there.
We'll be able to use
the regenerative properties
of this radiation to help billions.
The Son'a have developed
a procedure to collect
the metaphasic particles
from the planet's rings.
A planet in Federation space.
That's right. We have the planet.
They have the technology.
A technology we can't duplicate.
You know what that makes us?
Partners.
Our partners are nothing more
than petty thugs.
On Earth, petroleum once turned
petty thugs into world leaders.
Warp drive transformed a bunch
of Romulan thugs into an empire.
We can handle the Son'a.
I'm not worried about that.
Someone probably said the same thing
about the Romulans a century ago.
With metaphasics,
life spans will be doubled.
An entire new medical science
will evolve.
I understand your chief engineer
has the use
of his eyes for the first time
in his life.
Would you take that away from him?
There are metaphasic particles
all over the Briar Patch.
Why does it have to be
this one planet?
It's the concentration in the rings
that makes the whole damn thing work.
Don't ask me to explain it.
I only know they inject something
into the rings that starts
a thermolytic reaction.
When it's over, the planet will be
uninhabitable for generations.
Admiral, delay the procedure.
Let my people look at the technology.
Our best scientific minds
already have.
We can't find any other way
to do this.
Then the Son'a can establish
a separate colony
on the planet until we do.
It would take ten years
of normal exposure
to begin to reverse their condition.
Some of them won't survive that long.
Besides, they don't want to live
in the middle of the Briar Patch.
Who would?
The Ba'ku.
We are betraying the principles upon
which the Federation was founded.
It's an attack upon its very soul.
And it will destroy the Ba'ku.
Just as cultures have been destroyed
in every other forced relocation
throughout history.
Jean-Luc, we're only moving
600 people.
How many people does it take,
admiral, before it becomes wrong?
A thousand?
Fifty thousand? A million?
How many people
does it take, admiral?
I'm ordering you
to the Goren system.
I'm also ordering the release
of the Son'a officers.
File whatever protests
you wish to, captain.
By the time you do,
this will all be done.
Gallatin.
So the righteous Starfleet captain
finally released you.
Yes.
Did you encounter any problems
on the surface?
No, sir.
But it wasn't easy being among them.
I'm sure.
Just don't forget what they did to us.
We'll have them rounded up
in a day or two.
We needn't bother with the
Federation's holoship anymore.
- Just get the holding cells ready.
- Yes, sir.
I'm going to miss these
little flesh-stretching sessions
of ours, my dear.
Rerouting the transport grid
to avoid detection was wise, sir.
However, the transporter
is rarely used after 0200 hours.
Taking the captain's yacht
out for a spin?
Seven metric tons
of ultritium explosives.
Eight tetryon pulse launchers
and ten isomagnetic disintegrators.
Looks like you're planning
on doing some hunting.
Return to your quarters.
That's an order.
No uniform, no orders.
Captain, how could I look
at another sunrise
knowing what my sight
cost these people?
I feel obliged to point out
that the environmental anomalies
may have stimulated certain rebellious
instincts common to youth,
which could affect
everyone's judgment.
Except mine, of course.
Okay, Data,
what do you think we should do?
Saddle up.
Lock and load.
They won't begin the procedure
while the planet is still inhabited.
So our job is to keep
the planet inhabited.
Will, Geordi, go back and put
a face on what's happening here.
Make the council see the Ba'ku.
It's too easy to turn a blind eye to the
suffering of a people you don't know.
I'll be back before you know it.
We'll hold out as long as we can.
The injector performs perfectly
in every simulation.
Sir, as the Enterprise left orbit,
one of their support craft
went down to the surface.
- What?
- It appeared to be the captain's yacht.
Five persons onboard.
We're not waiting until morning.
Take the shuttles and get everyone
off the surface tonight.
Gallatin.
If Picard or any
of his people interfere...
...eliminate them.
We're leaving the village.
Take only what you need.
Bring food.
We may not be back for days.
It is a transport inhibitor.
It will help prevent spaceships
from beaming anyone off the surface.
These veins of kelbonite
running through the hills
will interfere with their transporters.
And when the terrain forces us
away from the deposits,
then we'll use transport inhibitors
as a compensation.
The mountains have the heaviest
concentration of kelbonite.
Once there, it'll make transport
virtually impossible.
There are caves in those mountains.
Then we should be able to hold out
for a long time once we're there,
but they're not gonna make it
easy for us to get there.
Captain? We've activated the
transport inhibitors around the village.
Good.
Let's move these people out!
Transporters are not functioning.
They're blocking the beams
with some kind of inhibitors.
We'll have to locate
and destroy them.
No, no. Son, you're carrying too much.
We have a long climb ahead of us.
We've lost three transport inhibitors.
There's a gap in the field.
Artim.
Father!
They're following
the kelbonite deposits,
using the interference
to block our transporters.
- Recommendations?
- Take me down. Let me talk to Picard.
Talk?
We should send down an assault team
and take them by force.
That is not an acceptable option.
If people get hurt, all the support
we have in the Federation...
Federation support, Federation
procedures, Federation rules.
Look in the mirror, admiral.
The Federation is old.
In the past 24 months,
they've been challenged
by every major power
in the quadrant.
The Borg, the Cardassians,
the Dominion.
They all smell the scent of death
on the Federation.
That's why you've embraced
our offer.
Because it will give
your dear Federation new life.
Well, how badly
do you want it, admiral?
Because there are hard choices
to be made now.
If the Enterprise gets through
with news
about their brave captain's
valiant struggle
on behalf of the defenseless Ba'ku,
your Federation politicians will waver.
Your Federation opinion polls
will open up public debate.
Your Federation allies
will want their say. You...
Need I go on?
There's an alternative
to an all-out assault.
Isolinear tags would allow
our transporters to lock on to them.
We'd have to tag every one of them.
That would take time.
And we don't have it.
The Enterprise is only 19 hours
from communications range
with the Federation.
I'll order Riker to turn around.
Picard's first officer.
Do you really believe he'll listen?
My ships are capable
of intercepting the Enterprise
before it reaches the perimeter.
I could send them to...
To escort it back.
But Commander Riker
might not want to come.
Send your ships.
Do you like being a machine?
I aspire to be more than I am.
I know why.
So people like us won't be afraid
of you anymore.
Perhaps.
Don't you ever get tired?
My power cells continually
recharge themselves.
I can't imagine what it's like
to be a machine.
Perhaps it would
surprise you to know
that I have often tried to imagine
what it is like to be a child.
- Really?
- Really.
For one thing, your legs are shorter
than everyone else's.
But they are in a constant state
of growth.
- Do you find it difficult to adapt?
- Adapt?
A child's specifications are never
the same from one moment to the next.
It is a wonder you do not trip
over your own feet.
Sometimes I do.
My legs are exactly
87.2 centimeters in length.
They were 87.2 centimeters
the day I was created.
They will be 87.2 centimeters
the day I go off-line.
My operation depends on
specifications that do not change.
I will never know the experience
of growing up
or tripping over my own feet.
But you've never had adults
telling you what to do all the time
or bedtimes or having
to eat food you don't like.
I would gladly accept
the requirement of a bedtime
in exchange for knowing
what it is like to be a child.
Do machines ever play?
Yes, I play the violin.
And my chess routines
are quite advanced.
No, I mean, haven't
you ever just played?
For fun?
Androids do not have fun.
Look, if you wanna know what it's like
to be a child, you need to learn to play.
Captain.
Mr. Worf, you need a haircut.
Accelerated hair growth
is often experienced
by Klingons during Jak'tahla.
- Jak'tahla?
- Roughly translated, puberty.
Although for a Klingon,
that scarcely does it justice.
Any severe mood swings,
unusual aggressive tendencies,
you let me know at once.
Yes, sir.
The Ba'ku need some rest, sir.
According to the geo-scan,
this is the safest area
within the next few kilometers.
Very well, we'll take an hour.
- Have them break out some rations.
- Aye, sir.
Right beyond that ridge
is where the caves begin.
We can hide there for days.
By now the Son'a
will have scanned this area.
They'll know that as well as we do.
It's been 300 years
since I've seen a bald man.
How is it that you never married?
And don't tell me it's just because
you haven't got around to it yet.
What's the rush?
I should warn you, I've always
been attracted to older women.
How are you doing this?
No more questions.
Commander, I'm showing two Son'a
ships on an intercept course.
- How long till they reach us?
- Eighteen minutes.
We won't be able to get a transmission
out of here for another hour.
- They're hailing us.
- Tell them our transceiver assembly
is down, that we can send messages
but not receive them.
I don't think they believe us.
Why not?
Photon torpedo.
Isn't that the universal greeting
when communications are down?
I think it's the universal greeting
when you don't like someone.
Full impulse.
Manifolds can't handle full impulse
in the Patch, commander.
If we don't outrun them, the manifolds
will be the only thing left on this ship.
I'll be in Engineering.
Red alert! All hands! Battle stations.
And have you noticed how your boobs
have started to firm up?
Not that we care about such things
in this day and age.
Thank you, Data.
I have an odd craving for the blood
of a live Kolar beast.
This environment
must be affecting me again.
And have you noticed how
your boobs have started to firm up?
Not that we care about...
Take cover!
Isolinear tags.
The transporters can lock on to them.
We have to find shelter.
There's a cavern at the base
of the next hill.
This way.
Shields at 60 percent!
Engineering to bridge.
We're burning deuterium down here!
We're gonna blow ourselves up.
We won't need any help
from the Son'a.
What's inside that nebula cluster?
Cometary debris,
pockets of unstable metreon gas.
- We don't want to go in there, sir.
- Yes, we do.
I'll take it from here, ensign.
It's time to use the Briar Patch
the way Brer Rabbit did.
Inside the caves! Quickly!
Everyone! This way!
Inside.
Definitely feeling
aggressive tendencies, sir.
They've detonated an isolytic burst!
A subspace tear is forming!
On screen.
I thought subspace weapons were
banned by the Khitomer Accord.
Remind me to lodge a protest.
Our warp core is acting
like a magnet to the tear.
We're pulling it like a zipper
across space.
Options?
We could eject the core.
- Will that stop the tear?
- You got me, commander.
That's your expert opinion?
Detonating the warp core
might neutralize the cascade.
Then again, it might not.
Subspace weapons are unpredictable.
That's why they were banned.
Tear is closing on us.
Impact in 15 seconds.
- Eject the core.
- I just did.
Impact in ten seconds.
Detonate.
Get me a medic over here!
It worked, commander!
The tear has been sealed.
Yeah, but there's nothing to stop
them from doing it again.
And we're fresh out of warp cores.
We're still 36 minutes
from transmission range, sir.
We're through running
from these bastards.
Another 43 reported taken, sir.
Captain, they're trying to drive us out
so their drones can tag us.
With all the hydrothermal vents
in the substrata,
the structural integrity of this cavern
is not going to hold for long.
- Is there another way out of here?
- I don't know.
Captain, tracking the water's course
may reveal another exit.
Mr. Worf, come with us.
I am reading a nitrogen-oxygen flow
behind that calcite formation, captain.
Will this structure hold
if we were to blast through?
I believe it is safe, sir.
Fire.
Get everybody into those caves.
And set up force fields
once they're inside.
Aye, sir.
Geordi, are those pockets
of metreon gas?
Yes, commander. Highly volatile.
- I recommend we keep our distance.
- Negative.
I want to use the ramscoop
to collect as much of it as we can.
- The purpose being?
- The purpose being,
I intend to shove it
down the Son'as' throats.
Commander, if one of their weapons
hits that gas...
It's our only way out of here,
Mr. Daniels.
I wouldn't be surprised if history
remembers this as the Riker Maneuver.
If it works.
Computer, access
manual steering column.
Transfer helm controls to manual.
Bridge, storage cells
are at maximum capacity.
They're powering
their forward weapons array, sir.
Blow out the ramscoop.
Stand by. Full thrusters.
Ramscoop released.
Captain.
Data, Troi,
keep these people moving!
Bring them out!
I suspect it won't be long
before the drones get here.
Keep moving.
They found caves on higher ground.
We'll be safe there.
Captain, take a look
at this med-scan.
His DNA profile.
How can that be possible?
Maybe we should ask them.
Artim, what are you doing? Come.
- Is this the last group?
- Yes, sir.
Get them ready to move out.
- We need to hurry.
- Anij went to find Artim.
- Go with Tournel!
- No! I want to stay with you.
It is safer there, go!
- Worf to Picard.
- Two life signs.
One of them extremely faint.
There are almost 4 metric tons
of rock blocking our way.
No. That might cause
another cave-in.
Anij?
Worf to Picard.
Yes. Yes, I can hear you.
We are trying to get to you, sir.
Anij?
Help is on the way.
Worf, hurry.
Anij is hurt.
How bad is she, captain?
I'm losing her.
We're coming as fast as we can.
Anij...
...stay with me.
Help me find the power
to keep you in this moment.
Stay with me.
Don't let go of this moment.
She's stabilizing.
Is it safe to move her?
Safer than leaving her here.
And you thought it would take
centuries to learn.
Order them to surrender, and I promise
you won't be court-martialed.
If a court martial is the only way
to let the people of the Federation
know what is happening here,
I welcome it.
The Enterprise has destroyed
one of my ships!
The other is on fire,
requesting assistance.
The Enterprise
would only fire to defend itself.
Ru'afo must have ordered the attack.
I can't believe he would have given that
order without your consent, admiral.
I wonder which of us
will be facing that court martial.
There is nothing further
to be gained from this.
You're right.
This is going to end now.
The Ba'ku want to stay on the planet?
Let them.
- I'm going to launch the injector.
- You're not going to launch anything.
In six hours, every living thing
in this system will be dead or dying.
You would kill your own people,
Ru'afo?
Your own parents? Brothers, sisters?
Didn't you know, admiral,
the Son'a and the Ba'ku
are the same race.
Picard just told us.
Our DNA is identical.
Which one were you?
Gal'na? Ro'tin?
Those names, those children,
are gone forever.
What's he talking about?
A century ago,
a group of our young people
wanted to follow the ways
of the offlanders.
They tried to take over the colony,
and when they failed...
When we failed,
you exiled us to die slowly.
You're Ro'tin, aren't you?
There's something in the voice.
Would you be his friend Gal'na?
I helped your mother bathe you
when you were a child.
She still speaks of you.
You brought the Federation into
the middle of a blood feud, admiral.
The children have returned
to expel their elders,
just as they were once expelled.
Except that Ru'afo's need for revenge
has now escalated into parricide.
It was for the Federation.
It was all for the Federation.
We're taking this ship out of here.
This mission is over.
- It is not over.
- It is over!
I do not take orders from you.
If you launch the injector
while the planet's still populated,
- the Federation will pursue you until...
- The Federation...
...will never know
what happened here.
Admiral Dougherty
will not be joining us for dinner.
Deploy the collector.
Do you have a problem
with that order?
May I talk to you alone?
- Deploy the collector.
- Yes, sir.
Moving them is one thing.
Killing them all?
No one hated them
more than you, Gal'na.
We've come a long way together.
This is the moment we've planned
for so many years.
Separate the Starfleet personnel
and secure them in the aft cargo hold.
See that Picard joins them.
The shields in that section
won't protect them
against the thermolytic reaction.
Thank you for reminding me.
Jean-Luc.
Come with me.
It must have been strange for you
when you were a hostage.
Surrounded by all the friends and
family you knew all those years ago.
Each one looking exactly
as they did then.
Like looking through the eyes
of childhood again.
And here you are,
closing those eyes.
Trying not to see what bitterness
has done to the Son'a.
How it's turned Ru'afo
into a madman.
And you...
Turned you into a coward.
A man who denies
his own conscience.
Get in.
Coward without the moral courage
to prevent an atrocity.
You offend me.
Is this how a Federation officer
pleads for his life?
I'm not pleading for my life.
I'm pleading for yours.
You can still go home, Gal'na.
Computer, close turbolift doors.
What you're asking me to do
is impossible.
You know how to disable
the injector?
I would need to be on the bridge.
The crew is loyal to Ru'afo,
an assault would fail.
Perhaps we can lure him away.
It doesn't matter where he is.
As soon as he realizes
something's happening,
he'll override my commands
with one word to his com-link.
If he doesn't realize
something's happening...
Can you get me to a transmitter?
I need to speak with Data and Worf
down on the planet.
We'll need their help.
Deck 12.
Initiate separation protocols.
Activating injector assembly.
Separation in three minutes.
Small craft is coming up
from the surface.
It's powering up its weapons.
- On screen.
- One person aboard.
It's the android.
He's no threat.
- Data to Picard.
- Go ahead, Data.
Captain, they're ignoring my attack.
Keep firing tachyon bursts
into the shield grid.
- Is Worf in position?
- Yes, sir.
He is ready
for simultaneous transport.
We're approaching the bridge.
Picard out.
Separation in one minute.
Sir, the Federation ship is creating
a disruption in our shields.
If they go out of phase,
it will increase our exposure
to the thermolytic reaction.
Very well, destroy that ship.
Reset our shield harmonics.
Do not delay the countdown.
Data to Picard, they are rotating
their shield harmonics.
I am attempting to return
to the surface, sir.
The Federation ship
has been disabled.
Separation in 20 seconds.
- What is that?
- I don't know.
Systems don't seem affected.
Separation in ten seconds.
Five seconds.
Injector assembly has separated.
Exactly as the simulations predicted.
I'm not showing any change
in metaphasic flux levels.
Your scanners
must be malfunctioning.
All ship functions are off-line.
How can there be no ship functions
if the viewscreen is working?
Artificial gravity is stable.
Life support is...
A holodeck?
We were transported to the holoship
when we reset our shields.
Everything we saw was an illusion.
Ru'afo authorization Delta 2-1.
Override all interlink commands
to injector assembly one.
Unable to comply.
Injector assembly one
has been deactivated.
All injector subsystems aboard
the collector are confirmed off-line.
Decloak the holoship
and engage a tractor beam.
Aye, sir.
The crew knows
something's happened.
I've secured the bridge.
This ship is equipped
with 14 long-range transporters.
Are they all useless?
They must have been locked
and secured
after we were beamed here.
Isolate one and reroute
its command sequence
through the auxiliary processor.
Sir, there's nothing we can do.
They already have control of our ship.
I don't plan on going back
to our ship.
Mr. Worf, destroy that thing.
Aye, sir.
Weapon systems
have been taken off-line.
The crew is rerouting
bridge controls.
Captain, there's a problem
aboard the collector.
The launch sequence has resumed.
Collector's shields have been raised.
Someone's onboard.
It's Ru'afo.
Can you override
the launch sequence from here?
Not without his access codes.
Is there a self-destruct?
Yes, but without the codes,
it would have to be activated
at the upper control matrix
on the collector.
Mr. Worf, try and find some way
to beam through those shields.
You'd have to detonate it manually.
There'd only be a two-second delay.
We may be able to transport
between his shield generators
if we are within 100 meters.
Take us into position.
Remain at your post, commander.
I'll need you to beam me back.
We're approaching the collector.
One minute before separation,
you'll see the cryogenic tanks venting.
Weapons fire could ignite
the exhaust.
Separation in two minutes
and 15 seconds.
Intruder alert. Intruder alert.
Captain!
Worf?
I'm picking up Captain Picard's
bio-signature onboard the collector.
- Enterprise to Picard.
- Number One!
We're approaching your position.
Do you need assistance?
I may need a lift in a minute or so.
We're on our way.
Separation in one minute.
- Report.
- It's Ru'afo's ship.
On screen.
Sensors are reading
over 100 Ba'ku onboard.
And one Klingon.
Target their ventral engines
and life support.
Set a collision course.
Stop!
Ru'afo, we're getting too old for this.
After today, that won't be a problem.
For either of us.
Separation in 30 seconds.
You really going to risk
igniting the exhaust?
All right.
- I will!
- No!
Shields at 60 percent.
Hold your course.
- He wouldn't.
- Yes, he would.
Now!
Stand by, captain,
we're right around the corner.
Sorry...
...time's up.
What kept you, Number One?
The Federation Council has asked me
to inform you that the Ba'ku relocation
will be halted while they conduct
a top-level review.
Sir? Ru'afo's ship is hailing us.
- On screen.
Captain, the Son'a crew would like
to negotiate a cease-fire.
It may have something to do
with the fact
that we have three minutes
of air left.
We have plenty over here, Mr. Worf.
Prepare to beam aboard.
You think when we get away
from this metaphasic radiation,
it'll change the way we feel?
Your feelings about her
have not changed
since the day I met you, commander.
This place just let them out
for a little fresh air.
I wish there were a way
to bring them back home.
Ask them.
I'm afraid there's too much bitterness,
on both sides.
Mother and son.
You arranged this?
I thought it might begin
the healing process.
What am I going to do without you?
I wish I could stay.
But these are perilous times
for the Federation.
I can't abandon it to people
who would threaten everything
that I've spent a lifetime defending.
I have to go back,
if only to slow things down
at the Federation Council.
But I have 318 days
of shore leave coming...
...and I intend to use them.
Data?
It's time to go.
I have to go home now.
Bye.
Mr. Data, I hope we'll see you again.
Oh, Data.
Don't forget, you have
to have a little fun every day.
Good advice.
Picard to Enterprise,
seven to beam up.
Energize.