Don't grieve, Admiral.
It is logical.
The needs of the many outweigh...
The needs of the few.
Or the one.
And I have been,
and always shall be, your friend.
Live long and prosper.
We are assembled here today
to pay final respects
to our honoured dead.
This death takes place
in the shadow of new life,
the sunrise of a new world,
a world that our beloved comrade
gave his life to protect and nourish.
He did not feel this sacrifice
a vain or empty one.
Of my friend, I can only say this.
Of all the souls
I have encountered in my travels,
his was the most
human.
Honours.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the continuing voyages
ofthe Starship Enterprise.
Her ongoing mission,
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new Iife forms
and new civiIisations,
to boldly go
where no man has gone before.
U.S.S. Enterprise,
Captain's personal log.
With most of our battle damage
repaired, we're almost home,
yet I feel uneasy,
and I wonder why.
Perhaps it is the emptiness
of this vessel.
Most of our trainee crew
have been reassigned.
Lieutenant Saavik and my son David
are exploring the Genesis planet,
which he helped create,
and Enterprise feels like a house
with all the children gone.
No. More empty even than that.
The death of Spock
is like an open wound.
It seems that I have left
the noblest part of myself back there
on that newborn planet.
Status, Mr Sulu.
On course, Admiral.
Estimating spacedock in 2.1 hours.
Very well. Mr Chekov,
I'll need a pre-approach scan.
Take the science station, please.
-Yes, sir.
-Uhura.
Any response from Starfleet
on our Project Genesis inquiries?
No, sir. There is no response.
That's very odd.
Scotty, progress report.
It's almost done, sir.
You'll be fully automated
by the time we dock.
Your timing is excellent, Mr Scott.
You fixed the barn door
after the horse has come home.
How much refit time
till we can take her out again?
Eight weeks, sir,
but you don't have eight weeks,
so I'll do it for you in two.
Mr Scott, have you always
multiplied your repair estimates
by a factor of four?
Certainly, sir. How else can I keep
my reputation as a miracle-worker?
Your reputation is secure, Scotty.
Mr Sulu, take the conn.
I'll be in my quarters.
Aye, sir.
Sir?
I was wondering, are they planning
a ceremony when we get in?
I mean a reception?
A hero's welcome, son,
is that what you'd like?
Well, God knows there should be.
This time we've paid for the party
with our dearest blood.
Steady. Steady, boys.
Keep scanning.
I thought you people were reliable.
Where the hell is he?
He's been here for some time.
Put me on hailing frequency.
Commander Kruge, this is Valkris.
I have purchased the Genesis data.
Ready to transmit.
Well done, Valkris. Well done.
What the hell is...
Disengage cloaking device!
Transmit data.
Now!
Transmission completed.
You will find it useful.
Then you have seen it?
I have, my lord.
Unfortunate.
Understood.
Thrusters.
What the hell's going on?
When do I get paid off?
Soon, Captain. Quite soon.
Success my lord.
and my love.
You will be remembered with honour.
Fire!
New course, Federation neutral zone.
Feed him!
Yes, my lord.
Approach control, this is Enterprise.
Ready for docking manoeuvre.
Enterprise is cleared to dock.
Lock on.
Systems locked.
Spacedock, you have control.
Affirmative, Enterprise.
Enjoy the ride, and welcome home.
Enterprise confirms.
Moving in.
Acknowledged. Doors closing.
Would you look at that.
My friends, the great experiment,
the Excelsior,
ready for trial runs.
She's supposed to have
transwarp drive.
Aye, and if my grandmother had wheels,
she'd be a wagon.
Come, come, Mr Scott.
Young minds, fresh ideas. Be tolerant.
-Acknowledged. Doors are closing.
-Updating.
Stand by umbilical and gravitational
support systems.
Aye, sir. Moorings activated.
All systems standing by.
Admiral, this is not possible.
Mr Chekov?
An energy reading from C-deck,
from inside Mr Spock's quarters.
I ordered Spock's quarters sealed.
Yes, sir. I sealed the room myself.
Nevertheless, I am reading
a life form there.
This entire crew seems
on the edge of obsessive behaviour
concerning Mr Spock.
Sir, security reports the door
to Spock's quarters has been forced.
I'm on my way.
Mr Sulu, continue docking procedure.
Aye, sir.
Jim, help me.
You left me on Genesis.
Why did you do that?
Help me.
Bones.
What the hell are you doing?
Have you lost your mind?
Help me, Jim. Take me home.
Bones, we are. We are home.
Then perhaps it's not too late.
Climb the steps, Jim.
Climb the steps of Mount Seleya.
Mount Seleya?
Bones, Mount Seleya is on Vulcan.
We're home, on Earth.
Remember.
Admiral, docking is completed.
Starfleet Commander Morrow
is on his way for inspection.
Uhura, get the medics down here!
Get them now!
You've all done remarkable service
under the most difficult conditions.
You'll be receiving
Starfleet's highest commendation,
and more importantly,
extended shore leave.
That is, all but you, Mr Scott.
They need your wisdom
on the new Excelsior.
Report there tomorrow
as captain of engineering.
With all appreciation, sir,
I'd prefer to supervise
the refit of Enterprise.
I'm afraid that won't be necessary.
But, sir...
I'm sorry, Mr Scott,
but there will be no refit.
Admiral, I don't understand.
-The Enterprise is not...
-Jim, the Enterprise is 20 years old.
We feel her day is over.
But we had requested...
We'd hoped to take her back
to Genesis.
That is out of the question.
May I ask why?
ln your absence, Genesis has become
a galactic controversy.
Until the Federation Council
makes policy,
you are all under orders not to discuss
with anyone your knowledge of Genesis.
Consider it a quarantined planet
and a forbidden subject.
To fully understand
the events on which I report,
it is necessary to review
the theoretical data
on the Genesis device,
as developed
by Doctors Carol and David Marcus.
Genesis, simply put,
is life from lifelessness.
It was the intention to introduce
the Genesis device
into a preselected area
of a lifeless space body,
a moon or other dead form.
The device, when delivered,
would instantaneously cause
the Genesis effect.
Instead of a dead moon,
a living, breathing planet now exists,
capable of sustaining whatever
life forms we see fit to deposit on it.
So?
Speak.
Great power to control, dominate.
Impressive. They can make planets.
Oh, yes.
New cities, homes in the country,
your woman at your side,
children playing at your feet,
and overhead, fluttering in the breeze,
the flag of the Federation.
Charming.
Station.
Yes, my lord.
-Share this with no one.
-Understood, my lord.
We are going to this planet.
Even as our emissaries negotiate
for peace with the Federation,
we will act
for the preservation of our race.
We will seize the secret of this weapon,
the secret of ultimate power.
Success, my lord.
We have reached destination planet
at .035.
Very well, Lieutenant.
Helm, execute standard
orbital approach.
Standard orbit. Aye, sir.
Communications,
send a coded message
for Starfleet Commander, priority one.
Federation science vessel Grissom
arriving Genesis planet,
Mutara Sector to begin research.
J.T. Esteban, commanding.
Aye, sir. Coding now.
Dr Marcus, it's your planet.
Begin scanning, please.
This is where the fun begins, Saavik.
Just like your father, so human.
All units functional. Recorders are on.
Scanning Sector 1 .
Foliage in fully-developed
state of growth.
Temperature, 22.2 Celsius.
Sector 2 indicating desert terrain.
Minimal vegetation.
Temperature, 39.4.
Sector 3, subtropical vegetation.
Temperature decreasing rapidly.
It's snow.
Snow in the same sector. Fantastic.
Fascinating.
All the varieties of land and weather
known to Earth within a few hours' walk.
Metallic mass.
Close-range scan.
A photon tube.
Gravitational fields were in flux.
lt must have soft-landed.
ln code to Starfleet.
Captain Spock's tube located
on Genesis' surface.
Yes, sir. Coding your message.
I don't believe it.
What is it?
If equipment is functioning properly,
indications are an animal life form.
-You said there wouldn't be any.
-There shouldn't be any.
Cross-referenced and verified.
An unidentifiable life-form reading.
-Do you wish to advise Starfleet, sir?
-Wait a minute.
We don't know
what we're talking about here.
-Why don't we beam it up?
-Oh, no, you don't.
Regulations specifically state,
"Nothing shall be beamed aboard
"until danger of contamination
has been eliminated."
Captain, the logical alternative
is obvious.
Beaming down
to the surface is permitted.
lf the Captain decides
that the mission is vital
and reasonably free of danger.
Captain, please, we'll take the risk,
but we've got to find out what it is.
Or who.
Absent friends.
Admiral, what's gonna happen
to the Enterprise?
-She's to be decommissioned.
-Will we get another ship?
I can't get an answer.
Starfleet is up to its brass
in a galactic conference.
No one has time
for those who only stand and wait.
Sir, about Dr McCoy, how is he?
Well, that's the good news.
He's home, resting comfortably,
pumped full of tranquilisers.
They say it's exhaustion.
He promised me he'd stay put.
Well, we'll see.
Mr Scott.
Come.
Sarek!
Ambassador, I had no idea
you were here.
I believe you know my crew.
I will speak with you alone, Kirk.
Please excuse us.
Ambassador,
I would have come to Vulcan
to express my deepest sympathies...
Spare me your human platitudes, Kirk.
I have been to your government.
I have seen the Genesis information
and your own report.
Then you know how bravely
your son met his death.
Why did you leave him on Genesis?
Spock trusted you,
and you denied him his future.
-I saw no future.
-Only his body was in death, Kirk,
and you were the last one
to be with him.
Yes, I was.
And you must know that you should
have come with him to Vulcan.
-But why?
-Because he asked you to.
He entrusted you
with his very essence,
with everything that was not of the body.
He asked you to bring him to us
and to bring that which he gave you,
his katra, his living spirit.
Sir.
Your son meant more to me
than you can know.
I'd have given my life
if it would have saved his.
Believe me when I tell you,
he made no request of me.
He would not have spoken of it openly.
-Then how...
-Kirk, I must have your thoughts.
May I join your mind?
Certainly.
He spoke of your friendship.
Yes.
He asked you not to grieve.
The needs of the many
outweigh...
The needs of the few.
Or the one.
Spock.
I have been,
and always shall be,
your friend.
Live long and prosper.
No.
Forgive me.
lt is not here.
I had assumed
he mind-melded with you.
lt is the Vulcan way
when the body's end is near.
We were separate.
He couldn't touch me.
I see.
Then everything that he was,
everything he knew,
is lost.
Please wait.
He would have found a way.
lf there was that much at stake,
Spock would have found a way.
Yes. But how?
What if he joined with someone else?
Engine room, flight recorder visual.
Stardate 8128.78.
Go.
The ship.
Out of danger?
Yes.
Back .77.
Flight recorder visual 28.77.
Go.
No! You'll flood the whole compartment.
-He'll die.
-Kirk! He's dead already.
Back .76.
Flight recorder visual 28.76.
Go.
You're not going in there.
Perhaps you're right.
What is Mr Scott's condition?
Well, I don't think that he...
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I have no time to discuss this logically.
Freeze.
Repeat and augment.
Remember.
-McCoy!
-One alive, one not, yet both in pain.
What must I do?
You must bring them to Mount Seleya
on Vulcan.
Only there can both find peace.
What you ask is difficult.
You will find a way, Kirk.
lf you honour them both, you must.
I will.
I swear.
Transporter Room,
stand by to energise.
Aye, sir. Energising now.
Grissom to Saavik.
We're picking up radiation
from the life form.
Affirmative, Captain. Our readings
are well below danger level.
Very well. Exercise caution, Lieutenant.
This landing is Captain's discretion,
and I'm the one who's out on a limb.
I'll try to remember that, Captain.
There are your life forms.
These were microbes
on the tube's surface.
We shot them here from Enterprise.
They were fruitful and multiplied.
But how could they have
evolved so quickly?
Saavik.
What is it?
Spock's burial robe.
No. Absolutely not, Jim.
You're my best officer,
but I am Commander, Starfleet,
so I don't break rules.
Don't quote rules to me.
I'm talking about loyalty and sacrifice.
One man who's died for us,
another with deep emotional problems.
Now wait a minute.
This business about Spock and McCoy,
honestly, I never understood
Vulcan mysticism.
You don't have to believe.
I'm not even sure that I believe,
but if there's even a chance
that Spock has an eternal soul,
-then it's my responsibility.
-Yours?
As surely as if it were my very own.
Give me back the Enterprise.
With Scotty's help I could...
No, Jim. The Enterprise would never
stand the pounding, and you know it.
Then I'll find a ship. I'll hire a ship.
Out of the question, my friend.
The council has ordered that no one
but the science team goes to Genesis.
Jim, your life and your career
stand for rationality,
not for intellectual chaos.
Keep up this emotional behaviour
and you'll lose everything.
You'll destroy yourself.
Do you understand me, Jim?
I hear you.
-I had to try.
-Of course.
-Thanks for the drink.
-Anytime.
-The word, sir?
-The word is no.
I am therefore going anyway.
-You can count on our help, sir.
-Thank you, Mr Sulu. I'll need it.
Shall I alert Dr McCoy?
Please. He has a long journey
ahead of him.
Long time, Doc.
Yeah. Anybody been looking for me?
I have, but what's the use?
What'll it be?
Altair water.
That's not your usual poison.
To expect one to order poison in a bar
is not logical.
Got it.
To your planet, welcome.
I think that's my line, stranger.
Forgive. I here am new,
but you are known,
being McCoy from Enterprise.
-You have me at a disadvantage, sir.
-I name not important. You seek l.
Message received.
Available ship stands by.
-How much and how soon?
-How soon is now. How much is where.
Somewhere in the Mutara Sector.
Mutara restricted.
Take permits many. Money more.
There aren't going to be
any damn permits.
How can you get a permit
to do a damn illegal thing?
Look, price you name, money I got.
Place you name. Money I name.
Otherwise, bargain no.
All right, damn it. It's Genesis.
The name of the place we're going
is Genesis!
-Genesis?
-Yes, Genesis!
How can you be deaf
with ears like that?
Genesis allowed is not.
ls planet forbidden!
Look, my backwards friend,
Genesis may be planet forbidden,
but I'm damn well...
Sir, I'm sorry, but your voice is carrying.
I don't think you want to be discussing
this subject in public.
I'll discuss what I like,
and who in the hell are you?
Could I offer you a ride home,
Dr McCoy?
Where's the logic in offering me
a ride home, you idiot?
lf I wanted a ride home,
would I be trying
to charter a space flight?
-How in the hell do you know who I am?
-Federation security, sir.
You're gonna get a nice long rest,
Doctor.
Saavik to Grissom.
We are definitely reading
a second life form.
We concur.
Proceed with caution, Saavik.
What the hell is going on down there?
Make it quick, Admiral.
They're moving him
to the Federation funny farm.
Yes, poor friend.
I hear he's fruity as a nut cake.
Two minutes.
Jim.
-How many fingers do I have up?
-That's not very damn funny.
-Your sense of humour's returned.
-The hell it has. What's that?
-Lexorin.
-Lexorin? What for?
You're suffering from
a Vulcan mind-meld, Doctor.
That green-blooded son of a bitch.
It's his revenge
for all those arguments he lost.
Let me see your hand.
This will make you
well enough to travel.
Where's Admiral Kirk?
-He's with the prisoner.
-Get him quickly.
Commander, Starfleet wants him
right away.
Keeping you busy?
Don't get smart, Tiny.
-Admiral, Starfleet...
-This man's sick. Here, take a look.
Side elevator. Agents on their way up.
Don't call me Tiny.
Unit two, this is unit one.
The Kobayashi Maru has set sail
for the promised land.
-Acknowledge.
-Message acknowledged.
All units will be informed.
-You're taking me to the promised land?
-What are friends for?
-Mr Scott, calling it a night?
-Yes, sir.
Turning in myself.
Looking forward to breaking
some of the Enterprise's
speed records tomorrow.
Yes, sir. Good night.
-Level, please.
-Transporter Room.
-Thank you.
-Up your shaft.
Roger. Old City Station at 2200 hours.
All is well.
Understood. All stations clear.
-You amaze me, Commander.
-How is that?
A 20-year space veteran,
yet you choose
the worst duty station in town.
I mean, look at this place.
This is the hind end of space.
Peace and quiet
appeals to me, Lieutenant.
Yeah, well, maybe that's okay
for someone like you,
whose career is winding down,
but me, I need some challenge
in my life, some adventure,
maybe even just a surprise or two.
Well, you know what they say,
Lieutenant.
Be careful what you wish for.
You may get it.
Good evening, Commander.
ls everything ready?
Step into my parlour, gentlemen.
That's Admiral Kirk. My God!
Very good for you, Lieutenant.
But it's damn irregular.
No destination orders, no encoded lDs.
-All true.
-Well, what are we gonna do about it?
I'm not gonna do anything about it,
but you're gonna sit in the closet.
The closet? What, have you lost
all your sense of reality?
This isn't reality.
This is fantasy.
You wanted adventure, how's this?
The old adrenaline going? Good boy.
Now get in the closet.
Okay.
Go on. Go on.
I'll just get in the closet.
Okay!
-I'm glad you're on our side.
-Can you handle that?
I'll have "Mr. Adventure"
eating out of my hand, sir,
and I'll see all of you at the rendezvous.
And, Admiral,
all my hopes.
As promised, she's all yours, sir.
All systems automated and ready.
A chimpanzee and two trainees
could run her.
Thank you, Mr Scott,
I'll try not to take that personally.
My friends,
I can't ask you to go any further.
Dr McCoy and I have to do this.
The rest of you do not.
Admiral, we're losing precious time.
What course, please, Admiral?
Mr Scott?
I'd be grateful, Admiral,
if you'd give the word.
Gentlemen,
may the wind be at our backs.
Stations, please.
-Engage all the systems.
-Aye, engaged!
-Clear all moorings.
-Cleared, sir.
One-quarter impulse power.
One-quarter impulse.
Sir, Commander, Starfleet
on emergency channel.
He orders you to surrender this vessel.
-No reply, Chekov.
-Aye, sir.
Steady as she goes, Sulu.
Yellow alert. Captain to the Bridge.
Yellow alert.
Bridge, this is the Captain.
How can you have
a yellow alert in spacedock?
Sir, someone is stealing the Enterprise.
I'm on my way.
Alert. Yellow alert.
All stations, yellow alert.
One minute to spacedoors.
Are you just gonna walk through them?
Calm yourself, Doctor.
Sir, Excelsior powering up
with orders to pursue.
Yellow alert.
-Status?
-Yellow alert.
All automates ready and functioning.
Automatic moorings retracted.
All speeds available
through transwarp drive.
lncredible machine.
Helm.
One-quarter impulse power.
Thirty seconds to spacedoors.
Warning. Secure spacedoors.
-Warning. Secure spacedoors.
-And...
-Now, Mr Scott.
-Sir?
-The doors, Mr Scott.
-Aye, sir. I'm working on it.
Danger. Spacedoors are closed.
Danger.
We have cleared spacedoors.
-Full impulse power.
-Aye, sir.
Stand by tractor beam.
Tractor beam, aye.
lf he tries to get away with warp drive,
he's really in for a shock.
Excelsiorclosing to 4,000 metres, sir.
Scotty, we'll need everything you have.
Aye, sir. Warp drive standing by.
Kirk.
If you do this, you'll never sit
in the captain's chair again.
-Warp speed.
-Aye, sir.
Warp speed.
Prepare for warp speed.
Stand by transwarp drive.
Transwarp at your command, sir.
Full power available.
Execute.
Full power available...
Engine room reports
full power available.
Transwarp drive, maximum velocity
in five, four, three, two, one.
Scotty, as good as your word.
Aye, sir.
The more they overthink the plumbing,
the easier it is to stop up the drain.
Here, Doctor,
souvenirs from one surgeon to another.
I took them out
of her main transwarp computer drive.
Nice of you to tell me in advance.
That's what you get
for missing staff meetings, Doctor.
Gentlemen, your work today
has been outstanding.
I intend to recommend
you all for promotion
in whatever fleet we end up serving.
Best speed to Genesis.
I am Saavik... Can you speak?
The Genesis wave.
His cells could have been regenerated.
Captain, this is Saavik.
Come in, please.
Yes, Saavik. Go ahead.
We have found the life sign.
lt is a Vulcan child,
perhaps 8 to 1 0 Earth years of age.
A child? How did he get there?
lt is Dr Marcus' opinion that this is...
That the Genesis effect
has in some way regenerated
Captain Spock.
Saavik, that's extraordinary.
What would you like to do next?
Request permission
to beam aboard immediately.
Saavik, does Dr Marcus think
there could be any chance
of radioactive contamination?
-No.
-None that he can detect, sir.
All the same, I'm going to advise
Starfleet and get instructions.
I'm sure Starfleet would approve, sir.
Probably true,
but let's do it by the book.
Stand by on this channel. Go.
Starfleet Command,
this is U.S.S. Grissom
on subspace coded channel 98.8.
Come in, please.
Sir, something is jamming
our transmission, an energy surge.
Locate.
Surge from astern, Captain.
Oh, my God.
Gunner: target engine only.
Captain, what is happening?
We're under attack!
Stand by for evasive.
I wanted prisoners!
A lucky shot sir...
Animal!
Sir, may I suggest...
Say the wrong thing, Torg.
lf it's prisoners you want,
there are life signs on the planet.
Perhaps the very scientists you seek.
Saavik calling Grissom.
Come in, please.
Very good.
Grissom, this is Saavik
on emergency frequency.
Come in, please.
Saavik, what happened to them?
lt would seem that Grissom
was destroyed by an enemy attack.
We must go.
They will soon come after us.
Estimating Genesis 2.9 hours,
present speed.
-Can we hold speed, Scotty?
-Aye, she's got her second wind now.
Scan for vessels in pursuit.
Scanning.
lndications negative at this time.
Did I get it right?
Great, Bones. Just great.
It's time for total truth between us.
This planet is not what you intended
or hoped for, is it?
Not exactly.
Why?
I used protomatter
in the Genesis matrix.
Protomatter,
an unstable substance which every
ethical scientist in the galaxy
has denounced
as dangerously unpredictable.
But it was the only way
to solve certain problems.
So, like your father,
you changed the rules.
lf I hadn't,
it might have been years or never.
How many have paid the price
for your impatience?
How many have died?
How much damage have you done?
And what is yet to come?
Bridge, nothing happening here.
This planet's ageing in surges.
And Spock with it.
lt seems they're joined together.
They are.
-How long?
-Days,
maybe hours.
I'm sorry.
It will be hardest on Spock.
Soon he will feel the burning
of his Vulcan blood.
I don't understand.
Vulcan males must endure it
every seventh year of their adult life.
Whoever they are,
they're getting closer.
-I'll go.
-No.
I'll do it. Give me your phaser.
Sir, Starfleet calling U.S.S. Grissom.
A warning about us.
Response?
Nothing, as before.
What's the Grissom up to?
Will she join us or will she fire on us?
Chekov, break silence.
Send Captain Esteban my compliments.
Aye, sir.
How are we doing?
It's funny you should put it
quite that way, Jim.
We are doing fine,
but I'd feel safer
giving him one of my kidneys
than what's scrambled in my brain.
Admiral, there is no response
from Grissom on any channel.
Keep trying, Chekov,
at regular intervals.
So it has come.
lt is called Pon farr.
Will you trust me?
We are secured from warp speed.
Now entering Genesis Sector.
Proceed at impulse power.
-Vessel entering sector.
-Yes. Federation battle cruiser.
-Have they scanned us?
-Not yet.
Engage cloaking device.
I'd swear
there was something there, sir.
What did you see?
For an instant, a scout-class vessel.
Could be Grissom.
Patch in a hailing frequency.
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling.
Please come in.
Do you read?
Spock!
I've come a long way
for the power of Genesis
and what do I find?
A weakling human,
a Vulcan boy, and a woman.
My lord, we are survivors
of a doomed expedition.
This planet will destroy itself in hours.
The Genesis experiment is a failure.
A failure.
The most powerful,
destructive force ever created.
You will tell me the secret
of the Genesis torpedo.
I have no knowledge.
Then I hope
pain is something you enjoy.
I ordered no interruptions!
But, sir,
Federation starship approaching.
Bring me up.
Grissom,
this is Enterprise calling. Do you read?
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling.
Please come in.
Battle Alert!
Grissom. This is Enterprise.
Admiral Kirk calling Captain Esteban
or Lieutenant Saavik. Please come in.
-Report status.
-We are cloaked.
Enemy closing on impulse power.
Range, 5,000 kellicams.
Good.
This is just the turn of luck
I have been waiting for.
Nothing on my scanner, sir.
Short-range scan, Mr Chekov.
Put it on visual, Mr Sulu.
Range, 3,000 kellicams.
Steady.
Continue on impulse power.
Range, 2,000 kellicams.
Stand by to transfer energy to weapons.
At my command.
There.
That distortion. See it?
Yes, sir.
It's getting larger as we close in.
Firing range, sir.
Gunner:
Target engine only - Understood?
Understood clearly, sir.
-Opinion, Mr Sulu.
-I think it's an energy surge.
Enough energy to hide a ship,
would you say?
A cloaking device.
-Red alert, Mr Scott.
-Aye, sir.
1,000 kellicams, closing.
-All power to the weapons systems.
-Aye, sir.
No shields?
If my guess is right, they'll have to
decloak before they can fire.
May all your guesses be right.
Klingon bird-of-prey, sir.
-She's arming torpedoes.
-Fire, Mr Scott.
Good shooting, Mr Scott.
-Precautionary, Mr Chekov. Shields up.
-Aye, sir.
Emergency power
to the thrusters!
Sir, the shield's nonresponsive.
-Scotty?
-The automation system's overloaded.
I didn't expect to take us into combat,
you know.
Emergency power.
Prepare to return fire.
Mr Scott, can you transfer power
to the phaser banks?
-I don't think so, sir.
-What happened?
Well, they've knocked out
the automation centre,
and I've got no control over anything.
Mr Sulu?
Nothing, sir.
So, we're a sitting duck.
Ready to fire emergency tube.
Why haven't they finished us?
-They outgun me 1 0 to one.
-My lord.
The enemy commander
wishes a truce to confer.
Put him onscreen.
This is Admiral James T. Kirk
ofFederation Starship Enterprise.
So, the Genesis commander himself.
A violation of treaty between
the Federation and the Klingon Empire.
Your presence here is an act of war.
You have two minutes to surrender
your crew and your vessel,
or we will destroy you.
He's hiding something.
We may have dealt him
a more serious blow than I thought.
-How can you tell that?
-I trust my instincts.
Admiral Kirk,
this is your opponent speaking.
Do not lecture me
about treaty violations.
The Federation,
in creating an ultimate weapon,
has become a gang
of intergalactic criminals.
It is not I who will surrender.
It is you!
On the planet below,
I have three prisoners
from the team who developed
your doomsday weapon.
If you do not surrender immediately,
I will execute them one at a time
as enemies of galactic peace!
Who is this?
How dare you take prisoners.
Who I am is not important.
That I have them is.
I will allow you to speak to them.
-Admiral, this is Lieutenant Saavik.
-Saavik.
Is David with you?
Yes, he is, and someone else,
a Vulcan scientist of your acquaintance.
This
Vulcan,
is he alive?
He is not himself, but he lives.
He is subject to rapid ageing,
like this unstable planet.
Hello, sir. It's David.
I'm sorry I'm late.
It's okay. I should've known you'd come.
Saavik's right. This planet is unstable.
It's gonna destroy itself
in a matter of hours.
David, what went wrong?
I went wrong.
I don't understand.
I'm sorry, sir. Just don't surrender.
Genesis doesn't work.
I can't believe they'd kill us for it.
Admiral, your young friend is mistaken.
I meant what I said.
And now to show
that my intentions are sincere,
I shall kill one of the prisoners.
Wait a minute!
Give me a chance to talk...
Kill one of them.
I don't care which.
Saavik?
David?
Admiral, David is dead.
You Klingon bastard,
you've killed my son.
you've killed my son!
You Klingon bastard.
There are two more prisoners, Admiral.
Do you want them killed, too?
Surrender your vessel.
All right. All right, damn you.
All right.
Give me a minute to inform my crew.
I give two minutes
for you and your gallant crew.
Take every last man.
Form a boarding party, armed heavily.
-They outnumber us, my lord.
-We are Klingons!
Once you control the ship,
we will transfer our flag there
and take Genesis from their
own memory banks.
Mr Sulu, what is the crew complement
of a bird-of-prey?
About a dozen officers and men.
With some of them on the planet.
I swear to you, we're not finished yet.
Bones, you and Sulu
to the Transporter Room.
The rest of you with me.
We have a job to do.
Commander, Klingon vessel.
Prepare to board this ship
on my next signal.
No tricks, Kirk.
You have one minute.
No tricks.
I'm looking forward to meeting you.
To the transport room.
Success!
Computer,
this is Admiral James T. Kirk.
Request security access.
Computer, destruct sequence one,
code one, one, A.
Computer,
Commander Montgomery Scott,
chief engineering officer.
Destruct sequence two,
code one, one, A, two, B.
Computer,
this is Commander Pavel Chekov,
acting science officer.
Destruct sequence three,
code one, B, two, B, three.
Destruct sequence
completed and engaged.
Awaiting final code
for one-minute countdown.
Code zero, zero, zero,
destruct,
zero.
Destruct sequence is activated.
Kirk, your time runs out.
-All set?
-Aye, sir.
Commander, Klingon vessel.
We are energising
transporter beam now.
Transporter, stand by.
My lord,
the ship appears to be deserted.
How can that be? They're hiding.
Yes, sir, but the Bridge
seems to be run by computer.
lt is the only thing speaking.
Speaking? Let me hear.
Nine, eight, seven, six,
five...
-Get out! Get out of there!
-...three, two...
-Get out!
-...one.
My God, Bones, what have I done?
What you had to do.
What you always do.
Turn death into a fighting chance to live.
Planet core readings.
Unstable, changing rapidly.
What about surface life signs?
There.
No, don't touch him.
Bones.
-What happened?
-He gave his life to save us.
Rapid ageing.
All genetic functions highly accelerated.
-What about his mind?
-His mind's a void.
It seems, Admiral,
that I've got all his marbles.
ls there anything we can do?
Only one thing, sir.
Get him off this planet.
His ageing is part
of what's going on around us.
Klingon Commander,
this is Admiral James T. Kirk.
I'm alive and well on the planet surface.
I know this will come
as a pleasant surprise to you,
but our ship was a victim
of an unfortunate accident.
Sorry about your crew,
but as we say on Earth, c'est la vie.
I have what you want.
I have the secret of Genesis.
You're gonna have to bring
us up there to get it.
You hear me?
I'm waiting for you.
What is your answer?
Drop all weapons!
Over there. All but Kirk.
Maltz,
prisoners are at beam coordinates.
-You should take the Vulcan, too.
-No!
-But why?
-Because you wish it.
Maltz - activate beam!
Genesis. I want it!
Beam the Vulcan up and we'll talk.
Give me what I want and I'll consider it.
You fool, look around you!
The planet's destroying itself!
Yes, exhilarating, isn't it?
If we don't help each other,
we'll die here.
Perfect. Then that's the way it shall be.
Give me Genesis.
Give me your hand.
I have had enough of you!
Maltz!
Don't. How many more?
Just him, sir.
Bones, help Spock.
We've got to break out of orbit.
-You, help us or die.
-I do not deserve to live.
Fine. I'll kill you later.
Let's get out of here.
Where's the damn antimatter inducer?
This? No, this.
That or nothing.
If I read this right, sir,
we have full power.
Go, Sulu.
Goodbye, David.
We are clear and free to navigate.
Best speed to Vulcan.
Mr Chekov, take the prisoner below.
-Aye, sir.
-Wait. You said you would kill me.
I lied.
Spock,
for God sakes, talk to me.
You stuck this damn thing
in my head, remember?
Remember?
Now tell me what to do with it.
Help me.
I'm gonna tell you something that I
never thought I'd ever hear myself say.
But it seems I've missed you,
and I don't know if I could stand
to lose you again.
Ambassador, they are on approach.
They're requesting permission to land.
Permission granted. Tell them...
Tell Kirk we'll be ready.
Mr Sulu, you're on manual.
It's been a while, sir. Here we go.
Retrothrusters.
Sarek is waiting above, sir.
Sarek,
child of Skon,
child of Solkar,
the body of your son breathes still.
What is your wish?
I ask for fal-tor-pan,
the refusion.
What you seek has not
been done since ages past,
and then, only in legend.
-Your request is not logical.
-Forgive me, T'Lar.
My logic is uncertain
where my son is concerned.
Who is the keeper of the katra?
I am.
McCoy, Leonard H., son of David.
McCoy, son of David,
since thou art human,
we cannot expect thee to understand
fully what Sarek has requested.
Spock's body lives.
With your approval,
we shall use all our powers
to return to his body
that which you possess.
But, McCoy, you must now be warned.
The danger to thyself is as grave
as the danger to Spock.
You must make the choice.
I choose the danger.
Hell of a time to ask.
I'm all right, Jim.
What about Spock?
Only time will answer.
Kirk,
I thank you.
-What you have done is...
-What I have done,
I had to do.
But at what cost? Your ship, your son.
lf I hadn't tried,
the cost would've been my soul.
My father says
that you have been my friend.
You came back for me.
You would have done the same for me.
Why would you do this?
Because the needs of the one
outweigh the needs of the many.
I have been,
and ever shall be,
your friend.
Yes.
Yes, Spock.
The ship.
-Out of danger?
-You saved the ship.
You saved us all. Don't you remember?
Jim.
Your name is Jim.