He looks so sad.
Rico!
I want that tree up to muster.
Check!
Kowalski!
What's the status on the approved
musical selection?
It's scheduled to begin...
...now.
Excelente!
Right on track.
Skipper!
Veggie pudding at 1900 hours.
ULOG to commence on my mark.
Engage!
ULOG engaged.
- Checkamundo!
- Skipper!
Eggnog at 2100 hours.
Writing our names in the snow at 21:05.
- Skipper!
- What is it, Private?
Ted, the polar bear, is all alone
this holiday, and he seems so sad!
Could we bring him a present
to cheer him up?
Kowalski!
Negative, Skipper.
We have four presents,
and there are four of us.
We can go and get him something.
Sorry, Private, no can do.
But no one should be sad
and alone in Christmas.
Exactly.
So, throw those troubles away
and be merry.
- Pronto!
- But, Skipper...
That's an order, mister.
All right, boys,
stand by for eggnog.
Aye, aye, Skipper.
- Eggnog!
- Private?
- I'll pass, thank you.
- Eggnog, eggnog, eggnog...
Go, go, go..!
Chug, chug, chug..!
Well done, Rico!
This guy can really hold his nog.
2110 hours, boys.
Engage cranberries.
Rico!
Not at the table.
Hold on a second.
Something's missing...
Cranberries, check.
Eggnog, check.
Give me a head count.
We have three heads, sir.
Where's the Private?
I don't know,
it would appear that he's... missing.
Missing?
Hoover Damn!
Wait.
There he is!
He just went to bed.
What the..?
What have you done with Private?
Talk, mister!
Skipper!
Over here.
I'll deal with you later.
Oh, no! He must be out there
all by himself.
He's one of us, men,
you all know the penguin credo.
"Never bathe in hot oil and Bisquick"?
No!
No! That's the walrus credo!
"Never swim alone. "
Private's out there all by himself...
...and we never leave one of our own.
Oh... yeah.
Now, let's go!
Oh! That's perfect!
Just the thing for a sad polar bear.
Kowalski?
Analysis.
Adrenalin sweating sardines.
These tracks are fresh.
He's close, I can feel it.
What kind of cut-rate junk is this?
It's lousy workmanship,
that's what it is.
We may have a problem.
Look at all this junk,
these are no good at all! Junk!
We need to get closer.
10 o'clock, men.
Plan, plan, plan!
So this is where you're hiding
all the good stuff!
He's in trouble!
- Kaboom.
- Lay down, soldier!
We're in observation mode.
Now, this is workmanship.
So, where's the goshdang squeaker
on this thing?
It's gotta have a squeaker...
Now, that's more like it.
Hey, stupid! I want this one.
- Grand Coulee Dam!
- Where's my change?!
Private's been captured!
Taxi!
Not on my watch, blue hair.
Kowalski!
Hey, I'm walking here!
Do I got a tip for you?
Drop dead!
Good evening, m'am,
Merry Christmas to you.
Buzz off!
Skipper...
How are we gonna get inside?
Kaboom, kaboom.
I have a better idea.
Oh, boy, that's gonna hurt!
Very generous, sir.
You have a Merry Christmas.
Hold that elevator!
- Skipper!
- Private!
Step on it, Kowalski.
What comes down, must go up.
Skipper.
All right, men.
Commence operation:
"Special Delivery"
'Tacky mushrooms!
- No more Mr. Cute and cuddly.
- Kaboom, kaboom, kaboom!
Rico! Enough with the dynamite already.
Why does Christmas
have to be every year?
What a pain in the..!
The taping... it's so sticky!
There we go!
Oh, you'll make such a nice
Christmas present...
...for my Mr. Chew.
Oh, no Mr. Chew,
you'll have to wait until morning
to open your present.
Yes you do.
Who is mommy's big boy?
Who is he?
Nice doggie!
Good doggie!
Good boy, down, down,
don't eat me...
...no, no, good boy,
leave me alone, don't eat me!
Santa Claus has come to town.
Skipper!
Help me, guys!
- Kowalski, secure the Private.
- I'm on it.
Watch your back.
Canine, two o'clock.
- I'm gonna need some cover fire.
- Rico!
- Kowalski! Status?
- Almost there, Skipper.
Let him have it, Rico.
Holy butterball!
No, no, don't eat me!
Kowalski!
Give me options.
Skipper.
Excelente!
Engage operation:
"Stocking Stuffer"
High five...
...low five...
...down low...
...too slow.
I think our work here is done.
Rico!
She didn't see anything.
Let's blow this popsicle stand, boys.
Kaboom?
Yes, Rico. Kaboom.
Come on, boys.
What is all this?
Mr. Chew, this is all your fault!
Bad dog!
You are on a big time out!
Thanks for rescuing me, Skipper.
Thank nothing of it, young Private.
It's the least we could do.
You remember the penguin credo?
What does deep frying in Bisquick
have to do with any of this?
Not that one! The other one!
"Never swim alone"!
Alone!
On Christmas! Don't you get it?
Come on, people, do I have
to explain this to everybody?
Poor Ted, he's all alone on Christmas,
with no one to swim with.
It's not too late,
young Private.
I've got a new plan to fit him in.
Guys..!
Seriously, this is the best Christmas
I've ever had.
Well, there it is then,
Merry Christmas for everyone.
What the..?
Who could that be?
Oh, I hope you don't mind.
I invited a few friends over.
What?!
# Jingle bells, Monkey smells...
#... Melman laid an egg...
#... Marty thinks that Alex stinks...
#... and the camel says: Oy Vey!