Hello, Wendy !
- Hello, Charlie ?
Are you working with scenographic team?
Not this year . She's too busy
I am . - Shame .
've Created Best Art Direction by
I have seen since I work here all these years .
Thank you , Charlie , it's really nice
from you , but I'm too busy .
I got the job !
- Congratulations !
I'll be the queen of makeup and costumes .
- I'll send a message Caroline .
I'm glad that at least one of
You order at the show this year .
Wendy says he 's too busy .
What if Shakespeare told
no time to write " Hamlet " ?
Come on ! Before I promaknuæem .
- From crazy addicted to control .
Most talented , the most successful designer
interior , with the best connections in Boston .
Addicted kontoroli !
- Congratulations , Tressa . - Thank you !
And to you, too . Take a look. missing
you be part of this? - Sure , but ...
Do not worry about me ,
let's talk a little bit about you .
Caroline wants to go out to celebrate .
- Good . Let me Skočko .
You know you do not like it .
- So what ?
I do not have time for that . - Stop it !
You need to relax a bit .
Allow me to transform .
Not Plešuæu snowflakes ?
- No Flakes .
I've been thinking about
Šeæernoj Villa . - Can .
It looks cool !
- Let me see .
You turned me into Lady Gaga .
- I struènjakinja .
I look radioactive. - It is
called " tinsel for otkaèiti be ."
You have the right to otkaèiti tonight .
Tressa , this is supposed
be your night. - Stop it !
What's with the old , spontaneous Wendy ?
Anyway is not fun anymore.
Not like this .
- Come on, Wen , relax !
That's it. You'll guise ,
and use it to
show a little spontaneity .
Okay, I will.
- Thank you .
Tonight could be the magic night.
Ladies , it's time for a martini .
Do not you dare
let us know! - I have .
You do not have to, it's Saturday evening parties , you do not !
Yes , Miss Hall ? ... Yes .
I'll take care of it.
Sure . Okay , bye .
Her flight is delayed . I'll just drop in
her apartment and turn on the heat and light .
Is this normal ?
I swear that woman that devises ,
it enjoys harassing you.
I'm so sorry . I have to . I'll catch up with you.
Hold it ! Before you go ,
I'll finish your masterpiece .
Thank you .
You've got half an hour .
- Close your eyes .
Hello? Wendy Walton .
Yes , nature ! It will be my
satisfaction edit your villa .
I will strike . Snow Princess .
- Šeæerna Villa .
Šeæerna Villa . Right.
Take part in ballet ?
- Not really .
Then , on this occasion ?
- Just go out with the girls.
This does not look good .
And I'm just looking.
Hold on !
You will not believe what happened !
- Rosy cheeks are you .
All shining , and it's not the glitter .
I was with a handsome guy in
an elevator that suddenly has started to fall .
I thought we die .
And then he kissed me .
Oh no ! - You bet !
And I retorted
kiss . - You did not!
It was a kiss
which I was to remember and when I
old , forgetful and in diapers .
And that spark . Spark is .
I've never experienced arcing .
I hope you've learned about him
name and took the phone number .
I did not . - What?
Are you kidding me ? - I do not .
There was some kind of a Christmas choir
and it was crazy , I had to run away ,
But you know what? She obeyed
You and I relaxed . I. ..
The feeling is wonderful.
- Who is this guy ?
It does not matter , because if we are destined
be together , I'll find it .
Or would he find me .
Hello , ladies . - Hi !
Who am I kidding ? I will not
see him again , right?
Will . I'm sure of it .
And if you can not see it , it's nice to see
back to the old Becky . - That's right.
Thank you , girls . - A night
has just begun ... - It's true .
In that name !
Hello?
Yes , Miss Hall ?
All right. Clearly , right there.
We do not have much time .
- How was the trip ?
Concentrate on
what with pressing . - What is it?
I have a very important lunch with Adam .
Your boyfriend who constantly travels
in the city ? - Yes , for the holidays .
I intend to take advantage of
how we zaruèili .
I 'll tell you what I do ? - Emily has free
day and I want it exchanged .
Did not Emily maid ?
My employee ,
just like you .
Do this until noon .
Be sure to purchase champagne .
Exclusively "Home Perignot " .
I will not accept any substitutes .
What is it on you ?
Tinsel . Tressa me
Last night's edited for release .
What if you recognized
one of my friends ?
Neither myself , I could not identify .
- Get rid of them . I do not want them around the apartment .
I'm going to relax at the spa in the " Ritz Carlton " .
Came the end of spontaneity .
Hi !
The task was performed .
Bravo ! - Thank you .
All right. Go before
Adam arrives. You look terrible .
"Home Perignot " ... nice .
Have fun !
Hi ! - Hello!
How did you know ...
- I'm Adam .
Dear , you're early !
I could not wait to see you .
Honey , meet my
Fantastic assistants Wendy .
I'm glad .
- Wendy just leaving .
I was glad .
- Thank you very much .
Do not fall .
They're beautiful ! answer
will satin sheets .
Shall we check ? - Do not ...
Before I officially greet .
What is it?
Nothing .
Probably tired from the trip .
- How could it not be. months
change cities
must be exhausting .
That's it.
I'm glad I
house. And for the holidays .
I hope you find the time and
energy planning for the future .
Actually , I have a suggestion .
I agree .
Do not dock until
I hear what you seek .
Whatever you ask of me ,
the answer will be "yes."
I ask you to tell me ukrasiš
house for the Christmas party.
The foundation of my family 's patron
Ballet " The Nutcracker " at the City Theatre ,
and I want to organize
admission for patrons .
Amazingly !
It will be a pleasure to decorate your house .
Thank you .
What purpose this hanged man? - Wendy
revealed who the guy in the elevator .
Would not that be good ?
- Would that not accidentally boy Miss . Hall .
Come on ! - And what's worse ...
I do not even recognize . Not even close .
Honestly , you were incognito . - Are
you sure he did not recognize .
Maybe, but since he is sleeping with your
boss did not want to reveal it in front of her .
You should tell him that it was you .
If you feel
spark , and he certainly is .
What am I supposed to say ?
" Hey , Adam , do not you recognize me ,
But you kissed me in the elevator .
And yes , I work for your
's future wife .
How dare you not recognize me ?
You may have škljokice , but
I am. You're supposed to see that. "
He is male . They insight
things . They should all draw .
No. I will concentrate more on the job and
forget the spark , and kiss him .
Good luck to you !
- Anyway, the constant traveling .
Probably more I will not even see it .
I would tell him . not
You can ignore the spark .
I bet he's the right one .
This is not a film
scenario , but my life .
No! The spark is officially off .
- Liar. - Why ?
Poor . - Shut up !
It's good to be home.
- Nice to have you here .
So many events that
we must not miss .
I was hoping for a little break .
Enjoyment of the home and the Boston Christmas.
We enjoy veèerajuæi with Dustellom
nazoènošæu and opening a new gallery .
Do not miss any of Victoria
's birthday party . Please!
Already months only
travel and hang out .
So , can we please focus is
my charity party? Please!
We can not !
These events are important for our careers .
Do you remember that trip
in Saint Barthelemy ?
We missed the Gala dinner , to
walking the beach and watched the sunset ?
I remember .
I ruined Manolo Blahnik shoes .
It is all proportion taken remember ?
- No, but you are so long absent,
that no one remembers that we are a couple .
A èudesan couple and we would
pity that we are not admiring public .
Good . We will go on ... and fun .
I was hoping for good
old of Christmas this year .
We'll have blinding Christmas.
I'm sure of it .
Yes , Miss Hall ! - Come on !
Yes , of course . 'll Be right there . Good .
Immediately Treis ? At 19:00, on Sundays ?
Why can not it wait until tomorrow ?
Do you think we are going ?
I'm sorry , but I must .
See you later.
In the afternoon, I received an offer from Adam .
- Congratulations , it's an important day .
Do not double the offer. Not yet .
He asked me to decorate his
house for the Christmas party.
Let's go there in the morning , at the crack of dawn .
Buy basket pastries and coffee .
Writes , Wendy !
Adam drinks coffee with cream ,
and for me already know .
Why do I do with it ?
For him decorate
house for the Christmas party.
And as with other clients ?
Should not they be paid to ?
Several of possible
new customers ...
Adam's party is a priority .
Others will have to wait .
We can not ignore all the others.
- This is an event in Boston.
Attend all her most important
theater patrons .
Really ? Why ?
Because of Adam's family is the foundation ,
covering theater and Artistic
projects in the country and around the world ,
because of this and so much travel .
The reception will be held in honor
premiere of the ballet " The Nutcracker " .
Read it sometimes newspapers .
Still do not understand why you need
me ? We have so many other things to do .
What's the problem ?
If you can not do with my future
his wife , and I easily replaced.
No, no problem .
Get to work !
Hello!
Wendy , do you?
- I am .
Good evening , Mr. Hughes .
Call me Adam .
You go from Priscilla ? - Yes .
I hear that you govern the house for
the premiere of " The Nutcracker " . - That's right.
I suppose , and you ? - Exactly.
My roommate is vizažistkinja
in " The Nutcracker " . - Is it ?
My roots are in the theater .
And my whole life revolves around it .
Unfortunately , we are replicas
related only to finance .
I worked for Art Direction
" Midsummer night " in Berkshire .
I love this piece . - " How mortals
can not be stupid ! " - That's right.
Merry Christmas !
Thank you .
I'm going to ... - I this way.
Then ... " The pain of parting
iMade sweet power ... "
" You spoke like forever ," good night ! " ... "
Well you know Shakespeare.
Why did you leave the theater ?
I do not know . Due to the pressures of real life .
Because opportunities to start a lucrative business .
Therefore, doing the
Priscilla . - Actually , yes.
A wise choice .
- I suppose it is.
Good night , Wendy .
- Good night , Adam.
I do not know will I be able to . work
in his house , and he constantly seeing plenty .
And that , knowing the kiss ,
While he has no idea about it .
That would be torture .
For me it's fate .
Merged you spell romance and Christmas.
It is not fate , but a golden opportunity ,
you've waited rintajuæi for this woman.
You have an opportunity
familiar and closer to
cream of Boston theater world .
The right of the nail ! - I know .
This could be my
amazing opportunity .
I think it's fate .
How do you see it ?
You had another
amorous encounter in the elevator .
I can not think of it .
Neither him . buy
I put the gift basket,
and in good spirits and determined to
try to extract the best out of this .
Just keep in mind destiny .
If you are still not able to remember ,
just give him the " Nutcracker " .
Excellent ! I'll put him
it in the gift basket.
Good morning , Wendy !
- Good morning , Adam !
Priscilla has not yet arrived .
Go ahead , Come .
Your home is incredible .
- Thank you .
This is for you . Pastries and coffee with
cream , to me and said Miss Hall .
Thank you very much .
Here , Come .
Nice touch . - Thank you .
I thought you would be able to appeal .
My roommate is working on " The Nutcracker " .
So , you mentioned
we do . Here , in Boston .
Delicious . Where did you get it?
All this from " Beantown Roasters "
where my other works
roommate Caroline , actress .
Can I ? - Here you go .
You have complete Shakespeare
collection . - I have .
And all been read with love .
Is this what you think it is?
" A Christmas song ," first edition .
Oh my goodness !
She was the first show that
I looked on Broadway .
My dad took me when I
was in the second grade of high school.
She gave me her grandmother .
The most precious is what I got.
She is beautiful . - Thank you .
Hi ! - Priscilla !
I apologize .
Hi , honey .
Hi ! - Good morning , Miss Hall .
Thank you for the basket.
- You're welcome .
Do you have any ideas and
desires related to regulation ?
I do not get that idea , but
You know what I mean Christmas. - I know .
I have not been home for
Christmas already for several years .
I want something memorable .
- And spectacular.
With you, it's guaranteed .
I just want to restore the magic of Christmas
in this house . - Be sure of that .
Wendy , this capture
ground and take action .
A detailed list of furniture and
ons . You know the drill . - I know .
Darling, shall we try biscuits ?
In addition to theater patrons ,
should invite more
several notables at the party.
Keep in mind that the theater
most important patrons .
Sure , but Christmas is ...
And as you said ,
This is our chance to take advantage of
first joint Christmas in Boston .
Wendy , would you join us ?
- Thanks, but I'm not finished yet .
It is not yet finished ! - Honey , it will be enough
time for taking photos and measurements .
Here , Wendy , I insist .
Croissant ?
Thank you .
I continue .
So ...
Do you know that there are first
release " a Christmas song ?"
Of course I do .
We could use
as inspiring for the draft .
It's a terrible idea .
First of all , " a Christmas story "
is totally overrated .
It is a slag .
But Mr. Hughes is tied to the book.
It is not sentimental reception ,
but should impress Adam's room.
The only thing that 's important to me . And him .
But if you expect it to be the celebration
engagement , it should be mushy .
Absolutely not! Neither Adam nor I have
time for sensitivity, .
Retrieve my good ice sculptures
and a pair of artificial trees božiænih .
Make sure that everything is
completely white.
I have not apologized
how do you know Adam ?
On dobrotovornoj party in Berkshire .
I've set this meeting ,
through joint friends .
You mean you're all
planned in advance ?
It is a bit ...
The calculated ?
Of course it was The calculated .
I knew who he was and that he is free .
And tell us the modes of
life completely coincide .
Do you like it anyway?
Of course I love him .
He's handsome , charming ,
smart , he saw the world .
It is a rich and respected , both look good,
We are ambitious , we want the same things ,
here we are in the same circle of people .
Indeed respond to each other .
The perfect couple . - Yes.
The perfect couple .
I have no doubt that this will also receive
be a celebration of my engagement .
Followed by a spectacular
Plans for the wedding .
With your help , of course .
Mr. Hughes ?
Glad to see you , Charlie .
What brings you here ?
I wanted to refresh memories .
Nice to have you back in Boston .
- Thank you , Charlie , it's good to be home.
I'm tired of rounds airport .
I never liked to fly .
My wife and I
only travel to the city .
Tell me , Charlie . how
did you know that she's the one ?
That was clear after
our first kiss .
My heart fluttered .
And after 39 years , her kisses
still have the same effect .
You are about to jump ?
I'm thinking about it .
Already have purchased the ring , which
tells you quite sure .
I was more than sure
when I bought it .
But since I came back to Boston ...
I do not know .
- Evora ? Blinking heart ?
I do not understand .
Evora means that you
prevents something from inside .
What indicates that you
you should give it up .
But if your heart is flashing ...
Then she must have those rights .
And what if at the same time have
and Evora , and treperiš ,
and if the Evora result of guilt over
spontaneous kiss in the elevator ...
What is your heart flutter ?
In this case you would
wished luck , Mr. Hughes .
Thank you very much , Charlie .
You're late for 4 minutes . - I believe that we will
all will be forgiven when you see my drawings .
The drafts ? - I was very inspired
Adam's homes and collections ,
so I made plans .
I worked almost all night .
Nedoraðene are still just sketches .
Are extremely ...
Deflecting .
How do you , for God's sake , the idea to
Adam might like something like this ?
Because of his first
editions of " a Christmas song ."
I like " Wuthering Heights " , but it does not
means that I want to live in a swamp .
Wendy , I'm extremely disappointed .
These sketches are just ...
Another three a Christmas tree.
Who has three a Christmas tree ?
And that's right . It was horrible .
The first tree to represent
of Christmas past , present other ,
a recent future . I crossed my mind
to make ornaments for the tree for the future of Christmas ,
could make the children of artistic
programs that support the " Foundation Hughes ."
Is that right ?
It will be a social event , not
artistic workshops childrens' kindergartens .
Children are the future .
- My not .
These sketches are utterly unacceptable .
Remove them . - proud
I was on these sketches .
You have no reason to be .
Good morning ! How are you ?
- Good .
Come on , look at my drawings .
The whole night I was working on them .
Good morning , Wendy .
- Morning .
Still astonishes me your talent .
- Thank you, darling , it's my job .
Can I be completely honest ?
Sure .
I'm looking for something like this
this year . I 'm , you know ...
Something more traditional .
That's what I 'd expected , so I created
Another draft , so he could choose .
He was still confused,
but you'll understand the idea .
I just asked for this .
I can not believe how you managed
capture exactly what I wanted .
Three the Christmas tree ,
past, present and future .
This is zadivljujuæe .
- A tree for the future ...
Decorations could make children from one
of your sponsorship projects .
This is great ! Incredible !
The whole idea is so Enhanced Hair .
I love it. Absolutely .
I totally see through .
- I never doubted it .
Thank you for this perfect sketch .
I can not wait to see them completed .
I have to go . I have a meeting .
Thank you very much , Wendy . - Hi !
It 's great past . - Yes.
Think you've captured the essence .
- I am. - Not true .
Your idea was
completely missed .
You're playing with the life of a young
lady! - These are my sketches !
You work for me , so that your work and my work .
As long as I give you wages ,
your own drawings .
That's not fair !
- Do you remember , Wendy ?
I think you just can not open
Rights doors in this city .
But if you prijeðeš , I'll see
never to do in this city .
Then you will be the maximum for
Based Assembly
house in New Hampshire .
And now , since you're so good
then hunted this project ,
I entrust you all
prepare for tomorrow .
In the morning, we start with the job .
Great!
What smradaèa !
- I have to tell Adam all .
And about the kiss , and on the drawings .
- No way !
Hands are you related to him . that
Kiss is ancient history.
And if I say that the sketches
My , you are asked if Priscilla ,
and will be her word against mine .
Could we make a hell
of life . - As it has not already ?
Then quit , Wendy . let
herself pulling it out from that.
I can not quit. I will not .
I have suffered for so long , how
I again poèinjala fascinated .
In addition , I want to see how
to realize my plans ,
even though I 'll be the only
who will know that they are mine.
Lord!
That's it . Adam .
- Lord! Scary !
I do not want to see me . - Stop
fidgeting , and has already seen .
Tell him everything . - I agree .
Recognition is 90 % of success .
You mean salvation ? - And it .
I can not say anything , and you
two shut up . - Hi , Wendy !
Hi , Adam ! These are my
roommates . Caroline ...
Actress ? Hi !
- Hi !
And Tressa .
- Vizažistkinja ?
Someone was attentive in class .
Excuse me ?
- Do not mind her .
I am thrilled with what this morning
Priscilla's sketches . Those are beautiful .
As if she read my thoughts .
And we were shocked . - Shocked !
In fact , it is nothing strange .
- I want to thank you for the team.
That is very important .
Entertainment will be amazing .
Wendy's incredibly talented .
So much so that literally sparkles .
No sparkles , no.
I'd like to see yours
drafts . - Already did .
Then , I'll see you in the morning .
Possibly . Waiting for me reloaded
day . I'm not entirely sure , but ...
I have to go . Coffee is ready ,
Priscilla and me waiting .
She pulled me on this machine .
Nice to meet you , ladies .
See you there! - Hi !
Girls ... - I get it !
You're a coward . - I did not !
Are ! Rights ! you just
said : " I can not say anything . "
I did not say that. I prayed
You two do not say anything .
Only when you said : " I can not say anything . "
I do not remember that. I
coward , but I use logic .
Logic wings or white meat ?
- Very funny . - Is not it ?
How was your day ?
- A fantastic . - Nice.
And yours? - Good .
Thanks for the coffee .
Give me your coat . - Thank you .
Shall I put a bit of a Christmas music ?
Please, anything but that!
Listening is Halloween .
Good morning , Wendy !
Good morning , Miss Hall ! met
you Tressa . - Yes , good morning !
What is it ?
- For Adam's book.
Oh, yes , of course !
Well , put it here . - Wait ,
go with the future of Christmas tree .
He'll be where I want. this
will soon be my house .
I do not like . Put it here .
Sorry .
Right here .
No, put it next to
door . Put it here .
Over here . - Unlike you ,
I know where you put it.
Lord! No! Are you okay ?
No, geese ! Bring me
ice ! - Immediately , Miss Hall .
Here it is , Miss Hall . - Give it to me !
Cracked it . - It's true .
- Bring me the bag ! - Immediately .
Take this !
Lord!
Lord, I am not Adam
allowed to see her like this.
If you really loved her, did not
matter how you look. - That's right.
Ubuduæe will I constantly think like this.
No one can not see me like this.
I need to look perfect for engagement ,
that would be a headline .
If Adam sees me like this ...
What should I do?
I'll go to New York.
I will go to my mother's with plastic
surgeon and he will quickly solve the problem .
Adam can not see me like this.
But what are we to decorating the house ?
You're responsible for everything , until I get back .
What I will say to Adam ? - If I had to
suddenly go out of town on business .
Nothing weird .
Damn it !
You know what this means ?
That we mortals can vent .
Staying alone with Adam .
That's it.
Finally it dawned on you ? - I guess .
Come on , waiting for a lot of us
job . - Good .
It looks wonderful.
Too bad you do not Priscilla
can see this . - Thank you .
We're making progress . - That's right.
We're ready for the trees . USA
they are on the right. - Oh, trees .
You're going to get them ? - Yes .
I like to buy them at night .
The Christmas lighting gives them a real vibe.
You intend to bring herself three trees ?
That was my intention .
I can not let you do that .
Not very . I'll go with you .
- I really did not need , can alone .
When you are dealing Interiors ,
get used to your hands full .
I'll make you feel better if you let me
help you . - Good . Come on.
What is the " pudding with figs ?"
I do not know , but it must be very tasty ,
doèim not want to leave until you get .
Sure . Perfect.
- Probably everyone sing .
They will get bored by the end of the evening . - It will not !
The Christmas songs I can never get bored .
When I was little , I went
I was at the tree with my dad .
We went to the farm and Derby Hill
literally plunged into the forest trees .
It would take at least an hour ,
While we chose perfectly .
Sounds like a revived
Norman Rockwell painting .
Exactly so .
Then we went home , cooked
cocoa and decorated tree and the same night .
And then we would with okiæeno
tree sat in front of the TV,
and watch the Christmas movies .
- What are your favorite ?
" Charlie Brown Christmas " , of course .
" The Grinch " , " Wonderful Life "
and " a Christmas story " .
Special memories .
Are .
This is nice . - Yes , it's perfect .
Tonight was the first time elected
the Christmas tree . - Are you kidding? - I do not .
In our house were submitted to the Christmas tree.
My father has traveled extensively , mother
was constantly busy .
And at Christmas we had
a special meaning .
Apart from my grandmother . it
it was she seemed special .
It is still ... - ... Not Dies
the prior 15 years . - My condolences .
There is still a lot of thinking about
her. She held the family together .
How did you engage in
work with the theater ?
In the middle I wanted to become an actor .
I trained at drama
section and learned by heart
all the famous Hamlet's soliloquies .
When I finished the shootout ,
Hall remained in torment .
I could hear the flies .
I was full of myself , I'm viewing it
Good Performance broken down by your feet.
And after a whole eternity , the teacher
was the first to react , I wondered :
"Adam, Do you realize that Hamlet speaks
suicide in this monologue ? "
So I decided to work behind the scenes .
And it very much .
Tressa ! Caroline !
Hi ! - Hi !
I Come here
Hi , Adam !
- How are you ? - Good .
Hi ! Tressa , Caroline ,
Please, sit down .
What are the Canol ?
- Rules of them this morning .
Often eat what you cook a dish
at work ? - I like to lick the spoon .
In fact it is stated on Facebook
as one of their pastime .
She received quite a few strange
friend requests . - That's right.
We talked about past Christmas.
Have you dug up some old ghosts ?
Actually we did. Several .
That 's what I thought .
You're funny .
I Hi ! - Hi ! delivery
for Priscilla Hall .
Here you are. - Where do you want to
dispose of them ? - Right here .
Lots of boxes. - Yes . They arrived decorations
the tree of past and present Christmas.
Children today are doing decorations for the tree
future Christmas. To arrive tomorrow .
Tomorrow arrives since Christmas. - Yes .
But what would happen if tomorrow
be present , and the future arrives ?
I do not understand ... Well ,
Stephen Hawking .
I have a surprise .
Pudding with figs .
How did you managed to find ?
- Not so easy .
Do not even look like
pudding . - It looks disgusting .
Yes.
You first . - No, ladies
have an advantage . Here you go .
Yet I am a gentleman .
And his taste is disgusting .
More like a fruit cake . - And I
I'll stick to dried figs .
But , thank you for this interesting ...
experience . - You're welcome .
I need to decorate the tree of Christmas past .
Would you help me?
With pleasure .
Hangs it up .
Where ? - Up there .
Here ? - Yes . Perfect.
Look at this .
She's beautiful .
Excellent. Right here .
And this ?
On the other side .
Here ? - Can .
Grandma would have loved this .
Liked her all this .
With her Christmas was warm and family ,
atypically for the rest of the Hughes family .
Before his death we donated
that Dickens book for Christmas.
It was a really special gift .
Because she had nothing . She sold
family jewelry to make me buy it.
Family Hughes has unlimited resources
and could buy hundreds of such books .
But I wanted her to buy their
money ... Especially for me .
Only now I understand how
this book is special .
I 'm glad you like blueprints .
I love it.
I was a little surprised that the
Priscilla decided for this approach .
Sometimes it seems that
We are from different planets .
And then come up with something like this .
Adam, I'm ...
I have to say that I am ...
- I'm sorry .
Priscilla . I apologize .
Priscilla ? Hi !
We are. We just talked about .
Nice! I love it.
A Christmas gifts to
current tree Christmas.
Is not nadahnjujuæe ?
I love it.
It got dark , I turn on
Light . - No, not yet!
All lighting is connected remotely ,
so you just need to press in. ..
Merry Christmas !
And the light emerges from the darkness .
Not even he can not win .
It's incredible .
Come see your book .
This is perfect.
Can you repay
dinner for all the effort ?
Sure .
For parties that away and see
do not serve pizza and beer .
They can only enjoy the
parties after the prime actors .
Will you come to the party
actors from " The Nutcracker " ?
I do not know . It could be me
be a very important night.
Just a little . Here it is . I want to propose .
Miss Hall ? - What do you think ?
I think it's wonderful .
But not for Ms Hall . - Come on ?
Pretradicionalan is ,
it is much more modern .
I bought it in Milan.
Then I was not sure
in that we should be together .
But returning to Boston ,
I was not sure whether I feel
heart flutters or knots.
But the other night I felt
right flicker . - Did you ?
Yes, but not with Priscilla .
I thought Priscilla
I feel Evora ,
but it turned out to
it is still blinking .
I feel a flicker .
- I'm not sure I understand .
Clearly , because it speaks
my friend Charlie .
When I saw Priscilla's draft ,
all the love and emotions
that is woven into them .
That's when I knew .
Drafts are ruled ?
- Without further .
It is those .
Would you like anything else ?
I do not want .
Account , please ! Thank you .
Isabella , " Measure for Measure "
Cordelia , " King Lear " . And Portia .
There is no end to them .
What is it?
Reminds me of the sled
from Priscillinih draft .
I like what is inserted
something so romantic .
Maybe I should propose
while driving the carriage .
I think she'd be more
liked something noticable.
You would not ! Are you kidding? I
this would be perfect .
Shall we run on ?
I want them first
try out . - I do not know ...
Come on , it will be fun .
Can ride ? - Can ,
for $ 25 . - Good .
Thank you .
Here you are.
Here you go.
Are sitting comfortably ?
- Yes, thank you .
Beautifully .
Are you okay ? - Yes.
We went back a whole . how
you're in love ? - We ...
Thank you . It was wonderful .
As we are not in town . reflection
lights on the water , pure air ...
It was wonderful .
Yes, it is .
My bag .
Merry Christmas !
- Merry Christmas !
Always recognize true love .
He talked about you , when you said
for it in the elevator . Flicker and sparkle .
That's what I thought , but he showed me
the ring . He thinks she's the one .
You're the one. Sketches , kiss .
You have to tell him everything ,
before zaruèi .
Zaruèit will be on false assumptions.
I tried , but have
Right . I am a coward .
She 'd tell him I say . - No!
If anything I find out now ,
I will look to The calculated .
And still would be my word against
Priscilla . - But , to discover the truth .
What will only embarrass
Adam , because I did not recognize .
Probably would have been angry that I did not
she and I ruined our friendship .
You would not even believe that my sketches .
And yet , and I pulled
Priscilla's anger at himself .
Imagining the worst .
And not the best , it is also possible .
As well as get to Lotte.
No, I'll try to forget it .
- Honey, for this you will need a lobotomy .
Caroline , get one
corkscrew . - Good .
Here Adam Hughes . I'm calling from the United States.
I bought a ring with you and I
I would see if they could get it back ?
Good . Try to fight back
Call me when you get back .
Thank you .
Oh, no ! - What is it? - Decorate the tree for future
Of Christmas will deliver only predveèer .
I have to say to Adam .
Hi , Adam , Wendy .
I just wanted to say I will
a children's ornaments overtake only predveèer .
Look at her!
She's so happy . - Yes.
Everything is so complicated .
- Why are you still in love with the unattainable ?
However, we should pay tribute to her . there are
excellent taste when it comes to men .
It's true .
We need her to help untangle this
disputes, but how ? - I do not know .
But if the guy broke her heart ,
my cowboy boots will hit him so
very ass that will spurs play .
She wants to decorate the third tree tonight .
Tell him , Wen .
I can not .
How many times do you need
repeat , I can not !
Take care of yourself , okay? - Can .
It's just a decoration .
These ornaments are priceless .
Look at this .
The idea to make them
children was extraordinary .
Now that we've decorated , I have
a little surprise for you .
Not pudding with figs ?
- It is not . I threw it away . - Good .
In honor of the Christmas traditions
your father and me , I'm here :
" Charlie Brown Christmas " , " The Grinch "
" Wonderful Life " , " the Christmas story " and
" The Christmas song Muppet " .
The last one was in memory of my grandmother .
Thank you .
Much to finish watching .
- Better Let's start immediately .
Are you going to finish watching them all ? - Yes .
Even the " Muppets " ? - Yes .
I have not watched them yet . - No one !
This is a Christmas classics . - I know .
Even the " Wonderful Life " ? - I do not .
Are you kidding? I cry every time
when Clarence gets wings .
They destroyed your childhood .
- Sad but true .
Can China ?
- Sounds great.
Good .
Hi !
Priscilla ... Welcome back !
I missed you .
- Obviously .
Ornaments have arrived late last night and wanted
We all end up to your return .
I'm leaving now .
- As you wish .
Thanks for your help , Wendy .
Goodbye , Adam !
I'm glad you 're back .
Stink on cheap fast food .
Do not fret , Priscilla .
Nothing happened .
I did not even think about .
It is my Deputy Assistant .
I went into the shower.
Hello?
Mr. Hughes can not occur .
Would you like to leave a message ?
He wants to return the ring
who bought it from you?
I will convey to him .
Darling , you look refreshed .
I could not stop thinking
about us while I was gone .
I've been thinking a lot .
We need to talk .
If you prefer, I have little
time before the meeting of the Committee .
No, you go ahead .
Should cIean this mess .
A lot of work before the party .
Then we'll talk when I get back .
Hello , Miss Hall ? - Comes
Now in Adam's house !
Yes , Miss Hall .
Apparently I missed Adam .
So much so that he rushed to propose to me.
Did you marry him ?
It is here , along with your
sentimental Tree future Christmas.
How appropriate .
It is. Congratulations !
When it poèistiš , finished
We . You're fired .
You're not welcome here . nor
come to think about Adam's party.
I trusted you , Wendy .
I thought you were gifted .
And what did you do?
You betrayed me .
I did not .
Nothing happened between Adam and
Me . You are the one I love , you proposed .
I do not want to listen to what you were doing together .
If you try to enter ubuduæe
in any contact with him ,
I realized his initial threat .
Never again you will not work in this city .
Now poèisti this .
It's my fault .
- You did . - Yes.
You did not ! - Yes ! I agreed
spend all that time with him .
And the purchase of trees , carriage rides and
the Christmas movies ...
Less would hurt that I kept
original plan and avoided him .
Why am I supposed to think at all
harsh drafts ? - Do not!
Because you're a talented designer .
They came to you from the heart .
He should already understand , after all
the time spent with you ,
that there is no competition . You're the one
rights , and she bezveznjaèa .
With her will live happily ever after .
- This link will be anything but happy .
Take .
Come to the theater , and it will
a little cheer . - I do not .
Come with me .
I fell in love with him . - I know .
I'm so sorry .
That hurts . - I know .
Come here . I'm so sorry .
Hi , I would like to talk
with someone from Social chronicles .
I would like to inform you that will
Sunday fun Adam Hughes
zaruènièka also be fun .
Yes , Priscilla Hall .
Select from
existing image pair .
Look at the ones with the last
Boston Pops concert season .
Nice.
I am their close friend .
Hello , Mr. Hughes !
- Hi , Charlie .
You look like you're from
shoulders fell the burden of the world .
Approx . I decided to return the ring .
Untangling you Evora
and heart flutters .
I believe I did , Charlie .
Dear , I'm glad you 're home.
We need to talk . - Without further .
I'll go first. I had a terrible day .
Wendy quit this morning . she
is that in these last days
realized he did not want
be part of our world .
Wendy quit ? - Yes.
But at least we wished
All the best . She said that we
perfect couple , which is , of course , true.
She's gone. - Forever .
He even wants to be either our celebration , which
would obviously be a celebration of our engagement .
I agree , my dear !
I can marry you.
Sure I will ! - Stop it !
Wait a minute . - I know that the ring is not
perfect , but we can get it back.
I'm thrilled ! proof
is to know how much I love you ,
and how much you love me . bit
we so happy together .
Priscilla . - Do not say anything !
Just remember the intimacy and passion
we shared the journey .
We have it here in Boston.
And if you want to cancel all social
obligations in order to be together ,
just the two of us , me anything
could not be more usreæiti .
I need a drink .
Adam Hughes , the Hughes Foundation
and Priscilla Hall , decorator - zaruèeni
Mom ? Did you see the second page ?
Tressa , what 's wrong with Wendy ?
He is too stupid jerk Adam
sum that is in love with her,
so zaruèio with that rich witch.
It was weird . He told me that he
heart flutter in the elevator ,
and that it does not intend to marry .
Come on , get out ! ?
- I would not work here.
It told me .
What a conundrum !
We have to do something.
- Count on me .
Excellent.
Is this really necessary?
- Extremely necessary .
I will not let you
destroy my premiere .
Sorry , Tressa . There are
do not feel particularly glamorous.
This will cheer you up .
- I should hardly think .
Come on, Wendy , we need you ! - So
is . - Do your best to be glamorous .
" I'm for it ," tonight you will not pass .
I'll be behind the scenes , there is no
the need for adjustment .
Yes, there is ! And what about fun
and all those cute ballet dancers ?
Lord! That is
Recently on my mind tonight .
Do not make me laugh !
Do it for the team.
Good . - Thank you !
Nice to see you. Cheers !
Thank you for coming .
Excuse me for a moment . Thank you .
You are very rude
to our guests .
This is our zaruènièka fun .
No, this is fun for patrons
City Ballet. - Of course .
I never formally proposed .
This is utterly irresistible .
That's the problem .
Nothing happened .
Of course it is . you bought
my ring . What are you doing?
Where is the centerpiece of " The Nutcracker " ?
- He does not belong here .
Here , because of this hate law
the Christmas tree. Create a mess .
Needles are everywhere .
I love them . I thought you were them
because of this and has included in the draft .
Which , of course , were Wendy's ,
and you have appropriated the credit.
Behind her work are my instructions .
What inspired you ?
Book your grandfather , of course . Stop it !
That book was my grandmother .
THEATRE CARPENTER
"The Nutcracker "
I apologize . Excuse
, sir .
Congratulations on your engagement .
Wendy , not as
how it looks . - Oh, there you are !
Wendy , you're cute .
I 'd like to apologize for all
What happened between us .
I'd really like to continue
work with you . You're very talented .
Stop it!
I'm sorry that I did not go
before you fired me .
I was not fired . - You fired
is ? - Wrong we understand .
I thought you quit giving , in order to
could return ... theatrical roots .
You know what , Miss Hall ?
I thought that was working for
You realization of all my dreams .
I thought I should be
successful interior designer .
And I was blinded
your glamorous life .
But that was before
I see your true colors.
So , go ahead , spend
the work of his poor threat .
Because if you spend the rest of his career
as a set designer in the public theater ,
It would be a dream come true .
And you ...
You chose her.
- What is going on here ?
I really believe that she
could make harsh drafts ?
Adam, I was in front of you
eyes all the time .
If you had that kiss in the elevator
something meant the concoction , he recognized me .
You're not a man to whom I fell in love .
You deserve each other .
Wendy ! Wendy !
Let her go , let it go .
Let's go back to our place .
I continue to have fun .
With these sequins itself . her face
sparkles like a disco ball. Come on!
Help me .
You're not just a style completely
wrong , Priscilla .
What are you doing?
Well , I did not understand ,
but know that my heart
leapt in that carriage .
I felt the same spark as
with a kiss in the elevator .
I just want to know ...
Can you forgive me
I have been so blind ?
I'll consider it .
Have you thought what you said about ..
About falling in love ?
I am.
Thanks to a broken elevator
and beautiful , sparkling woman ,
in life has returned
the true meaning of Christmas.
I fell in love.
Benefactor Adam Hughes and set designer
Wendy Walton announce wedding
Translation and interpretation: lilien