subs and sync by Rubens
www.addicted.com
Have you ever wondered
how it all gets done?
How Santa gets in and out
of millions of homes
all in one night?
Let's just say,
he has a little help.
The operation
has its challenges...
But we're always prepared.
Our mission statement is...
Get in. Get out.
Never be noticed.
I'm part of
Prep & Landing.
An elite unit of elves
getting houses around the world,
ready for the Big Guy's arrival.
My name is Wayne.
Callsign:  Little Drummer Boy.
And I've been doing this
a long time.
A really long time.
Now I'm ready to move up
and leave this job behind.
Oh, yeah...
Next year's gonna be different.
Hey-hey-hey...  Excuse-me.
This spot is reserved for...
Wayne?
No ticket this time,
Waterkotte.
You received the promotion?
I was not informed of that!
I'm just heading over to
Magee's office right now.
You know, make it official,
blah, blah, blah.
You just make sure you get
a parking sticker on there pronto, mister!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!   Scratch it,
and I'll put you on the naughty list.
Just kidding...
But I could.
All Prep and Landing teams
report in.
# Oh, jingle bells
Wayne is swell #
# He's a director #
# Don't be late, for our date
Under the mistletoe! #
- Hey, Wayne, we're gonna miss you!
- And I'll miss you, Gabe.
It's Bryan!
Naughty List Houses
coming online now.
All coal elves,
check-in.
Oh, here he comes,
here he comes.
- Hey, new boss.
- Hey, boss!
My wife, she made you a fruitcake.
Wife? Thank you!
Whoa... Heavy!
Oh, it feels more like
a pound cake, huh?
Yeah. Yeah? Yeah.
Okay.
What was your name again?
Gristletoe Joe, sir.
But my friends call me Nancy.
I'm gonna remember you
when I'm in charge, Nance.
You tell that lovely wife of yours that
I am gonna savor every last bite, yeah.
(whispering) - From me to you.
- Hold on. Hello?
I'll see you at the christmas
party tomorrow.  Okay. bye!
- Hi, Magee.
- Hello?  Oh, yeah?
Well, this year I'm santa's secret santa.
Okay, what am I supposed to do
about that, Jerry? ugh!
Hi, Wayne.
- Aw, did you lose a bet, sweetie?
- It's my celebration tie.
Wayne, you didn't get
the promotion.
- What?
- Peterson got it.
- My partner?
- Yeah.
So, no parking sticker?
You're disappointed.
Oh no. No!
I'm glad for Peterson.
What are you crazy?
'Cause he was trained by me.
I mean seriously are you crazy?
I'm so glad...
that the Big Guy notice him
and not me.  So there you go.
Well, good!  Because now
you have a new partner to train.
Uh, Tiny? Tiny?
Ah, Tiny.
Send him in.
Ooh... I think you'll really like him.
Top of his class
at Kringle Academy.
- A little help here?
- It was a small class.
Please?
- I'm Lanny, callsign Treeskirt.
- Lanny?
I'm so excited
to be working with you!
I had a poster of you
on my wall growing up.
Talk about a Christmas gift, huh?
Okay!... Trasher is the last transport,
so let's get a move on.
Thrasher?
Thrasher the reindeer?
Oh, there he is!
Great garland!
I heard Dasher had a cousin,
but I always thought you were a myth!
- I am a myth.
- What?
Tell anyone I exist,
and you won't exist.
Wayne, what's Thrasher's
top speed?
Mach 2, mach 3?
I bet it's more like mach a-billion!
This is so tinsel!
Does the phrase "silent night"
mean anything to you?
3, 2, 1...
Wow! That house is
a winter wonderland.
We have an L-shaped
living chamber.
Two visible exits
to the left.
And to the east.
No hidden cameras.
Hey, you know, it seems like you've got
this real holiday zest going.
You know what?
What do you say you fly solo?
Solo?
Solo.
- But it's m-m... my first mission.
- You are highly trained, aren't you?
I'll report in
at regular intervals.
I'm going upstairs.
Right.  And I'll handle
cookie assessment.
Treeskirt to
Little Drummer Boy.
No creatures stirring.
Over.
Hmm? Oh. Mm-Hmm.
Uh-huh.  All right.  Oh.
Stockings are hung with care.
- Am I doing okay?
- Oh, doing fantastic.
That's right.
I'm being naughty.
Tell your buddy Peterson
to put me on his list.
Oh, a bike!
Oh, he's gonna be so happy!
- Ahh. Merry Christmas!
- A Christmas Special!  That's nice.
Do you want to watch
a Christmas Special? You do?
Oops.  Oh, another one.
Do you like that? I don't.
That one? too bad.
Oh, here we go.
Uh, Little Drummer Boy...
Mm, I could really use
some advice here.
Go with your gut, kid.
Merry Christmas, Big Guy.
Stale.
It's jingle time.
Open hangar doors.
- Doors open.
- Cue rosebud.
Instruments are holly jolly.
Rev up the engines.
Reindeer ready to roll.
We are go for Partridge.
He's on his way.
I've made the list, sir.
- You checked it twice?
- Per redundancy protocol.
Prep & landing teams
are under way.
- Everything seems to be in proper order.
- Excellent.
Thank you, miss Holly.
The Partridge is in the pear tree.
We are go for launch.
- Vehicle?
- Dash away.
- Engines?
- Partridge?
- Dash away.
Dash away all!
Ten, Nine, Eight, Seven...
Six, Five, Four,
Three, Two, One.
Ho, Ho...
Go!
Okay, people, this is it!
364 Days of preparation,
one night of perfect execution.
Nothing will go wrong.
Sir?  There's a storm alert
over sector 7.
Oh, frostbite.
Hi, I'm Timmy.
What's your name?
I-I... huh...
It's Wayne.
You're a lot smaller than
Santa's helpers at the mall.
Are you a baby elf?
No, I'm not a baby.
I have a pension.
- Aah!
- You're squeezy.
Little Drummer Boy,
creature stirring!
ANOTHER ONE!
Security breach.
Subject has been sparkled.
Hey, is this one of the Big Guy's cookies?
Not anymore.
We are definitely
behind schedule now.
Then we'd better get going.
But... but doesn't section code 808 state
"All children shall be snug in their beds"?
So you were having
a jolly holiday downstairs.
Oh, yeah.
Fa la la la la.
What's wrong?
I mean, don't you even care?
I've been working prep & landing
for 227 years,
and believe me, the thrill is gone.
But this is the most tinsel job ever...
You bringing joy to children?
- Sorry!
- Look, Treeskirt,
We are just tiny ornaments
on some gigantic tree,
slaving away...
All for what?
"For what"? For him.
Just look at this face, Wayne.    Imagine
the joy on this face tomorrow morning.
Imagine all the great memories
he'll pass on to his children.
And his children's children.
The thrill may be gone for you, Wayne.
But it's not gone for him.
You'll learn, rookie.
I thought you were *the*
prep & landing guy, Wayne.
But you're just a lump of coal.
Yeah. Well, sometimes,
we don't get what we want.
- Yes, dear?
- Wayne, it's Magee.
I'm sure you've noticed
the snowstorm is pretty bad.
Oh, well, I have now.
I mean, uh, oh.
You... you're not on the roof?
You're not... you're not done?
Okay. Fine.
We have a coal in the stocking.
- What?
- We're putting him to bed. Relax.
I told you to pull it together,
not crumble like a Christmas cookie!
- If you have...
- Eight Maids A-Milking, this is Jingle Belle.
Come in, Eight Maids A-Milking.
I really hate that call sign.
Can barely hear you, Jingle Belle.
- We are in the soup here.
- We're flying blind, man!
Tell her we're flying blind!
Why didn't I listen to Jerry
and stay in toy design?
Tiny... Bring me Big Red.
It's just a little snow, Magee.
I can handle it.
You don't understand, sir.
The site's not prepped.
We have no choice.
Figgy pudding.
It's never come to that.
What about Timmy?
Sir, with all due respect,
There are millions of other kids
counting on you.  It's just not safe.
We'll make it up to Timmy
somehow, I promise.
All right, then.
You heard her, team.
Figgy p-pudding?
But that means the Big Guy's
passing us by.
What about Timmy?
What about his Christmas?
Well, I, uh...
I never meant...
This to happen.
This will be the best Christmas ever.
Thanks, Wayne.
- Magee, patch me Through to the Big Guy.
- Wayne, it's over.
Patch me through, or I'll tell
everyone about you and Tiny!
- Patching you through.
- Hello? This is Partridge.
Sir, my name's Wayne
from Prep & Landing.
I need you to come to this house, sir.
Oh, I'm afraid Magee's
rerouting me, son.
Sir, there's a child here
that's really excited for you.
We cannot let him down.
I can land you safely.
I have a plan,
and there is time.
Please, sir, let me do my job.
I can't let Timmy down.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Let's give it a shot, my boy.
This is the most tinsel job ever,
huh, partner?
Huh... I shouldn't never
have patch him through.
Sir!
Roasting chestnuts,
he's turned back!
Oh! no!
No, no, no, no!
You can't see anything in this storm!
Except your winter wonderland.
How are we gonna make it
through all this snow?
Laughing all the way, my friend,
laughing all the way.
Lanny, I need some rope!
Is this enough?
Light 'em up!
Good job, Treeskirt!
Yes!
Aah! I'm gonna die!
I'm alive!
Little Drummer Boy...  Little Drummer Boy,
we don't see the landing strip.
Almost there, sir!
We have a visual!
The landing zone is prepped!
We're going in.
Cut the engines.
Coming in too hot!
It's too late to pull up, man!
It's too late to pull up!
Keep it together, Dancer!
Hang on!
Huh? (gasps)
The tailhook!
Hi... I don't have an appointment, uh...
But I was wondering if, um...
- Relaxing... He's been expecting you.
- He is?  Oh, well, uh...
Okay.
Hey, wayne!
You're missing the party!
They're gonna start
the gift exchange! Whoo!
Uh, no. no.  You... you go ahead.
I'll catch up later.
Come in, Wayne.
Sir, I am very sorry
about last night.
If you want to transfer me
or fire me, I..
I completely understand.
But, please, make sure
you find Lanny a new partner.
He's a good elf, sir.
Well...
That's why I assigned him to you.
But don't be silly, Wayne.
I'm not going to bite your head off.
Everyone slips onto the
naughty list once in a while.
I'm glad you stopped by, though.
So I could say Merry Christmas.
It's... It's Timmy's house.
It's a reminder of why
our job is so important.
Now go on.   We're not getting
any younger, you know.
Thanks, Santa.
Oh, Wayne...
One more thing.
Well, what...
What did he say?
- He offered me a promotion.
- Wow!
Director of The Nice List.
Congratulations.
- I turned him down.
- What?
I'm more of a Prep & Landing guy.
Aah! a fruitcake!
Mmm!
Thanks, Magee!
The best Christmas ever!
subs and sync by Rubens
www.addicted.com