Subtitles by explosiveskull
[electronic buzz]
[beeping]
[metal click]
[shrill]
[harp]
♪ Jolly old Saint Nicholas ♪
♪ Lean your ear this way ♪
♪ Don't you tell a single soul ♪
♪ What I'm going to say ♪
[Daisy]
What can I get you?
♪ Christmas Eve is coming soon ♪
♪ Now, you dear old man ♪
♪ Whisper
What you'll bring to me ♪
♪ Tell me if you can ♪
[harp]
♪ Jolly old Saint Nicholas ♪
♪ Lean your ear this way ♪
♪ Don't you tell a single soul ♪
[indistinct conversations]
Tony, can I get
a refill on that? Regular.
Then we've got dark, decaf,
americano and espresso.
[song continues]
- Piping hot.
- Thank you, sir.
No, thank you, Daisy.
I don't know how you do it.
It's in the air.
Everybody's in the holiday
spirit, can't you feel it?
Yeah, but you're
especially chipper.
I know, I'm super excited.
I'll be home for the first
time in two years.
I saved all my money to get
my family great presents.
I get to spend
the whole six weeks,
all the holidays.
I don't think I'm going to bed
tonight, I'll go for a run.
- Stay young, kid.
- Lord knows I'm trying, Tony.
[clinking together]
♪ Now, you dear old man ♪
♪ Whisper
What you'll bring to me ♪
♪ Tell me if you can ♪
[ominous music]
♪ Jolly old Saint Nicholas ♪
♪ Lean your ear this way ♪
♪ Don't you tell a single soul ♪
♪ What I'm going to say ♪
♪ Christmas Eve is coming soon ♪
♪ Now, you dear old man ♪
♪ Whisper
What you'll bring to me ♪
♪ Tell me if you can ♪
[breathing]
♪ Christmas Eve is coming soon ♪
♪ Now, you dear old man ♪
♪ Whisper
What you'll bring to me ♪
♪ Tell me if you can ♪
[breathing]
["Deck the Halls" playing]
[bushes rustling]
[trembling breath]
[heavy footsteps]
No!
[slosh]
[gurgles]
♪ Deck the halls
With boughs of holly ♪
♪ Fa la la la la la la la la ♪
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly ♪
♪ Don we now our gay apparel ♪
♪ Fa la la la la la la la la ♪
♪ Troll the ancient
Christmas carol ♪
- Hey, beautiful tree, guys.
- Yeah, he cut it off himself.
- Yeah, I did.
- Nice job, bud.
How much we owe you?
What's your name?
- Rudolph.
- Like the reindeer?
Yeah, I get that a lot.
♪ Troll the ancient
Christmas carol ♪
♪ Fa la la la la la la la la ♪
[girls cheering]
Smell that pine!
Thanks for bringing us
up here, Cut.
Yeah, breathe it in, dude.
I'm going to find me
the perfect tree.
Are you girls getting one?
Maybe, what do you think, Margo,
do we have room?
I don't know,
I'm here for the party.
[Cutler chuckles] Yeah!
Last year, Cutler and I
found the cutest tree,
I knew we had to come back.
You've been here before?
Hell yeah, found this place on
a random road trip in college.
Oh, you mean the stoner drive?
That's awesome.
You have to come
the first weekend
or all the good trees are gone.
That makes sense.
Oh my god, I'm just noticing
your sweater, it's Blitzen?
It's funny.
Don't worry we are definitely
gonna get Blitzen.
[all chuckling]
Yeah we are.
- Game!
Wait, what are we doing?
It's like, it's game,
it's like...
It's like challenge or dare.
Someone says game
and we all have to play.
Like these Christmas sweaters.
That's why I have to wear
this hideous thing.
Aha!
Let's go chop
some flaping trees!
All right, what do we have here?
Saws.
All right.
- Roberto.
- Thank you.
[loud laughter]
- And, Art, this is yours.
- Thank you.
Oh, yeah!
God.
- Babe?
- No, thank you.
This place is awesome.
Yeah, except there's no
cell service.
You think they'll be able
to fix it by now.
[Bella] What's that building
across the way?
Some homeless refuge, like ew.
Used to be some fancy hotel,
but people stopped going there.
Now, just
the occasional squatter.
Wouldn't go anywhere near
if I were you.
Why not?
It's a real dangerous place.
Yeah, well, looks pretty sick,
like a movie or something
That's super creepy.
I love creepy.
Oh, it's real creepy,
I'd stay away if I were you.
This guy is so creepy.
Are we talking about
how creepy this shooot it is
or are we chopping down
some flaping trees?
- Yeah!
- Let's do it!
Where are your Colorado?
Back lot, up over the hill.
Truck will pick you up,
we close in an hour.
Sun down, you better be ready.
You got it, man.
Ok, thank you, thank you.
Ok, let's do it!
[indistinct chatting]
- How do you know Margo?
- We work together.
Nice,
so you are in wardrobe too?
Yeah, I mean, mostly we just
follow the designer around,
take notes, grab coffee,
run errands, that sort of thing.
Yeah, it is fun.
How do you know these guys?
I actually just found
Art and Cutler on Craigslist.
They needed a roommate
I just moved out here,
Thing just kind of...
You know, worked out well.
- From where?
- Iowa.
I'm from New Mexico.
- Oh, wow, long way from home.
- Yeah, it is.
But I really like it here,
I mean,
there's so much more going on.
Fair enough.
- Game.
- What are we playing?
Greens for the greenery.
I'm one with the trees.
- Margo, you know I don't...
- Really?
It's like not that hardcore.
- I mean, have you ever even?
- Yes, I have.
[silent]
Whatever, let's play.
Yo, let's get out of the path.
Good call.
Is that guy always so flaping
agreeable and cheery?
Come on, it's better
than being an asshole.
Robbie is a good dude,
ain't nothing wrong.
I think he's sweet.
Well, flap you, guys.
Ok, just ignore her,
she's just...
Being a bitch.
No, that was not
what I was going to say.
But it's the same thing.
It's cool, guys,
doesn't bother me.
[coughs]
[all laughing]
That's how you do it.
Bella, catch.
- Why not, right?
- There you go, Kate.
Take it all in, baby.
Game, game.
Game!
Frolic.
Sounds naughty.
So pair up, go into the forest,
and do ever your dirty
little mind's desire.
I've got Cutler, obviously.
Obviously.
Okay.
Well, we have already played,
so...
Let's go newbies.
Okay.
Margo.
So, I didn't really know we were
taking on when I signed up.
It's cool, don't worry.
We don't have to do anything,
I'm down to just chill.
Awesome, okay.
Or we could keep drinking.
I think I'm going
to take a pass.
I'm already feeling
pretty light-headed.
Do you? No worries.
You know, I think most of these
games are stupid anyway.
What's the point of frolic
when Cutler always gets Bella?
We're not spinning
a bottle or anything random.
- So you're into Bella?
- I mean...
We had a thing once in college,
but like...
she wasn't feeling me.
She was more into Cutler.
And that doesn't make things
awkward between you guys?
Those two do whatever they want.
They don't give a flap, so...
You know, screw it,
give me that.
That's a stiff drink.
So, what do you say
if we play that game after all?
Let's play.
- I flaping love Christmas.
- flap you, you should love me.
Of course I do,
but I get my fat Christmas bonus
so I'm buying some shiny rocks
for my arm candy.
Asshole.
- The shiniest rocks.
- They better be.
Now let's go find
the perfect Christmas tree.
Let's go.
Margo!
Hey!
Looks like you had fun.
Oh, yeah, that was fun.
- Like your games, Bella.
- Thank you.
Where are Kate and Art?
flaping weirdo probably told her
he loves her,
she probably ran off.
Ok, that's mean.
Oh, look, there they are.
[Bella] Having fun?
Yeah, Art was telling me
some stories
from your college glory days.
Oh, yeah, which ones?
All of them.
Wow, and she didn't run away?
That bodes well.
Guys, it's getting dark.
Let's chop some trees down
before it closes.
[Kate] Right!
Is that all? No trees?
I couldn't found
those brats anywhere.
We drove the path, hit the back
lot, and all the side areas.
flap man, there's the SUV
they're still around here.
The old lady is cooking up
a stew, I gotta get out of here.
flap, I'm not waiting around
for those little shits.
Screw this shooot!
flap.
- You got this, Ruddy?
- Yeah, I got it.
Just do another lap here,
you don't find them, flap them.
- I'm getting out of here.
- Give me a ride to the bus.
- Hey, can I get a ride too?
- Hop on.
I got it, don't worry about it.
Have a nice flaping evening.
- Take it easy, Rud.
- Yeah, you too, buddy.
flaping assholes.
flap these kids, dude.
flap out of here, I'm leaving.
[child whispering]
Oh, Christmas tree.
Cutler!
- What's up?
- I love it.
So I can leave this one?
Yeah, [unintelligible]
I love when you talk shooot.
Yeah, flap the Colorado,
let's get this, we are set.
You got it, babe.
Where is everyone?
So pretty.
- You two are not getting a tree?
- No.
- No, our apartment is too small.
- Yeah, we live in a shoebox.
My room is literally the size
of the walking closet.
Timber!
- There you guys are.
- Hey, you guys see that truck?
- No.
Need any help with that, Cutler?
I'm a good helper.
I'm good, thanks though.
Looks like everything's
shut down.
[Cutler]
Damn, we missed it.
[Bella]
Free trees, bitches.
It'll be a bitch
trying to strap these on.
I think I got rope in my bag.
You always figure it out, babe.
[Margo] Look at the stars!
We're playing a different game.
- All right, moving along.
- My bad.
Have you ever been inside?
That hotel over there.
[child whispering]
Deck the halls.
Oh, no, not for me.
I'd go.
I'd go and see what kind
of shooot is in there.
Yeah.
Wow, looks great, guys.
Thanks.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this calls for a celebration.
- Game?
- Game!
How about a new game?
I don't know if you will.
Call it, kid.
Exploration.
We're going to the hotel.
- Yes.
- Nice.
I'm not playing that game.
You have to play,
that's how game works.
- No.
- Come on, Bella, it'll be fun.
It'll be so spooky.
You're not actually scared,
are you?
Bella.
I... you better stay beside me
the entire flaping time.
Babe, don't worry,
I'll protect you, I promise.
Look, in fact, I think mom
got some lights in the back.
Great.
Boom, check it out.
Always prepared.
Yeah, aren't you?
Actually,
I bought some flashlights
since were up in the boonies.
- Look at you.
- On top of it.
These are
quick up there, right?
Ok, guys, now this is a party.
Yeah!
Wow.
Here we go.
Oh my god, this is so exciting.
I don't know, it is literally
in the middle of nowhere.
This is not
the middle of nowhere.
- You should go to New Mexico.
- Or Iowa.
I drink to that.
Hey, don't worry,
you'll be fine, Bella.
There's a clearing over there.
Come on, let's go.
Ah, this place is so scary,
I love it.
So sick, I wonder how many
bodies are in there.
That's not funny.
I think four, what do you think?
I think maybe at least ten.
You guys suck.
They're just kidding,
there are no bodies in there.
- I bet there's one body.
- Cutler!
Hey, you think we can just walk
straight through
that front door?
I don't know,
looks pretty boarded up.
We could probably open it.
Onward, hoe.
Who are you calling a hoe?
- Oh, I just...
- I'm just flaping with you.
Why are you being such a dick?
Not being a dick,
just having some fun.
[child whispering]
Deck the halls.
[man groaning]
[laughter]
Oh, flap.
Looks like they're definitely
trying to keep people out.
So, how do we get in?
It's like one of those
urban explore things.
Let's look for loose boards
or nails that we can pull out.
This isn't a good idea.
- Thanks.
- Are you having fun?
Oh, my God, yes,
I'm having tons of fun.
I haven't let loose
like this in...
maybe ever.
You know your friends
are completely insane.
I mean, these games are crazy.
They get crazier.
Wait, crazier than this?
Yeah, they love
to flap with people's heads.
Come on,
let's go around the side.
Look at this place.
They are assholes.
Hey, why are you being
so uptight?
I'm not being uptight, Margo.
I don't want to be here,
this place creeps me out.
Yeah, that's why
it's so fun, Bella.
Come on, stop being so paranoid.
- So we didn't find any-
- Oh, shooot!
Sorry.
Jesus, it's not funny.
I'm so, so sorry.
You should've seen
the look on your face.
I hate you.
No you don't, you don't hate me,
you love me.
You love me, that's why
you wear that ugly sweater.
- Your games are stupid.
- My games are fun and funky, ok?
Who doesn't like
wearing festive sweaters?
Girls, I hate to ruin your
little menstruation session,
but we're not finding any way
in here so we gotta go round.
Can we get the hell out of here?
This isn't fun.
[Art] Stop being such a baby.
flap you, Art!
You're gonna
speak to me like that?
Guys, come on, chill out.
Geez, sorry, everyone, let's go.
Whatever Bella wants,
come on, game over.
Whatever, Art.
Babe, I got you, ok?
So that's how you treat me now?
Why don't you just
calm the flap down?
Don't talk to me like that.
- I'm just...
- I don't like this game.
I don't like all the games
you play either.
That's how this shooot works,
you know this.
This place just freaks me
the flap out.
That's the point, isn't it?
Come on, let's just go.
I bet there's someone in here.
Yeah and he's going
to come after you,
it'll be like freak vs. weirdo.
Which one is Art?
That farmer said
there's the occasional squatter.
Oh my God, imagine,
we could get
two of them to fight
and then live stream it.
We are out of service up here.
No, no, no, wait, we can make
them fight until they're dead
and then we can hang them
on the bridge
and wait for birds to eat them.
Ok, Margo,
this place is scary enough.
I mean, I'm down,
I'd crush a hobo, let's do it.
You guys are fucked, like,
seriously fucked in the head.
You don't really think there's
a squatter there, do you?
I don't know, only way
to find out is if we go in.
Let's go.
Let's look for a thick piece
of wood or a branch
and we can pry this off.
So smart.
[Art] All brains that guy.
Don't forget the looks
and muscle.
I'm the total package over here.
Ok, total package,
why don't you find us
a way to get in?
Hey, guys!
Think I found a way in.
Nice find, man!
Here we go.
[Bella] This is stupid
[Cutler] Come on,
just get used to it.
Holy shooot!
What the flap happened here?
Oh, shooot.
Oh my flaping god.
Oh my god it's an oven.
[Bella] Stop.
[Margo] Oh my god,
look at this place.
[Bella] Guys, this is so stupid.
Stop, stop, this is such
a bad idea.
Bella, relax, come on,
it's not that bad.
[Bella] It's that bad.
[Cutler] Really?
[Bella] Yes, we need to get out.
Looks like someone did
a real number in here.
Where's the flaping hobo?
Hello?
[Robbie] Hello?
[Margo] Anybody home?
Oh my god, there's a ball room
in here!
Onward, hoe!
Got another bottle?
I got you.
Let's do it.
You are coming or what?
Oh my god.
[Cutler] Great game, Art.
[Bella] Yeah, great
flaping good, Art.
Now that I think of it,
you haven't said anything
Wait, I thought we were playing
find the hobo.
I'm always playing
Wait, what? Why?
I want to play a new game.
So, don't want to play frolic?
The kid's horny as flap.
Uhm... how about...
hide and seek?
Yes, I love that game!
Throwback, I like it.
All right, kid.
You called it, you're up.
Go somewhere and count
I don't know, like a 100 or so.
Let's go.
One...
Close your eyes, no cheating.
Two... three... four...
five.
[child whispering]
Tis the season to be jolly.
[bells jingling]
Game on, bitches.
Stop.
Oh, this place is flaping dope.
It's creepy as shooot.
We don't even know
the half of it.
Looks like
it's been abandoned forever.
Looks like homeless people
took a shooot here, disgusting.
Oh, man.
Look at the graffiti
on the walls.
I just want to get out of here.
Babe, just relax, it's fine.
I'm going upstairs.
- No.
- This will calm the nerves.
I'm not really in the mood,
Cutler.
They don't like how you let Art
push you around,
you're supposed to be the alpha.
Art doesn't push shooot,
all right?
I've been dying to come
since we found this place.
And you're right, I'm the alpha.
Yeah, well, you're acting
like a flaping lap dog.
Really, Bella?
And who the flap is this new
flaping tweep?
What the flap is his deal?
Why do you always
have to be such a...
- Robbie is fine.
- Are we fine?
Of course we're fine.
We're flaping perfect.
You're my número uno.
Well, doesn't feel that way...
and I'm not going upstairs.
Then you can roll solo.
Because nobody pushes me around.
Nobody.
Are you flaping serious?
God dammit, Cutler.
What an asshole.
Let's go down here.
Are you even listening?
I am, I just think
you need to let go.
Have a little fun.
[Bella] Cutler, don't!
- Don't.
- Wow.
Look at this place.
flaping disgusting.
Stop, Cutler.
Oh my god
Oh my god, lighten up, Bella.
This is so stupid, Cutler.
Get the flap out of here.
[Cutler] Bella, relax.
People fucked in these rooms.
Oh, man.
You know, I hope I find Robbie
somewhere in a dark corner.
I'm going to make that boy
blush so hard.
Aren't you seeing
that guy from work?
Yeah, but come on,
Kate it's nothing serious.
Robbie is so cute,
he's like a little puppy dog.
Better hope he finds you
and not the hobo.
God, imagine.
Yeah, but seriously,
how fucked up would it be
if there really was
a hobo in here?
Watching us from the shadows.
He'd be pissed that we've been
creeping around.
Unless I made him blush too.
Margo, you are not hooking up
with a hobo tonight.
Sorry, it's just something
about this place
- that just makes me feel so...
- Horny?
And I thought my head was off.
Who said that it wasn't, huh?
Oh my god, look at these stairs!
Oh my god, I'm going to go
to the top floor!
If you see Robbie, send him up.
God.
How do this place make you feel?
I feel on edge, but...
in a good way, you know?
I want to keep going.
Shall we?
Game on.
Game... come on, let's not
give away our positions.
Let's go upstairs.
- Ladies first.
- Thank you.
Ninety seven, ninety eight,
Ninety nine.
One hundred.
Game on.
Come out, come out
wherever you are!
I'm not going to hurt you.
[bells jingling]
Brilliant.
This place.
flaping cool.
This floor?
No, let's keep going.
Never seen anything
like this before.
Don't they have like creepy
caves in New Mexico?
Wouldn't know, my friends back
home are not out of their minds
like you guys
with all these games.
We're pretty wild.
I mean, between that, this,
and the booze, I feel like
a completely different person.
- This floor?
- Ah...
One more.
Cool, I'm going to jump off here
and make things interesting.
I'll catch up with you later?
- You bet.
- See you.
Perfect.
Oh my god.
Hey, Kate.
Oh, hey, friend.
This place is so crazy.
I know, it's like
out of a nightmare.
I know, I wonder what's taking
Robbie so long.
You do know he's never
going to find you, right?
This place is huge.
Yeah, you have a point.
You'd probably go and start
looking for him.
I think I'm going to explore
more on my own first.
- All right, have fun.
- You too.
You better buy me
the nicest Christmas present
for putting me through this.
Oh, nothing but the best.
Cutler, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop.
- God.
- Oh, baby, let's go in here.
The flaping death room?
Let's get the hell out of here,
Cutler, it's so creepy.
[Bella] Oh my god.
[Cutler] Look at all these TVs.
[Bella] I don't care,
we need to go, please.
I'd hate to have to clean
this place up.
What a dump.
What the fu...
[sniffing]
[bells jingling]
Oh my god!
Oh my flaping god,
oh my god, are you all right?
Oh my god.
Help, somebody help!
Oh my god!
Cutler! Art!
I'm going to help you!
Bella, Bella!
I promise.
[screams for help]
Margo?
[footsteps]
[screams for help]
Margo?
Hey, babe,
how about a dirty movie to get
the party going?
Of course not.
Can you imagine this place
during its heyday?
Ew.
[screams for help]
- What was that?
- What the flap?
Did you hear that?
I think that was Margo.
- Where does it come from?
- I don't know, upstairs?
That's not good.
Cutler, let's just get the flap
out of here.
- Holy flap!
- [Bella] Oh my god!
OK, all right, Art,
you're funny.
What the flap?
Robbie?
Okay, you got us.
Oh my god!
[high-pitched screams]
[bells jingling]
Bella, Bella, Bella, Bella!
I'm losing you, I gotta go
and find... I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry,
I will come back for you.
I promise, I promise.
I promise I will come back
for you, I'm so sorry.
[high-pitched screams]
[loud screams]
Stop, stop!
[bells jingling]
My god.
Are you okay?
Did you hear Bella scream?
Yeah, I heard a couple.
I thought
I heard you scream, too.
There's a girl upstairs,
she's chained to the bed.
Is this another game?
No, no, no, no!
There's a girl upstairs,
she's chained, her throat slit
and she said there's somebody
in here!
Ok, in that case,
we have to go and find her.
No, no, no, we need to go
find Bella, she was screaming.
Bella is with Cutler,
and to be honest, she's kind of
sensitive anyway.
Look, if there's a girl upstairs
we have to get her.
No, we need to go
and find Bella!
I'm going up, you do you.
No, flap you,
we need to find Bella!
Oh, flap!
[screams]
Bella?
What is happening?
Oh, God, please don't
let this be happening.
I should've
never left New Mexico.
Oh my god!
Who's there?
[Art] Kate?
Oh my god, Art, it's you!
I'm scared,
did you hear those screams?
I don't know
where they come from.
There is a killer flaping hobo
right here.
There's somebody living here,
I saw cans of open
fresh food in the kitchen.
That's fucked.
We have to find Margo and Bella
and make sure everyone's ok.
I got it, all right?
They're not gonna flap
with us, all right?
Okay.
[Art] Come on.
[Kate] Ok.
Which way is the girl?
She's down there.
Wait, wait.
That room there.
Holy shooot.
Wait, no, this isn't the room.
Are you seeing this?
There's something seriously
fucked up here.
Who draw this shooot?
The girl that was chained
to the bed
said that there was
somebody here.
That's another one
of your games.
Who the flap would make
something like this up?
Know what, Robbie?
I'm done with you.
Look, you can't leave me.
Why not? You obviously
don't believe me.
Just in case this is real.
Who would make up
something like this?
All I'm saying is between all
this stuff, my mind is a haze.
- We need to find that girl.
- Wait.
No, no, no, this wasn't
the right graffiti.
- It's an upper floor?
- Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, the stairs, yeah.
You said you saw
open cans of food,
that can give us an idea
of who's in here.
Ok, I saw, I saw...
I saw two cans of food
a spoon, and a table.
[loud bang]
Someone's coming,
someone's coming, Art!
Who's there?
Hey, I don't know
who that is, but...
there's a lot of us,
so don't try anything stupid.
shooot, it's Bella!
What happened? Are you ok?
He killed him, killed him!
What are you talking about?
Santa killed Cutler.
What are you saying?
A guy in a flaping Santa's mask
killed Cutler.
- You're kidding, right?
- Where did it happen?
On the second floor,
he killed him.
We must get the flap out
of here.
Ok, just breathe, Bella,
calm down.
I can't calm down.
No way, this has to be a trick.
No, we need to get
the flap out of here now.
And leave Cutler behind,
especially if he's hurt?
He's dead!
There's nothing we can do,
if we don't get out
we'll be the next ones.
flap that, I'm gonna find him,
I won't leave my friend behind.
I'm coming with you.
- Are you coming?
- You wanna show us where?
I can't.
Wow, that's fucked, Bella,
real fucked.
I gotta go find him myself.
Don't leave me, please,
don't leave me.
I'm sorry, Bella.
flap!
flap, flap!
I think this is the floor.
I think it's this way.
Right behind you.
[child whispering]
Deck the halls.
Tis the season to be jolly.
That's the room.
- That's the room right there.
- Stay behind me.
There's no one in here.
Wait, no, she was there!
No, no, no,
there was someone right here!
There was a girl right here
and blood.
And I dropped
my lantern right there!
This is one of your...
No, I swear, Robbie,
this is not a game.
Look, there's chains on the bed!
I don't know it's probably,
this is an old place
No, no, I'm telling you, Robbie,
there is seriously something
fucked up going on here.
Let's find the others
and get out of here.
No, no, no, I am telling you
the truth.
I'm done with this.
[door squeaking]
No, this just doesn't
make any sense.
I don't know how she could've
gone out that room.
Where the flap
is everybody else?
The same place as
your imaginary friend.
My god, this is so crazy.
Oh, by the way,
good idea to play hide and seek
in a place like this.
Are you kidding me?
I'm not the one who decides
to come in here to play
the adventurer or explorer
or whatever
this stupid game's called.
Oh, now you decide
to say no to something.
What's that supposed to mean?
Know what?
Whatever, I don't care.
Help me find my friends,
and get the hell out of here.
[bells jingling]
Seems like some kind of joke.
A kind of Cutler mind flap.
I know what I saw, Art, I'll
never forget that flaping mask.
- Clear.
- God, I can't even...
I need to see it for myself.
Call me skeptical, but a guy
in a flaping Santa mask?
Why the hell
did you make us come in here?
Clear.
I didn't make you do shooot.
I don't have to play the game.
flap you, Art, you're a real
piece of work, you know?
Yeah, takes one to know one,
right?
Can we stop fighting?
Kate, I wouldn't get
in the middle of this.
Art and I have history
of hating each other.
Yes, better to be a by-stand
than it is to be in the way.
Yeah, Art likes
to manipulate things because
he's the flaping king.
I learned it
from a bitch or two.
God, just make it out of here.
- Once we find Cutler.
- And everyone else.
Oh, man.
What the fu...
[loud screams]
[bells jingling]
- Oh my god.
- Jesus flap.
There's no other way out
of this room.
♪ Lean your ear this way ♪
♪ Don't you tell a single soul ♪
♪ What I'm going to say ♪
♪ Christmas Eve is coming soon ♪
♪ Now, you dear old man ♪
[heavy door knocking]
We have to find a way out.
flap, we have
to get out of here.
[Kate]
Quick, help me move this.
Oh my god.
We can't go back out there,
he's flaping there.
Windows, we can go out
the windows.
Great idea, Kate,
let's jump 40 feet, flap!
Ok, help me move this!
[heavy door knocking]
[Bella]
Why is this happening?
Bella, shut the flap up,
find something to fight with.
There's two of us and one of him
and we are not going down
without a fight, now go!
Wait.
Did you hear that?
[heavy door knocking]
It's coming from this floor.
We need to grab something
to fight with.
[heavy door knocking]
How's this?
Yeah, that's good.
Let's go.
[heavy door knocking]
Wait.
It stopped.
I think he was down there.
He's got us here.
He's close.
Keep your head on a swivel.
[child whispering]
Whisper what you'll bring to me.
[Kate] I'm going to die
in this flaping room!
Jesus Christ, Bella,
pull yourself together!
Wait, Robbie, Robbie.
Did you hear that?
[Margo] Wait.
The door.
[Robbie] It's probably where
those screams came from.
[Kate] I won't flaping die
in this room, flaping die!
flap, flap, flap!
[Bella] Don't open!
[Margo] Wait, Kate?
Bella, is that you?
It's Margo, it's Margo!
Do not let her in!
What?
[Margo]
Guys, this is us, let us in!
- Bella, we have to...
- He could be using her, Kate.
Do not let her in.
[Robbie]
Guys, are you in there?
Are you ok?
Robbie is out there too.
Robbie could be flaping Santa!
- Do not let her in.
- Bella, I'm opening the door.
flap, yeah, sure, just kill us.
That's flaping great!
- Oh my god!
- Come here, come here!
What happened?
He flaping killed Cutler!
- Who, me?
- Art, too, Art's dead too.
What the flap are you saying?
I didn't kill anybody.
Cutler and Art are dead?
Oh my god!
No, no he was with me.
Bella, he was with me
the whole time.
Who the flap killed Cutler
and who killed Art?
Some flaping freak
with a Santa mask.
A Santa mask, really?
There was a girl
on the fifth floor,
she was chained,
blood all over the bed
and she said somebody
is in here.
That explains the cans of food
I found in the kitchen.
I'm telling you there was a hobo
serial killer rapist in here!
So, so fucked.
We have to phone the police.
We can't call the police, Margo.
There's no flaping service
in this hick town.
We need to get the flap
out of here, then!
Where are the car keys?
Cutler.
I am not going back there!
Ok, someone has to or we are not
getting out of here.
flap, you three stay together.
I'll go get the keys,
where's Cutler?
Down the hall,
in one of the last rooms.
I'm going with you,
there's a killer on the loose,
you can't go alone.
You can't leave us in here,
it's a death trap.
Why don't you meet us in
the kitchen, where we came in.
We'll get the keys
and meet you there.
We're coming down with you and
we'll split in the staircase.
Ok, let's go.
[panting]
[child whispering]
Deck the halls.
[door squeaking]
[Robbie]
What the flap?
[keys rattling]
It's clear.
[Kate] Come on, stay close.
It's just at the end
of this hallway, ok?
Ok, let's go.
Wait, wait, wait.
We'll see you downstairs, ok?
You're going to be ok?
I think so,
just please be quick.
[Kate] As quick as we can be.
Please, do.
Does this seem strange?
How do you know this is not
a fucked-up game?
Why would they do that?
Are you kidding?
These people
are completely narcissistic.
All they do is get fucked up
and play these stupid games.
I thought you liked them
as roommates!
Better than being alone,
but doesn't mean I like this.
Ok, this isn't a game, Robbie.
How do you know that?
I saw Art get killed!
Yeah, how he died?
I mean... I don't know.
So you never actually
saw him die?
No, but...
And you never saw
Cutler die either?
You just took Bella's word.
Yeah, but did you see the look...
Are you kidding me?
This is to flap
with the newbies!
What about the cans?
I saw them with my own eyes.
Oh, yeah?
Maybe there was a hobo around,
that doesn't mean there's
some flaping psycho killer!
Until I see flaping evidence,
I don't believe shooot.
We're about to find out,
we're here.
Moment of truth.
Oh my god.
Oh, shooot.
- See?
- Oh my god, this isn't a game.
Of course not, people
don't die playing games!
We need to find the keys
and get the flap out of here.
- So, so fucked.
- I'm not finding anything.
There's no keys,
no wallet, nothing.
Oh, god, I'm sorry,
I'm so, so sorry.
Where is his backpack?
I don't see it.
God dammit,
the killer probably took it!
What do we do?
Ok, we need to calm, focus,
and come up with another plan.
[heavy footsteps]
The kitchen's
through there, wait.
Can we wait in the hallway?
I don't want to get trapped,
it'll be easy to find us.
And the killer, we should just
get the flap out of here.
What about Kate and Robbie?
It's not safe in here, Margo.
We can't just leave them.
flap them, I don't know them.
Are you for real right now?
Margo, there's a killer
on the loose,
we need
to get the flap out of here.
And go where?
Anywhere.
No, that's not right.
It wasn't right to come here.
Yeah, we're here now, ok?
We're not just leaving them,
we're in the middle of nowhere,
- it's pitch black and freezing.
- Shush.
Where are you gonna go?
Who the flap cares?
Just get the flap out of here.
The kitchen's there.
No, Bella, I've told you,
I'm not leaving them.
I can't go alone
You're stuck here, doesn't it?
Oh my god, don't do this to me.
You know what, Bella?
You do you.
I hate you.
Oh my god, why?
Why is this happening?
Why they killed Cutler?
What the flap is going on?
Hey.
Everything is going to be ok.
We're gonna get out of here,
I promise.
Okay.
[loud screams]
You hear that?
We need to find Bella and Margo
and get out of here.
Hurry!
[loud screams]
[indistinct yelling]
This way, this way!
[Bella] This way.
[Bella] Check in there.
[panting]
[sobbing]
Bella, Bella?
Bella!
I can't open the door!
Stop, I can't!
Bella!
[screams]
Stop, stop it!
I can't, I can't, stop!
Stop, my god, stop!
I can't, I can't.
Please, please!
[screams]
[Margo yelling]
Bella!
Oh my god, he's here!
Stop!
[loud screams]
flap you!
No, no!
[panting]
Please, please, please!
[gasping for air]
Where are they?
What the flap?
Ok, the screams came
from that way.
No, I'm done with this.
I don't know these people
and neither do you.
flap, flap!
flap this shooot.
Margo?
[heartbeat]
Bella?
Margo, where are you?
[pounding heartbeat]
[bells jingling]
[muffled screams]
[owl screeching]
Holy shooot.
[squish]
[groaning]
flap, flap, flap!
[bells jingling]
flap, flap.
[loud scream]
♪ Jolly old Saint Nicholas ♪
♪ Lean your ear this way ♪
♪ Don't you tell a single soul ♪
♪ What I'm going to say ♪
♪ Christmas Eve is coming soon ♪
♪ Now, you dear old man ♪
♪ Whisper what
you'll bring to me ♪
♪ Tell me if you can ♪
flap you, flap you
you flaping weirdo.
Oh, I wasn't the freak?
Art? But I saw you die.
What the flap, I saw you die!
But did you really?
What the...
[loud screams]
What's wrong with you?
I told you I loved you
and you...
threw it in my face.
Made me the body of jokes
then paraded your relationship
with Cutler
in front of me
like I didn't matter.
You flaping kill everyone.
I just wanted you and Cutler
but your friends keep
getting in the way.
You're going to rot in hell!
I've got a while, but you
keep it warm for me down there.
[squelch]
Oh my god, oh my god!
Oh, oh my god!
You're the tree guy!
Thank you, thank you!
No, please don't, please don't.
You were right when you said
I was creepy.
[difficult breathing]
Oh, I like this.
Thanks, buddy.
[weak scream]
♪ Jolly old Saint Nicholas ♪
♪ Lean your ear this way ♪
♪ Don't you tell a single soul ♪
♪ What I'm going to say ♪
♪ Christmas Eve is coming soon ♪
♪ Now, you dear old man ♪
♪ Whisper
What you'll bring to me ♪
♪ Tell me if you can ♪
Merry Christmas.
[heavy breathing
through the mask]
[child whispering]
We wish you a Merry Christmas.