Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Fa-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la
'Tis the season to be jolly
Fa-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la
Don we now our gay apparel
Fa-la-la, la-la-la
La-la-la
Troll the ancient Yuletide carol
Fa-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la
Whoa!
Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Ha-ha. There must be much,
much more holly.
'Tis the season to be...
What's this? There's too much holly.
Whoa! Slow down, lad.
Don we now our gay apparel
No, no, no, no more mistletoe.
Chip, away from
those presents, dear.
Mama, I found one for me!
Can I open it, Mama? Can I?
-Well, just one.
-Oh, boy!
It's good to see the boy
having a proper Christmas.
Not like last year.
Yes.
This is much more agreeable.
Well, I thought last year
was quite nice.
Yes, well, I suppose I...
I did manage to save Christmas.
-You?
-Yes, me.
If not for my skillful
and decisive leadership,
all would've been lost.
Leadership? Ha!
You could not lead a horse to water.
What are you yammering about?
It was all my idea.
Your idea?
Everyone knows it was mine.
Heavens. How many times are
we going to have to go over this story?
-Story?
-Until someone gets his facts straight.
-Why don't you tell it, Mama?
-Capital idea.
Well, I don't know.
Come now, Mrs. Potts.
Surely you recall
how I saved Christmas.
Tut-tut-tut-tut. No leading the witness.
Please, Mama, tell the story.
Oh, all right.
Ah! Now we will hear
what really happened.
Well, let's see.
Belle, terrified by the master's anger,
ran away from the castle
straight into a pack of wolves.
But the master saved her.
They began to be friends.
Ah-ah-ah.
That's where l came in.
Where could he be?
Goodness knows.
We've searched every last corner.
I'm beginning to think
he's not in the castle at all.
Voilà! There he is!
-Wonderful!
-No time to waste.
We must find a way
to get them together.
Let's go! Love will not wait.
You really think she's the one?
Will she break the spell?
I knew it from the moment
I set eyes on her.
If anyone can reach the master,
Belle can. Such a kind soul.
And her looks
don't hurt either.
Wait for me!
-Hi, Belle.
-Oh, hello.
Chip, do you know what day it is?
Well, it's not Tuesday...
No, silly. Today is December 24th.
-The day before Christmas.
-And what a beautiful day it is.
A wonderful day for a morning stroll.
Yes, yes. Nothing starts the day
like a brisk walk around the grounds.
Yeah!
Or you could go ice-skating.
-Ha-ha. Wahoo!
-Yes, fresh air, exercise. Ha-ha.
-In moderation, of course.
Come along, Belle, dear.
The great outdoors awaits.
Yeah, let's go!
Oh. Good morning.
Huh? Whoa...
Oh, dear. Are you all right?
Uh... Uh...
I fell and I landed on my...
On... On the ice.
It's pretty slippery.
Yes, it's slippery.
This is a perfect day for skating.
Come on.
Hmm?
No.
-Go on, Master. It might be fun.
-Go for it!
Hmm. Hmm?
Come on!
Not so fast.
Ooo-ooo la-la.
Come on. Why don't you try it like this?
One, two, three. One, two, three.
See? It's easy.
One, two, three.
Ho-ho-ho.
Yes, I think this may work.
Bravo! Bravo! Encore!
Fife, you approve?
Oh, Maestro, it's magnificent!
Oh, come along. It's merely an opera
to bring the house down.
-Ooh!
Is there a part for a piccolo?
Absolutely.
Solo for Fife in B-flat.
-Ooh. I'd do anything for a solo.
-Yes.
I know. Now, Fifey,
in the midst of my crescendo,
I thought I heard merriment
outside the window.
Have a little look-see, will you?
Wow! Would you look at that?
Well, I think I might.
I'll just pick myself up and...
Oh!
What's this? Heavens, look.
I'm bolted to the wall!
Oh, right.
Um, the master is skating.
Skating? Why on earth
would he do a thing like that?
Probably because that
pretty girl is holding his hand.
-What? Belle?
-Hey.
Maybe if she falls in love with him,
the spell will be broken,
and we'll be human again!
Trust me, Fife.
-Humanity is entirely overrated.
Before the enchantment,
there was no need
for my particular brand of genius.
But now the master needs my melodies
to feed his tormented soul.
I am his confidant
and his best friend.
And I won't let some peasant girl
ruin it for me!
Fife, see to it that this blossoming love
withers on the vine.
Yes, Maestro Forte.
One, two, three.
One, two, three. One, two, three.
I think I've got it!
Hey, down in front. I wanna see.
Let me see. I wanna see, too!
Shh!
Quiet. Oh, this is very promising.
Ah, yes, there is something in the air.
-Could it be love?
Love? Oh, oh, oh, ooh.
Uh. Oh. Oh.
I've got to stop them.
Oh!
Help!
Whoa-oh-oh-oh!
What's that little toot up to?
Whoa!
Mmm-mmm.
Stop!
It's a Christmas angel, see?
Oh.
This is no angel.
It's the shadow of a monster.
Oh, Forte is going to be so proud of me.
I don't know why I bother.
Now he's worse than ever.
Don't lose heart, dearest.
I hate Christmas.
The music helps?
Your music is the only thing
that helps me forget.
Don't worry, old friend.
I'm here for you,
just as I have been,
just as I always will be.
Why is the beast such a grump?
I don't know. He's always like that.
-Even at Christmas?
-Yep.
Belle, what's Christmas?
Oh, Chip, you must know
about Christmas.
Stockings in front of the fire? Tree?
Tinsel? Presents?
Presents? Do I get one?
Of course. Everyone gets
a present on Christmas.
-Oh, even the master?
-Yes, even the master.
-What are you gonna get him?
-I don't really know him well enough
to know what he would want.
-What would you want?
-Well, what I love most
in the world are my books, my stories.
Why don't you get the master a story?
You're right, Chip. A story.
When l get to know him
We'll find more things to say
One day I wiII reach him
There has to be a way
Everyone needs someone
He must need someone, too
When l get to know him better
Here's what l will do
l'll read him stories
From picture books
all filled with wonder
Magic worlds where the impossible
Becomes the everyday
We'll find a mountaintop
And some moonbeams to sit under
l'll lead because l know the way
So much to discover
l do it all the time
l could live inside bright pages
Where the words all rhyme
We will slay the dragons
That still follow him around
And he'll smile
Yes, he'll smile
As his dreams leave the ground
Stories and stories
About mermaids, kings
and sunken treasure
Magic worlds where the impossible
Becomes the everyday
l know a tiny place
Just a dot too small to measure
l'll take him there
l know the way
Stories about heroes
Who overcame their deepest sorrow
They'll put hope into his heart again
He'll cherish every day
He'll find a better world
And the strength to face tomorrow
l'm sure that
when he knows the way
He'll want
To stay
Do you think the master
will like his gift?
I do.
So does this mean
we're gonna have a Christmas?
Uh-huh. Absolutely.
Absolutely not.
Why not?
Out of the question. Not a chance.
Dream on. An impossibility. Forget it.
Come on!
-Suck in that gut.
-Mon ami. Get with the spirit. Unwind.
-Oh, dear.
-Come on, love. Have a heart.
Yeah. Come on.
-No, no, and... Let me think...
-Uh-huh? Uh-huh?
-No!
This is where I put my foot down.
Wait. Get out of...
The master has forbidden Christmas!
-Oh, dear.
Forbid Christmas?
No one can forbid Christmas.
He doesn't wish
to be reminded of his past,
and Christmas is
a most painful reminder of it.
I, for one, do not wish to torture him.
I, for one, think a little Christmas
cheer would do him some good.
-Yeah.
-Oh? Hmm.
The girl is right.
It is up to us to do something.
Gosh! It's not our place
to get involved.
No, no, no, no! We just can't
mind our own beeswax, can we?
Just have to stick our wick
where it doesn't belong.
Whoa!
-Oh, humiliating.
-Pish posh.
I think it's a wonderful idea.
But the master doesn't want it.
His castle, his rules.
It's not fair.
He's right. It's not fair!
Don't whine, glasses.
Sorry.
Look at us,
squabbling and bickering.
Breaks my heart to see it, it does.
And we used to be at our very best
at Christmas.
Why, we used to prepare
a feast for the entire castle.
Ah! You could have
some stuffed turkey.
-Cranberry sauce.
-Shortbread cookies.
Mince pies.
Potatoes.
-Gravy.
-And Christmas pudding!
Uh, pudding? With... With custard?
What do you think we are, barbarians?
Of course with custard.
-And raisins and brandy,
-and all those things you like.
Ohh. Oh, I...
-All right.
-Yes!
But if the master finds out about this,
he will be furious,
so, everybody, keep quiet.
Come on!
What are we waiting for, Christmas?
Good heavens, we don't have
much time. It's Christmas Eve!
-I'll see to the dinner.
-I'll get some mistletoe.
We need to brighten this place up.
Belle, I know someone who will help.
Now, now, wait for me.
I'm in charge here. I'm in charge.
Wait for me!
One-thousand one,
one-thousand two,
one-thousand three...
-Are we there yet?
-Not yet.
Oh, boy, there sure
are a lot of stairs here.
One-thousand seven,
one-thousand eight,
one-thousand nine, one-thousand ten...
Hello?
Do not be afraid, mes amis.
It is I, Lumiere.
We have come to pay you a little visit.
-Lumiere?
-Angelique.
-Ah, Lumiere, finally.
I thought we were to be locked away
in this dusty attic forever.
Ah, Angelique, mon amour.
Your eyes are still so lovely
after all these years.
Lumiere, please!
You'll tarnish the halo.
Oh, yes. This is Belle, our guest.
-Pleased to meet you.
-And this is Angelique.
She is the castle decorator.
You mean was the castle decorator.
I am not responsible
for this baroque atrocity.
When I was in charge,
the castle was full of light and beauty.
But, chérie,
that is why we have come.
Gather around, mes enfants.
-We are planning the greatest
Christmas celebration ever.
No, stop!
-What is it, chérie?
Why do you raise my hopes...
I... I mean, their hopes...
Only to have them dashed?
Well, no more.
But it's Christmas Eve.
Without you, we'll never get
the castle decorated in time.
Ha! Christmas? Hmph!
I refuse to hope for it anymore.
I will not be disappointed again.
But this is to be
the greatest celebration ever.
We cannot do it without you.
Well, but of course you cannot.
Christmas takes planning
and organization.
No. No, I won't do it.
It won't change anything.
I believe it will.
There is more to
This time of year
Than sleigh bells and holly
Mistletoe and snow
Those things come and go
Much deeper than snow
Stronger than the strongest Iove
we'll know
We'll ever know
As Iong as there's Christmas
l truly believe
That hope is the greatest
Of the gifts we'II receive
As Iong as there's Christmas
We'll all be just fine
A star shines above us
Lighting your way and mine
Just as Iong as there's Christmas
there wiII be Christmas pud
Tons of turkey
And cranberry sauce and mince pies
if we're good
-Lots of logs on the fire
-Lots of gifts on the tree
All wrapped up in red ribbons
Wonder if there's one for me
We're due for a party
Where on earth do we start
l may wear my tiara
you bought me in Montmartre
All the silver will sparkle
And the china will gleam
And we'll be as shiny
as a brand-new centime
-After dinner we'll play games
-Till the morning breaks through
Then we'll meet in the garden
-This is what we shall do
-We will build
We will build a snowman
that'll reach to the sky
lt will stay up until July
What are you doing? Stop, stop, stop.
Put me down. Put me down.
This is ridiculous.
Everyone knows that
the lights go on first.
I don't want to go
all the way up there on the top.
As Iong as there's Christmas
l truly believe
That hope is the greatest
Of the gifts we'II receive
As Iong as there's Christmas
We'll all be just fine
There'II aIways be Christmas
So there aIways wiII be a time
When the world
ls filled with peace
And warmth
We're gonna have
the greatest Christmas ever.
Oh, I hope so, Chip.
You on the left,
you on the right, follow me.
-There is decorating to be done.
Yes, yes, yes, yes. But keep in mind,
the master mustn't find out.
Ooh, yes.
Christmas?
She's planning Christmas?
Yes. Awful, isn't it?
Perhaps she doesn't know
how I feel about Christmas.
-But she does know.
-Hmm?
She just doesn't care like I do.
She's actually trying to bring
Christmas back to the castle.
And you know how much
we despise Christmas.
The day my life ended.
-Bring me my presents!
-Your Highness,
please accept this humble gift
as a token of our appreciation.
I know I speak for everyone when...
Ah, just give it to me!
A storybook? You call this a present?
I hope you have something
better for me, Forte.
Yes, sir. Of course, master.
What is that?
Um, a small piece in your honor, master.
Ew! I hate it.
Forte, that stuff is gloomy.
Who disturbs my Christmas?
Please, take this rose
in exchange for shelter
from the bitter cold.
I don't need a rose.
Go away, you wretched old hag!
You have been deceived
by your own cold heart.
A curse upon your house
and all within it.
Until you have found one
to love you as you are,
you shall remain forever a beast.
But we've come so far since then.
We've risen above the tragedy.
Where is she?
I believe she's gone to the boiler room,
or so, a little birdie told me.
Tweet, tweet, tweet.
Oh!
Aah!
Hey, hey, hey. Come on.
Get out of the way.
-We're workin' here.
-Excuse me.
-Let's go. Let's go.
All right, you guys.
Now, get back to work.
The castle doesn't heat itself,
you know.
So, what can I do you for, lady?
-I'm looking for a log.
-All right. Logs we got.
What do you want? Hard wood?
Soft wood? We got it all.
We got birch, maple, pine, oak...
- Concrete.
-My head. Don't worry. It'll pass.
So, make up your mind already.
Is it all right if I just browse?
Suit yourself. Take your time.
Me, I got work to do.
Huh.
Hmm.
-Whew.
Hey, what am I payin' you for,
being boring?
Do that on your own time.
Get out of here!
Yes.
Oh!
What are you hiding?
It's a Yule log.
Huh?
A... A Yule log.
It's a wonderful tradition.
One log is chosen and everyone
in the house touches it
and makes a Christmas wish.
Mmm, wishes are stupid.
You made a Christmas wish last year.
Is this what you wished for?
No.
But I will keep wishing.
And when the log is burned
on Christmas morning...
There will be no Christmas.
-But...
-No! I am the master here.
How can you be so selfish?
You cannot possibly understand.
You have no idea
what it's like to lose everything,
to be trapped in your own castle,
to be a... A... A...
Prisoner?
The only one holding us prisoner here
is you.
Well, I'm not giving up.
Prisoner.
Hiya, Belle.
You should see the ballroom.
It's all decorated and pretty
and there's garlands everywhere.
I think the master's gonna
be really excited
when he finds out about Christmas.
Well, he... He already knows.
Really? Was he excited?
Actually, Chip, he's forbidden it.
But I thought
he couldn't forbid Christmas.
You know, Chip, he can't.
We'll have Christmas
with or without him.
Hurray! Can we get a tree now, Belle?
It's the only thing we're missing.
All right, then. Let's go get a tree.
But first...
Shh.
Psst, Belle.
The master. Hurry.
What about this one?
Mmm...
Mmm.
Nah, too skinny. Come on.
Ooo la-la.
-Ohh, Lumiere.
-She's beautiful, no?
Yes, and I'm hideous.
Not to mention
ill-tempered.
What? What is that?
Ooh, it looks like a Christmas present.
Oh-ho-ho. It's for you, master.
It's from a girl.
-Mrs. Potts?
-No. From Belle.
Belle?
Uh-uh-uh. Master, you can't open it.
Well, why not? It's for me, isn't it?
Because it's not yet Christmas.
Master, we all understand
how you feel about Christmas.
But when a woman gives a man a gift,
she's saying, "I care about you."
Hmm.
But I don't have a gift for her.
It is not too late.
Well, I guess I could
get her a little something.
Forte, stop the noise!
Noise? Noise?
This is my masterpiece.
Master.
I... I want you to compose a song.
-It's a present for Belle.
-What? Belle?
And make it happy!
Oh, but happiness is so depressing.
What's next? Love songs?
Wedding marches?
It's all that girl's fault.
What about this one?
-Hmm, too wiggly.
-Too wiggly.
Fife!
Pay attention.
I need you to pace when I think.
The girl is evil, I tell you.
She pulls him from my grasp.
She fills his head with dreams of love
and hope and Christmas!
Well, what you gonna do?
You can't stop Christmas.
No, but I can stop the girl.
Chip, this is the last one.
That's not it. That's just a weed
wishing it was a tree.
Chip, we've looked
at every tree on the grounds.
But it's more this way than that.
It will have to do.
-What a headache I have.
-I'm sorry.
I... I'll get a saw.
No, that's fine.
I don't want I should put you out.
Oh, all right.
Do you have some oil?
I just thought a little massage...
But if it's no, it's no. Go on.
What are you waiting for?
Knock yourself out.
You never get headaches, I guess.
Lucky you.
-Really, I can get a saw.
-Who wants a saw?
I said go ahead with the whacking
and the hitting. Who's stopping you?
-Shh.
What is that?
Ohh.
It's beautiful.
And now for a little Fife.
Sultan, wait!
Don't worry yourself about me.
I'll just sit here. Snow is fine.
A little wet, but who's complaining?
Yes, my dear. Come to me.
Come here, boy. Come here.
-Good doggy. Nice doggy.
Sultan?
Back off, doggy.
Oh.
Hello?
Well, maybe there's nobody here.
Maybe we should go.
What's the matter, Sultan?
Oh, hello. I don't believe we've met.
I... I'm Belle.
-And you are?
-Fife.
-Down, boy, down.
We heard the most beautiful music.
-Was it you?
-Me?
You thought that was me?
Mademoiselle, please.
I am Maestro Forte,
court composer
and your most humble servant.
Pleased to meet you, Monsieur Forte.
I'm Belle.
Yes. The entire castle is talking
about you, child.
They say you're planning
a Christmas gala. Marvelous idea.
The very thing to shatter
the master's dark and gloomy past.
But you must make this
the grandest celebration ever.
-Have you gifts?
-Yep.
-Food?
-Garlands, ribbons, wreaths?
-Check.
Spangles and "fandangles"?
The trinkets, the trimmings,
the trappings?
-Yep, we got 'em all.
-A tree?
See, Belle? I told you.
Well, we found one.
But it was on the piddlin' side of puny.
But did you look in the Black Forest?
There you will find a tree
better than any you can dream of.
Better? We gotta go, Belle!
-We gotta!
-Chip, we can't.
I... I promised your master
I wouldn't leave the castle grounds.
I gave my word.
Chin up, son.
There's a profound lesson here.
Keeping your word is much more
important than bringing joy to another.
You're twisting what I said.
Not at all. I agree with you.
Look after yourself.
Let the master do the same.
Never mind that the tree
was always his favorite part
of Christmas.
Please, Belle? Please?
It looks dangerous.
Mademoiselle,
you are in more danger
in this very room, I assure you.
All right.
-Yes!
-We'll take Phillippe.
If we hurry, we can be back by nightfall.
-Hurray!
-Au revoir, Monsieur Forte.
You'll keep my secret, won't you?
Of course, mademoiselle.
The master will remain
completely in the dark.
Au revoir, Fife.
Fife! I want you to follow her.
Make sure they don't come back.
Oh, yeah, but, Maestro, she's so nice.
When you're finished fawning, Fife,
perhaps you can recommend
someone else to play your solo.
No! I'm going. I'm going.
-Cogsworth!
-Oh, dear. Yes. Coming. Coming.
Cogsworth!
Running, running. Almost there.
You bellowed, sir?
Find Belle. I... Uh...
Well, I...
She has to hear a song.
Yes, sir. Right away, sir. Uh, yes.
Splendid. Yes, well... Splendid.
Ho-ho-ho-ho-ho-ho.
Belle. Belle?
Where is she? Belle?
Careful, careful.
Too fast! Get out of the way! Stop!
Huh!
Amateurs.
Belle? Here... Excuse me. Hello?
Has anyone seen Belle?
I can't find her anywhere.
And the master is demanding
to see her now.
-He's got a song he wants her to hear.
-Ho-ho.
Last I saw of her, she was going
with Chip to look for a Christmas tree.
Right. We must conduct
a search of the grounds.
-Lumiere, you're with me.
-Cogsworth!
I'm waiting!
Oh, dear. Running, running, running.
I'm almost there, sir.
Mrs. Potts, stall the master.
All right, Lumiere, we're...
Lumiere? Wait, I'm leading.
Me first, you second.
Belle! Belle! Where is she?
Belle? Belle?
Belle, where are you?
Lumiere, wait.
Hmm?
The Black Forest!
Come along. Hurry now!
Oh, no.
This is catastrophic!
Cogsworth, quit dawdling.
I'm not dawdling. I'm waddling.
Well, don't waddle then.
We're in a hurry, you lazy old clock.
Hmm? Hmm?
Why am I still waiting?
-Mrs. Potts!
-Coming, sir! Coming!
What a brisk day!
Why, you look positively chilled
to the bone.
Where's Belle?
How about a nice cup of tea, sir?
Just a spot.
Hmm.
Forte, play Belle's song!
Hot.
You're not singing!
Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Fa-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la
Louder!
'Tis the season
A bit more tea, sir?
Good for the heart, you know.
No, thank you.
-Just a spot?
-No more.
-Well, there's always room for tea, love.
-I said, "No more."
-Oh, dearie me!
-Mrs. Potts,
are you trying to distract me?
Goodness, no, sir.
Heavens. Is that a yellow-bellied,
double-breasted sapsucker?
-Rare this time of year.
-Enough! Where's Cogsworth?
-Where's Belle?
-Belle?
We can't find her, sir.
What?
Leave me!
Show me the girl.
-I will bring her back!
-No!
Um, she's abandoned you.
-Listen to your old friend, won't you?
Have I ever steered you wrong?
Led you astray?
No. But the girl...
The quickest way
to break your heart
Make you depressed and ill
ls to get tangled up inside
The side effects could kill
All passion is a waste of time
A deadly game pour vous
l am your friend
Your cher ami
l wouldn't lie to you
lf you must love someone
may l suggest
You love yourself
Just think it through
You'll never leave
and you will find you'll get more rest
You'll always feel
as good as new
Your freedom is the most
important thing, my friend
You must be strong
You mustn't bend
Don't talk for hours
Don't send flowers
Don't write poems
Don't sing songs and dance
Beneath the stars
that shine above
Don't fall in love
-Oh, don't do it.
Oh!
As soon as your heart
rules your head
Your life is not your own
lt's hell when someone's always there
lt's bliss to be alone
And love of any kind is bad
A dog, a child, a cat
They take up so much precious time
Now, where's the sense in that
Love takes the wildest heart
and makes it tame
lf you're turned on
then just turn off
Emotions are a thing
all great men overcame
Please, don't make
this grande catastrophe
Don't get attached
to anyone or anything
There's nothing worse
than things that cling
You'll go to pot
You'll turn to drink
You'll never rest
You'll end up mad
And looking like
some poor demented dove
Don't fall in love
Don't fall in love!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
They cannot mix bells with holly.
Still, I have to admit,
not bad for amateurs.
I knew this was hopeless.
There. That's it! That's it!
Oh, Chip, it's perfect.
-Do you see her?
-Not yet. Now, come along. Hurry!
-You go on. I'll never make it.
Save yourself.
Ah, it will be summer
before we reach them.
What the... Whoa!
Oh, dear!
Faster! Faster!
I think we finally found a use for you.
Clock boarding! No, snow clocking!
Whatever!
Whoo!
Whoa!
-It's the best tree ever!
-Chip, you're right.
Merry Christmas!
And a happy Hanukkah!
We better hurry.
It's getting very stormy.
Again with the chopping.
Oh, I gotta do something.
Forte's counting on me.
Timber!
Phew!
Take it away, Phillippe!
Whoo!
Whoa!
Oh, no!
Aah! Aah! Aaah!
Fife?
Uh, hi, Belle.
Nice tree.
What are you doing way out here?
Uh, nothin'. I just was walkin'.
I mean, I love the bitter cold. I mean...
Hee, hee!
Phillippe!
Oh, no!
The tree, Belle!
We're gonna lose the tree!
Whoa!
Chip! Oh!
Where is he?
Whoa! Whoa!
Oh!
-Hold on, chérie. I will save you!
-Oh, dear!
Oh, no. Oh, gosh. Oh, no.
Oh, gosh. Oh, no. Oh, gosh.
Oh, no!
-Oh, Chip, thank goodness you're safe.
-I wasn't scared.
Oh, no! No!
Belle!
Oh, no, what have I done?
It's all my fault.
We all share some blame, mon ami,
for daring to hope for a Christmas.
You said you'd never leave.
I wasn't trying to leave.
I just wanted to make you happy.
You broke your word.
And for that, you will rot
in this dungeon forever.
I should have known
you'd never be anything but a beast.
Midnight.
Merry Christmas, Cogsworth.
If only it were.
Oh, my dear old friend,
I told you not to feel for her.
Things were so much simpler
before she came along,
before we dared to hope.
Oh, I thought she was the one.
Belle?
There she is.
-Merry Christmas.
-Doesn't look so special to me.
Oh, Chip, I'm sorry.
Nothing's changed.
I told you nothing would change.
I told you the master
would not allow this.
I told you
Christmas was a hopeless folly!
But
I was wrong.
When l felt lost
And lonely
Not a dream in my head
Your words lifted my spirits
High
Remember what
You said
As Iong as there's Christmas
l truly believe
That hope is the greatest
Of the gifts we'II receive
-As long as
Our guiding star
Shines above
There'll always be
Christmas
So there aIways
Will be a time
When the world
is filled with peace
And love
Ah, it tears me up
to see you this way, master.
Why do you torment yourself?
There's the symbol of your curse.
Destroy it, and end
these adolescent notions
of love and redemption.
End your pain forever.
Yes! Do it!
Smash it!
Belle?
What are you doing? What is it?
Oh, a storybook.
Does this one have pretty pictures
you can color?
Utterly dreadful, master.
No! This one's different. It's from Belle.
Well, that would account
for the creative wrapping.
Quiet!
I want to read.
"Once upon a time,
there was an enchanted castle.
"lts master seemed as cold as winter.
Deep inside his heart...
"His cries of anger echoed through
the stone wall of the castle.
"Though surrounded by servants,
he was all alone.
"And in that simple act of kindness,
"he knew someone cared.
"Christmas that year was spent
exchanging humble gifts.
"But the greatest gift
that anyone received
"was the gift of hope."
Hmm.
Hope.
-No, master! Come back!
She'll only prolong your torment!
You know what, Belle? I don't need
a tree to celebrate Christmas.
-And I can do without mistletoe.
-Well, I don't need tinsel.
-Oh, I don't need holly.
-And I don't need a wreath.
-I don't need ornaments!
-And I don't need turkey!
-I don't need stuffing!
I don't need pudding!
To each his own, my friend
You know how to get me stressed
But when it comes to
making Christmas speciaI...
l'm a cut above the rest
lf you could see things clearly
you would say that l've been blessed
You can't hold a candle
to my timing
l'm a cut above the rest
You belong side by side
You should never be apart
'Cause when you're both together
you're really twice as smart
"Twice as smart."
She does have a point.
Yes, well, two heads
are better than one.
They say that as a team
we have got to be the best
Now we found something
we both agree on
We're a cut above the rest
There's no doubt that as a team
we two are the very best
Everyone who knows us must agree
We're a cut above the rest
There's no doubt that as a team
you two are the very best
Everyone who knows you must agree
-We're a cut
-A cut above
Above the rest
Uh-oh! It's the master!
Uh, Belle...
Can you forgive me?
Of course. Merry Christmas.
-All right!
Let's give Belle the Christmas
she's always wanted.
So, Beast gets girl,
and it's a happy ending for everyone.
Enchantment lifted,
and Forte fades into the background.
No longer important. No longer needed.
I think not!
What is it, Mama? What's happening?
Watch out!
Forte!
-Whoa!
-Hurry, now. Hurry.
Can you believe I never took a lesson?
Belle!
-Oh, no!
-Belle!
Help!
Oh, no.
Maestro! Stop!
-What do you think you're doing?
-Don't you see, Fife?
They can't fall in love if they're dead.
I'll tell you what I see.
A big, old windbag!
You could've joined me, Fife,
but I see my triumph is a solo act.
My solo... It's blank!
So naive.
-No! No, no!
-You're second fiddle, Fife,
and that's all you'll ever be.
Forte!
We can remain as we are
forever and ever!
Forte!
Enough!
Heavens! Master.
You're not singing.
Careful.
Oh, no, the bell jar!
-Whoa! Got it. Got it.
-Oh, careful.
Is this happy enough for you, master?
I know I'm downright giddy!
Oh!
Master, the keyboard.
-You got it?
-Got it. Got it.
Whoa!
Help!
No!
Forte.
Oh, yes, it is lovely.
And you said it was impossible.
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
I said it was impossible without me.
-Everyone, shh-shh! Here they come.
-Wow!
The setting is perfect.
Oh, aren't they beautiful?
-It's wonderful!
Hurray!
And what a wonderful Christmas it was.
I suppose if anyone saved Christmas,
it was Belle.
Merry Christmas, one and all!
-Merry Christmas.
-And merry Christmas to you, sir.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, everyone.
I believe we have
a little something for you, Chip.
A present? Oh, boy! Thank you.
Open it!
Look, Mama! A storybook!
Would you read it to me?
-I'd love to, son.
-Oh, boy!
Maestro?
-Yes, master?
-Would you do us the honor, old friend?
I'd be delighted.