Okay, Ellie, I got her.
The Christmas rock.
Just got her
out of storage.
I wanted to surprise Peaches.
Where is our sweet
little angel? Huh?
Incoming!
There's your
sweet little angel.
Sorry, Dad.
Yeah!
It's on!
You guys need
to chill out.
Peaches.
The Christmas rock!
I love it! I love it!
I love it! I love it! I love it!
No, no, no, don't.
Too late.
I'm stuck.
This is the same Christmas rock I had
when I was a kid.
It's an heirloom that's been in our
family for generations.
Tonight when Santa comes by
with his presents,
he'll see this rock and know that
a very special little girl lives here.
♪ Oh, Christmas rock,
oh, Christmas rock
♪ You're 30 tons of granite
And every... ♪
You know you're singing
to a rock, right?
It's a Christmas
tradition for the kids.
Don't sabers have
Christmas traditions?
Oh, yeah!
Every year my dad would bring home
the biggest, fattest gazelles he could find
and then we'd
all rip into their...
...our presents.
And we'd play games
with the gazelles
and dance with them
and not eat them. The end.
Merry Christmas,
my mammals.
Wow!
That's some crazy rock.
Step away from the stone.
Why?
You'll break it.
Sid can't break a rock.
Don't tempt him.
Uncle Sid, we need this
so that Santa can find us tonight.
What, this?
Oh, pfft.
He could go right past it.
You need something
bigger, taller, sparklier.
Something with a pizzazz.
Um, a tree!
A Christmas tree?
Do you know
how ridiculous that sounds?
There's millions of
trees out there, Sid.
How would anyone
notice this one?
Well, we could
decorate it.
Crash, Eddie.
Sweet!
And,  voila!
It does look pretty good.
Ah, it'll never catch on.
It's beautiful.
Hmm. It needs a certain
razzle-dazzle on top.
Something that says Sid.
And just like that,
a tradition is born.
Hey!
Seriously, what did
you think was gonna...
Yep. That says
Sid, all right.
Okay, okay. Let's just
keep it together.
It really is about
the spirit of Christmas, isn't it?
You're about to be
a spirit of Christmas, Sid!
Manny, please.
I'm so sorry.
You know what, Sid,
I'm the least of your worries.
You gotta answer to Santa.
Santa? Santa Claus?
He is never gonna
forgive this.
You just got
yourself on Santa's...
Uh, ah,
Santa's Naughty List.
Santa has a Naughty List?
Yeah! Yeah!
And if you're not good,
then he puts your name on it.
We're never good.
Then why start now?
Well, if your name's
on the Naughty List,
you don't get Christmas.
But no! Why me?
Besides the fact
that it's my fault.
The Naughty List?
Where did you come up with that?
Relax. Sid's gullible
but he's not that gullible.
He knows this Santa
stuff is just for kids.
What? You don't
believe in Santa?
Um, I, well...
Of course, he believes.
That's the magic
of Christmas.
If anyone deserves to be on the
naughty List, Dad, it's you!
She sure told you,
didn't she?
Well, too bad,
I'm a grown-up.
Grown-ups don't believe
in the Naughty List.
I'm not getting Christmas.
Don't cry, Sid.
Why not?
Your tears are
freezing solid.
Why am I on
Santa's Naughty List?
Why? Why?
My guess, because he doesn't
have a loser list.
Well, thanks for
trying to cheer me up.
I still feel terrible.
Pull it together,
Uncle Sid.
We've got work to do.
But I'm still sulking.
No time.
We're going to the Pole.
The North one?
Yep. We're gonna
find Santa
so I can prove to my dad
that he's real.
And we're gonna
get you off that list.
And us, too!
We may be naughty
but we still want Christmas.
Peaches, honey,
you can't come with us.
This is a very
dangerous journey.
The North Pole is a desolate land
of ice and snow.
This isn't exactly Miami.
Come on, Uncle Sid,
I want us all to have
Christmas together.
Hmm. I don't know.
It's wildly irresponsible and impulsive
but let's do it!
Northward, ho!
- Ho ho ho!
Uh, guys, let's
follow the northern lights.
North. Get it?
Northward ho!
Santa ho!
Ho ho ho!
♪ On the ninth day
of Christmas
♪ My true love gave to me
Nine fleas a-biting
♪ Eight pounds of ear wax
♪ Seven frosty fingers
♪ Six frosty fingers
♪ Five rotten... ♪
Eggs?
Huh. I think we just
marched off the Earth.
No, it's a white-out.
We'll be safe
as long as we all...
stay together.
Peaches, where are you?
Uncle Sid?
Peaches?
Huh?
Eddie? Where are you, Eddie?
Oh, wait. I'm Eddie.
Okay, everyone, grab hold of your
buddy and follow me.
I have an excellent
sense of direction.
Wait.
Bless you.
Thank you.
Ha! Did you see
what I just did there?
You're a reindeer.
Yeah, I know.
You can fly!
I know!
You're amazing!
Check it out, Sauerkraut.
I can hover, roll and zing.
Zing?
Zing! Bam!
What's your name?
My name is, um,
uh, Prancer.
Prancer?
It's a family name.
Oh, don't listen to them.
You saved our lives
and we'll never forget you.
Have a merry Christmas.
Are you sure you
don't need my help?
Oh, no thank you.
You've done more than enough.
Look, we'll take
it from here.
The reindeer
comes with us.
Uh, what do you think?
You want an honest answer
or a Christmas answer?
Uh, Christmas answer.
It's gorgeous.
Manny?
Have you seen Peaches?
I can't find her anywhere.
And Sid, Crash and
Eddie are gone, too!
Last I saw them,
they were trying to figure out
how to get off
Santa's Naughty List.
What Naughty List?
I made it up!
We gotta find them.
Diego, can you pick
up Sid's scent?
I can but it makes
my eyes burn.
- Do it!
Got it.
So, Prancer, how long will it
take us to get to the, uh, North Pole?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
You can't walk to the North Pole.
It's too far.
But I can fly you there.
No sweat, on Air Prancer.
Oh, oh, no,
we couldn't.
No, no, no, no.
My family raised me
to be good to strangers and there's
really no one stranger than you guys.
Huh?
Shotgun!
We've run into
a little turbulence, folks.
Please fasten
your seatbelts.
I'm not too heavy, am I?
No, no. You're light
as a feather.
A 788 pound feather.
Do you come
equipped with barf bags?
Peaches! Peaches!
Manny, where's Diego?
Diego! Buddy, are you okay?
Glad you didn't kiss me?
Are you sure this is North?
I don't know. I...
I'm all scrambled.
Wait, tracks!
Uh, Diego?
The geomagnetic whatever,
it's messing with
my sense of direction.
Oh, well,
that's just great!
We're completely lost,
my little girl is missing and...
Manny, honey,
everything's gonna be fine.
How?
Just believe in
the magic of Christmas.
Oh, this is silly.
Just try it.
It's not gonna work.
Do it for Peaches.
I believe.
Manny, look!
The northern lights!
North. Get it?
Um, that was just
a coincidence, right?
Who cares?
I'll take it. Let's go.
We must be getting close.
Sugar plums!
Peppermint bark!
Yellow snow, my favorite!
Don't, just don't.
Halt!
None shall pass.
Oh. Oh, hi, little guy.
So, who are you?
We are the Santourage.
We keep intruders out so Santa can
do his work without interruption.
I knew he was real!
You've gotta let us see him.
It is forbidden!
Turn back, I command you.
Bye!
Oh, yeah?
You and what army?
Oh, that army.
Hasta luego.
Feliz Navidad.
But you gotta let me in.
I'm on the list!
He must not be disturbed
or we won't get presents.
You have been warned.
Unleash heck!
Bring it on,
you little fleabags!
You're no match for the power of...
flight.
Everybody, grab a leg
and pull!
Ow! Huh?
Run!
♪ You better watch out
You better not cry
♪ Better not pout
I'm telling you why
♪ I am coming to town
Yes!
♪ Oh, I'm making a list
And checking it twice ♪
Ah, nutmeg!
Ho ho, no!
Oh.
Sid?
Sid, where's Peaches?
Peaches!
Where are you?
Over here!
Wait, wait.
The reindeer fly up here?
This one does, cuz.
Peaches!
Daddy!
Oh, baby, we were so worried
about you.
Oh, you...
You are so grounded!
Sorry, Daddy.
I'm talking to Sid.
Frolicking fruitcake!
It's Santa!
Just 'cause there's a fat guy,
doesn't make him Santa.
I'm not fat!
It's this suit, it's very poofy.
Manny, it is Santa!
And he's just as
old and decrepit as I imagined.
And, oh, so jolly.
Oh, look at this mess.
Two hours to Christmas
and everything's ruined!
My toys, my sleigh!
All my hard work.
Um, would this be a good time to talk
about getting off the Naughty List?
Sid, there's no such thing.
There is now, Manfred.
Thanks for the idea.
Wait, wait!
How do you know my...
...name?
Santa?
Hey, what did we do?
Ahem.
Oh, right.
Destroyed Christmas.
Peaches, you were...
I mean, I mean, I was...
That's Santa!
Standing right there.
He's real!
Duh!
There's gonna be a lot of disappointed
kids tomorrow morning.
Ow!
There's gotta be
a way to fix this.
Dad, it's impossible!
There's only eight of us.
And 800 of them!
Wait, us?
You mean, as in, us?
You never thought to give the old
fat boy a hand, huh?
Come on, Peach.
You taught me to believe.
What do you say?
Hit it! Ow! Not me!
♪ Deck the halls with
moss and rock weed
♪ 'Tis the season...
What's a season?
♪ Fa-la-la-la-la
Just play along.
♪ I can fix this, Mr. Santa
♪ We can
fa-la-la-la-la-along
♪ Give a sloth a chance
Now, can't you?
♪ Too many "la's"
are in this song
I have no idea
why I just did that.
That's a toy!
And that's a toy!
And this?
This is no good for anything.
♪ Sid has got
the proper spirit
♪ Fa-la-la-la-la
Hey, not too bad.
Beautiful!
Don't let Sid near it.
♪ Fa-la-la-la-la
Come on now, Dad.
♪ We can do it
♪ If we hurry
♪ Lend a claw
♪ Lend a paw
♪ Everyone
♪ Even if you're
small and furry
♪ All together
we can get it done
A ball of twine?
Who's gonna want that?
Whoo!
All right!
What do we do with this?
Oh, why don't
we put it here.
Hey!
Something about
that mistletoe...
♪ This shall go
down in the annals
♪ Fa-la-la-la-la
♪ And we're not through
♪ Peace and goodwill
towards all mammals
Oh, you shouldn't have.
Just for you.
♪ Things were looking
grim and tragic
♪ But we got busy
and pulled it off
♪ Now we found
some Christmas magic
♪ All because of
each and every sloth
"All because of
each and every sloth"?
♪ All because of each
♪ And everyone ♪
I can't believe it.
These presents!
The decorations!
This sleigh!
Ain't she fly?
I bet the mini sloths could help you make
presents every year! Right, guys?
Well, we're gonna
need hats.
Cute hats.
In fact, it looks like you got enough toys
for every child on Earth.
Every child?
Around the world?
I wish I could,
but I don't see how.
Santa, I'm giving you
the biggest Christmas gift of all.
Me! You're flying
Air Prancer tonight.
Oh, that's the spirit,
Prancy boy!
Time to put this
deer in high gear.
Vroom, vroom!
Up, up and away!
Come on!
Saving Christmas
here we go!
Anytime you're ready.
I can't believe it!
I failed.
This family doesn't
give up that easy.
All right, Dad!
Come on, Prancer.
We have to keep trying.
You're the only flying
reindeer we've got.
Unless you know
10 others.
You're right.
I can't do this alone.
Wait, where you going?
Perfect.
Wow! Heck of a day,
eh, Santa?
Come on! Ho ho ho.
Oh. Still on the
Naughty List, huh?
Okay, so we traveled
about 30 feet so far.
If we keep up this pace, we should make
it around the world in what?
Let's say just under
8000 years?
Bah, humbug!
Hey, guys!
Manny's right!
Nothing's impossible
if you pull together.
Meet my family.
Dasher, Dancer, Vixen,
Comet, Cupid, Donner...
Whoa!
...and Blitzen.
Blitzen?
And I thought
Prancer was bad!
Nice name.
It suits you.
Thanks, Prancer.
I thought I was
such a hotshot,
but sometimes you
gotta have a little help.
That's what this herd
has taught me...
Stay.
...among other things.
Now, let's do this.
Ha-ha! Yeah!
Hey, Manfred, nice job!
I got Christmas!
See what happens
when you believe, Dad?
I gotta say, I'm kinda digging
the holiday magic.
Merry Christmas, you two.
Ho ho ho!
All right! Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Merry Christmas!