Synchronized By : Eng.Taki
Rudy, voice-over:
To tell you the truth,
I never was much
for the holidays.
Been forever since
I'd known a holiday,
since I'd seen my family,
since I'd been with a girl,
since I'd driven a car.
You see, cars are
what put me here.
Iron Mountain,
maximum security.
I was riding a hard 5
for grand theft auto.
Meanwhile, most of
my esteemed raping
and murdering colleagues
were up for parole in 3.
World works like that sometimes.
All the time, in my experience.
That's me, Rudy Duncan,
menace to society,
on the left.
Guard: Move it out!
The guy on the right's
Nick Cassidy,
my best friend.
Back then, we were both looking
at 3 days to a new start.
That's what you
talk about in prison.
How you're gonna get it right.
How you'll never make
the same mistakes.
[Whistling Silver Bells]
We walk outta here,
we hit that road,
what's the first thing
you're gonna do?
Hot chocolate.
What?
That's the first thing
I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna go out and get myself
a mug of hot chocolate.
And a piece of pecan pie, right?
That's right.
A piece of pecan pie.
Yeah. She's gonna
be out there, man.
She's gonna be right there.
Right there, waiting.
P.A.: Emmett Johnson,
report back to your cellblock.
She got us a motel
on highway 5.
Lock ourselves in
the whole week,
drinkin' wine,
takin' baths, man.
Huh?
[Laughs]
[Inhales]
Yeah.
[Indistinct Speech Over P.A.]
You know, Nick,
all those pictures she sent,
you sure that's really
her in the pictures?
because I did hear sometimes
these girls send pictures
that's not really them.
It's like their prettier,
you know,
cousin' or somethin' like that.
Why you gotta say a thing
like that, man?
Ah, I'm just sayin',
you know, I heard that.
Why? Why you gotta
say a thing like that?
I'm just sayin',
I mean, uh...
you know, maybe I
should take her out.
Spend a day or two with her.
Make sure she's the right girl.
Just a day or two.
Maybe a night or two?
Yeah. Whatever it takes.
Just make sure
you're gettin' the right
merchandise, you know.
Yeah, you know what?
Enjoy your hot chocolate, Rudy.
Think I'll take my chances
with Ashley.
Yeah, I figured. I figured.
P.A.:
Shower release, first tier.
Guard:
Hold up. Hold.
P.A.:
Pop gate 3.
[Door Buzzes]
Rudy:
Oh, shooot.
What's up?
Alamo's back.
Nick: Don't look like
he missed the sunlight.
Bro, I'm fucked.
Pincher said he thinks
I'm the one who ratted him out
for beating up Creed,
because I was there.
He thinks I'm the reason
he ended up in solitary.
flap, Rudy.
Guard:
Move out!
And stop!
Move in!
Nick:
Listen to this.
"I've made my list,
and I've checked it twice,
"and as long as you're naughty,
it's gonna be nice.
"All that gets me
through the day
"is to close my eyes
and imagine holding you,
"kissing you...
"touching you,
"because I know
I'll feel at that moment
I've found the reason
for my whole entire life."
She sounds pretty mature for 25.
Yeah.
You grow up in Detroit,
you get mature real quick.
Yeah. Either that or those
pictures are 10 years old.
[Chuckles]
Uhh!
Sure as hell don't make me
miss Millie Bobeck.
Guess I owe Millie, though.
If I hadn't been rolling her,
I would've never ended up here.
Yeah. You hadn't cracked
that guy's head open,
you never would have
found true love.
Jealous.
You know, Nick,
what if she sees you,
and, you know, you just
don't do it for her?
You know, I mean physically.
Rudy:
She just... you know, it's not there.
What are you gonna do?
Well... me and her,
we got a connection.
Oh, Jesus Christ. Get this
fuckin' shooot out of my face.
You should've written
to that magazine, Rudy.
Oh, I should've, yeah.
I'm gonna walk outta here,
I'm gonna walk right
into a relationship,
and you, my friend,
will walk out
with the bus fare...
searching for the drunkest
skirt in the room.
That's right.
"Morning, gorgeous.
More eggnog?"
[Laughs]
Should've written, Rudy.
You could have got
yourself a girl.
Yeah. Should've done
a lot of things.
[Sighs]
All I want
is just to make it
back to Sidnaw,
sit down for Christmas dinner,
sleep in my old bed,
watch some ball games
with my old man,
eat leftovers
for about 6 months.
I thought you hated that place.
Some of my dad's
Christmas turkey.
Nick: Yeah, what makes you
think your dad'll forgive you?
Well, he said
I'd pay for it.
You know?
Me and my easy money.
That's what he called it.
After wasting 5 years
of my fuckin' life,
I'd have to say
the guy had a point.
Ohh.
5 years, man.
[Sighs]
I did my time.
I just want to go home.
[Man Yelling In Distance]
Guard:
Keep the line movin'!
What's this?
Holiday Jell-O.
What's this shooot in it?
Swallow it and ya see.
Just so you know...
Hey.
This man and I are
out of here in 2 days,
so while we're inhaling
London broil and lobster bisque,
you're still
gonna be standing here,
nick: smelling up
the mystery cream flap.
Who's in prison now?
Alamo, man, it wasn't me.
Guard:
Back in line!
It wasn't me.
2 days, man. Come on.
Remember how her brother's
a truck driver down there?
Thinkin' he might be able
to help get me some work.
What, workin' security?
[Chuckles]
Nah.
Nah, I'm through with that shooot.
Ashley's right,
I gotta start doin' somethin'
I got a stake in.
Get a business goin'.
I don't know, man.
I've been in the business world.
Hot-wiring cars, Rudy,
does not qualify
as a small business.
"Chop shop consultant"
doesn't work on a resume.
Rudy:
All right.
Nick: I just wanted to be
the boss of somethin', ya know?
Have people working for me.
Oh, man, what's wrong with you?
Monsters...
in the gelatin.
It's just a roach, Zook.
Yeah, it's protein.
It's good for ya.
Monsters...
in the gelatin!
All right, calm down.
There are monsters in the gelatin!
Guard:
Hey, Zook! Sit the flap down!
Zook:
Monsters... in... the gelatin!
Look at this shooot!
Hey! Jesus!
Sit down! Sit down!
Son of a bitch!
Ooh ha!
You eat this shooot!
Uhh!
Guard:
Sit down! Don't move!
Stay out of it.
Stay out of it, Rudy!
Stay out of it!
Inmate:
I didn't do nothin', man! Be cool!
[Voice Inaudible]
Inmate:
You want some fuckin' monster?
Eat this, cocksucker!
2 days, man.
flap!
Nick: Just stand there!
Don't move, don't move!
We have nothing to do with it.
We have nothing to do with it!
Man:
Hey, hey! Come back here!
Rudy, watch out!
Uhh!
Guard:
Down!
Get down!
Guard:
Get up against the wall!
Rudy:
Nick.
Ohh, Ashley...
I'm gonna be there.
Oh, my God!
Nick:
Jesus, Rudy. Ashley, Ashley.
OK, you're gonna be all right.
Hold on, just hold on.
Nick:
No, Ashley, I'm gonna be there.
Guard! Jesus, guard!
I'm gonna be there.
Guard! Guard!
Jesus Christ.
Guard: Back, back, back!
Get your hands up!
Oh, my God.
Nick! Nick!
Guard:
Get him out of here now!
Nick! Nick!
Nick!
Rudy, offscreen:
Nick! Nick!
Well, least he won't
be comin' back.
[Laughs Evilly]
Ooh. You need some company
tonight, Rudy,
you just gimme a holler, huh?
[Kisses]
Inmate:
Shut the flap up!
[Humming]
Inmate:
You gonna take that shooot, Rudy?!
You gonna do something, Rudy?!
Inmate:
Yeah, I want some company, too!
[Sniffles]
[Sighs]
Guard:
Open outer gate!
Your world,
and welcome to it,
you dumb fucks!
Don't be a stranger, now.
We'll keep the lights on for ya!
Over here.
Boy:
Mom.
Man:
Hey, baby. Lookin' good.
Woman:
Jesus!
Aqui, mira.
Man:
Claudia?
Woman:
Hey. You look good.
Come over here.
Hey. How you doing?
Nick, voice-over:
"All that gets me through the day
"is to close my eyes
and imagine holding you,
"kissing you,
touching you."
Don't do it, Rudy.
Don't you fuckin' do it.
[Kissing]
[Giggling, Moaning]
Mmm, baby.
[Laughing, Moaning]
Rudy:
Jesus Christ.
You Ashley?
I'm Nick.
Etta James:
# At last #
[Horn Honks]
# My love has come along #
# My lonely days #
# Are over #
How's your coffee?
# And life is like a song #
It's good.
Jeez, it's got to be about
10 degrees out there.
The radio said negative 5.
Rudy:
Negative 5?
Yeah.
I don't think it's negative 5.
The radio said.
Oh, windchill, you know,
is probably what they meant.
Windchill factor.
Yeah.
Look, Ashley, I'm sorry.
I, uh, I was scared
that I was gonna walk out there
and you were gonna
take one look at me
and just turn around.
Rudy:
You know, I was scared
I was walking into heartache.
All those letters
and all those words,
and you have a picture
in your mind, and...
I was scared you'd see me,
and I just wouldn't be that...
Rudy:
picture that you had in your mind.
I figured you walked
out of there
and you saw my clothes
or something,
and you just walked
right the other way.
You know, maybe you saw
my coat or my hair...
Oh, hey, I like your coat.
Maybe you, um...
Maybe you saw me,
and I didn't...
Rudy:
Ashley... no.
That was me.
I thought you said
you had curly hair.
I do. It's very curly.
When it gets long,
it's really curly,
but I had to cut it short.
I can grow it back out again,
if you want.
I mean, I can get,
you know, pretty bushy.
No. No, no, no.
I want you to be
who you want to be.
Do that again.
What?
Smile like that.
Come on, one more time.
God, I have been dreaming
about that smile...
for so long...
Ashley Mercer.
# At last #
You're better than the pictures
in my mind, Nick.
You're real.
Dean Martin:
# Oh, the weather outside is frightful #
# But the fire is so delightful #
# And since we've no place to go #
# Let it snow, let it snow
let it snow #
# Man, it doesn't show signs
of stoppin' #
# And I've brought me
some corn for poppin' #
# The lights
are turned way down low #
# Let it snow #
# When we finally kiss
good night #
# How I'll hate goin' out
in the storm #
# But if you really
hold me tight #
# All the way home
I'll be warm #
# And the fire is slowly dying #
[Rudy Laughs]
# And, my dear
we're still good-bye-ing #
# But as long
as you love me so #
# Let it snow, let it snow
and snow #
[Sighs]
Can I ask you something?
Mmm?
This the first time you ever
done somethin' like this?
You... oh, look at you.
You're so pretty, sweet.
Why you writing to some con
you don't even know?
I told you, Nick, remember?
Tell me again.
[Sighs]
All the guys I've ever been with,
they never wanted
to get to know me.
Who I am, inside.
They just wanted to get inside.
Guy like you, Nick...
God, I mean, 6 months
before you can even touch my face.
I figure a guy like that
was gonna have to work
to get to know me
some other way.
But when I read
what you wrote to me,
I said...
here's a guy they say
is a criminal,
but he's not.
Just protected his girl.
I mean, somebody
got killed, but...
he's not a killer.
because he did what he had to do
to save somebody.
And the world just
didn't see it that way.
State of Michigan, anyway.
You wrote me some
wonderful things, Nick.
It wasn't all me, you know.
Aw, it was all you.
[Laughs]
The guy I was in with, you know,
he helped me with
some of the, you know,
some of the romantic stuff.
He's a good guy, actually.
You'd like him. Ha.
I'm talkin' about the heart...
not the words.
Yeah, well...
some of the heart
might have been his, too.
Yeah?
He should have signed his name,
then he'd be here right now.
[Rockin' Around The Christmas Tree
Playing On Radio]
Brenda Lee:
# Rockin' around the Christmas tree #
# At the Christmas party hop #
# Mistletoe hung
where you can't see #
# Every couple tries to stop #
Merry Christmas!
Ho ho ho!
Ashley:
Mmm-ah!
Merry Christmas, Santa! Whoo!
Rudy:
Leave Santa alone!
Provisions, Nick.
- What?
- Provisions!
[Ashley Laughs]
Oh, we are going
to be naked,
drinking cold champagne,
but we are not leaving
that motel room
till after New Year's.
OK, well, I think
we got enough stuff.
Come here, you need a coat.
No boyfriend of mine
is gonna walk around
in a negative-5-degree windchill
without a good-looking
goddamn coat.
Yeah, but I... you already
got me all this stuff.
I didn't get you anything.
Nick, you got out.
You're here.
You're my Christmas.
It's $200, Ash.
Ha ha, I know.
But you forget where I work.
Beauty and fragrances.
Yup. 50% off, my friend.
Ho ho ho.
[Laughs]
Just until the holidays, Nick.
You know, we'll let her
have her holidays,
then we'll tell her.
P.A.:
Attention, shoppers...
Ashley:
Hey, Nick.
Yeah.
You know what I was thinking?
What?
Well, after our little
holiday hideaway,
maybe instead of
going back to Detroit,
we can go gambling.
Don't you think that'd be fun?
You know, drive up
to that Indian place
you used to work at.
I don't know about that.
What are you talking about?
I haven't gambled in forever.
I got some luck, you know?
Blackjack, Nick,
blackjack I'm good at.
And they'd give us
some free games,
wouldn't they,
since you worked there?
Whoa, I worked security.
I don't think they're going to be
rolling out the red carpet for me.
Yeah, slots...
Whoo! Baby, am I good at slots.
You don't even know.
It would be so much fun.
Come on.
You can't be good at slots.
You just pull the handle.
No, but we'll walk in there
like high rollers.
You know, it'll be fun.
Look, Ash, we're not going
anywhere I used to work.
OK? That's it.
OK.
I'm sorry. I just...
you know, I thought maybe
you had friends there,
and you'd like to see them.
Hey, it's OK.
I just... look, you know...
I've been in prison for 2 years.
Those guys really
don't want to see me.
Trust me.
Well, they don't know what
the hell they're missing.
I'm gonna tell them
not to bother us
for the rest of the year.
When I get back in that room,
you better be wearing
nothing but a candy cane.
# I have no gifts to bring #
# Ba-rump-ah-pum-pum #
[Chuckles]
# Da-da #
# A gift to give a king #
[Mutters]
# I've got a girl... #
Ohh!
Hi, Nick.
Aah! Ah, shooot.
I owe you a drink.
Uhh!
[Coughing]
Welcome home, Nick.
[Coughs]
Look, man, you don't know me.
Ho ho ho.
Oh, I know you.
I know you real well.
[Coughs]
You can't.
Uhh, the hell I can't.
Ashley:
Watch out, baby!
Rudy:
Ashley!
I'm bringin' in the tree!
Yaah! Nick!
Mmm!
Aah!
Looks like somebody's
been havin' some fun.
[Laughs]
Hey, sis.
Happy holidays.
[Screaming]
You bastard! Ohh!
Take it easy.
Don't hurt her.
Right. Sorry, Monster.
[Ashley Grunting]
So...
this is the guy
you've been waitin' for.
The man of your dreams.
Gabriel.
What are you doing?
I read a lot about you, Nick.
Gabriel, what are you doing here?!
I read you're a man
of some knowledge.
Ashley:
Gabriel.
A man of some travels.
Look, man, I'm not him.
Whatever you want from Nick,
you got the wrong guy.
Nick.
Ohh!
No! No!
Aah ha ha!
[Coughs]
Well, who are you now?
I'm not him, man!
[Coughs]
I'm not... She just...
She thinks I'm Nick. I'm not him.
Put him in the truck.
Wait a minute.
I was in the joint with him.
That's how I knew
about him and her.
I took his place.
Gabriel:
You what?
I...
OK. I got out.
Nick didn't.
I knew about her letters, and...
Rudy:
Jesus Christ, man,
whatever you want from Nick,
I-I'm not him, OK?
I just...
I wanted to be.
You're not Nick Cassidy?
No, man,
I just shared his cell.
But you were sayin' you were?
Yeah.
So you could get with my sister?
So you could get down her chimney?
Yeah.
And you think tellin' me
that's gonna help your cause?
No!
[Coughing]
No.
Is this him?
Please don't hurt him,
Gabriel! Don't!
Is this the fucker
you've been writin' all year?
Don't, please don't.
Is this Nick Cassidy?!
Yes! Yes!
Yes.
Well, he better learn
to give you some respect.
No!
Get her out of here.
No. No.
No!
[Rudy Coughing]
Man, they got
a shitload of cookies.
Take them.
What about the tree?
Merlin:
You want the tree?
Yeah.
[Laughing]
[Coughs]
Uhh.
I read your letters, convict.
Don't play no reindeer games with me.
Ashley:
He read your letters.
One day, I wasn't...
I wasn't there,
and he... he came in,
and Jane-Janey tried to stop him,
but he read your letters.
What letters?
He knows you worked
at that casino.
Shoo.
What?!
Oh, my God, you set him up!
No. No, I didn't. I didn't.
When'd you decide
to do it, Ash?
Huh? After which one
of his letters?
What, the 40th?
The 50th?
The first? What?!
Ashley:
No, Nick...
Look, I'm not Nick!
OK?!
You thought you'd flap him over?!
Aw, shooot! Guess what?
He fucked you!
Because I never worked
in any casino,
and I can't help you,
because I'm not him!
No, you don't understand!
I love you!
Aw, Jesus Christ!
Hey, hey, hey, man!
Watch your mouth.
It's Christmas.
Listen to me.
My brother has killed people.
I know this.
You don't know him.
You don't know
what he's capable of.
He will kill you. If you keep
telling him that you're not you,
he will kill you.
Says here the retail industry
does 50% of its business
between December 1st
and December 25th.
That's half a year's business
in one month's time.
It seems to me
an intelligent country
would legislate a second
such gift-giving holiday.
Create, say, a Christmas II,
late May or early June,
to further stimulate growth.
Ever since you been
goin' to night school,
you've been giving me
headaches, Jumpy.
Christmas II.
[Chuckles]
Just...
"My sweet, sexy Ashy-Lashy." Huh.
"I have been dreaming
of you constantly,
"and knowing you are out there
"makes these walls
not seem so close
"or so strong or so cold.
Gabriel: "Saah... someday
I'm gonna take you up
"by Lake Superior.
"Before I went in,
before goddamn Millie,
"I used to work up at this casino,
Gabriel:
"workin' security.
"Used to watch for people
stealin' chips,
"counting cards,
getting piss-drunk,
"that kind of stuff.
"Indian place.
Easiest job I ever had."
You're a good writer, Nick.
Gabriel:
I give this writing...
an A-plus.
Now, you just tell us
what we need to know,
and you two kids,
you get to go
live happily ever after.
You... You give me
little nieces and nephews.
Listen to me, man.
I never worked at a casino.
No, Nick.
Now, just shut up.
That guy who wrote that letter?
That's Nick Cassidy.
I was in the joint with him.
He rode a 2-year
manslaughter bit
for killing some guy
who was bothering
his girlfriend in a bar.
Rudy:
He's dead.
He wrote those letters.
He worked at a casino.
Me? My last job
was at a quick booth.
I did 5 for lifting cars.
That's it, he was my cellmate.
That's how I know him.
I'm not him.
I'm sorry about your sister.
Rudy:
I just got out of the joint.
I... I just wanted...
I don't know anything,
I don't remember anybody,
I just wanna go home.
Bury this guy.
No. Gabriel, no.
Ashley:
Gabriel, you promised.
Gabriel:
I promised that when he helped us,
we'd be gone.
When he helped us.
This guy doesn't wanna play!
Ashley:
No, you promised me.
And you promised me
you'd get your sweetheart to help!
Gabriel:
He'd rather die
than be with you.
He'd make a fucked-up
boyfriend anyway.
Bury this guy
all over the place.
No. No!
Gabriel:
Come on.
Gabriel, no!
Shut up!
Uhh!
Now, don't get no blood
on my shoes.
[Merlin Chuckles]
All right, all right,
all right, all right!
What do you wanna know?!
Rudy: About the casino!
About the Tomahawk!
Jesus Christ,
what do you wanna know?!
[Wheezing Laugh]
Spent 6 months
writing love letters.
My pen pal fucks me over.
Thanks for the stamps, Ash.
All right, what do you
want to know?
Everything.
Nick, I love you, baby.
Nick, I love you.
Gabriel:
Hey.
She said she loves you.
Say somethin'.
I had better sex in prison.
[Chuckles]
Throw him back in the rig.
Monster, he's not the guy.
Whole time you were drivin',
up front,
he was telling her
he's not the guy,
Pug:
he's not the guy.
Now, I understand
why he'd tell us
he's not the guy,
but why would he tell her
that he's not the guy?
Maybe...
Maybe he's not the guy.
Look, man, if I went in
the joint with a library card,
I'd come out with a library card.
The man who wrote those letters
loved Ashley, boys.
He lived for her.
Where's she work?
What?
Wrote you a hundred letters,
didn't she?
Where's she work?
Lindstrom's,
beauty and fragrances.
What's her middle name?
Uh... Samantha.
What'd they call her
in high school?
Bam-Bam.
What'd they call her in college?
What college?
What's her greatest fear?
Brother.
Ooh, oh.
Wrong. It's drowning.
Wrong.
It's her brother.
That's love?
It's time to start talking...
Nick.
Time to start tellin' tales.
Get him up here.
No. No! No! flap that!
Nick doesn't do anything
until Nick gets
something for Nick.
Got it?
I want some hot chocolate.
You want to hear about
some job of mine,
I want to see some
goddamn hot chocolate.
And some pecan fuckin' pie!
Mmm. Sure nice pie.
[Joy To The World
Playing On Radio]
So, when you worked there...
Mmm.
You knew the place...
[Clears Throat]
OK.
You know what?
I could really go
for some onion rings.
[Gasps] You said talk!
That's all you said.
Gabriel, you said
you wanted to talk...
Shut up!
You just said you wanted
to talk to him.
Gabriel:
You can't choose your family, Ash.
Unlike friends and lovers,
that does relieve you
of the burden
of worrying you chose wrong.
[Sighs]
How much money
is in that casino?
Hard to say.
Well, take a guess.
5 million?
Jesus.
You, uh, you wrote Ash
a letter with a story
about working Christmas eve.
About how they send half
the security guys home.
Nobody's comin' in and out,
and the rest of you
are gettin' shooot-faced.
Is that a true story or not?
Uh, Christmas eve.
We're takin' down
that casino, convict.
And you're the guy
that's gonna tell us how.
That's what we can see.
Now, you tell us
what we can't see.
Where the private doors go,
where the alarms are,
what the upstairs
looks like... all of it.
It's not the Tomahawk.
What the hell
are you talkin' about?
What's this, the cage?
I mean, the cage is over here.
You got...
This whole thing's mixed up.
That's what it looks like, Romeo.
Since when?
Rudy:
I mean, where... What's this?
That's the prime rib buffet.
5.99.
Buffet? Buffet is
over here by the bar.
Rudy:
I mean, what...
This map looks like it was
made by a bunch of retards.
It's all wrong.
[Gasps]
Stop it.
It's my map, you little shooot!
Ohh.
Now, we cased the place.
We saw it.
Yeah, and I worked there,
for a year.
The map is kinda messy, Monster.
They must have
remodeled the place.
What?
Rudy:
The big guy, the boss,
the guy who ran the place,
uh, was in charge.
Jack Bangs.
He was always talking about
giving the place a makeover.
They must have gone
ahead and done that
while I was in the Mountain.
Rudy: I mean,
this thing's all changed around.
I can't help you with this.
I don't know where security
or anything is.
I have no idea.
Look, look, I don't care
about the pancake breakfast.
I want...
Look, you want to know
about money, right?
OK, where you got
the buffet down here,
that used to be Bangs's office.
And he kept the safe in there.
And that safe
had all the money
that he was skimming in there.
And it was called
the Powwow Safe.
Powwow Safe?
Rudy:
Yes. Powwow Safe.
because he was stealin' money
from the tribe.
The guy had thousands in there.
Millions, probably.
Millions?
In the Powwow Safe?
Millions.
But, uh, I mean, you know...
you know, now you're telling me
his office is moved.
I mean, God knows
what else is different.
You know, the security,
the... the...
Rudy:
You know, you want me to show you
what goes where.
I have no idea!
Well...
I guess we don't need you then.
Well... not necessarily.
Because, if you get me inside,
then I know where
the money moves.
I know the security routines.
I know their signals
to each other.
Rudy:
I know how they operate.
You get me in there,
then I can work with this map.
Then I can tell you
if anything's changed.
Wrong, convict.
You walk in there,
they recognize you.
So what?
If they recognize him,
they'll remember him
when the job goes down.
They won't recognize me.
Trust me.
Why not?
because you're gonna
get me a disguise.
Rudy: Look, I give you
the wrong information,
you shoot me, right?
I mean, it's pretty simple.
Now, you got 2 choices...
You can either
get me in there,
I can take a look around
and case the joint,
check out security,
and I can tell you if
I can work with this map
or you can just
shoot me right now.
Rudy: Wait a minute.
Whoa, what's this?
What happened to working together?
Would you rather be
back in the Mountain?
I might as well be.
Don't get 50 channels
in the Mountain.
Tomorrow, you got singing
for your supper to do.
Man On TV:
Christmases like these.
I've always looked on
Christmas as a good time.
Help yourself.
Man On TV:
Kind, charitable.
Sure. Take that.
I don't need it.
TV:
It's the only time
when people open
their hearts freely,
the only time when men
and women seem to realize
that all human beings
are really members
of the same family.
[Gasps]
[Shaking Bed]
Nick.
Nick...
let me help you.
Get your own room, Ashley.
Ashley:
Let me help you.
Get your own room!
He said when you come out
he wants to talk to you.
That's all.
I thought he meant after
New Year's, you know?
Oh, yeah, but you knew
what he wanted, right?
I thought we had
a few more days.
For what?
What are you going to do?
Talk me into helping?
- What, did he promise you some of the money?
- No.
Well, shooot, you should've
at least gotten that.
Get your own flaping room.
Christ, you know
how I hate him.
You know how I feel
about my brother.
How flaping stupid
are you? Huh?
What did you think
was going to happen?
This thing's going to be over,
and he's just going
to let me go?
He's going to shoot me
in the back of the head
like this.
Or I'm back in prison
for the rest of my life,
and that's it for me.
This is my life, too, you know.
This is not just about you.
You think he's just
going to let me walk?
You... You think he's not going
to take this out on me, Nick?
I am in this, too,
and I am really scared.
Please.
Ohh.
Nick.
Nick...
do you remember
all those letters
you wrote me
about me and you
against the whole world?
We can still have that.
We can have it all
if you just...
if you just give him
what he wants.
Why do you have to keep
fighting him?
Why can't you just
give him what he wants?
Why?
[Sighs]
God.
You know...
it's just my luck.
I finally meet a boy
that I'm crazy about,
and my brother wants him
worse than I do.
What do you want
from me? Sympathy?
Rudy:
I don't feel bad for you.
Why didn't you tell me
your brother was a criminal?
Gabriel knows some guys
in Miami and New York...
guys that he helps
get guns to Detroit.
Ashley:
That's it. That's all I know.
And that's who he's
working for on this one?
No.
He doesn't want
to work for anyone.
Well, what's the last place
they took down?
What?
Monster and his merry men...
what's the last place
they robbed?
Who they ripped off.
What did they do?
I don't think they've
robbed anywhere before.
They just...
They drive guns.
They've never done a robbery?
Really?
Nick.
We can get out
of this. No...
There's no "we,"
Ashley, OK?
Hey!
Get... Get your own room.
Go! Leave!
Fine...
but if I told you
what he wanted,
you would've been gone.
You would've gotten
on that bus,
and you would've stayed on it.
And if that makes me selfish,
then I am selfish.
Ashley:
If that makes me a liar...
God... I am a liar.
But I have been dealing
with my fucked-up brother
and his fucked-up friends
for way too long.
And I am stronger
than him now...
because he showed up
for money...
and I showed up for love.
Sing it to somebody
who gives a shooot.
You're so quick
to make me your enemy?
Then tell me something, Nick.
Tell me...
What did you show up for?
What did you really want?
With me?
[Sniffles]
Pug:
No. Miss, miss, miss, miss.
Oh, man.
Well, well,
you still got
the touch, Monster.
[Laughs]
Whoa!
Look what Santa's dwarves
have brought you.
Hmm. What do you say
to Santa's dwarves?
It's elves, bro.
[Laughs]
You say, "Thank you."
Radio:
# Oh, yeah #
# Candles burnin' low #
# Lots of mistletoe #
# Lots of snowy mountains #
A cowboy?
# Everywhere we go #
You're sending me
into an Indian casino
dressed like a cowboy?
Thought this through entirely?
It was that or a ballerina.
Well, I mean, I...
I'm going to need some money.
It is a casino.
# That's what Christmas
means to me, my love #
# Whoa, yeah #
# Ah, yeah #
10 bucks?
What do I do with 10 bucks?
Don't tip.
Look, if we're going
to be working together,
you know, you can't just
send me in there
like the Lone Ranger
with 10 bucks to throw down.
You know, you want me
not getting noticed.
Not getting noticed costs
at least a couple hundred.
Ante up, boys.
# The little cards you give me #
# Will touch my heart for sure #
# All these things
and more, darlin' #
# Whoa #
# That's what Christmas
means to me, my love #
# Oh, yeah, ah #
# I feel like running wild #
# For the safety
of a little child #
# Greet you 'neath the mistletoe #
Don't lose.
Yeah. Yeah.
Do I get, like,
a country-western name,
or are we just going to...
If you get recognized,
you'll get
a country-western funeral.
Come on.
Get your hands off me.
Are you ready
to go gambling, darlin'?
Here.
She is now.
All right.
Y'all keep an eye
on my guitar, now.
Who's robbing who here, Gabe?
Get in there and watch them.
Jumpy.
[People Chattering,
Machines Whirring]
Nick, you know, you're making
it really hard to apologize.
Is that what
you're trying to do?
Say it with car keys.
Nick, a lot of relationships
start out like this,
you know... family problems?
Save it, Bam-Bam.
Hey...
I think I liked you better
when you were in prison.
Yeah? Is that why
you keep trying
to put me back in?
[Machine Noise
And Chatter Stops]
Well, I just...
I just think you were a hell
of a lot more understanding.
Well, I was a different person then.
As I was saying, boys,
there's an "S" word
I'd like to throw
into the conversation here,
because it's a big part
of what's going on...
a big element.
The "S" word.
[Chatter And Machine Noise Playing]
It's a serious matter
with serious effects,
so I'd just like
to get it out there,
throw it out there,
so that we can
know about it,
talk about it, hear it,
maybe even do
some things about it.
Mr. Bangs, um...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[Lowers Volume Of Tape]
Thank you.
Snow.
Are you with me here, boys?
Now, I'm talking big-time, grade-A,
God-quality,
S-N-O-flaping-W
snow.
Now, look...
you guys hired me
because you wanted
Las Vegas quality.
I brought it to you.
You wanted Las Vegas press.
I gave that to you.
But I cannot give you
Las Vegas profits
until you people get together
around a campfire,
smoke a pipe,
and do some kind of
flaping spirit dance
about this goddamn snow.
We understand the Paiute's casino
saw a profit of
$12 million last year.
Don't talk to me
about the Paiutes, OK?
I have it on
very good authority
they're cooking the books.
The Wyatolla Reservation
made 17 million.
All right, look...
keep this under
your feathers, boys,
but it just so happens
that next week,
I'm bringing in
a great lounge act.
3 Russian broads.
They all look like Meryl Streep.
They can juggle anything...
your house, your car,
your mother-in-law.
Mr. Bangs.
We're doing the right thing here...
Mr. Bangs,
the tribe is concerned
that many of your new ideas
are not bringing in
any new revenues.
I'm putting liquor into drinks.
I'm paying 10 times odds on craps,
and I got the girls showing
16% more skin.
And by the way,
you show me another buffet
that offers
both Coke and Pepsi.
Don't even bother looking,
because it doesn't exist.
OK, so, now, what else
do you people want me to do?
[Chatter And Machine Noise
Tape Playing]
So, does it look
remodeled a lot?
Yeah. Yeah, it does.
They did a lot of work.
This restaurant here
is the main expansion,
and they moved
the games around.
The big guy's office...
They did a hell
of a job with that.
Hell of a job.
Do you know that guy?
Yeah. That's, uh...
ahem.
That's Mike.
Mike. Yeah.
He works here.
Spend some of your
brother's money.
I'm going to go look around.
I was just thinking
maybe you fellas would
like to stick around...
you know,
try the 5.99 prime rib.
Thank you.
Couple of rum and Cokes, please.
You want that rum and Coke
or rum and Pepsi?
Woman:
Did you keep going?
Bangs:
Bear.
Bear, give me a bottle of
any goddamn thing you got.
Come on, hurry up.
Jeez, rolling 2-dollar
flaping bettors.
I can't go back to Vegas, Bear.
I can't go back.
They'll kill me.
What does the tribe want?
What do they want?
They want their roads
paved with gold
is what they want.
Talking to me about
the flaping Paiutes.
The Paiutes are
on the interstate, OK?
Bangs:
There's nothing I can do
about that, my friend.
And I certainly
didn't pick this spot
for your reservation.
Neither did we.
Yeah, yeah.
Thanks a lot.
Hey, how you doing, cowboy?
How are you?
Good. Great.
Jack Bangs is the name.
Hey, listen.
Listen, now,
you look like
an intelligent fellow.
Let me ask you something.
Bangs:
Do you think that Upstate Michigan
needs another roadside casino,
or...
do you think that Upstate Michigan
needs an international
gaming destination?
Bangs:
What do you think?
Roadside casino.
How'd you hear about us?
Radio, TV, cable?
Prison.
Dealer:
Place your bets, please.
I can't go back to Vegas.
[Slot Machine Beeps]
Oh, God!
We won! We won!
Oh, flap.
What the hell
was that all about?
Nothing, man.
He just wanted to know
how I, you know,
heard about the place.
Just flaping turn it down
a little bit, all right?
Ease up off me.
You're welcome.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
Jesus Christ.
Here, hold this.
What are you doing?
You know what?
Security's not all that changed.
Let me just go clean
this up, all right?
Just... Just...
What was that?
His face fell off.
Take this.
Woman:
Come on.
Hey, baby.
Give me one of those.
How are you?
flaping freezing.
How long you work here?
5 years... since it opened.
How long since your makeover?
My what?
I'm taking about the place...
The remodeling,
moving everything around.
Tomahawk's been the same
ever since I started, buddy.
It's the losers that change.
[Glass Breaks]
Lying motherfucker!
Uhh!
Go, kid, go!
Hey.
shooot.
[Tires Squeal]
[Engine Stalls]
Come here!
Oh, man, it's your jacket.
You can have it.
- He gave me a hundred bucks.
- shooot!
What the hell happened, man?
The man fucked up!
This building is
the same from day one!
It hasn't been changed!
Monster, he was talking
to the manager inside there!
Merlin:
There he is!
Go, go, go, go!
Come on!
Get him back!
Come on.
Merlin:
Keep on running, Romeo!
Keep on running!
As fast as you go,
Merlin:
we'll get there!
We're truckers, motherfucker!
- We drive for a living!
- [Gunshot]
[Panting]
Help! Help!
Help!
He thinks he's getting away.
- Aah!
- Ooh!
Oh, shooot.
Ohh!
- Unh!
- Ohh!
Ashley:
No!
Gabriel:
Aah!
Ahh.
Uhh!
Rudy:
Come on. Come on.
We got to get to those trees.
[Gunshot]
[Crack]
Ohh!
Oh, shooot!
[Both Gasping]
Come on!
Gabriel:
Get them out of there!
Come on!
Get him out!
Is she all right?
All right!
All right, all right!
At the rate you're going,
I'm going to have trouble
considering you family.
Man:
Hey! Hey, there!
You folks need some help?
[Grunts]
Hey, I say, you need some help?
[Slurred]
Get out of here, man!
Shut the flap up!
Look, man,
get the flap out of here!
Well...
if you need some help...
Ashley:
Gabriel, no!
Rudy: [Slurred]
Gabriel, he won't hurt us!
Gabriel, he won't remember us!
Don't do it!
Shut the flap up!
Rudy:
No! Stop!
[Gabriel Firing Gun]
Oh, God!
Ashley:
No!
[Ashley Sobbing]
Jesus... please.
I'm just a farmer.
I got a wife and family.
I got a hunger...
and a headache.
[Rock Music Playing]
Hey, Monster.
[Imitating Guitar Solo]
[Music Stops]
Boy:
Here they are! Come on!
Get out of here.
[Shivering]
[Merlin Locks Door]
Nick the Trick.
[Laughs]
The master of disguise.
I'm surprised you never
escaped from the Mountain.
What? Yeah.
Never tried.
Well...
in the spirit of the season,
convict...
I'm going to give you a chance.
I understand you're unhappy.
It's been kind of rough.
You need a little guidance.
You're like a wanderer
who's just lost his way
in the night.
So we're going to have
a little contest.
We're each going to get
one of these.
Whichever one hits closest
to the bull's-eye
gets what he wants.
You land closer,
you get Ashley.
You kids get to go free.
I land closer...
then we start getting your help.
[Shivering]
Hmm.
May the man who
really wants it win.
Yeah?
Oh.
shooot.
You got something
to say to me, Nick?
2 out of 3?
Aah!
Ohh.
What's this?
This... This isn't the Tomahawk.
No, no. I've never
seen this before.
They must've given
the place a makeover.
Gabriel:
Yeah. The buffet was over here.
The blackjack was over here.
The bar used to be over here.
I don't know.
I can't help you.
I have no idea.
Something tells me you're not
being totally honest with me.
What'd you tell
that casino manager?
Nothing that matters. Nothing.
You were talking to him.
What'd you tell him?
Nothing.
He thought I was some gambler.
Maybe something about a robbery?
No, man. I swear...
I swear to God.
Aah!
Jesus Christ, man,
he thought I was some gambler.
He didn't know me, man!
He didn't recognize me!
Jesus Christ!
I've been driving rigs
a long time, convict.
Gabriel: Worked for people
who wouldn't keep me on
unless I was driving
15 hours a day.
[Laughs]
Tell them I was tired,
shooot, they'd just hire
someone else.
Gabriel:
A thousand miles by sundown,
or the gang don't eat
come sunrise.
shooot.
And every road,
every mile,
it's nothing but moms and pops
Gabriel:
and car-seat kiddies
giving me that look to go to hell
and get off their
happy goddamn highway.
Ohh. Ohh, ohh.
So...
So I have worked
and I have slaved
and I have waited
for the highways to split open
and for the rivers to roil
and for God in the heavens
to reach down and show me
some sign of my reward...
to grant me with my gift
and say to me,
"Gabriel, my son,
you are done with the road."
Well, convict...
that gift was granted.
Look, man, I swear to God.
He just wanted to know
how I heard about the place,
that's all.
He didn't know
it was me, Gabriel.
Gabriel, he didn't
know it was me.
Rudy:
Please.
Man, Monster,
just don't start trying to hit me.
[Laughs]
Nick...
I've been trying to hit you.
Aah!
[Laughs]
Aah! Uhh!
Uhh!
Because I do not deserve
to be in some shooot-bag motel
in the middle of bum-flap Michigan
throwing darts at a worthless...
Aah!
flaping convict!
Ahh! Ahh!
Ahh!
Ahh. Ahh.
Ahh.
Uhh.
You know...
You know something?
My little sister...
Gabriel:
she deserves a world better than you.
Tonight, we're going to take
one more look at that map.
And this time,
you better have
something worth saying.
[Switching Channels On TV]
Rudy:
Ahh.
Ahh. Uhh.
Oh, my God.
Ahh! Uhh!
Ashley: Jesus Christ,
what happened to you?
What did you do to him?
Hey!
What did they do to you, Nick?
- Aah!
- Jesus Christ.
What the flap
did you do to him?
Bastard. Get out!
Get out!
Just get out.
Oh, my God.
Nick, are you all right?
Hmm.
Let me see.
Aah!
Oh, God.
Come here.
Had some...
p-points to make.
Shh, baby.
We're going to get you
out of these wet clothes.
OK?
- Uhh.
- Oh, God.
Aah!
Oh, God.
OK.
Come here.
Rudy:
Jesus.
There you go. OK.
Ohh. Ohh.
All I wanted to do was
to make it back to Sidnaw,
just have some of
Mama's gravy, you know,
and some of Aunt Lisbeth's
cranberry cakes.
She makes them with...
with real cranberries.
It's really good.
Uhh. Uhh.
We'll get there, baby.
- Jesus.
- We'll get there.
Shh.
Just rest.
OK?
Uhh.
You saved my life, Nick.
Huh?
You could've run, but you didn't.
You saved me.
I saved you because
I love you, Nick.
Why did you save me?
Be...
The guy I was in with,
Rudy the car thief...
sometimes I read him
your letters.
I mean, I know they were
private, but...
you know...
he'd...
I'd read them to him,
and he'd...
get this look on his face.
I swear,
I think he imagined
you were writing to him.
And I know sometimes,
I think he...
he fell in love with you, too.
You gave a couple
of guys hope, Ashley.
Oh, it was a good thing.
We're going to get
out of this...
together, I promise you.
I promise you.
Ash?
We're going to need one.
Ashley:
What?
A gun.
We got to find a way
to get me a gun.
What?
And I'll need to be
inside the casino
when it happens.
I can't just be outside
drawing some map.
Nick, what are you talking about?
We need to find a way to
make me a part of this.
A part of what?
A part of them?
Look, Ash,
if we're helping them
with the robbery,
we got to be doing more
than walking away
like that's winning,
like that's some kind of
Christmas flaping bonus.
You mean take the money?
Yeah. Take the money.
Look, you want him out
of your life for good?
Rudy: Want a real new year
to look forward to?
If we're going to do this,
then we ought to do it.
It's Christmas, Ash.
I think we deserve a present.
Start singing, Nick.
# I have no gifts to bring #
Rudy:
# Ba rump bum bum bum #
[Rudy Laughs]
# A gift to give... #
You want it?
Let's go!
Merlin:
Yeah. You want to keep playing, huh?
Come on, let's get it on!
- Let me go!
- Calm down.
Merlin:
You want to keep playing?
I got a toy for you.
Merlin:
Let me get my toy.
Yes. Let's play!
- Hey, man. Hey.
- Merlin: Shut up!
Now you get
your pussy ass over here
and do what the flap
you're told!
Now when you're spoke to,
you listen and answer.
It was a joke, anyways.
Uh, ahem. All right.
What you want to do, um...
is get to the top level up here.
Rudy:
OK? And you do that
through this door
on the western wall.
Um...
when you...
You want to get
to the security,
and then from the security,
you get down
into the cashier cage,
and then you go into
the count room.
Now, there'll be
a guard in there,
but he doesn't have a gun.
Rudy: Uh, the door's
accessed by a keypad.
The cashier will know the code.
What about the Powwow Safe?
That's upstairs.
You'll want to get to that.
We're going to get
to the Powwow Safe.
That's good.
We're going to get there.
Rudy:
What you want to do is,
you got to get a guy
in the cage
and a guy on the floor
Rudy:
and somebody up top.
Then you need a sweeper
on the side,
a lookout out front,
and somebody
watching the back.
So, that's... how many?
That's 6.
We got 5,
keeping Ashley outside.
And you need 6.
No.
Look, man,
I'm not making this shooot up.
You know?
You go in there with 5 guys,
you're going to either
leave an exit unguarded
or an alarm unguarded.
No.
I know what I'm
talking about. You...
Raise your hand if you've
ever done a robbery before.
Rudy:
Anyone? Anyone?
Whoever has done
a robbery raise your hand. OK.
I have.
You need 6, Gabriel.
Ashley:
You do.
What are you going
to do about it?
Gabriel:
All right.
I want a drawing
of that security level...
Every door, every guard,
every ashtray.
Yeah. All right.
So, 6 guys... that's 6 guns.
[Laughs]
No way.
Well, what am I going to do?
I'm no threat
without a gun.
No, you're not.
What's the matter, Gabriel?
Huh?
Isn't this what
you wanted him for?
Ashley:
Areas of expertise?
No guns.
Well, you know, fine.
It's up to you.
But what you got
to figure out, then,
is how you're going to get
up to that security level
without anybody knowing
anything's wrong.
I can tell you right now
going in there
with AKs and ski masks
Rudy:
Ain't going to do that.
[Laughs]
Well, that part, Nick,
was planned out the day
I read your letters.
Oh, yeah? What?
We're all going
to dress up like cowboys?
Gabriel:
No, no, not cowboys, Nick.
Not on Christmas eve.
You got to be kidding me.
'Tis the season, convict.
Ho...
ho ho.
TV: Coming up at 11:00
on the Channel 5 News,
these top stories.
The search intensified...
Here's your Picasso.
Reported missing this morning
on the Powahatchee Lake.
Investigators suspect foul play.
It better be.
Also, lottery fever...
Uhh!
Ahh.
Uhh.
Man:
How long you guys been going out?
[Truck Door Closes]
Let's get ourselves
some free drinks.
Aw, yeah. I could use one.
shooot.
Only guy in the gun club
who doesn't keep a gun
in his truck.
[Engine Starts]
Rudy:
shooot.
Merlin:
Fucker decided to build him
a silicone tongue so
that the boy could talk.
Now, you ever see
a motherfucker
with a breast-implanted tongue?
Pug:
Man, this guy I'm talking about,
black lung was the least
of his problems, man.
He had so much smoke
coming out of his skin
people would say,
"Hey, where's the barbecue?"
Yeah.
Ashley:
No! No!
No. Get away from me,
goddamn it.
Get off me!
Just get off me.
You heard what I said.
Stay away!
No. You stay away from me.
Stay the hell away from me.
You want me to scream?
I'll flaping scream.
I swear to God.
Gabriel:
He was trying to stop me.
You just about killed me.
Gabriel:
I wasn't shooting at you.
I was just trying
to stop him,
put him down, shoot him
in the flaping knees.
I'm a good shot.
I wasn't going to kill him.
Yeah. You're such
a goddamn good shot
that who went through
the goddamn ice, huh? Who?
Hey, I didn't put you
on that ice.
You would never
have been there...
I just about goddamned died, Gabriel.
Gabriel:
Baby, I know that.
When I saw you fall,
I could've put the gun
in my mouth
and pulled the trigger then.
I know you have
to be with him...
but it is killing me.
Gabriel, we just have
to keep doing this and...
I'm going to cut out his heart.
Gabriel:
Is he ready for that?
He's helped us do the map.
He's done what we need.
We don't need him anymore.
I don't trust the little fucker.
We can do this without him.
I'm going to kill
that motherfucker tonight.
No.
Jesus.
You drive me crazy,
you know that?
Hey...
Ashley:
No. You listen to me,
because we have to be
smart about this.
The more he wants me,
the more his help's for real.
Ashley:
He's manpower.
That's all he is.
He's just more manpower.
Gabriel, he wants
to help now.
He wants to Rob it.
Ashley:
He wants to rob you.
[Scoffs]
He wants the money?
No, baby.
He wants me.
Your little sister.
If only Ma and Pop...
Could see us now.
Gabriel:
Hey...
if only this guy would play
the game by the numbers.
Well, from where I stand,
the only thing he's been
doing right so far
is flaping my girlfriend.
I don't want you with him.
When I'm with him,
I'm wanting you.
Ashley: All those letters
to all those goddamn cons
are finally going to pay off.
Ashley:
So don't get crazy, OK?
Because it's working.
Uhh!
He's our money man.
We finally found one,
didn't we?
Yeah.
Ashley:
Oh, baby.
See ya later, assholes.
Pug:
Who's Jumpy calling?
Merlin:
Ex-wife, probably.
Which one?
All the ex-wives he's got,
he's probably going to have
to take down 3 casinos.
You track down Gabriel?
Nah. He's with his girlfriend,
making up for lost Nicky time.
[Laughs]
Pug:
Come on. Hey, let's go get a drink.
Merlin:
I should go and check on Romeo.
Go smile on
the motherfucker in love.
shooot.
You know what?
I'll meet you in the bar.
[Door Opens]
[Breathing Heavily]
Aw, flap.
Hmm.
[Beeps]
Come on, give me something.
If I can flaping hot-wire cars,
I should flaping
hot-wire a hotel door.
- [Beeps]
- Yeah, there we go.
Damn.
[Door Closes]
Who's slamming doors?
[Beeps]
How you doing?
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
[Sighs]
shooot.
Ahh.
Damn.
Ashley:
Hey.
Nick.
Where should we go?
Huh, baby?
When we're gone from here,
when we can do anything,
where should we go?
I don't know about you.
I'm going home.
We go together, remember?
Wherever.
Well, I'm going home.
Tomorrow's Christmas eve, my love.
My love.
Tomorrow's Christmas eve.
And your charges, sir.
Happy holidays.
[Music Playing Faintly]
Ohh!
Ho ho!
That's for the hundred bucks
worth of pay-per-view.
Uhh!
That's for the 200
you took out of the minibar.
That's enough.
It was on my credit card!
I figured since you guys
were paying for the room...
[Rudy Coughs]
So...
[Rudy Groans]
you wanted a weapon, convict?
Aah! No! Don't!
[Men Laugh]
Well, now, look at
what Santa's dwarves
have brought you.
Merlin:
What do you say to Santa's dwarves?
It's elves...
Santa's elves.
You say,
"Thank you," motherfucker.
[Laughter]
Rudy:
You hang around with criminals,
you end up making
a lot of plans.
But all the jobs
I ever pulled,
all the cars I ever stole,
no plan ever went down
the way it had been drawn up.
My plans to escape never worked,
and being on parole,
going to the police
wasn't an option.
What's the matter?
You nervous?
Right now,
you're just a truck driver.
You haven't done
anything wrong yet.
If you do this, you're going
to spend the rest of your life
wishing you hadn't.
Pug:
Thanks for the reminder, Nick.
Relax.
Have a drink.
# Rum pum pum pum pum #
[Laughs]
Ain't that your thing?
Pug:
Hey, hey! Thirsty!
This diversion you're doing...
you'd better do it just
the way Monster planned,
or there ain't going to be
no more rest of your life.
And all through the house,
not a creature was stirring.
[Children Talking On TV]
Why don't you send
most of your boys home, Ed?
Tom, why don't you go spend
Christmas with your family?
Ed:
Don, you can shove off.
Merry Christmas, Jack.
Man On TV:
Good to see you again.
Girl On TV:
Nice to see you.
Nobody even
comes here to cheat.
Rudy:
Ho ho ho!
Hello!
Eggnog for everyone.
Santa's here.
Good to see you.
Merry Christmas.
And we'd like some money, please.
We're here to win money.
Do you have any money?
How are you gentlemen
doing tonight?
Very good, Captain,
except that we're out of work.
Seasons greetings.
He's from Lindstrom's.
I'm from Save-Away.
How you doing?
No more toys for the kiddies,
but we do have
charitable donations.
All right, fellas, in?
[Jingle Bells Playing]
Hey, sweetheart,
how you doing?
I'm flaping freezing.
What can I get you?
- 21.
- Oh, Jesus.
You just hit from my cards.
I'm sorry, mister.
Dealer:
Dealer has 18.
And look at that, Grandpa.
Yeah. I'm going
to win your sled.
Heh heh heh!
Save-Away.
Over here.
I saved you a seat.
Play my hand.
Lindstrom's.
How you doing?
Aren't you going to take
those beards off?
No, I'm not going
to take those beards off.
This is my lucky beard.
Mind my beard.
Watch out for this guy.
He's a flaping jinx.
OK, Santa number 3,
what can I get you?
Could the fat man
with the flying horses
get quarters, please?
Watch my bank.
All right.
5, 9.
No way.
Pop, you're...
Goddamn it, you're
hitting from my card. No.
You don't even know
what it is.
He doesn't hit.
Why don't you go
find a chimney somewhere
and fall in, huh?
Rudy:
Son of a bitch!
You are killing me here.
That's the way it goes. Ha!
Ed:
There's 2 more coming.
Bangs:
There you go.
That's what I like to see.
Now, that's the spirit.
Jack, is there a union
for department store Santas?
Hey, who the flap knows?
Then go get another table!
For old people!
You're old!
You're taking Santa's money!
There is no other table.
Oh, bullshit!
Rudy: What kind of a people
cheat Santa Claus?
Waitress:
What the hell are you doing?
Security!
- Hey!
- Rudy: You took it!
You're... You're cheating me!
Officer:
Hey, pal! Come here, buddy!
Lay down, Pop.
It's all right.
- Come on!
- Stay down.
Santa Claus is kicking
the shooot out of your guards.
The security room...
Right at the top of the stairs.
Right, right.
Take a right.
Security room. He...
flap.
That flaping convict. Jeez!
Turn off the flaping alarm!
What the heck?
Get away from the desk!
Drop them!
Put the guns down!
Merlin:
Drop them!
[People Yelling]
Aah!
[Gunshots]
Get down!
Put the guns down!
Put them down!
Ahh!
Christ!
[Firing Gun]
Here it is, motherfucker.
Aah!
Ahh!
[Gun Cocks]
[Gunshot]
I don't like you!
Your piss is all you need, Romeo.
Shut up!
Shut the flap up!
Everybody!
[Shouting]
Cuff them.
Cuff them!
Come on!
Oh, no.
Oh, no, listen, no.
No. Please don't
do this here, OK?
Please... Please don't do
this to me, all right?
Listen.
Bangs:
Look, let me tell you something.
This... This is not the...
This is just not another
card club, all right?
This is the Tomahawk Casino.
We're an international
gaming destination.
We're in guidebooks.
Show's over.
Move, goddamn you!
These guys aren't
flaping around. Let's move.
Get in there.
Go ahead. Just... Just
do what my friends say.
They're a little bit...
disturbed.
[Locks Door]
Pug: What's the security code
for the count room!
Code? What code?
Just use the key!
Nick said code!
Who the flap is Nick?!
Oh.
- Ahh!
- [Gunshot]
Aah!
[Gunshots]
Drop your guns!
Throw your guns down!
Show your hands!
Drop that gun!
[Officers Shouting]
All right, all right,
all right, all right!
Drop it now!
You motherfucker!
No guns in the count room!
Merlin:
flap you!
Put them up in the air!
shooot!
Merlin:
No guns in the count room!
Forget about him
and get the money!
Ashley: Forget about him
and get the flaping money!
Forget about him.
There's no future for people
like you and me, Nick.
Ha ha!
The places we come from...
bland towns, mill towns,
small lives.
No future,
just more of the same.
If you want a future,
you got to stand up and steal it.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
The Powwow Safe!
I want the Powwow Safe!
Where is it?
I can't... I can't move back
to Las Vegas.
I do not give a shooot
about Vegas!
The money is in the car.
Let's get out of here right now.
He won't tell us where it is.
- Ashley: What?
- Gabriel: The Powwow Safe.
Remember Nick Cassidy?
A security guard
named Nick Cassidy?
Yeah, Nick Cassidy.
Where is he?
Gabriel, we have enough money.
Let's get the flap out of here.
Where is he?
Not Nick Cassidy.
Nick Cassidy worked
for me 2 years ago.
Cowboy.
Hop along.
[Laughs]
That's the story
of your life, Ash.
You fucked the wrong guy.
Rudy Duncan, honey.
We still gonna spend
Christmas together?
You flaping bastard!
Hey, hey, hey.
No! Goddamn it!
You are lucky, convict.
You're going to be
spending Christmas
with the birthday boy himself.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
There is a Powwow Safe,
all right?
There is a Powwow Safe.
I did time with
Nick Cassidy, right?
Rudy:
Some shooot, he told me.
Some shooot, I remember.
He told me the manager
keeps a secret stash
in his office...
a Powwow Safe.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- No! There is no safe!
He's stalling us!
There's no safe!
Rudy: I overheard it.
There is a Powwow Safe.
Ashley:
He's been stalling us from day one.
- There's no safe.
- There's a Powwow Safe.
Rudy:
I heard him.
Then where the flap is it?
Behind the liquor cabinet.
Oh, Jesus.
[Laughs]
Hey, hey.
- Get up.
- Please.
Get up. Open it.
I can't go back to Vegas.
I don't give a flap
about that!
Get up!
Open it!
Hurry up!
Bangs:
Oh, God. I can't go back.
Pow...
wow.
Powwow.
Jumpy:
Aah!
Ohh!
Hey, Santa Claus!
Welcome to the Tomahawk!
[Both Grunt]
Rudy:
Oh, shooot.
[Machine Gun Fire In Casino]
Yes!
Uhh!
No!
Get up.
[Liquid Dripping]
[Laughs]
Yeah.
God is good.
Merlin:
Now...
what do you say...
to Santa's dwarves?
Hmm?
You say, "Thank you."
Merlin:
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
[Blows]
Uhh!
[Sirens]
Never make
the same mistake twice.
[Laughs]
You just did.
[Sirens]
The wrong guy.
We took the place down
with the wrong guy.
Is this Christmas, huh?
[Laughs]
Gabriel:
Is this Christmas?
God bless us, every one.
Gabriel:
Come on. Unh!
Uhh!
Smart, aren't you?
So smart. You're smarter
than everybody, huh?
Powwow Safe.
A little gift for us
in the Powwow Safe, huh?
Well, I got
a gift for you
from Pug and Merlin
and Jumpy,
you son of a bitch.
You're going where they went.
And they're going
to find you there,
and they're going to
kick your flaping ass!
You feel smart? Huh?
You think you're lucky?
Well, let's see
how lucky you are!
Come on!
Here's how lucky you are.
You got out of the Tomahawk,
into your car,
made it halfway to Canada
until you caught
some ice on the road.
Get down there!
Take a look.
By the time you hit
the bottom down there,
the whole car
was burning like a comet.
Must've burned up
all that money, too.
Was it your idea,
Monster, or was it hers?
Well, she told me about
the convict magazines.
Had to figure there'd be
some guys in the pen
with some useful knowledge
with nobody to talk to
and nobody to listen,
so...
we just stocked up
on stationery.
Gabriel: It's a hard life
being a trucker's girl.
Oh.
- Baby.
- [Laughs]
Come here.
I saved your life.
You shouldn't have.
He really loved you,
you know that?
Rudy:
Nick...
he really loved you.
Who wouldn't?
[Laughs]
Rudy: Maybe this is where
you wanted him, Ashley...
some stranger
at the bottom of a ravine
with a burned-up heart.
Maybe.
Rudy:
But it didn't happen,
because what you did for him,
you made him the happiest
he'd ever been.
Shut up.
Get up. Come on.
Get in the car.
Hey. Hey!
Gabriel.
Don't go getting
all noble with me, Rudy.
Guy takes a shiv for you,
Ashley:
you go chasing his girlfriend?
Don't talk to me about greed.
What? What did you say?
I said don't talk to me
about greed.
No, not about that...
about you said
a guy takes a shiv for you.
I never said anything about a shiv.
Rudy:
How'd you know there was a shiv?
You said the real Nick
died saving you.
No, I didn't.
I said he died.
Rudy:
I never said how.
- Yes, you did.
- No.
I never said how.
I said he died.
You said he was stabbed.
I never said how.
Ashley:
You said he was stabbed,
that he took a shiv...
a knife, a shank, whatever.
Ash?
How'd she know there was a shiv?
How'd she know?
Jesus Christ.
Men.
Ohh! Ahh!
Uhh.
Ohh.
[Person Whistling Silver Bells]
[Whistling]
Merry Christmas, Rudy.
[Nick Chuckles]
We made it, baby.
[Laughing]
Oh, yes, we did.
We made it.
Got a little messy, but...
I'll tell you all about that
once we're on the road.
For your information...
I never flap the wrong guy.
Nick:
So...
Rudy...
I want you to meet Millie Bobeck.
Remember Millie Bobeck,
don't you?
Nick:
My girlfriend, before I went in.
Worked at that bar in Motor City
where I manslaughtered
what's-his-name.
See...
Millie here,
she used to serve drinks
to these gun-running truckers.
Real big talkers,
schemin' about
a real score one day.
2 years in the Mountain,
man, what the hell?
Why not let her
get friendly with them?
Tell them her real name
was Ashley.
Tell them about
this idea she had,
about writing guys in prison.
Millie:
Find a sucker
who could show them
a sure thing.
Ohh.
Millie:
You know...
they would've never done it
without you, Nick.
Tsk.
[Sighs]
I mean, Rudy.
Nick: I always wanted
to rob that casino, Rudy.
Way back when I worked there.
What better way than to get
some guys to rob it for me?
Paid the Alamo a hundred
to put the shiv in me.
Nick: He's a lifer, man,
what does he care?
He was supposed to stab me
in the yard later that day,
but when that food fight
started, man...
I couldn't believe it.
The slash across the ribs,
the homemade blood capsule,
Nick:
gets you a nice, warm hospital bed.
Paid a guard to spread
the word I bought it.
And once the wound healed up,
got out of the Mountain
this morning.
Nick:
Tonight, I am a rich man.
Get in the car.
Keep your gun on him, honey.
How'd you know I'd do it?
Because every time
I read her letters, Rudy,
you listened.
Nick:
Besides, man,
even if you hadn't taken the bait,
we still had a shot.
She'd just have to convince them
they could do it alone.
What do you know?
Good old Rudy came through.
Good old predictable Rudy.
Nick:
Goes for the easy money,
every time.
5 Santas walked into
that Tomahawk, Rudy.
That's what the witnesses will say.
So, we gotta have 5 Santas
not walk out.
Gotta have 5.
[Scoffs] How many things
could have gone wrong?
Huh? A thousand?
You think we don't know
what a long shot is? Huh?
My girl Millie
was steering you, man.
Nick: You fucked it up,
she would've cut and run.
They'd be looking
for Ashley Mercer.
Whoever she is.
6 months of telling you
Tomahawk stories.
Guess now you know why.
[Door Closes]
You gave them the confidence
to walk in there, Nick Cassidy.
Nick:
That's all we needed you to do.
You said some nice things
about me, man.
Appreciate it.
You know what?
You're right.
I do love her.
Nick:
And she...
she loves me.
You had that part right
all along.
[Chuckles]
It's Christmas, sugarplum.
Let's light up the tree.
Nick:
Uhh.
Rudy:
shooot.
Uhh! Uhh!
Write me.
Ha ha ha.
Aw, shooot.
It's like ridin' a bike,
like ridin' a bike.
Good-bye, Rudy, my man.
Nick:
Nice spending... time with ya!
Uhh!
[Engine Starts]
Rule one... never put a car thief
behind the wheel!
Aah!
No.
No!
Millie:
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Uhh!
Millie: 5 Santas walked
into that Tomahawk, Rudy.
That's what
the witnesses will say.
So, we gotta have 5 Santas
not walk out.
Gotta have 5.
Nick:
Rudy.
Rudy, you and me, man.
You and me.
[Stammers]
We can split the money,
huh? Hmm?
Rudy, that whore,
Millie Bobeck?
Did you think I was
serious about her, man?
Nick:
I was gonna kill her!
You gotta believe me.
You gotta believe me,
I swear it.
Nick:
Believe me!
Believe this.
Rudy!
Rudy, help me!
Nick:
Rudy!
[Engine Starts]
Singers:
# Come, they told me #
# Pa-rum-pa-pa-pum #
# A newborn King to see #
# Our finest gifts we bring #
# Pa-rum-pa-pa-pum #
# To lay before the King #
# Rum-pa-pa-pum #
# So to honor Him #
# Pa-rum-pa-pa-pum #
# When we come #
# I have no gift to bring #
# Pa-rum-pa-pa-pum #
# That's fit to give a king #
# Rum-pa-pa-pum #
Rudy, voice-over:
All I wanna do
is make it back to Sidnaw,
sit down for Christmas dinner,
watch some ball with my old man,
sleep in my old bed,
have leftovers
for about 6 months,
eat some of that
Christmas turkey.
Like I said,
I never was much
for the holidays...
until now.
Synchronized By : Eng.Taki